<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>The effect of soil amendment and irrigation schedule on growth and yield of onion (Allium cepa L.) and seasonal irrigation applied.</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ramalan</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A.A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Agricultural Engineering Department, Ahmadu Bello University, PMB 1044, Zaria, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>An experiment was conducted at the Irrigation Research Farm of the Institute for Agricultural Research Samaru, Zaria, Nigeria (11°11′N, 7°23′E, 686 m above sea level) to assess the influence of applying soil amendment and irrigation schedule on onion growth, yield and irrigation applied. The amendment, Alcosorb 400, at rates 0, 300, 600, 900 kg ha-1 and irrigation schedule at fixed frequency of 7 days, and soil moisture tension of 30 and 60 cb were combined in a factorial experiment laid out in a randomized complete block design in three replications. Results showed significant influence of the amendment on leaf length at 16 weeks after transplanting and leaf yield. At the rate of 300 kg ha-1, leaf length and leaf yield were highest at 35.60 cm and 6.22 t/ha respectively. While bulb yield and seasonal irrigation applied were unaffected by the application of the amendment, they were both influenced by irrigation schedule. The highest yield of 17.72 t/ha was obtained with the 7 day fixed interval of irrigation. At 30 and 60 cb, significant decline resulted in yields of 12.25 and 10.63 t/ha respectively. The maximum seasonal irrigation depth was 482 mm of water. The interactions of Alcosorb 400 with irrigation schedule were found not significant (p=5 %).</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>137</start>
          <end>140</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_3&amp;4/agriculture-6.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>