<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Adoption rate and continued use of selected arable crop technologies among farmers in Oyo State Nigeria</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Oladele</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">O. I.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development, University of Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Kareem</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A. I.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development, University of Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Adoption and continued use of any new technology is a dynamic process which will change over time and may be influenced by a wide range of factors such as changes in funding, administration, linkage system and delivery system will reflect in the sustained use of technologies. A multi-stage random sampling process was used to select one hundred and eighty farmers representing ten percent of the farmers. 72.2% were high adopters while the remaining 27.8% were in the low adopter category. For maize and cassava, fertilizer use and fertilizer application have the least adoption rate 75.6% and 30.6% respectively. For cowpea planting distance, storage practices, seed dressing, and spraying and for yam the use of improved varieties, seed/sett dressing had the lowest adoption rate. In the total continued use of the technologies tested about 16 percent have a score 1- 24 and they are regarded as low continued users. 34.3% of the respondents still using 25-36 of the adopted technologies they classified as medium continued user. High continued user are those farmers that are still using 37-48 (49.4%) of the tested technologies.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>291</start>
          <end>294</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_3&amp;4/environment-11.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>