<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>FYM, lime, and magnesium induced yield of jute (Chorchorus capsularis L.) and nutrient availability in acid tarai soil of eastern India</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Bandyopadhyay</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Prasanta K.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Chemistry and Soil Science, Bidhan Chandra Krishi Viswavidyalaya, Mohanpur, West Bengal, 741252, India.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Jute (Corchorus capsularis L.), the source of golden fibre is one of the major crops grown in eastern India, especially in the state of West Bengal. A field experiment was conducted at the University farm, Coochbehar (26°19′N, 89°23′E and 43 m above mean sea level), on an acid Entisol in the humid tropical tarai agroclimatic zone of West Bengal with Jute (cv. JRC 321) to study the direct effect of FYM, lime and magnesium sulphate along with recommended doses of NPK fertilizers application on the fibre yield and their residual effect on nutrient availability in the soil. There were increase in CEC and exchangeable Ca and Mg content of the soil and the availability of residual NPK due to application of FYM. Incorporation of lime and magnesium sulphate alone or in combination decreased the exchange as well as pH dependent acidity through increasing high base saturation while lowering the exchangeable Al3+ to nil. The available NPK increased significantly with liming. Jute crop responded significantly in terms of yield, and the highest yield was observed with the application of FYM, which was at par with lime treated plots followed by magnesium sulphate in combination with lime, and magnesium sulphate alone.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>194</start>
          <end>196</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_3&amp;4/agriculture-16.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>