<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600001">
      <dc:title>The use of remote sensing and geographic information systems for irrigation management in Southwest Europe</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., López-Francos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Montesinos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.-P., Berthoumieu</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical information systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water management</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The loss of competitiveness and the abandonment of agricultural activities in many rural areas of Southwest Europe are worsened by problems related to water shortage and the rise in natural hazards such as droughts. Remote sensing and geographic information systems offer a huge potential to improve water management in agriculture, as they are able to provide a great amount of relatively cheap information, which can be automated, and processed and analysed for a wide range of agronomic, hydraulic and hydrological purposes. New developments in ICTs allow the products of those technologies to be easily available for end-users for practical applications. This publication is a result of the TELERIEG project (Use of remote sensing for irrigation practice recommendation and monitoring in the SUDOE space, SOE1-P2-E082, 2009-2011), co-financed by the Programme Interreg IVB-Sudoe of the EU-ERDF, with the participation of 9 beneficiary institutions from France, Portugal and Spain. The final target was to achieve a better environmental protection through more efficient and rational management of water resources in agriculture and a more effective prevention and response against natural risks. The project has generated a vigilance and recommendations system for vast areas. Specifically, data collection, information analysis and decision-making services were developed, based on geographical information systems (GIS) and remote sensing, allowing water users and managers to have timely information and a useful decision-making tool for irrigation water management. The chapters of this book were part of the learning and support materials prepared by the lecturers of the international course on “The use of remote sensing for irrigation management”, organised by the Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Zaragoza in November 2011, with the aim of disseminating the knowledge and tools created by TELERIEG and by other initiatives in the field of the application of remote sensing to agricultural water management. The chapters collect information at different levels: generalities on remote sensing and the theoretical basis of its application to agriculture, methodologies for specific measurements and applications, and field experiences and case studies. The book is accompanied by a DVD containing additional materials which were used for the course, such as presentations, teaching practical materials (images and data), software practicals and the pdf version of the book chapters.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/b67.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 239</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600002">
      <dc:title>The TELERIEG Project</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., López-Francos</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Decision support systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>INSPIRE</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>SUDOE</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>TELERIEG</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The TELERIEG (The use of remote sensing for irrigation practice, recommendation and monitoring in the SUDOE space, www.telerieg.net), co-financed by the Interreg IVB SUDOE Programme of the European Union, has spent three years of activity with the objective of developing knowledge and tools on the application of remote sensing and geographic information systems for the improvement of irrigation water management and the response to natural risks affecting agriculture in the Southwest of Europe. The main results include an automated image processing that generates daily maps with useful parameters for irrigation management, and a geoportal adapted to the INSPIRE Directive, made up of large databases of agroclimatic and cartographic information, as well as utilities and tools based on geographic information systems and remote sensing allowing users to calculate irrigation requirements at plot scale. A collaboration network has been created of institutions working in the field of remote sensing and irrigation water management, using the most advanced techniques of high resolution images processing for estimation of agronomic parameters at field scales. All these results have been disseminated at local and international scale, covering mainly the project areas of Southwestern Europe but also other Mediterranean countries. The technologies developed by TELERIEG can contribute to improvements in optimization of the agricultural production factors mainly water.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006590.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 7-13</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600003">
      <dc:title>Background of TELERIEG project</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.-P., Berthoumieu</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water management</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Irrigation management is now possible by monitoring plant and soil water status in a special location in a field that is supposed to well represent a larger surface. This place, used as a reference, is often equipped with point sensors (as EnviroScan and others) to measure the precise variation of the available water into the root zone. Completed with weather forecast it enables a decision taking about the best moment and best amount of irrigation, preventing any risk of stress by lack of water or lack of air (brief saturation with anoxia) and reducing diffuse pollution by drainage (see PRECIRIEG project, www.precirieg.net). As it is quite expensive and time consuming to install probes in many locations the TELERIEG (www.telerieg.net) project is trying to reveal the potential of remote sensing tools in order to extend the principles of precise irrigation advice over larger irrigated areas. In this article we describe the different objectives and principal findings that are presented in other papers in this book.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006591.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 15-24</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600004">
      <dc:title>Geographic information systems: data versus information. Introduction to remote sensing</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Montesinos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Fernandes</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Data</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Information</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In a modern society, decision-making process realised by managers or planners must be based on true information which has been obtained from reliable and consistent data. Geographic Information Systems are tools that allows us to convert pre-existing data into information Remote sensing is defined as the ability to obtain information from an object without physical contact with it. Remote sensing term is restricted to all methods that use the reflected or irradiated electromagnetic energy of objects.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006592.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 25-30</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600005">
      <dc:title>Generation and interpretation of images</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Montesinos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Fernández</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Digital image processing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Information recording</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>A digital image is a representation of a real object using a numerical two-dimensional matrix where each element is called pixel. The digital process is the set of numerical transformations performed on the original matrix to obtain more appropriate representations of the image, depending on applications. Restoration processes are aimed to eliminate the radiometric errors sounds and geometric distortions generated during the compilation and transmission of data. The highlight consists on a set of techniques to improve the visual interpretation of the image. The multitemporal and multispectral character of remote sensing data allows transformations that produce new components or bands of the image.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006593.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 31-36</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600006">
      <dc:title>Spanish National Remote Sensing Program, a way to achieve massive use of remote sensing data</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.J., Peces</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>G., Villa</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Arozarena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>N., Plaza</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.A., Tejeiro</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>E., Domenech</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Image processing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>PNT</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Satellite imagery</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Spain</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Spanish National Remote Sensing Program (PNT) provides regular coverage of the Spanish territory with current and historical satellite imagery. This imagery is acquired with multi-user licenses for all Spanish Public Institutions, and processed once with geometric and radiometric processing agreed by experts of Spanish scientific community, and it is distributed to all users from Spanish Public Institutions. This way, we promote the massive use of remote sensing data. Spanish imagery is structured in three levels of spatial and temporal resolution: (i) High resolution: Images from 2 to 10 m of spatial resolution in panchromatic mode and from 10 to 30 m in multispectral mode. It is acquired a complete coverage every year with summer images. From 2005 to nowadays SPOT5 satellite is selected to provide that type of resolution. In future, with Spanish high resolution satellite called Ingenio, we will have several annual coverages. (ii) Medium resolution: Images from 10 to 15 m of spatial resolution in panchromatic mode and from 20 to 50 m in multispectral mode. It was planned to acquire at least four coverages every year, but since January 2008 all Landsat5 (TM) imagery captured over Spain is acquired. During 201, as well, Spot4 and Deimos1 images are being acquired. (iii) Low resolution: Multispectral images from 50 to 1000 m of spatial resolution, with a periodicity of 1 or 2 days. MODIS and MERIS sensors are the main source of this type of resolution. Nowadays, in PNT, more than 2000 images are processed every year to obtain derivate products such us georeferenced images, mosaics of images, etc. To reduce the time between the collection of data and the moment the information is available, PNT has designed a storage infrastructure suitable to the volume of information, an appropriate workflow, distribution control and an efficient spreading.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006594.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 37-46</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600007">
      <dc:title>Introduction to ILWIS GIS tool</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Montesinos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Fernández</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>ILWIS</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land management</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water management</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>ILWIS for Windows is a Windows-based, integrated GIS and Remote Sensing application consisting of: (i) Display of raster and multiple vector maps in map windows; (ii) Display of tables in table windows; (iii) Interactive retrieval of attribute information, (iv) Image processing facilities, (v) Manipulation of maps in a Map Calculator; (vi) Manipulation of tables in a Table Calculator; (vii) GIS analysis tools and (viii) Script language to perform \'batch\' jobs. With Windows, you can start one operation and keep it running while you start one or more additional applications. This is a sort of multitasking. You may work with both Windows and DOS application programs, you can perform one or more ILWIS calculations in the background and at the same time display maps, run other ILWIS operations, print, etc. http://52north.org/communities/ilwis/.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006595.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 47-52</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600008">
      <dc:title>Use of remote sensing for the calculation of biophysical indicators</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>Z., Hernández</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>D., Sánchez</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Pecci</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>D.S., Intrigiolo</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Albedo</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Evapotranspiration</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>LST</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NDVI</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NOAA-AVHRR</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>SUDOE</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Telerieg</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In recent years, remote sensing has emerged as one of the most useful tools in agronomy. A series of biophysical indicators can be derived from satellite images and become inputs for decision support systems in irrigation management, crop planning or determination of crop yields, thus achieving a better management of resources. An automated system implemented under the Telerieg project provides these indicators on a daily rate to aid in decision-making.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006596.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 55-63</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600009">
      <dc:title>Assessment of vegetation indexes from remote sensing: theoretical basis</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S.G., García Galiano</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Indicators</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vegetation index</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Uncertainties in agricultural activities due to the scarcity of water and the increase in droughts could be ameliorated by considering early detection and spatio-temporal characterization of water stress conditions at a regional scale from remote sensing. Theoretical aspects of the spatio-temporal assessment of vegetation indexes related with soil moisture, based on remote sensing and meteorological data are presented.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006597.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 65-75</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600010">
      <dc:title>Estimation of irrigated crops areas: generation of water demand scenarios</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Montesinos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Fernández</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Demand</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Mapping</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vegetation index</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The study of the evolution of agricultural demand is one of the most significant aspects for water management, not only due to the specific weight that it represents inside the global river basin demand, but also to the difficulty to estimate it. The irrigated area map is elaborated from digital processing of available satellite images, and is based in the analysis, interpretation and classification of vegetation index maps, where numerical information is collected and is linked with the photosynthetic activity rate, vegetation cover vigour and vegetation vigour within each crop.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006598.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 79-84</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600011">
      <dc:title>Remote sensing based water balance to estimate evapotranspiration and irrigation water requirements. Case study: grape vineyards</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>I., Campos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Boteta</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>C., Balbontín</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Fabião</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Maia</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Calera</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Evapotranspiration</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Soil water balance</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vegetation index</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vineyards</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water requirements</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In this paper the basis for the incorporation of remote sensing data into a soil water balance through the relationship between the basal crop coefficient (Kcb) and vegetation indices (VI) for grape vineyards is described. The remote sensing soil water balance has been applied in previous studies obtaining accurate estimates of actual evapotranspiration and crop coefficient in grape vineyard, and this methodology is evaluated in order to estimate irrigation necessities in an irrigated vineyard in Albacete, Spain. The model was also applied in vineyards under high deficit irrigation management. The model results: total irrigation necessities, crop evapotranspiration, and water stress coefficient (Ks) are analyzed. The evolution of Ks was compared with experimental measurements of stem water potential ((s). Ks calculated present values between 0.2 and 0.4 during July and August, indicating severe stress levels. The s tendency coincides with the modelled Ks, showing a parallel evolution and values of about -1.4 MPa during the stress period. The evidences presented indicate that Kcb derived from VI overestimate the actual crop coefficient under water stress conditions. In these cases, it is therefore essential to properly estimate the stress coefficient in order to accurately estimate actual crop evapotranspiration and crop coefficient.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006599.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 85-94</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600012">
      <dc:title>Models for assessment of actual evapotranspiration from remote sensing: theoretical basis</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S.G., García Galiano</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Baille</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Evapotranspiration</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NDVI</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In the evaluation of the onset, severity and duration of situations of water stress and droughts, indicators based on processes with intensive use of remote sensing can be used. In the monitoring of agricultural activities as well as the management of water and forest resources, spatio-temporal distributions of information of actual evapotranspiration (ETact) are crucial. This work presents the theoretical aspects of spatio- temporal assessment of ETact process, from remote sensing and meteorological data.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006600.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 95-103</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600013">
      <dc:title>Estimation of actual evapotranspiration from remote sensing: application in a semiarid region</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S.G., García Galiano</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>R., García Cárdenas</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Evapotranspiration</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NDVI</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The potential of remote sensing for the recommendation and monitoring of irrigation practices is irrefutable. GIS have enabled the development of operational spatio-temporal tools for monitoring agricultural activity which can overcome the uncertainty brought about by problems related to water scarcity and increasing drought events. This paper presents an operational methodology for estimating actual evapotranspiration from Landsat images, and its application in the Region of Murcia (Spain).</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006601.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 105-117</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600014">
      <dc:title>Thermostress. An automatic imaging process for assessing plant water status from thermal photographs</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M.A., Jiménez-Bello</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>C., Ballester</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.R., Castel</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>D.S., Intrigliolo</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Thermography</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Image analysis</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Leaf temperature can be used for monitoring plant water status. Nowadays, by means of thermography, canopy temperature can be remotely determined. In this sense, it is crucial to automatically process the images. In the present work, a methodology for the automatic analysis of frontal images taken on individual trees was developed. The camera used in this investigation took at the same time thermal and visible scenes, so it was not necessary to overlap the images. During the processing in batch no operator participated. This was done by means of a non supervised classification of the visible image from which the presence of sky and soil was detected. In case of existence, a mask was performed for the extraction of intermediated pixels to calculate canopy temperature by means of the thermal image. Sunlit and shady leaves could be detected and isolated. Thus, the procedure allowed to separately determine canopy temperature either of the more exposed part of the canopy or of the shaded portion. The methodology developed was validated using images taken in several regulated deficit irrigation trials in persimmon and two citrus trees cultivars (Clementina de Nules and Navel Lane-Late). Overall, results indicated that similar canopy temperatures were calculated either by means of the automatic process or the manual procedure. In addition, differences in midday stem water potential and stomatal conductance among irrigation treatments were associated with differences in canopy temperature in persimmon trees. The procedure here developed here allowed to drastically reduce the time amount used for image analysis also considering that no operator participation was required. Indeed, the tool here proposed will facilitate further investigations in course for assessing the feasibility of using thermography for detecting plant water status in woody perennial crops with discontinuous canopies.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006602.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 121-129</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600015">
      <dc:title>The use of multispectral and thermal images as a tool for irrigation scheduling in vineyards</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Bellvert</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Girona</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Leaf water potential</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Multispectral imagery</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Thermal imagery</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Multispectral and thermal imagery were studied to evaluate the relationship between grapevine water status and Plant Cell Density index (PCD) and Crop Water Stress index (CWSI). Grapevine water status was determined with a pressure chamber by measuring the leaf water potential (leaf) of 184 grapevines distributed homogeneously within a 11 ha vineyard. Image acquisitions and leaf measures were obtained simultaneously at noon. Results showed that PCD could be useful to discriminate well-watered zones in a vineyard. However the relationship between PCD vs Psi leaf seemed to vary between different zones of the vineyard. This inconvenient did not exist with CWSI. The relationship between Psi leaf and crop-air temperature differential was strong and presented a high coefficient of determination (r2 equal to 0.714; P less than 0.0001) at noon. Accordingly, this methodology showed potential to be used as a tool for irrigation scheduling. Further studies should be directed to explore the convenience of CWSI measured at other moments of the day and the optimal thermal image resolution to obtain the best results.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006603.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 131-137</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600016">
      <dc:title>Study of the effects of irrigation on stem water potential and multispectral data obtained from remote sensing systems in woody crops</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.J., Alarcón</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>P., Pérez-Cutillas</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Precision agriculture</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>This study is part of the work carried out in experimental plots of different research centres (IMIDA, CEBAS, UPCT and IVIA) that are part of the TELERIEG project, with the aim of improving irrigation methods in irrigated crops in the region of Murcia, significantly contributing to a better management of drought. The work was carried out, on the one hand, on two parcels of citrus fruit (mandarin and grapefruit) where several different irrigation treatments were applied, which generated varying degrees of water stress on the studied trees. Three sources of irrigation water were also used, each one different in nature and quality, in order to study their impact on the development of crops. On the other hand, work was also carried out on a parcel of peach trees, where several different irrigation treatments were applied, which also generated varying degrees of water stress. This variability in tree water status was measured in the field through stem water potential at midday (Psi s), and from the air by capturing images with a multispectral camera to estimate the values of the near-infrared spectrum (NIR) and the normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI).</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006604.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 139-146</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600017">
      <dc:title>Use of remote sensing and geographic information tools for irrigation management of citrus trees</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M.A., Jiménez-Bello</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L.A., Ruiz</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>T., Hermosilla</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Recio</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>D.S., Intrigliolo</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Image analysis</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Cover plants</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The most widely used method for estimating crops water requirements is the FAO approach, which takes into account: (i) climatic variables included in the reference evapotranspiration and (ii) the crop type, characterized by the crop coefficient (Kc). In citrus trees, Kc is mostly function of the tree ground covers (GC). In large areas tree ground covers (GC) can be estimated by means of remote sensing tools, and once tree water needs are calculated, this information can be implemented in geographic information systems. The present article summarizes some of the research conducted in order to estimate citrus water needs in large irrigated areas. It describes first how tree ground covers (GC) can be obtained by using image analysis tools applied to multispectral images. Tree water needs are obtained and they are compared with the real water applications for a case study of citrus water use associations. The results obtained allowed to conclude that the tools developed might be useful for improving irrigation efficiency showing some of the deficiencies currently found in irrigation management of collective water networks.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006605.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 147-159</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600018">
      <dc:title>Automated extraction of agronomic parameters in orchard plots from high-resolution imagery</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Recio</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>T., Hermosilla</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L.A., Ruiz</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Efficiency</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Image analysis</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Trees</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Sensors</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The availability of high spatial resolution images obtained from aerial and satellite sensors together with the development of new image analysis methods are providing an important impulse to precision agriculture techniques and applications. We describe an automated methodology for the extraction of agronomic parameters from tree orchard plots based on the use of high-resolution remotely sensed imagery, which can be further used to increase the efficiency of irrigation and agricultural plot management in the SUDOE area. These methods are based on parcel-based image analysis, and a variety of parameters are obtained including tree detection, location and counting, planting patterns, tree crown, vegetation cover and others. Since common data and image processing techniques are used, they can be easily implemented in production processes and cover large agricultural areas. The methods are tested on citrus orchard plots located in Valencia (Spain), showing a good performance in particular for adult trees. In addition to the particular use of the ground cover for the estimation of water requirement, these parameters can also be used as support tools for agricultural inventories or database updating, allowing for the reduction of field work and manual interpretation tasks.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006606.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 161-174</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600019">
      <dc:title>Thermal infra-red remote sensing for water stress estimation in agriculture</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Labbé</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>V., Lebourgeois</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Jolivot</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>R., Marti</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Image analysis</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Monitoring</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vegetation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Thermal infrared images can be used to estimate vegetation water content of the plant and thus to locally adapt (precision agriculture) and globally adjust (sustainable management of water resources) irrigation water quantities. Thermal imaging cameras using micro-bolometer sensors loaded on light aerial vehicles are suitable to produce thermal images. These images are helpful for irrigation monitoring if they are: (i) coupled with simultaneous acquisition of images in the visible and near infrared bands; (ii) geometrically corrected to be superimposed with other images; and (iii) radiometrically corrected to take into account the drift of the thermal sensors and the effects of the atmosphere on the measured temperature.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006607.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 175-184</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600020">
      <dc:title>Contribution of airborne remote sensing to high-throughput phenotyping of a hybrid apple population in response to soil water constraints</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>N., Virlet</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Martínez</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>V., Lebourgeois</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Labbé</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.L., Regnard</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Genetic variation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Imagery</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Malus domestica</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In this study, we developed a remote sensing approach, normally applied to management of crop irrigation, with the purpose of phenotyping a plant population in the field. The experiment was performed on \'Starkrimson\' x \'Granny Smith\' apple progeny (122 hybrids, 4 replicates) at adult stage, cultivated in field on Diaphen platform (INRA Montpellier, France). Airborne images acquisition in RGB and NIR bands permit to compute the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), while differences between tree canopy surface measured by thermal IR imaging (Ts) and air temperature (Ta) made it possible to calculate water stress indices. The Water Deficit Index (WDI), derived from the Crop Water Stress Index (CWSI), was considered for its applicability to discontinuous plant cover. WDI was computed on each individual tree, and focused on its central zone (60 cm diameter buffer). The first results showed significant genotypic effects and drought effects for indices during imposed summer water shortage, without interaction between them. Moreover, this first experiment permits to determine field measurements that are necessary to validate the method, linking image interpretation and tree water status variables.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006608.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 185-191</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600021">
      <dc:title>Irrigation decision support system assisted by satellite. Alqueva irrigation scheme case study</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Maia</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>L., Boteta</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Fabião</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Santos</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Calera</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>I., Campos</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Water management</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Earth observation satellites</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NDVI</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Decision support systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>TELERIEG</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>AQUASTAR</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>EFMA</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>DEMETER</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>COTR</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>In irrigated farming systems is important to increase the processes for the rational use of water improvement, to achieve water maximum productivity, respecting the environment. For that, the Irrigation Advisory Services (IAS), included in the Irrigation Extension Services (IES) must be considered a regular instrument for the best irrigation management. To increase the IES efficiency, COTR proposed, firstly, with the development of the AQUASTAR-Alqueva project, and now within the TELERIEG project, to apply the irrigation scheduling methodology developed in the DEMETER project (Calera et al., 2005) to the Alqueva irrigation area (EFMA, Portugal), and based on that, develop the IES, based on Earth observation technologies and other information and communication technologies, which allows near real time to estimates the real crop water use at a large scale. In this work we intend to show the results and the operational side of the irrigation decision support system developed for the Alqueva irrigation scheme.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006609.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 195-201</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600022">
      <dc:title>Transpiration and water stress effects on water use, in relation to estimations from NDVI: application in a vineyard in SE Portugal</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M.I., Ferreira</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>N., Conceição</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Silvestre</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Fabião</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Vitis vinifera</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Crops</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>NDVI</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Remote sensing can give contributions to answer the classical questions in irrigation management: when to irrigate and how much (irrigation depth). In order to compare with estimations partially derived from remote sensing, evapotranspiration (ET) and its components (transpiration, T and soil evaporation, Es) as well as selected water stress indicators were measured in a commercial vineyard with deficit irrigation, in SE Portugal. A combination of micrometeorological, sapflow and microlysimeter methods were used to measure water flux densities. The seasonal results reported (2009) are explored in relation to T obtained from practical models based on meteorological data (reference ET, ETo), crop basal coefficients (Kcb) and stress coefficients (Ks) where the use of the normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is included. Results from stress cycles (2010) confirm the selection of predawn leaf water potential (PLWP) as water tress indicator for the purpose of the analysis. A preliminary conclusion, confirmed later, on the meaning of NDVI in the conditions of this study (-0.2 MPa greater than gt;PLWP greater than -0.7 MPa), suggested that it is not affected by short term but by long term water stress. Kcb measured and estimated from NDVI agreed generally well, with exceptions. The comparison between T measured and estimated from ETo.Kcb.Ks (being Ks obtained from PLWP) highlights the importance of Ks on T estimation. For practical uses, alternative tools to obtain Ks are proposed.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006610.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 203-208</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600023">
      <dc:title>Contribution of remote sensing in analysis of crop water stress. Case study on durum wheat</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>A., Jolivot</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>S., Labbé</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>V., Lebourgeois</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Drought stress</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigation</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Evapotranspiration</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>WDI</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>S-SEBI</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Precision irrigation requires frequent information on crop conditions spatial and temporal variability. Image-based remote sensing is one promising techniques for precision irrigation management. In this study, we investigated the use of broad band multispectral (visible, near infrared and thermal infrared bands) and thermal airborne imagery for the characterization of water status of durum wheat crop through two indices: the Water Deficit Index (WDI) and the Simplified Surface Energy Balance Index (S-SEBI). Comparisons between these two indices and the ratio between actual and potential evapotranspiration (AET-PET) show that such techniques are promising for precision irrigation management.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006611.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 209-216</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600024">
      <dc:title>Application of INSPIRE directive to water management on large irrigation areas</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>P., García</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., López</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Caro</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Atenza</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>D., Sánchez</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>Z., Hernández</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>R.M., García</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>R.P., García</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Water management</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Irrigated land</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>INSPIRE</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>OGC</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The goal of this paper is to illustrate how INSPIRE can facilitate orientation and advice to calculate the water requirements of crops. These technologies can provide information adapted to specific conditions, updated daily and in an interactive way. These tools permit the integration and management of georeferenced agroclimatic data, soil maps, quality of waters, crop information and technical parameters of a farm. The final objective is to develop a decision support system to facilitate decision-taking processes in a comfortable and generic access on-line, incorporating different techniques and access into GIS data. The information technologies and in a more precise way, the new technologies, applied in different agriculture environments, can introduce important improvements in optimization of the agricultural production factors. Directive 2007/2/EC1 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 14 March 2007 establishing an Infrastructure for Spatial Information in the European Community (INSPIRE) entered into force on the 15th May 2011. INSPIRE lays down general rules to establish an infrastructure for spatial information in Europe for the purposes of Community environmental policies, and policies or activities which may have an impact on the environment. One of the aspects that INSPIRE regulates is the interoperability and harmonization of spatial data sets and services for 34 so-called data themes that are laid down in the three Annexes to the INSPIRE directive. These include land-cover, land-use and weather data.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006612.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 217-222</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600025">
      <dc:title>Soil salinity prospects based on the quality of irrigation water used in the Segura Basin</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>F., Alcón</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., Atenza</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.J., Alarcón</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Spain</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Agriculture</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Water</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Soil salinity</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Watersheds</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Geographical Information Systems</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>WATSUIT</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Segura river</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The main objective of this study was to determine the effect of the quality of irrigation water currently used in various agricultural demand units (ADU) on the soil-water salinity, assessing the effects of its use on crop yields and soils agronomic properties. The current state of the water quality used in all ADUs of the Segura Basin (Spain) was identified through sampling points located in surface and groundwater bodies. The geographical relationship established between water quality and crops in each ADU allowed a prospective analysis of the major agronomic risks of salinity, infiltration, toxicity by undesirable ions and the resulting environmental risks of soil degradation. WATSUIT software was used for each existing relationship between water bodies and ADUs. The results of this study provide geo-referenced knowledge of the current status of water quality and of the problems that its use may cause on the crops and the environment. It is also the starting point in establishing actions to increase the quality of irrigation water improving environmental conservation.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006613.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 223-229</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
								
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2014600026">
      <dc:title>Radar-aided understanding of semiarid areas: Maximum depression storage and storm motion</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J., García-Pintado</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>G., Barbera</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>M., Erena</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>J.A., Lopez</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>V.M., Castillo</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>F., Cabezas</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2012</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
																
      <dc:subject>Farmland</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Semiarid zones</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Flooding</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Hidrology</dc:subject>
																
      <dc:subject>Models</dc:subject>
												
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>Weather radar supports the estimation of accurate spatiotemporal rainfall inputs. These may be of great help to hone water management strategies, as those involving irrigation plans or flood risk analyses. If these strategies are supported by simulation models, the radar-based estimates should lead in turn to lower biases in estimates of model parameters and to improved model structures. E.g., flash floods pose a danger for life and property and, in semiarid agricultural areas, have a strong relationship with soil loss processes. Unfortunately, in arid and semiarid environment the runoff generation shows a complex nonlinear behavior with a strong spatiotemporal non-uniformity. Predictions by forecasting models are subject to great uncertainty and better descriptions of physical processes at the watershed scale need to be included into the operational modelling tools. We analyze a convective storm, in a 556 km2 semiarid Mediterranean watershed, with a complex multi-peak response. Radar was instrumental in the understanding and analysis of runoff generation. In the central area, a significant time-variability in the maximum depression storage resulted in the a posteriori model structure, pointing to failures in agricultural terraces and/or protection structures. Sensitivity analysis to storm motion indicates that a partial coverage upstream-moving storm on the infiltrating plane results in greater responses.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006614.pdf
																</dc:identifier>
      <dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN">2-85352-482-5</dc:identifier>
      <dc:type>Journal Article</dc:type>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p. 231-239</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">En</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.67()</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
				
</ags:resources>