<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600148">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Changes in North Africa production systems to meet climate uncertainty and new socio-economic scenarios with a focus on dryland areas]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Nefzaoui]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Ketata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., El Mourid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production system]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cereals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agropastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ruminants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feeds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Production systems in North Africa are typically marked by the scarcity of water resources throughout the region. This scarcity is expected to worsen and to negatively affect food security under the grim scenarios of climate change with a predicted 20% reduction of precipitation by the end of the century and 0.2oC temperature increase per decade in the coming 2 decades. Most affected areas are those of the pastoral and agro-pastoral systems where rainfall is both low and highly variable, and productivity is continuously threatened and indeed negatively by the unfavorable changing climate. A clear change is being witnessed through the evolving livelihood pattern, marked by a more sedentary living of local populations and a strong preference for more remunerating and less-labor intensive activities, including high value animal and plant products, such as niche products, honey, aromatic and medicinal plants, and offfarm derived income including handicraft and eco-tourism. In areas less affected by drought, lowland cerealbased systems including integration of intensive livestock production are dominant. In those areas farmers are more benefiting from technological advances including mechanized farming operations, supplemental irrigation of cereal and forage crops and occasional full irrigation of high value commodities, including fruits, vegetables, and highly nutritious forage crops for animal fattening and intensive dairy production. Mountainous regions have been traditionally neglected despite their rich biodiversity and more abundant water resources. Nonetheless, local populations in all regions are more and more proactively involved in deciding on the strategies to address the dilemma of securing better livelihood and conserving natural resources in a global environment marked by a relentless climate change.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006988.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 403-421]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600149">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Selection of oat varieties to the North of Morocco. Need of diffusion and renewal of the varieties]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Noutfia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., El Mourabit]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Alfaiz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plant diseases]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dry matter]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Oats]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Selection]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Oat is the main fodder culture in the Northern West region of Morocco where it is used as green, hay, silage or grain. However, the improvement of this culture faces several constraints related to the unavailability of varieties adapted to local conditions characterized by a long rainy period and development of many leaf diseases. This study summarizes the efforts in the selection and dissemination of high yielding varieties with a long development cycle and good resistance to foliar diseases. Five varieties namely Ghali, Tissir, Zahri, Amellal and Nasr, have been selected and recommended for the area. In experimental station, these varieties reach yields of 12 tons of dry matter (DM) and 4.5 tons of grain per hectare while some imported varieties capped at 6 and 3 tons per hectare of DM and grain respectively. In the field, new varieties record yields of 10 tons and 2.4 tons per hectare of DM and grain respectively, against only 6 tons of DM and 0.6 tons of grain per hectare for local seed widely used in the region.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006886.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 233-236]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600150">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Characterization of a local germplasm of sulla (Hedysarum coronarium) in the north of Morocco]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Noutfia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Mrabet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., El Mourabit]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Ayadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., El Othmani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evaluation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sulla]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chemical composition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dry matter]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the west-northern region of Morocco, the sulla (Hedysarum spp) an endemic forage plant is subject to severe genetic erosion that needs a special attention to preserve and to valorise this patrimony. In this context this study was carried out to collect and characterize local germplasm. Thirty ecotypes were collected and compared with Italian and Spanish varieties. Agronomic assessment showed that 80% of collected ecotypes were creeping types and 20% were upright ecotypes. They were conducted as monocropping and gave yield exceeding 10 tons per hectare of dry matter. Plant chemical analysis indicated that the local germplasm showed a higher protein content than Italian and Spanish varieties: 25.9, 23.1, and 14.1 per cent, res - pec tively. For the cellulose content, no significant differences were found among ecotypes (20 per cent of DM). As conclusion, since local germplasm presented better productivity indexes it is evident to conduct a breeding program for development of this crop as strategic feed resource for the region.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006885.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 229-232]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600151">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Reform of the CAP: Progress for grasslands and livestock farming?]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Peeters]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agri-environment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Public goods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Greening]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[CAP]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The European Commission (EC) presented recently a proposition for a reform of the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP) after 2013. This proposal continues some of the present objectives and includes new ones that take into account the enlargement to new Member States. The mechanisms designed by the EC for reaching these objectives, especially for the "Greening" component of pillar 1, are though very unlikely to succeed. The definition of permanent grassland is far too restrictive and inadequate. Seminatural grasslands and High Nature Value farmland are not specifically targeted although they are the most valuable ecosystems of the farmland area. Greening measures are too general, not targeted, not contractual and based on one-year farmers' commitments. They do not include farmers' advice and training, and a convincing control system. Most CAP expenditures should shift from pillar 1 to pillar 2 and the agrienvironmental scheme. In the medium term, CAP expenditures should support the emergence of a market of public goods (biodiversity, landscape and carbon storage mainly) supported by pillar 2 budget (public money for public goods!). An increase of the grassland area and the implementation of an efficient system for biodiversity conservation in agriculture are highly desirable.The European Commission (EC) presented recently a proposition for a reform of the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP) after 2013. This proposal continues some of the present objectives and includes new ones that take into account the enlargement to new Member States. The mechanisms designed by the EC for reaching these objectives, especially for the "Greening" component of pillar 1, are though very unlikely to succeed. The definition of permanent grassland is far too restrictive and inadequate. Seminatural grasslands and High Nature Value farmland are not specifically targeted although they are the most valuable ecosystems of the farmland area. Greening measures are too general, not targeted, not contractual and based on one-year farmers' commitments. They do not include farmers' advice and training, and a convincing control system. Most CAP expenditures should shift from pillar 1 to pillar 2 and the agrienvironmental scheme. In the medium term, CAP expenditures should support the emergence of a market of public goods (biodiversity, landscape and carbon storage mainly) supported by pillar 2 budget (public money for public goods!). An increase of the grassland area and the implementation of an efficient system for biodiversity conservation in agriculture are highly desirable.The European Commission (EC) presented recently a proposition for a reform of the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP) after 2013. This proposal continues some of the present objectives and includes new ones that take into account the enlargement to new Member States. The mechanisms designed by the EC for reaching these objectives, especially for the "Greening" component of pillar 1, are though very unlikely to succeed. The definition of permanent grassland is far too restrictive and inadequate. Seminatural grasslands and High Nature Value farmland are not specifically targeted although they are the most valuable ecosystems of the farmland area. Greening measures are too general, not targeted, not contractual and based on one-year farmers' commitments. They do not include farmers' advice and training, and a convincing control system. Most CAP expenditures should shift from pillar 1 to pillar 2 and the agrienvironmental scheme. In the medium term, CAP expenditures should support the emergence of a market of public goods (biodiversity, landscape and carbon storage mainly) supported by pillar 2 budget (public money for public goods!). An increase of the grassland area and the implementation of an efficient system for biodiversity conservation in agriculture are highly desirable.The European Commission (EC) presented recently a proposition for a reform of the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP) after 2013. This proposal continues some of the present objectives and includes new ones that take into account the enlargement to new Member States. The mechanisms designed by the EC for reaching these objectives, especially for the "Greening" component of pillar 1, are though very unlikely to succeed. The definition of permanent grassland is far too restrictive and inadequate. Seminatural grasslands and High Nature Value farmland are not specifically targeted although they are the most valuable ecosystems of the farmland area. Greening measures are too general, not targeted, not contractual and based on one-year farmers' commitments. They do not include farmers' advice and training, and a convincing control system. Most CAP expenditures should shift from pillar 1 to pillar 2 and the agrienvironmental scheme. In the medium term, CAP expenditures should support the emergence of a market of public goods (biodiversity, landscape and carbon storage mainly) s]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006825.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 29-34]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600152">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Agronomic evaluation of introduced accessions of Vicia narbonensis L. under contrasting environments and two years period]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Zoghlami Khélil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Hassen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Ben Salem]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Ben Youssef]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Subhumid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiarid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia narbonensis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This work aimed to evaluate agronomic and nutritive characteristics of 9 accessions of Vicia narbnonensis received from ICARDA under the framework of germoplasm exchange. They were evaluated in two contrasting locations (Oued Mliz, semi arid and Oued Béja, sub humid) during two cropping years (2009-2010 and 2010-2011) in comparison with two checks arranged in a randomised complete bloc design with three replications. Seed yields, pod and seed number, flowering date and winter vigour were scored. During first year, analysis of variance showed significant effects of site, accession and their interaction for all agronomic traits. Flowering and pod set are earlier in Oued Mliz while pod maturity was earlier in Oued Béja with highest number of pods. Seed number and seed weight were higher in Oued Mliz. Significant correlations were obtained between flowering and pod set and flowering and pods/plant. Among these accessions, 6 were selected and evaluated the following year. During second year, seed yield of these accessions was two times higher in Oued Béja. Based on yield and yield components, two accessions were released for cultivars registration.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006869.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 149-153]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600153">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Landraces of forage maize as source of genetic variability for organic farming]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.B., Monteagudo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Campo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Salleres]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Moreno]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Indigenous organisms]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organic agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Maize]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Concern for the preservation of the environment is a constant at present. The European Commi - ssion has developed specific directives to prevent pollution and degradation of the environment. In agriculture, organic farming is presented as an alternative to intensive agriculture that is more polluting and straining on natural resources. Most of the maize breeding materials currently commercialized are not adapted to organic farming conditions and the gene pool has been shrinking after years of genetic selection. Therefore, the landraces used in breeding programs could introduce new genes to obtain materials adapted to new agriculture systems. The aim of this work was to evaluate forage maize hybrids developed at Centro de Investigaciones Agrarias de Mabegondo (CIAM) under Organic Farming. These hybrids were obtained by crossing different Galician landraces with an inbred line which has Galician landrace background. These hybrids have shown good levels of genetic diversity of all studied traits. They were more vigorous and earlier than commercial ones. They had variability of fiber and lignin content but similar digestibility of in vitro organic matter, thus breeding programs could discern and exploit these traits. Therefore, landraces could provide new genes to current breeding programs in order to obtain materials more suited to new agricultural conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006884.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 223-227]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600154">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Research priorities for grassland science in the Eastern Mediterranean Region]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.P., Kyriazopoulos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rangelands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mismanagement]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean region]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Grasslands and rangelands have long been solely considered as a place for livestock grazing with no regard to the many other ecosystem goods and services that they provide. Mismanagement affects significantly the forage production and the biodiversity in the Mediterranean grasslands. The study of functional traits of plant species related to their response to grazing or other agronomic practices could contribute to the further understanding of various management effects on these ecosystems. For the appropriate management techniques to be applied, the multifunctionality of these ecosystems and the climatic change should be taken into account.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007009.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 523-526]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600155">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of juniper encroachment on herbage production and biodiversity in a natural grassland: Preliminary results]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.P., Kyriazopoulos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.M., Abraham]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z.M., Parissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Korakis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Manousidis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Chrisovelidou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Papanaretou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shrubs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biodiversity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Encroachment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Juniper]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The encroachment of woody species in natural grasslands has recently increased, especially in arid and semi-arid environments. In the Mediterranean region, this is mainly attributed to the dramatic decrease of the traditional human activities such as pastoral management and fuelwood collection, which controlled the encroachment of woody species. The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of Juniperus oxycedrus encroachment on herbage production and floristic diversity in a natural grassland. The research was conducted in the area of Megalo Dereio, which is located in Evros region, in north-eastern Greece in 2010. Herbage production was measured and ecological diversity indices were determined at three different shrub cover regimes (open, moderate, dense). Herbage production decreased progressively as juniper cover increased. Floristic diversity was significantly higher in the moderate shrub cover regime, while it was dramatically reduced in the dense shrub cover regime.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006931.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 299-302]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600156">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of soil microtopographic gradients on dry matter yields and species richness in two Mediterranean pastures]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Aguiar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Rodrigues]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.E., Fernández-Nuñez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Domingos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Pires]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium subterraneum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biodiversity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Species]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The Sown Biodiverse Permanent Pastures Rich in Legumes (SBPPRL) mix a large number of species and cultivars of improved annual pasture species adapted to Mediterranean climate, with a predominance of Trifolium subterraneum. On a commercial mixed farm were explored the effects of soil microtopographic gradients on dry matter (DM) yields and species richness in two intensively grazed nearby pastures – a stabilized SBPPRL and an old seminatural annual pasture (SNP) – established in the same soil catena, with a high P2O5 and K2O availability. As expected the SBPPRL had higher DM yields than the SNP, more stable along the slope system, and with a larger legume fraction. The indigenous genotypes of the SNP seemed unable to translate into biomass soil fertility improvement. SBPPRL improved pasture species depressed significantly pasture species diversity and species spatial turnover. In the SBPPRL legumes mainly substituted many short living low productivity autochthonous species common in the SNP. The buffering of soil ecological gradients is probably important in the explanation of the superior agronomic performance of SBPPRL. SOM accumulation is certainly involved in this process.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006930.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 295-298]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600157">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Determination of the socio-economic factors that affect the sustainable pasture management in Central Anatolia region of Turkey]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Cevher]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Köksal, Ö]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I.C., Ceylan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Tatlidil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Socioeconomic factors]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rehabilitation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[According to the pasture law and regulations, the responsibilities of the farmers on pasture management have increased since 2004. Therefore, the farmers' attitude and behavior in this subject have gained importance on pasture management. The aim of this study is to present the pasture management methods of farmers in the pastures areas where rehabilitation and amelioration process are completed, and to present the factors that affect farmer's behavior on sustainable pasture management. The data used in the study were obtained by a survey among 271 farmers who live in 18 villages of 3 provinces (Ankara, Kayseri and Konya). The chi square, regression analysis and multiple correspondence analysis methods were used in evaluation of the data obtained. The significant variables that come from 40 variables used in the study were subjected to multiple correspondence analyses. As a result of the regression analysis, it is found that there is a significant relationship (p less than 0.05) between the sustainable use of the pastures and: the educational level of farmers, their living places, the use of fodder seeds that are provided for them, the participation in pasture rehabilitation activities, the utility found on the rehabilitation activity, the sustainability of the increase in fodder quantity obtained from the rehabilitation project, the use of the pastures out of purpose, whether or not the farmers are willing to rent pastures, the complying with the plan of grazing and the willingness to belong to a pasture management union. To define which categories of the variables found statistically significant in regression analysis were effective, a multiple correspondence analysis method was used. As a result of this analysis it was found that there is a significant relationship between the variable groups that comply with the grazing plan, use of fodder crops seeds, declare willingness to participate in pasture management unions and rehabilitation activities and the sustainable pasture management.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006991.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 433-438]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600158">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of Bacillus sp. on P uptake in Vicia sativa, Vicia ervilia, Medicago sativa grown in greenhouse conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Cevheri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ç., Küçük]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia ervilia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Inoculation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bacillus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Bacillus sp. MK4 isolate was isolated from Şanlıurfa soils, Turkey. MK4 isolate was biochemically characterized. MK4 isolate was evaluated in vitro for plant promoting traits like ammonia (NH3) production, antifungal activity, phosphate solubilization. In addition, the effect of Bacillus sp. MK4 on P uptake by Vicia sativa, Vicia ervilia and Medicago sativa under greenhouse conditions was studied. Seed inoculation of this bacterial isolate resulted in significant increases in shoot and root weight of Vicia sativa, Vicia ervilia, Medicago sativa with or without added P source.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006942.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 337-341]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600159">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Locations and some agricultural properties of Medicago orbicularis L. genotypes present in Antalya flora]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Erdurmus]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Çakmakçi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago orbicularis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flora]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Annuals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Turkey, which is at the intersection of three gene centers, and especially Mediterranean basin, is the gene centre of many legumes used in agriculture. There are more than 900 legumes species and most of them are annual plants. 30 of these species are medic (Medicago L.) species. Annual medics originated from Me - di terranean. 13 of them, which also have high adaptation capacity, have economic importance. With regards to contribution of the length of vegetative period, annual medics have great importance. Thus, some of the annual medics reach the grazing maturity in early spring and some of them develop after the unsuitable conditions of summer season and provide significant contribution to grass yield of pasture in late au tumn. In general, despite the use of perennial plants in the world, annual medics are much more promising than perennials in the pasture with limited rainfall in summer. The ecological conditions of our country are very similar to the region where annual medics have importance in the grass yield. Annual medics have great importance for the improvement of roughage production in our country. In this study, the coordinates of spread areas of Medicago orbicularis L., which is one of the species of annual medics, were determined with GPS in Antalya natural flora. Also in natural flora, development shapes of plants, leaflet width and length, hairiness of leaf surface, flower color, plant length, amount of fruits in plant and hairiness in bean were analyzed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006881.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 207-211]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600160">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of Rhizobium isolates from Melilotus officinalis nodules at various stress conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Ç., Küçük]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Cevheri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rhizobium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Roots]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Melilotus officinalis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pasture are an important part of agricultural systems and to increase their productivity and quality persistent forage legumes are needed. Melilotus officinalis is an important forage legume. Rhizobium bacteria can form nitrogen fixing nodules on legume roots. In this study, we phenotypically characterized 17 Rhizobium isolates from Melilotus officinalis nodules. About 47 per cent of isolates were resistant to pH 8, 27 per cent were resistant to 40 degrees C temperature and 17.6 per cent were resistant to 2-2.5 per cent NaCl concentrations.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006958.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 361-365]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600161">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Bio-agronomic traits of Psoralea bituminosa and P. morisiana accessions collected in Sardinia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.A.M., Melis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.A., Re]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Usai]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Marchetti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Seed  characteristics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Psoralea]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Furocoumarins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Psoralea genus (Leguminosae) includes some species with promising features as pasture legume in Mediterranean areas prone to drought. Eight Sardinian and 7 Spanish accessions of P. bituminosa were evaluated during 2009-2011. Forage production and its furocoumarin content, seed yield and mass were observed. The total forage yield ranged from 68.4 g DM plant-1 in Loculi to 252.6 g DM plant-1 in Albo-HTolFrio, with the accessions showing differences in the seasonal production also. The 1000 seed weight varied from 15 g in Llano del Beal to 35 g in Monte Gonareddu, while Llano del Beal and Monte Rosello showed the highest seed yield (about 30 g pl-1 year-1). A high variability was observed for furocoumarin content, too. These preliminary results are very encouraging in view of the valorisation of Psoralea as perennial forage legume for marginal rainfed areas.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006867.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 139-144]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600162">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Legume-cereal mixtures ensiling in Sardinia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Ruda]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.S., Atzori]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Correddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Cannas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.M., Carroni]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Silage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sardinia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia faba minor]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Small ruminants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lupinus albus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pisum sativum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Triticale]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Animal feeding accounts more than 50% of farm production costs, often principally due to the protein component acquisition. Cereals and legume mixtures silage could represent an interesting source of high nutritive value forage in non-irrigated lands. Mixtures can provide an adequate proportion of nitrogen and carbohydrates in the ensiling substrates, needed to help lactic fermentation and pH reduction, essential to the conservation process. The aim of this trial was to compare silage of three leguminous-triticale mixtures, in order to obtain a preliminary evaluation for high quality and stable forages production, destined to ruminant feeding in Mediterranean areas. The trial was carried out in Sardinia between autumn 2010 and spring 2011. Mixtures of Triticale (Triticosecale WittMack)-white lupin (Lupinus albus L.), triticale-pea (Pisum sativum L.) and triticale-faba bean (Vicia faba minor L.) were evaluated. After six months of ensiling process in glass jars, silage was analyzed, by determining: pH, dry matter, fibrous fractions, crude protein, ash content, NFC plus lipids and estimated DM digestibility. Mixtures with pea and triticale Amarillo reached the highest content of DM. When used in mixtures with triticale and in respect to lupin and pea, faba bean obtained the lowest values of NDF, ADF, and ADL and the highest content of NFC+lipids. Faba bean was also able to maintain the highest protein content. Considering the CP content of silage, the 30:70 seeding ratio resulted the more convenient. A more detailed evaluation of obtained results should be performed also considering the biomass production per hectare at farm level.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007003.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 489-492]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600163">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Role and management of permanent grasslands]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C.O., Sabanci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meadows]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livestock]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Permanent grasslands are open areas covering nearly one fourth of the total land area in the world. Temperate grasslands such as prairies, pampas, steppes or paramos have hot and dry summers, and rainy cool winters. Grasslands are vitally important for livestock as a feed source, environmental protection, conservation of genetic resources, preservation of natural resources, sustainable agriculture, wildlife habitat, tourism and leisure. As a science and technique, the grassland management provides the maximum production with the conservation of vegetation, soil and the other natural resources. The effective management of grasslands depends on a number of different factors such as the characteristics of grassland, plant species, livestock type and environmental sources. Use of proper grazing system is the most important practice in management. The main principles of grazing management are grazing capacity in relation to the number and kind of animals, grazing period and grazing distribution. Grassland management also involves weed control, fertilization, burning, and seeding with natural grasses or other plants.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006896.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 285-293]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600164">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Forage production of the drought tolerant Mediterranean forage legume tedera (Bituminaria bituminosa var. albomarginata) in the mediumrainfall zone of south Western Australia as affected by plant density and cutting frequency]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Real]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Kidd]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Density]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Australia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tedera]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mowing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bituminaria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The Mediterranean perennial forage legume tedera (B. bituminosa var. albomarginata) remains green all-year-round, reducing the summer/autumn feed gap, providing high quality forage when most other pasture options have senesced. At Mount Barker Research Station in south Western Australia (annual rainfall 2010-11 of 445 mm), the forage production of two tedera accessions (T1 and T6) was studied under densities of 1, 2, 4, 8 and 16 plants m-2 and cutting frequencies of 1, 2, 3 and 4 times yr-1. The experimental design was a split-split-plot with 4 replicates. The first two years of the experiment were kept weed-free and results are presented for the second year. The density and cutting frequency were the only highly significant effects. Densities of both 8 and 16 plants m-2 provided the greatest forage yield of 5.8 tonnes DM year-1, while densities of 1, 2 and 4 plants m-2 produced 2.1, 2.4 and 4.5 tonnes DM year-1 respectively. The cutting frequency of 1 yielded best with 5.8 tonnes DM year-1 followed by 2, 3 and 4 cuttings with annual productions of 4.1, 3.7 and 2.8 tonnes DM respectively. In this environment, forage produced using densities of 8 to 16 plants m-2 can be accumulated and used at strategic times of the year to reduce the costs associated with supplementary feeding.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006985.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 387-390]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600165">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of nitrogen and phosphorus fertilization on dry matter yield and quality of an abandoned rangeland]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Budakli Carpici]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.M., Tunali]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Celik]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phosphorous]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crude protein]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dry matter]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDF]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ADF]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nitrogen]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The object of this study was to determine the effects of nitrogen and phosphorus fertilization on dry matter yield, crude protein content, ADF, NDF and total digestible nutrient of an abandoned rangeland in Bursa-Turkey in 2008 and 2009 years. Nitrogen was applied as urea (46 per cent N) at 0, 50, 100, 150, 200 and 250 kg ha-1rates. Phosphorus was applied as triple super phosphate (42-44 per cent P2O5) at 0, 50, 100 and 150 kg ha-1 rates. Fertilizers were broadcasted by hand. All of nitrogen rates increased dry matter yield and the yield reached the peak value at 200 kg ha-1 rate, followed by 150 and 250 kg Nha-1rates, but the differences among rates were not so great. All but 50 kg ha-1 nitrogen level increased crude protein content, but no differences among their effects. The effects of nitrogen rates on NDF values were the same and positive when compared with the NDF value of unfertilized range. All phosphorus rates did affect only the crude protein content of hay, indicating similar effects as a result; to produce higher and quality forage from abandoned rangelands like in the experimental region the 150 kg N ha-1rate can be recommended with economical considerations.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006940.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 333-336]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600166">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Exploring the use of alternative forage legume crops to enhance organic livestock farming in a context of climate and socio-economic changes]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., López-i-Gelats]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartolomé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia ervilia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Socioeconomic environment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Onobrychis sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia narbonensis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trigonella foenum-graecum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livestock]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Organic livestock farming is going through notable growth in the Mediterranean Europe. This increase is being sponsored by the EU agri-environmental schemes, but also by the rising interest of consumers. However, constraints exist that threaten to curb the present trend. One of them is the lack of good quality forage. There is thus a need to investigate if unusual forage crops could produce good harvests under organic management in Mediterranean conditions. Accordingly, we have conducted an initial exploration on the nutritional value of alternative forage legume crops that organic farmers are growing in Catalonia (Spain), specifically: sainfoin (Onobrychis sativa), fenugreek (Trigonella foenum-graecum), Narbon vetch (Vicia narbonensis) and bitter vetch (Vicia ervilia). These forage crops are well adapted to poor soils, harsh weathers, and low water, fertiliser and phytosanitary applications. They have been traditionally cultivated in the Mediterranean region, but they have been gradually dismissed due to the spread of high-yielding forage varieties. The preliminary results indicate that not only these crops are forages of an excellent nutritional value, but they show similar or even superior nutritional values when cultivated organically. However, further research is required in this domain to gather further evidences.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006993.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 443-447]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600167">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Vulnerability to Climate Change of Turkana pastoralist of dry savanna]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., López-i-Gelats]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartolomé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Rivera-Ferre]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastoralism]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adaptation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Strategies]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pastoralism is a dynamic grassland management system which implies complex and multiple interactions among people, livestock, environment, as well as local and traditional knowledge and formal and informal institutions. In Turkana, a region located in Northern Kenya, most of the population’s livelihood depends on extensive herding. Most of them are experiencing the adverse impacts of changes in climate, particularly recurrent droughts and occasional floods. This is threatening the socio-ecological balance they are part of. Some argue that pastoralists are among the most vulnerable to climate-related hazards. However, others maintain that they are well-equipped to tackle climate change, as they have proved throughout history. What is the case in Turkana? By means of a set of interviews to Turkana pastoralists and relevant stakeholders in the region we attempt at shedding light on this question. While it is obvious that pastoralists have been adapting and trying to remain flexible for centuries, and that this has allowed them to live in the dry land ecosystems of Eastern Africa; it is also evident that several socioeconomic trends are hindering their adaptive capacity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006834.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 69-72]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600168">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Preliminary selection of Lolium perenne L. natural populations for pasture improvement purpose in rainfed Mediterranean conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Sanna]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Saba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sassu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Franca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[rainfed farming]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lolium perenne]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiarid climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Previous researchs have established how Lolium perenne L. genetic conservation, evaluation and development have priority for Mediterranean permanent pasture sustainability, and how new persistent and drought tolerant varieties could contribute to mixtures of annual and perennial legumes for pasture improvement purpose. Nevertheless, scarce is the availability of perennial ryegrass cultivars responding to semi-arid climates adaptation criteria; their persistence being reduced by incidences of summer droughts. The attempt to extend this availability has been started through a collection of germplasm and consequent field evaluation of natural populations, originating from different pedo-climatic sites of Corsica and Sardinia islands in the Mediterranean Sea, in terms of productive parameters, habit, phenology and persistence. The field evaluation trial was carried out at the Ottava experimental station of the Sassari University (570 mm average annual rainfall, North Sardinia, Italy). Starting from initial 30 natural populations, 11 preliminarily selected accessions were compared over three years, under rainfed conditions, following the UPOV rules for the identification of new cultivars, with the purpose to estimate the potential inclusion of most interesting accessions in programs that lead to varietal certification.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006882.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 213-217]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600169">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Economic effects of the changing regime of autumn rains onto sheep breeding farms]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Dono]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Giraldo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Cortignani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Animal breeding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sheep]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livestock management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rainfed farming]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The change in the autumn rain regime can create problems for sheep breeding based on pasture or non-irrigated grass. A reduction in the useful rain hampers the growth of grass production, preventing grazing, and requiring farms to tap into the stock of hay to feed animals in the autumn-winter season. Farms may have to rent more land to produce grass in the spring in order to expand their forage production with an increase of costs that will be difficult to endure in a declining milk prices scenario. This analysis assesses whether the changes in climate variability, which are already under way, alter the probability distribution of rainfall in autumn, reducing the days of rain for the growth of grass. The economic effects of this and other changes will be evaluated by means of a Discrete Stochastic Programming territorial model that allows to represent the choices of farms under uncertainty; in this work we present a preliminary simulation concerning the effect of autumnal rainfall on sheep breeding. The analysis shows the different situation of a farm type that grows the grass completely non-irrigated, another with a limited supply of water from wells and a third that can tap into the water supply of a Water User Association.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006855.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 73-76]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600170">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Silvopastoralism in Mediterranean Basin: Extension, practices, products, threats and challenges]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Moreno]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Pulido]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Environment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Services]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trees]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Regeneration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Encroachment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean basin]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dehesa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Silvopastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Ranching generally causes a progressive deforestation. Nevertheless in Mediterranean countries trees are still present in many pastoral systems, here referred to as silvopastoral systems (SPs). Trees provide products as fruits as human food, fruits or leaves as fodder, wood and firewood, environmental services like patches of soil fertility and shelter for animals, and environmental goods such as carbon sequestration, water yield and quality and reinforced biodiversity. However, most of the SPs locate in marginal areas, have low commercial profitability and are subject to two divergent trends, intensification and extensification or abandonment that compromise their long-term persistence. Here we analyzed current threats/constraints and new challenges for the future of SPs based on experience gained in Iberian dehesas. We stress the need of a comprehensive and categorized map of SPs and a database of management practices as adaptive solutions to environmental and socioeconomical contexts. We propose a set of topics for future research projects that should integrate traditional and scientific knowledge favoring innovative techniques for production of timber and non-timber forest products, livestock, and cultural and environmental values.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007008.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 517-521]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600171">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Competition for soil water among trees, shrubs and pasture in Iberian Dehesas. Consequences for pasture and tree productivity]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Moreno]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Rolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Cubera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Competition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Silvopastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The low tree density in silvopastoral systems results in increased pasture productivity and allows remnant trees to cope with summer water deficit. However, the worldwide phenomenon of savanna shrub encroachment could compromise the benefit of wide tree spacing in these water limited forests. We analyze the effect of shrub encroachment of Iberian dehesas for soil water dynamic and tree water status. The consequences for oak tree and pasture productivity are discussed. Increased tree density resulted in a worsening of tree water status and acorn productivity. Cistus shrubs showed a net competitive effect for soil water which influenced negatively the pasture yield, and the functional state and acorn production of the trees. By contrast, Retama shrubs affected positively the soil moisture of uppermost soil layers (hydraulically lifted water) and showed a facilitative effect for pasture yield without influencing the functional tree state and acorn production.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006859.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 93-96]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600172">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of component ratios and management of an annual ryegrass-burr medic mixture on the forage quality]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.A., Re]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Saba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Franca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mixed pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Resowing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A trial was carried out to evaluate the benefits of grass-legume mixtures in terms of sward establishment, dry matter yield, self-reseeding ability and unsown species control. In this paper we present the aspects related with the forage quality. Two annual self-reseeding species coming from Sardinian candivars Lolium rigidum Gaudin NURRA (L) and Medicago polymorpha Anglona (P) were used. The trial was carried out in Sardinia (Italy) comparing two pure stands (L100P0 and L0P100) and three mixtures (L75P25, L50P50 and L25P75), where 100 represented the standard dense sowing rate of each component in pure stand. Two different cutting treatments were compared: two cuts vs three cuts. Crude protein, NDF and ADF of the different treatments were determined. Mixtures assure a more seasonally-balanced quality of forage respect to the pure stands; two cuts achieve a higher CP content. Results are important for defining suitable strategies at farm level, in terms of grazing techniques.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006962.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 381-385]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600173">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Searching for new annual legumes suitable for pasture establishment in Southern Europe]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.A., Re]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Dettori]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Franca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pasture establishment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Europe]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The high plant biodiversity of Mediterranean basin, shaped from both the millennial agro-pastoral activity and the pedo-climatic variability, has produced a natural selection of pasture species, suitable for several uses in farming systems. Many of the recently released Australian annual legumes varieties are not always suitable for pasture establishment in southern Europe, mainly because of their early flowering and high hardseededness, which affect the persistence capability. In order to clarify the low persistence of the Australian varieties and to identify new interesting materials for the Mediterranean forage scene, ten accessions of Lotus ornithopodioides, Ornithopus compressus, O. sativus, Trifolium hirtum, T. mutabilis and T. spumosum were compared in North-Sardinia. These accessions, were evaluated for bio-agronomic traits as vigour, phenology, seed production and hardseedness breakdown. Results revealed the potential suitability of many of tested materials for both Mediterranean pasture improvement purposes and multifunctional uses.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006891.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 257-260]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600174">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Fodder trees and shrubs in range and farming systems in semi arid regions of Tunisia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Ammar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Lahyeni]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Ben Younes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., López]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Lahsoumi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farming systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutritive value]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Digestibility]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tunisia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Browse plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Five cultivated shrub species endemic to the semi arid regions of Tunisia, Acacia fimbriata, Allocasuarina verticillata, Medicago arborea, Anthyllis barba-jovis L and Opuntia ficus-indica, were studied as a source of animal forage. The experiment was carried out in an experimental land in Mograne (Zaghouan, East central Tunisia). Plants were on average 4 years old conducted without irrigation. Sampling was made at the end of autumn (November) 2008. By the exception of O. ficus-indica all studied species had high crude protein content (more than 15 per cent). An. barba-jovis followed by M. arborea had the highest N contents (more than 22 per cent). Cultivated Al. verticillata had the highest ADF and ADL contents, 50 per cent and 32.8 per cent, respectively. By the exception of A. verticillata and A.barba-jovis, in vitro dry matter digestibility (IVD) was higher (more than 80 per cent). It was concluded that some of these cultivated shrub species is compared with some leguminous forages and convenient even in dairy farms as a source of nitrogen. Moreover, the choice of alternate feed resource should not be restrictive but must fit within the existing farming systems, and be adapted to the economic realities of the farmer.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006936.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 323-326]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600175">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Technical culture of kenaf produced under Tunisian semi arid conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Ammar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Lahyeni]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Lahsoumi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Ben Younes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., López]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sowing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutritive value]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kenaf]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Maturity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spacing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Kenaf, Hibiscus cannabinus L, is a warm-season annual fiber crop. The stem is a source of fibre production. In Tunisia, Kenaf production was introduced in the humid and Saharian regions since 1998. Possibility of its culture in Zaghouan, a Tunisian semiarid region, and the optimal density for a higher yielding and nutritive value was our main objective. Three seeding densities (seeds per m²) were used: 27 (D1); 13 (D2) and 5 (D3) seed per m2. Harvesting was at 75 days age. The highest yield (11.6 t per ha) in terms of edible dry matter (DM) was recorded for D1 and the lowest (6 t per ha) for D3. Protein content was higher (more than 17 per cent) in leaves and lower (less than 12 per cent) in stems. The main handicap of its production is water resource. Agricultural companies should be carried out to well introduce this plant in the agriculture systems since it can be a good precursor for some cereal culture due to its capacity to incorporate a high organic matter amount in the soil.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006874.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 173-176]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600176">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Agro-pastoral production system of Egypt. Climate change, vulnerability and opportunities for poverty alleviation]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.R.M., Metawi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poverty]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Surveys]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agropastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Small ruminants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Agro-pastoral production system in the northwestern coastal zone of Egypt is characterized by varied agricultural activities including raising small ruminant's flocks, beside cultivation of barley and some fruits as Olives and Figs. This system has been fragilized by drought that has become more frequent and worsened by human activities. A survey study was conducted to identify and analyze the causes, impacts and management mechanisms of drought crisis in this area. The sample of the study encompassed 162 agropastoralists. Major findings were extracted for the causes of drought vulnerability included socio- economic, livelihood and agriculture. The annual income of the household reduced by 58.3% in the drought years. The various Bedouins coping mechanisms were inadequate to reduce the negative impact of drought. Results highlight small ruminant role on alleviating poverty and helping household to deal with climate variability. The share of small ruminant in the households economy in the dry year ranged from 60%-67%.The perception of small ruminant to escape poverty is completely linked to the flock size. Based on the findings and conclusions of this study, specific recommendations were made to reduce effects of drought crisis.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006863.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 113-116]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600177">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[A new annual summer forage crop: Cowpea]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Ayan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Can]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Arslan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Mut]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flowering stage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cowpeas]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Turkey]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Genotypes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Four cowpea genotypes (YBS1, YBS2, YBS3, YBS4), were evaluated for forage yield and related parameters at two locations (Samsun and Suluova) in Turkey during 2011 summer growing season. The effects of genotype, location and GxL interaction on 50 per cent flowering stage, fresh and dry forage yield were significant. Average value of the 50 per cent flowering period and dry forage yield were 49 days and 688 kg per da over the locations and genotypes. The period of 50 per cent flowering among genotypes was longer, however, forage yield was higher at Suluova than Samsun. The highest dry and forage yield was obtained from genotype YBS3 which is also latest in flowering at both locations.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006875.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 177-180]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600178">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Agricultural traits of blue grass accessions in Black Sea Region of Turkey]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Ayan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Gulumser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Arslan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Can]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Tongel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anatolia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Natural grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Turkey]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agronomic characters]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Breeding of blue grass (Poa sp.) is a very important issue in Turkey and seed collections play a key role in enhancing the genetic pool. For this reason, blue grass seeds were collected from Northern Anatolian Region in 2007, and were subsequently characterized. Accessions were sown in seed trays and then seedlings were transplanted to field. At the end of the measurements and observations, the results were: (i) plant heights ranged between 22 and 100 cm; (ii) internode distance between 2.5 and 25.0 cm; (iii) main stem diameter between 0.10 and 1.38 mm; (iv) number of internode between 2 and 3; (v) flag leave blade length between 1.2 and 23.9 cm; (vi) flag leave blade width between 0.10 and 0.50 cm; (vii) panicle length between 3.10 and 16.60 cm. Number of spikelet in Poa sp. was found between 15 and 207, number of tiller per plant was between 19 and 382, number of fertile tiller per plant was between 0.11 and 15.6 g, dry matter yield per plant was between 10.03 and 27 g, 1000 seed weight was between 0.10 and 0.70 g.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006872.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 165-168]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600179">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Policy approaches to grassland in planning documents of Ministry of Food Agriculture and Livestock in Turkey in the context of climate change]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Dede]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Serefoglu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Strategic plan]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Planning]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The grassland-based policy approaches are strongly linked with the livestock management be - cause the livestock nutrition system which is based on grazing intensively particularly on hilly and remote areas. This situation has been predominantly reflected in planning as the interventions directed to regulating the grazing intensity (over-grazing) and erosion control. The most comprehensive and concrete interventions for the establishment of policies for grassland in the context of impacts, mitigating and adapting to climate change have been seen in the Strategic Plan (2010-2014) and Performance Programmes. The needed re - sources for implementing the measures regarding grassland management and climate change accounts for 6.5 per cent of total budget in Performance Programme 2012 showing significant increase of importance given to cli mate change when compared with the Performance Programme 2011. The measures regarding erosion control in IPARD Programme may be classified as the practices for mitigation purposes although it is not implied as a measure targeted to climate change in the Programme.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006862.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 107-112]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600180">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Daily growth evaluation of an irrigated lucerne crop]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Delgado]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Muñoz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Andueza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Harvest]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Growth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dry matter]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The daily growth of a lucerne cv ‘Aragón’ crop was determined under irrigated conditions in Zaragoza (Spain) during the period 2006-2009. Forage yield and crude protein percentage were evaluated every eight days as average on seven vegetation cycles per year applying the method of Corrall and Fenlon. The productive period of lucerne was from the beginning of March to the end of November. The annual maximum dry matter yield was 15.901 kg ha-1 in the third year, and the maximum growth was reached on 30 June 2008, 119.5 kg ha-1 day-1. The crude protein percentage decreased from 22.9 per cent at mid- April to 15.5 per cent at mid-July; later, it increased up to 24.5 per cnet at the middle of November. These results represent a contribution to the optimization of lucerne crops management.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006947.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 349-353]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600181">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Assessing grazing animal production systems on large Greek islands: A case study on the island of Crete]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Hadjigeorgiou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Zervas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rangelands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production system]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Islands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Greece]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biodiversity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Greece has a long history of breeding sheep and goats utilizing the indigenous vegetation, under a system of free ranging or shepherded grazing, which in combination to some shepherds’ practices formed the present land cover and biodiversity. Islands present an interesting model for animal farming activity. The study area was the island of Crete in the South Aegean Sea. The land area covers some 825,000 ha and officialy holds a population of 600,000 inhabitants, while considerable numbers of sheep and goats (1,270,000 and 580,000 respectively) are raised. These animals produce 88,000 tonnes of sheep milk and 52,000 tonnes of goat milk, together with 14,300 tones of sheep and 6,600 tonnes of goat meat. Production systems applied in this island, were investigated and flocks were divided in semi-intensive and extensive. However, since pedoclimatic conditions vary widely, in order to advise grazing management rules in the different areas, a combination of National Statistics, CORINE and field data was used to define system dependence on local grazing resources. Subsequently grazing capacities were determined and advised to the local authorities together with management guidelines with the aim of maintaining the preserved areas under moderate grazing activity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006995.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 453-456]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600182">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[New annual legumes as winter crops for intensive forage rotations in Galicia (NW Spain). I – Dry matter yield]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Valladares]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Pereira-Crespo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Flores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Díaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Resch]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., González-Arráez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Bande-Castro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[X., Rodriguez-Diz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Piñeiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Serradella]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sole cropping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forages]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[It is presented in this paper the dry matter yield results obtained in an experiment where six species of annual legumes were sown in small plots in mid-October 2009 as a winter monoculture crop and harvested in the next spring following a silage-cutting strategy. Legume species were: Crimson clover; Balansa clover; Persian clover (ssp. resupinatum and ssp. majus); Arrowleaf clover and French serradella. Forage was given a first cut at two weeks intervals in six harvest dates beginning at mid-march, and a second cut was taken after six weeks of regrowth. Sown legume dry matter yield varied broadly among species across cutting dates (from 3.3 to 6.6 t ha-1 and from 0.8 to 3.4 t ha-1 in first and second cycles, respectively) and among cutting dates across species (from 1.5 to 8.5 t ha-1 in the first cycle and from 3.7 to 0.2 t ha-1 in the second). In spite of the good average productivity of most of the legume species studied, their low dry matter (DM) content in spring (from 9.8 to 19.0 per cent DM) could make difficult to obtain and adequate fermentation quality of silage harvested by the end of April to fit in the rotation with maize.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006889.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 245-249]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600183">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Evolution of the floristic diversity of an artificial mixture meadow under semi-arid climate in Algeria]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[semiarid climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasses]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Meadows]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evolution]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In Algeria, the restoration and the creation of meadows on hydromorphic grounds of the wadi bed fields constitute a major issue of agricultural and environmental development of the semi-arid zones of altitudes which farming systems are mixed: agriculture-livestock. Within a site of this area, the diversity and frequency of the vegetable species were measured during 4 successive years on a long duration created mixture meadow and on a natural control one. Results were compared in the aim to understand the dynamics of these two types of vegetable formations subjected to traditional management practices. The results made possible to learn several lessons as for the productive provisions of the sown mixture meadow like on the fodder species having shown the best provisions of adaptation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006934.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 313-317]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600184">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Preliminary results on climate change evidence from coprolites of Myotragus balearicus Bate 1909 (Artiodactyla, Caprinae)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Rivera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Baraza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Alcover]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Bover]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Retuerto]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[X., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartolomé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stomata]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Buxus balearicus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Carbon dioxide]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Plants may vary their stomata density as a function of environmental factors, such as [CO2], drought and temperature. Under the present atmospheric conditions, it is expected that leaves have different stomata density than they had hundreds or thousands of years ago, due to the rise of CO2 in the atmosphere. Microhistological analyses of coprolites of the extinct Myotragus balearicus from Cova Estreta (Pollença, Mallorca), with a radiocarbon age of 4950 plus minus 38 BP (3775-3640 2σ cal BC; Wk-33010), have shown a diet including an important amount of Buxus balearica epidermal fragments. Three of these coprolites were used to estimate the stomata density on Buxus balearica epidermal fragments from this period. Additionally, three samples of the endangered Buxus balearica, the sole species of Buxus currently present on Mallorca, were collected in three different localities and leaves were examined under microscopy to determine the stomata density. A significant difference between epidermal fragments from coprolites and epidermal fragments of living plants (c² equal to 34.46, P less than 0.0001, L-R c² test), with a density average of 27.21 and 19.05 stomata per mm2 respectively, has been recorded. The current lower density of stomata could be a plant response to climatic change in the Mediterranean islands.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006833.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 65-68]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600185">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Adaptation of Australian self-reseeding forage legumes to three environments of Sardinia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sitzia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Vargiu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Mulè]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.A., Re]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The important role of annual self-reseeding legumes is well known and their use in livestock systems is consistent with low input agriculture trend. Australian commercial varieties of self-reseeding legumes mainly derive from Mediterranean basin germplasm. They have been selected for environmental conditions of southern Australia where they are cultivated. Each year a large amount of seed of Australian varieties is imported to southern Europe. Therefore it is necessary to investigate their adaptation and yield capacity to local environmental conditions. A two years trial was performed in three Sardinian sites with different pedoclimatic characteristics, with the aim to compare the agronomic performances of Australian self-reseeding legume varieties belonging to Biserrula, Ornithopus, Medicago and Trifolium genera. Earliness of flowering, forage yield and variety persistence in the second year were evaluated. Varieties of Trifolium spp. had the best productive performances, coupled with the highest persistence in subterranean clovers. Varieties of Biserrula and Ornithopus spp. proved to be not well adapted to the three sites and showed low herbage mass production.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006893.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 265-269]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600186">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Yield and nitrogen fixation capacity by inoculated white lupin (Lupinus albus L.)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Canu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.M., Carroni]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sassu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nitrogen fixation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Straw]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[White lupin (Lupinus albus L.) crop can gain a renewed interest due to its higher crude protein yield than other rainfed grain legumes, and for the request as an ingredient of functional or healthy food products. It is a new crop in Sardinia (Italy) and very few studies provide information about the N fixation ability of this species which needs to be preferably evaluated at local level from direct measurements. This study was aimed at quantify the DM yield and the N fixed by white lupin, using the Isotopic Dilution method, in three Sardinian sites. Grain dry matter yield and its N proportion did not differ between sites whereas the proportion of N derived from the fixation showed a wider variation. The aerial DM of white lupin fixed from 140 to about 270 kg ha-1 of N. Even if results differed among sites, very high percentages of N derived from the atmosphere were found and a relationship of 53.7 kg of fixed N per tonne of grain DM produced by this legume was established.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006895.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 277-281]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600187">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Growth rates, biomass yield and forage quality of three local Poaceae in Annaba’s region, North East Algeria]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Boudelaa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Slimani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ladjama]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Benkadour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Nadjeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Growth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poaceae]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biomass]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the Algerian context, the development of durable fodder agriculture and breeding require complex strategies of which one of the elements consists in developing the use of fodder species adapted to the local biotope characteristic of Mediterranean climate. The aim of this work consisted to study and cultivates 3 Algerian varieties of Poaceae fodder, reed canary grass Phalaris arundinacea, rye grass Lolium multiflorum and tall fescue Festuca arundinacea in order to evaluate their agronomic performance; the growth rates and the field biomass output. The obtained results showed that the biomass production was more important for the reed canary grass in compete cycle than in incomplete cycle of vegetation, contrary to rye grass and tall fescue. Moreover, the analysis of growth kinetics showed that it is the spring growth which presented the best characteristics of the plant development and dry matter (DM) yield production. From fodder value, the reed canary grass and the tall fescue are well provided in Total Nitrogen Matter (TNM) and relatively low in Fodder Units (FU). Contrary, the rye grass is rich in energy compounds (EU) but contains low protein content.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006877.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 187-190]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600188">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Pasture improvement programs carried out on some coastal pastures and highland ranges of Antalya]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Çürek]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Erdurmus]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Çeçen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Aydinoglu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.T., Bilgen]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Çakmakçi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Highlands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rangelands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Botanical composition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plant cover]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hay]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Coasts]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A great portion of the grassland in Antalya is in poor condition due to long dry period in summer season and improper range management practices. In this work three highland pastures, 3800 ha in total, and three coastal pastures 175 ha in total were studied, and hay yield improvement was aimed. At the beginning all coastal pastures and highland ranges were covered with fences, to control grazing periods. All pastures were fertilized in different seasons during program. In some parts of controlled pastures, seed mixtures were sown. The first year of the study all pastures were closed for grazing animals. The following years animals were grazed from May-October. Bushes and unflavoured plants were cut to give a better growing chance to favour grasses. Loop and 1 m. frame methods were used to obtain, hay yields, average plant covered areas percentage, and botanical composition in all coastal pastures and highland ranges. As a result, all data were shown improvement of all pastures were satisfactory, but coastal pastures observed better behaviour than highland ranges in all determined characteristics.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006944.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 343-347]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600189">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Evaluation of lambs propensity towards different accessions of Psoralea]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Decandia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Acciaro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sitzia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Cabiddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Manca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Molle]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Giovanetti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Psoralea]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feeding habits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sheep]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feed intake]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Animal propensity towards a food is mainly based on pre-ingestive stimuli, and could be measured by the intake rate. A short-term test, using the micro-swards method, was carried out to measure lambs propensity for different accessions of Psoralea genus, a perennial legume widely distributed in Mediterranean regions. The following 4 accessions of Psoralea were evaluated: Psoralea bituminosa crassiuscula Vilaflor; Psoralea bituminosa bituminosa Llano del Beal; Psoralea bituminosa bituminosa Monte Rosello; Psoralea morisiana Punta Giglio. The forages were offered, in a 4x4 latin-square design with 3 replicates, to 12 Sarda lambs, first adapted to the test routine with Hordeum vulgaris L.. Fresh matter intake (FMI) and DM intake (DMI, g head-1), number of bites (NB, n.), eating time (ET, min), bite frequency (BF, n. min-1) and intake rate (IR, g min-1) were measured in 5 min sessions. Overall, lambs showed a low propensity for all accessions of Psoralea with a slightly higher DM IR for Vilaflor (P less or equal to 0.05).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006879.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 197-200]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600190">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Options available for improved forage production under highland conditions. The Pakistan experience]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Dost]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cereals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sole cropping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Intercropping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The forage production and availability were affected by single cut vs. multi-cut, hybrid vs. varieties, legumes vs. cereal crops, sole cropping vs. intercropping, altering planting dates, different types and doses of chemical fertilizer. Non winter dormant/ improved alfalfa and Egyptian clover varieties were 2-3 times more productive than the local landraces commonly cultivated in the region. The improved forage production techniques also provided forage during the deficit periods. Improving the performance of the high-altitude summer pastures being difficult and time-consuming task and would not alleviate the winter forage scarcity problem. Main emphasis should therefore, be put on improving fodder production and conservation on the agricultural holdings. Since holding size is minute, the aim must be to maximize production per unit of area. Fodder production in these isolated, high areas had been little studied. The population has had no easy access to the technology and seed supplies available in the plains and, for the higher areas, technology from lower down is not appropriate.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006880.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 201-206]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600191">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Use of front face fluorescence spectroscopy to identify sheep milk from different feeding diets]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Hammami]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Karoui]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Selmi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Rouissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soybean meal]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Discriminant analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Factorial analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Faba beans]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ewe milk]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spectroscopy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lactation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The present study aimed to determine the potential of front face fluorescence spectroscopy (FFFS) to discriminate between milk samples belonging to Sicilo-Sarde ewes fed with three different feeding groups –named control, scotch bean meal and soybean meal– throughout the lactation stage (11 weeks). Milk samples were classified by factorial discriminant analysis. Similar results were obtained by separately applying factorial discriminant analysis (FDA) on each intrinsic probe [aromatic amino acids and nucleic acids (AAA plus NA), tryptophan, vitamin A and riboflavin]. In a second step, concatenation technique was applied to FFF spectra. Results obtained showed a good discrimination among milk samples with regard to lactation periods and diet compositions. These results showed that spectroscopic techniques may provide useful fingerprints and allow the identification of milk samples according to the feeding systems given to the ewes throughout the lactation periods.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006996.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 457-460]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600192">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Influence of water deficit on growth parameters of perennial grass species]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Karatassiou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Lazaridou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Kostopoulou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Antoniou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Leaf area]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phalaris aquatica]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agropyron intermedium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bromus inermis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Water is one of the most important environmental factors controlling the production of perennial grass species under semi arid Mediterranean conditions. In this experiment, the influence of water deficit on the growth parameters of three perennial grasses (Agropyron intermedium, Bromus inermis and Phalaris aquatica) was investigated. For this reason the shoot weight, the leaf weight and the leaf area were measu - red every fifteen days during the growing season and the specific leaf area (SLA) was calculated. P. aquatica presented the highest leaf and shoot weight, leaf area and SLA while A. intermedium the lowest leaf and shoot weight, leaf area and SLA. B. inermis showed an intermediate behaviour. The results suggest a differential performance of the three species in terms of growth under water deficit conditions. P. aquatica showed higher tolerance under drought conditions followed by B. inermis.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006832.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 61-64]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600193">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Competition in an alfalfa-tall fescue mixture under Mediterranean conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Lazaridou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Kostopoulou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Karatassiou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Leaf area]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Festuca arundinacea]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Competition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The focus of the current study was to evaluate the competitive ability of two forage species (alfalfa- Medicago sativa L., and tall fescue- Festuca arundinacea Schreb.) grown in dry and disturbed soils either in mixture (1:1) or in monocultures, for capture of sunlight. Two levels of water regimes were used: a) frequent irrigation by sprinkler to the point of field capacity and b) no irrigation (drought) conditions. The plants were cut in about 20 day time intervals, at height of 7 cm above soil surface. Measurements of the leaf area and the dry weight of leaves and stems were conducted during two successive growing seasons, and the leaf area ratio (LAR), the leaf weight ratio (LWR) and the leaf area index (LAI) were calculated. Our results showed that: mixture reduced significantly LAR and LAI of alfalfa only under irrigation, while these indices were unaffected in tall fescue; under both water regimes, the alfalfa LAI was higher to the corresponding tall fescue LAI; drought and mixing did not affect LWR, which remained higher in tall fescue compared to alfalfa during the season of experimentation. We conclude a lower competition ability of alfalfa to tall fescue under irrigation and therefore lower productivity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006858.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 87-92]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600194">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Developing a coherent monitoring system for Mediterranean grasslands]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Louhaichi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.D., Johnson]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.E., Clark]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Belgacem Areiz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Johnson]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vegetation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[VegMeasure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dynamics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Grasslands are one of the world‘s most widespread vegetation types, covering nearly 20% of the land surface and represent a major source of production of agricultural products. However, grassland vegetation across the Mediterranean region is changing at an unanticipated rate. These changes are the result of climatic and socio-economic changes. Because changes in agro-ecosystems affect the livelihoods and development of rural communities, it is important that planners and policy makers be able to determine grassland condition and trend in relation to climatic and managerial factors at specific locations. Over the past decade we have been developing monitoring technologies and protocols that can be used at local scales which speed the collection, processing, and storage of indicators of grassland health. By coupling digital photography, GPS technologies, information collected with accessory devices, and computer software applied in a strict monitoring protocol, we are able to rapidly monitor grassland vegetation. Repeated measurements over time at the same locations provide information regarding environmental trend and rate of change. When we couple our local scale measurements with landscape scale remote sensing data such as satellite or high altitude aerial photography, we have a more complete picture of vegetation dynamics and system change which facilitates interpretation and development of mitigation strategies.Grasslands are one of the world‘s most widespread vegetation types, covering nearly 20% of the land surface and represent a major source of production of agricultural products. However, grassland vegetation across the Mediterranean region is changing at an unanticipated rate. These changes are the result of climatic and socio-economic changes. Because changes in agro-ecosystems affect the livelihoods and development of rural communities, it is important that planners and policy makers be able to determine grassland condition and trend in relation to climatic and managerial factors at specific locations. Over the past decade we have been developing monitoring technologies and protocols that can be used at local scales which speed the collection, processing, and storage of indicators of grassland health. By coupling digital photography, GPS technologies, information collected with accessory devices, and computer software applied in a strict monitoring protocol, we are able to rapidly monitor grassland vegetation. Repeated measurements over time at the same locations provide information regarding environmental trend and rate of change. When we couple our local scale measurements with landscape scale remote sensing data such as satellite or high altitude aerial photography, we have a more complete picture of vegetation dynamics and system change which facilitates interpretation and development of mitigation strategies.Grasslands are one of the world‘s most widespread vegetation types, covering nearly 20% of the land surface and represent a major source of production of agricultural products. However, grassland vegetation across the Mediterranean region is changing at an unanticipated rate. These changes are the result of climatic and socio-economic changes. Because changes in agro-ecosystems affect the livelihoods and development of rural communities, it is important that planners and policy makers be able to determine grassland condition and trend in relation to climatic and managerial factors at specific locations. Over the past decade we have been developing monitoring technologies and protocols that can be used at local scales which speed the collection, processing, and storage of indicators of grassland health. By coupling digital photography, GPS technologies, information collected with accessory devices, and computer software applied in a strict monitoring protocol, we are able to rapidly monitor grassland vegetation. Repeated measurements over time at the same locations provide information regarding environmental trend and rate of change. When we couple our local scale measurements with landscape scale remote sensing data such as satellite or high altitude aerial photography, we have a more complete picture of vegetation dynamics and system change which facilitates interpretation and development of mitigation strategies.Grasslands are one of the world‘s most widespread vegetation types, covering nearly 20% of the land surface and represent a major source of production of agricultural products. However, grassland vegetation across the Mediterranean region is changing at an unanticipated rate. These changes are the result of climatic and socio-economic changes. Because changes in agro-ecosystems affect the livelihoods and development of rural communities, it is important that planners and policy makers be able to determine grassland condition and trend in relation to climatic and managerial factors at specific locations. Over the past decade we have been developing monitoring technologies and pr]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006829.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 47-51]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600195">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Enhancement of agro-pastoral productions in the rural community of M’Nahba (Wilaya of Marrakech – Morocco)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Lubino]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Mortaji]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sitzia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.P., Roggero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Melis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean zone]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rehabilitation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Degradation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rural development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Resowing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Livelihood in rural communities of Morocco is based primarily on breeding of meat sheep in agropastoral systems where forage resources are scarce and mainly represented by cereal residuals and fallow. Intensive sheep grazing and frequent agricultural tillage on cereals, practiced by rural population as a consequence of the abandonment of nomadic life, have progressively contributed to serious soil degradation and erosion. This degradation of the ecosystem has been leading a rural exodus towards urban areas within and outside the country. The present contribution is devoted to illustrate the holistic approach and activities carried out by a bilateral cooperation project Sardinia-Morocco aimed at the rehabilitation of degraded pastures by means of alley cropping, the enhancement of socio-economic conditions and the exchange of knowledge and know-how between Sardinian and Moroccan stakeholders.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007005.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 497-501]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600196">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Performance of some tall fescue varieties grown under Algerian semi-arid conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Mefti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Bouzerzour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Chebouti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Kebour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Abedleguerfi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water use efficiency]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Perennials]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasses]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiarid climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dry matter content]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Within farming systems, perennial grasslands provide numerous positive environmental effects such as improvement of soil structure, erosion decrease, control of nitrate leaching and maintenance of biodiversity. In order to develop grassland crops with improved persistence and enhanced water use efficiency, 7 cultivars of tall fescue (Festuca arundinacea Schreb.) were evaluated for agronomic behaviour and persistence in the semi-arid region of Setif during the 2007-08 cropping season, corresponding to the third year of production. The measured traits focused on accumulated dry matter (DM), water use efficiency (WUE), plant height (PHT), relative growth rate (RGR) sward persistence (PER) and earliness (DHE). The study revealed the existence of variability for some traits, and identified cultivars having high dry matter yield and good water use efficiency. The results indicated too that the tested genotypes differed significantly for the measured traits. Fletcha, FletchaEF and Fraydo gave the best dry matter yield, RGR, PER and WUE, while Lutine, Sisa and Centurion performed poorly under semi-arid growth conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006866.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 135-138]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600197">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Production and persistence of Mediterranean perennial grasses under contrasting climatic scenarios]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Poirier]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.L., Durand]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Volaire]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mortality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Survival]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Summer]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the current context of increasing droughts due to climate change, this study analyzed the effects of a range of severe summer water deficits (-329 to -710 mm) and summer high temperatures (plus 3 and plus 6 degrees C than ambient temperatures for 2-3 weeks) on the persistence and production of perennial forage grasses. We compared a Mediterranean cultivar (cv) of cocksfoot (Dactylis glomerata L., cv Medly) and of tall fescue (Festuca arundinacea Schreb, cv. Centurion), in both a Mediterranean and a temperate site in France. The results show that (1) the annual production was variable but reduced on average by 40 per cent along the range of tested water deficits; (2) the thresholds of significant increased mortality occurred at around 560 mm of water deficit; (3) deeper water uptake can be associated with the greater persistence of tall fescue at high water deficit and (4) an after-effect of summer water deficits resulted in an increase of frost sensitivity especially for cocksfoot. To cope with climate change, breeding programs for Mediterranean cultivars should aim to improve both frost tolerance and drought survival through increased summer dormancy]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006831.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 57-60]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600198">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The impact of climatic variations on the role and sustainable management of natural ecosystems in the Middle Atlas (Afenourir wetland area case)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Qarro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Ezzahiri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Population pressure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Humid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The Afenourir lake (wetland area; 33 degrees 17’N - 5 degrees 16’W) is located in the Central Middle Atlas of Morocco south of Ifrane province about 30km south of Azrou. The lake is part of the perimeter of Ifrane National Park as established in October 2004. It belongs to the Western Palearctic biogeography region. Afennourir area has several land statutes that are subject to rights of land use and various other regulations: (i) the ethnic use tenure, under the authority of the Interior Ministry, (ii) the private domain of the State, this is the forest area which is under the tutelage of forest department, (iii) the swamp area is under the supervision of the watershed hydraulic agency of Sebou. The Afennourir site constitutes important water resources to local people in this area where the physical land characteristics do not allow the storage of rainwater and snowmelt and to develop real rivers. Therefore, the waters of the lake are highly coveted as evidenced by the large number of wells around the lake especially in the eastern part. At present, the area knows the existence of illegal forty wells. The pumping of water from these wells knows great importance.Water withdrawals, either for domestic or for watering the cattle, are valued to 180 m3 per day. This quantity pumped at the wells has a direct effect on the lake since both are fed from shallow aquifer. This situation is more aggravated by climatic conditions which are often dry and which are favorable to the habitat establishments around the lake leading to livestock concentration in the area increasing the needs for water and forage.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006861.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 103-106]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600199">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Drought and high temperature resistance evaluation of Dactylis glomerata L.]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.M., Carroni]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Pitzalis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Sulas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Ledda]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Relative humidity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dactylis glomerata]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought resistance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Photosynthesis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[With the aim to identify cultivars characterized by high drought and temperature resistance and high water use efficiency a study was carried out on 1 accession (Jana) and 4 Sardinian ecotypes of orchard grass (Dactylis glomerata L.) (Bolotana, Bonorva, Bonnanaro, Platamona). To evaluate the adaptive responses of different D. glomerata ecotypes, two trials were carried out in order to evaluate drought resistance under rain proof shelter and controlled water supply, and to evaluate high temperature resistance in a greenhouse where high summer temperature (daily maximum temperature haigher than 50 degrees C) were monitored. On December 2010 seeds were sown in seed benches at the beginning of March the plants were transplanted at the 5th leaf stage in 45 litres pots, utilized in the drought resistance trial, and in a container (25 x 0.8 m), utilized in the high temperature resistance trial. In drought resistance trial, two water regimes were applied: 1) Control, soil humidity was kept at the field capacity, 2) W1, pots water losses were reintegrated at 80 per cent. Above ground plant biomass, net photosynthesis, transpiration rate, stomatal conductance, leaf relative water content (RWC) were monitored throughout both trials.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006892.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 261-264]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600200">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Sustainability of a beef cattle production system in Mediterranean marginal areas]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sitzia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.M., Marrosu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Acciaro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Decandia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marginal land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Beef cattle]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this work was to evaluate the strategic role of Sardinian marginal areas in the sustainability of beef cattle production systems. The study was conducted between April and November 2011 in an experimental area (24 ha, 670 m a.s.l.) of North-West Sardinia, dominated by woody vegetation, mainly oak species, with an herbaceous cover limited to the 12 per cent of the surface. Twenty-four calves, divided in 4 groups according to the breed: Sarda, castrated Sarda, Sardo-Modicana and a progeny by Charolaise bull and Sarda cow, were used. The animals after weaning, at 6 month of age and 168.5 kg plus minus 16.2 of live weight (LW, means plus minus SE), were raised at pasture (0.4 LU ha-1) receiving a supplementation from the end of summer. Monthly animals were weighted and the herbage availability was monitored. The farm meteorological data were registered daily. The pattern of LW and growing rate (kg head-1day-1) show a strong dependence from herbage availability, the latter becoming negative during the summer. The studied system shows a shortness of feed during summer and beginning of autumn, due to the delay of autumn rain, confirming the strong relationship between animal performance and seasonal changes in Mediterranean conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006987.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 395-399]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600201">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Root colonization of hybrid maize cultivars by mycorrhizal and pathogenic fungi at establishment in an acid soil with high phosphorus content]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Sainz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Aguín]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Bande]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Aris]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Pintos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.P., Mansilla]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Zea mays]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phosphorous]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pythium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fuxarium oxysporum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arbuscular mycorrhiza]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The formation of arbuscular mycorrhizas (AM), a symbiosis between roots and Glomeromycetes that improves P nutrition, health and stress tolerance of plants, can be important for establishment of maize in acid soils. In this work, a field experiment was set up in a limed acid soil with high Olsen-P content to study the colonization of roots by AM fungi and/or other soil borne fungi in 48 maize hybrid cultivars. Plants were under a severe drought at establishment. One month after sowing, AM fungi colonized over 40 per cent of the root length of most cultivars, suggesting a mycorrhizal dependency of these plants to withstand water stress conditions. Ten cultivars presented less than 20 per cent of AM root colonization. As determined by molecular methods, the most frequent AM fungi were Gigaspora decipiens and Glomus spp. Roots were also colonized by Pythium spp., Fusarium solani, and F. oxysporum.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007001.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 477-481]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600202">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[An evaluation of overall fodder production in extensive silvopastoral systems with different cover of shrub understory. The case of Iberian dehesas]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.L., López-Díaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Rivest]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Rolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Moreno]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shrubs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Acorns]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Retama shaerocarpa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cistus ladanifer]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forages]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Grazed Mediterranean open woodlands, as the Iberian dehesa, are an outstanding example of silvopastoral system where shrub encroachment has been proposed as an effective means to facilitate tree seedling recruitment and ensure the system persistence. The aim of this essay is to test the effects of different intensity of shrub encroachment on different fodder components of the system: acorn production, forage shrub and grassland yield. Metabolic Energy (ME) was increased by R. sphaerocarpa due to the increase of grass production and the contribution of shrub fodder in addition to the supply of acorns. Instead, the ME supplied by C. ladanifer layer, did not compensate the reduction in grassland and acorn production because of the low metabolic energy that C. ladanifer canopy provides.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006989.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 423-426]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600203">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Selection of pasture and forage species adapted to changing environmental conditions in Mediterranean climates]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.R., Norton]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Volaire]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought resistance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Summer]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dormancy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dehydration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Over the last two decades, many agricultural regions of the Earth with Mediterranean climates have suffered from changing climatic conditions in the form of extended periods of intense drought. These droughts have been associated with an increasing awareness of and concern about climate change and the likely future nature of Mediterranean-type climates. Coping with climate change will be a difficult problem to address because most models for Mediterranean-climate regions predict drier and hotter environments such as for example, in south-western Australia and the western Mediterranean Basin. In south-eastern Australia, while the overall amount of rainfall is predicted to decline, summers are expected to receive more rain and winters become drier. Assuming these predictions are correct, the pastures and rangelands of these regions will experience stresses that without intervention or altered management may cause their wholesale collapse. Not only would this seriously reduce the production of food and fibre from grazing animals it would also lead to a decline in the numerous ecosystem services provided by grasslands such as the services which improve and protect soil structure contributing to the sustainability of cropping through the reduction of nitrate leaching and the maintenance of biodiversity. In Australia, pastures research to adapt to these future climate scenarios has so far primarily focussed on improving plant growth models and assessment of the ability of agricultural soils to sequester more atmospheric carbon. Around the Mediterranean Basin, forage plant research is still mainly focussed on annual crops, cereals and irrigated lucerne. In both regions the focus now needs to shift to the development of more climate resilient perennial plants and agronomic systems able to use these more resilient plants efficiently. Pre-breeding research is needed to identify germplasm resources within the major perennial pasture species with enhanced levels of drought and heat tolerance. This paper describes methods to identify and measure two of the important drought tolerance traits used by perennial herbaceous plants, dehydration tolerance and summer dormancy.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006864.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 119-128]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600204">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Nutrient and tannin content of browsing shrub legumes informally used for small ruminant feeding in Canary Islands, Spain]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.R., Ventura]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Bastianelli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Hassoun]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.P., Flores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Bonnal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., González-García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shrubs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adenocarpus foliosus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cytisus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Browsing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crude protein]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tannins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tedera]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDF]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cytisus proliferus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Bituminaria bituminosa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this study was to contribute to the characterization of nutritional potential, with special attention to the profiles on phenolic compounds and condensed tannins, of some native browsing shrub legumes informally used for ruminant feeding in Canary Islands. The species selected for this study were Bituminaria bituminosa var. bituminosa, Bituminaria bituminosa var. albormaginata, Chamaecytisus proliferus var. palmensis, Chamaecytisus proliferus var. canariae and Adenocarpus foliosus. Crude protein (CP) ranged from 10.6 per cent (Bituminaria b. bituminosa) to 18.5 per cent (Adenocarpus foliosus) whereas neutral detergent fibre (NDF) was between 39.9 per cent (Chamaecytisus p. canariae) and 51.6 per cent (Bituminaria b. albormaginata). Condensed tannins expressed as catechin equivalent ranged from 0.1 per cent (Bituminaria b. albormaginata) to 0.5 per cent (Bituminaria b. bituminosa), and total phenols expressed as tannic acid equivalent ranged from 0.9 per cent (Bituminaria b. albormaginata) to 3.5 per cent (Chamaecytisus p. palmensis). The organic matter digestibility (OMD) ranged from 51.9 per cent (Bituminaria b.albormaginata) to 71.5 per cent (Chamaecytisus p. canariae). Current results support the thesis that, according to the more local empiric practices, native flora of Canary Islands have an under exploited potential with the capacity to assist eventual changes in ruminant feeding systems strategies. Nevertheless, deeper characterization and in vivo evaluation studies of the species covered in this study are required at different seasons and vegetative stages (e.g. digestibility in vivo, palatability, voluntary intake, productive response).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006986.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 391-394]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600205">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Irrigated fodder as the pillar of cattle products' supply chains in the South Mediterranean area: present situation and future prospects]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.T., Sraïri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean zone]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cattle]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Groundwater]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Recent evolutions of livestock systems in the South Mediterranean area converge towards an intensification of production. Rangeland systems located in rain fed areas may not be sufficient to ensure the supply of animal proteins. As a consequence, increased efforts are needed to get more milk and meat from irrigated areas, which imply a steady output of high quality forage. The study of water uses by livestock in irrigation schemes requires a complex methodology, which has to take into account various functions of production: (i) from water volumes of different sources to fodder (quantity of biomass and its distribution throughout the seasons) and then (ii) from forage to cattle products (both milk and meat at the same time as farms are often not specialised). Moreover, climate change affects water availability and intense pressure on groundwater may put at risk many livestock systems. In this study, we take the example of the Tadla large scale irrigated scheme (105,000 ha) to present the issue of water productivity through cattle. Then, we discuss the future prospects of this topic, given the possibilities of on-farm intervention to achieve a “Livestock Revolution”: improving farms’ income with a sustainable use of the available water resources.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007002.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 483-487]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600206">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Increasing production and improving quality of lamb's meat through grassland cultivation and rotational management]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Atti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Mahouachi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Growth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Carcasses composition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lambs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feedlots]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this study was to evaluate lamb's growth and carcass characteristics on grazed grassland compared to feedlot (FL) system. The grassland consists in two separate plots of green barley (GB) and perennial ryegrass (RG). Forty five lambs (14.8 plus minus 2.9 kg live weight (LW)) were divided into three groups. Two groups were conducted on rotational grazing with a stocking rate of 60 lambs per ha, one on GB and the other on RG and received daily 350 g of concentrate per lamb. The last group was conducted on FL with ryegrass hay and the same concentrate ad-libitum. The whole grass yield was higher for RG grassland than for GB one. The crude protein content of grass was higher for both species (14 per cent) than ryegrass hay (8.5 per cent ). The mean daily herbage availability was 0.850 and 0.720 kg DM per lamb of RG and GB, respectively. Indoor daily intake was 450 g of hay and 650 g of concentrate per lamb. For 60 lambs, the owner needs 2.76 vs 2 ha in FL and grassland grazing system, respectively. Lamb's final LW and average daily gain were higher for grassland lambs (28.3 kg and 140 g) than FL ones (26.9 kg and 121 g). The whole LW gain was 176, 200 and 210 kg for FL, GB and RG treatments; which equivalent to 254, 399 and 420 kg LW gain per ha in FL, GB and RG, respectively. Furthermore, grassland lamb's carcasses were less adipose (18 per cent ) and contain more muscle (57 per cent ) than that of FL (26 per cent fat and 51 per cent muscle). Grazing grassland with rotational management leads to higher lamb production with higher muscle and lower fat carcass concentrations than FL system. This production system is more economic and resulted in lamb meat with high nutritional characteristics.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007006.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 503-507]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600207">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The quantity and quality of different forage resources (fallow land, grassland and stubble) in the semi arid area of Sétif]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Tedjari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Madani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiarid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Productivity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutritional value]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This work aims at the knowledge of the pastoral resources productivity and quality used in the Sétifan High Plains. During one year (2003), monitoring the production and the nutritional value of natural pastures, fallow and stubble was conducted in seven farms. This study allowed us to move to the farm plot, specifying the feeding system characteristics; the floristic composition and the resources energetic value studied so far (fallow land, pastures and stubble). The results showed significant differences and varied according to the different seasons. For the grassland, the productivity is 11t per ha. It is of 3 to 4t per ha for stubble and mown fallow; while the production of grazed fallow is of 2t per ha.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007004.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 493-495]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600208">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Change in milk composition and fatty acid profile of dairy ewes depending on nature of two annual grasses species in sub-humid region of Tunisia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Maamouri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Atti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasses]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ewes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fatty acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Milk yield]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tunisia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sicilo-Sarde]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this synthesis is to investigate the forage production of two annual grasses species (green barley and triticale) and their effects on milk production, composition and fatty acid profile of dairy ewes in the Tunisian sub-humid area. The first regimen was based on green barley (GB) and the second regimen was based on triticale (T). The concentrate supply was 300 g per day per ewe for each group. The dry matter forage production was 2.4 and 5.4 t per ha for green barley and triticale respectively. Milk production was significantly higher for T group than GB one (540 vs 460 ml per day). Fat and protein content (g per kg) were higher for ewes fed triticale pasture than ewes fed green barley pasture (39.1 vs 33.6 g per kg of milk fat and 26 vs 24 g per kg of milk protein for T group and GB one respectively). Milk of ewes fed triticale had a higher percentage on poly unsaturated fatty acid (PUFA) than ewes fed green (6 vs 2.9 per cent for T and GB respectively), on total unsaturated fatty acid (UFA) (28.7 vs 26.3 per cent for T and GB respectively), on C18:0 (11 vs 8.5 per cent for T and GB respectively), on C18:1 (23 vs 21.4 per cent for T and GB respectively) and on C18:2 (3.5 vs 1.7 per cent for T and GB respectively). Milk from ewes fed triticale had a higher linolenic acid (C18:3) proportion than milk from ewes of GB group (0.9 vs 0.5 per cent respectively). The milk CLA content was significantly higher for GB group than for T group (7.3 vs 3.2 per cent respectively). In conclusion, the cultivated triticale pasture seems conduct to higher production and healthier ewe’s milk comparing to green barley except CLA percentage which the highest value was found in ewe’s milk fed green barley.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006998.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 465-468]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600209">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The effect of seed size and some priming method on germination of Vicia sativa L.]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Onal Asci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Seed size]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vicia sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Priming]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Germinability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The sudty was conducted to determine the effect of seed size and some priming methods on germination of common vetch. Seed was fractionated into two classes “small or large seed”. The seeds for each seed size were primed in different priming medium. Germination performance of large seed is higher than small seed. PEG solution is suitable for common vetch.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006887.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 237-240]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600210">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[REFORMA: a new project for identification and selection of resilient, water- and energy-efficient forage and feed crops for Mediterranean agricultural systems]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Annicchiarico]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Julier]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Pecetti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Abdelguerfi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Bouizgaren]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.C., Brummer]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Burstin]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Hayek]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Thami Alami]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pisum sativum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[MAS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Protein concentrates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Crop-livestock and feed systems have huge importance for Mediterranean regions to satisfy the increasing demand for animal products, increase the economic stability of smallholders and produce typical animal products with high added-value, while contributing to sustainable farming, environment protection and efficient nutrient cycling. These systems are threatened, however, by the marked insufficiency of high-protein feedstuff, the overexploitation of forage resources, the increasing costs and/or the decreasing availability of irrigation water and mineral fertilizers, and the increasing drought and heat stress arising from climate change. The development of resilient, water- and energy-efficient forage and feed legume crops could definitely alleviate these constraints. This is the objective of the ArimNet project “Resilient, water- and energyefficient forage and feed crops for Mediterranean agricultural systems (REFORMA)”, which joins nine research institutions from Italy, France, Algeria, Morocco, Tunisia and USA in an integrated manner to develop: 1) lucerne varieties with tolerance to severe drought, salinity, heat and grazing; 2) pea varieties with drought tolerance, targeted to grain and forage production; 3) cost-efficient marker-assisted selection procedures, and ecologically-based breeding strategies, for lucerne and pea; 4) lucerne-based and pea-based forage crops, taking into account the legume plant types, the associated grass or cereal species, the level of site drought stress, the acceptability by farmers, the forage quality and the target utilization.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006860.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 97-102]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600211">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Comparative estimation of crude protein, phenols and tannins concentration of Lotus corniculatus growing in different habitats]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Giagourta]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z.M., Parissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.P., Kyriazopoulos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.M., Abraham]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lotus corniculatus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crude protein]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tannins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Lotus corniculatus is a temperate perennial legume that contains condensed tannins which increase the animal production and decrease bloating in ruminants. The aim of this study was to investigate differences in crude protein (CP), total phenols (TPH), total tannins (TT) and condensed tannins (CT) concentration of L. corniculatus individuals growing in oak forest and in open grasslands. The collection of plant material was conducted in Taxiarchis area, Chalkidiki, Northern Greece from four sites in an oak forest and four sites in adjacent open grasslands. Twenty individual plants of L. corniculatus were randomly collected at the flowering stage in summer 2011 from each of the eight sites and were analysed for CP, TPH, TT and CT concentration. According to the results, the CP concentration was significantly higher in individuals from the forest in comparison to individuals from the open grasslands. Inversely, the individuals from the open grasslands had significantly higher concentration of TPH, TT and CT compared to those from the forest.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006871.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 161-164]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600212">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of limited water supply on Melilotus officinalis nutrient content]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Kostopoulou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Karatassiou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Barbayannis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Melilotus officinalis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutrients]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of the present study was to investigate the influence of limited water supply on nutrient accumulation of Melilotus officinalis tissues. For this purpose a pot experiment was conducted, where half of the pots were fully irrigated (up to field capacity) and the rest were irrigated with half the quantity of water. Irrigation plan was applied for five weeks during the growing season. At the end of the experiment, randomly selected plant material, divided in roots, shoots and leaves, was dried and the content of K, Na, Mg, Ca, Cu, Fe, Zn and Mn was determined. The results showed that the limited water supply interacted with the mineral content of M. officinalis plants, increasing the concentration of K, Ca, Mg, Cu, Fe and Mn in the leaf tissues. Accumulation of these nutrients could serve as a means to alleviate the adverse impact of drought on important metabolic processes, enhancing M. officinalis tolerance to water stress.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006857.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 83-86]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600213">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Challenge the roots. Moving toward a sustainable agriculture]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Mulè]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Manca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Vargiu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Roots]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[MInimum tillage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Models]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forages]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The research would demonstrate how to reduce the total input in a forage system (i.e. fuel, pesticides, chemical nutrients), as well as in any other agricultural system, without decreasing the production. Since 2009 the field test has been carrying out in Sardinia, Italy. An integrated forage system, including leguminous and cereals, deals with minimum and no tillage techniques. The collected data, such as chemical and physical characteristics of the soil, forage quality and quantity at various steps (pasture, hay and grain) represents the input to develop and calibrate a model, or to extend the results to a large scale, in a similar environment. The results determine the feasibility to extend this approach, in several agricultural areas, characterized by a Mediterranean climate, and similar pedological feature]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006999.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 469-472]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600214">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Messina (Melilotus siculus) – a new annual pasture legume for Mediterranean-type climates with high tolerance of salinity and waterlogging]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.G.H., Nichols]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N.L., Teakle]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.L., Bonython]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.A., Ballard]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Charman]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.D., Craig]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Salinity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nitrogen fixation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rhizobium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plant breeding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultivars]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Waterlogging]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Messina (Melilotus siculus) is a new annual pasture legume with high waterlogging tolerance and much higher salt tolerance than other legumes. Glasshouse and laboratory studies have identified several mechanisms for both salt and waterlogging tolerance that explain its adaptation to saline, waterlogged soils. Field trials are underway to select the best adapted line for release as a new cultivar. Selection is also being conducted for an adapted salt tolerant Rhizobium strain. This paper discusses the ecology, physiology and agronomy of messina and progress towards its release as a new pasture species for saline, waterlogged soils in Mediterranean-type climates.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006870.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 155-159]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600215">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The hydrodynamic relationships of two herbaceous species in a grazed Morus alba L. silvopastoral system]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.S., Sklavou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Karatassiou]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C.N., Tsiouvaras]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Noitsakis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Relative humidity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium subterraneum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Poa bulbosa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In most Mediterranean areas water is one of the major determinants of plant growth. The water relations of herbaceous species was studied in a Morus alba L. silvopastoral system under moderate grazing. The experimental area was divided into six fenced plots in order to exclude uncontrolled grazing. Three of them were randomly assigned to be grazed (0.9 sheep/ha/year) while the other three remained ungrazed. Half of every plot was ploughed and seeded with Trifolium subterraneum cv Mt. Barker while the other half remained with the natural herbaceous vegetation. The water potential (Ψ) and relative water content (RWC) of T. subterraneum and of the dominant native grass Poa bulbosa were measured. Although grazing does not modify the internal water status of T. subterraneum and P. bulbosa, both species seem to have the ability to control their water balance probably by pathetic regulation of osmosis.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006997.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 461-464]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600216">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Importance of Kochia prostrata (L.) Schrad in arid and semi arid regions for livestock feeds]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Özköse]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kochia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livestock]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The limiting factor in primary productivity in arid and semi arid regions is precipitation. So, selected forage species that are tolerant to drought and salinity are very important for livestock production. Forage kochia [Kochia prostrata (L.) Schrad.] which grows in unsuitable conditions, is important plant in desert and semi-desert regions. Forage kochia is a perennial xerophyte and semi-shrubby plant which grows up to 30-100 cm tall. The root system of forage kochia may extend to a depth of 10 m or more. Kochia prostrata is very variable and there are a lot of eco-types in the world and particularly in Turkey. Forage kochia is especially important for artificial dry land pastures (100-350 mm rainfalls per years). Forage kochia has been used as a year around grazing forage plant and when properly managed survives long years (average: 15 years).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006961.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 375-379]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600217">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Morphological characterization within some Algerian populations of Trifolium striatum L. (Fabaceae)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Issolah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Abdelguerfi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ecology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Natural environment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feed legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morphology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Within the framework of the evaluation and utilization of the plant genetic resources having a fodder and pastoral interest in Algeria, a morphological characterization was done on three Algerian populations Trifolium Striatum L. This species is regarded as quite scarce in Algeria. Several characteristics relating to plant vegetative and generative such as, fruiting heads, pods and seeds were studied. The ecological factors (rainfall, altitude) as well as geographical coordinates (latitude and longitude) of the population natural environment were taken into account during the statistical analysis. Preliminary results showed the existence of an intraspecific variation. Width of the fruiting heads characteristic was found to be particularly interesting for the taxonomic level and should deserve a special attention. The variation noticed in some characteristics of the plant, maximum height, maximum width, winter daily growth rate, length of the fruiting heads, would be linked to longitude and latitude parameters of the natural habitat of the populations. The conservation, the valorization and the development of this fodder legume, adapted to humid regions with a lot of rainfall in Algeria, could contribute towards the natural enrichment of soils with nitrogen fixation and the improvement of the living standards of the local communities through the expansion of livestock farming.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006883.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 219-222]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600218">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Dehydration tolerance and drought survival summer dormant Moroccan ecotypes cocksfoot (Dactylis glomerata L.)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Kallida]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Shaimi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Volaire]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dactylis glomerata]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought resistance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Summer]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dormancy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dehydration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Summer dormancy in perennial grasses is a major trait conferring plant survival and persistence in Mediterranean areas. The aim of the present study was to characterize the effect of summer dormancy on dehydration tolerance in six Moroccan ecotypes and two cultivars “Kasbah” and “Porto” of Dactylis glomerata in a glasshouse experiment. Measurements included the ratio of green-senescent aerial tissues, soil water evolution, water content in survival organs and plant survival rate. D8 and D9 ecotypes showed high senescence when soil moisture was 5 per cent, while Kasbah (dormant cultivar) was at 52 per cent of areal senescence. Proportion of senescent tissue reached 98 per cent for all ecotypes at soil humidity of 1.9 per cent. Under severe drought, water content of apices decreased to reach 0.31 g H20 g–1 dry weight, which was a lethal value for four tested ecotypes and cv. Porto. Except for Kasbah, D1 and D6, which remained alive with little hydrated apices. The soil moisture associated with 50 per cent of plant mortality was 2.5 per cent for Porto and D8 but decreased to 1.9 per cent for D14. Kasbah, D1 and D6 could survive until 1 per cent soil moisture. These results are ascribed to efficient strategies of both dehydration avoidance and tolerance in the best surviving genotypes.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006856.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 77-82]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600219">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The determination of pasture type alfalfa lines]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Altinok]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Türk]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Erol]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Akçelik Somay]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[characterization]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this research was to characterize 56 collected alfalfa populations growing with two experiments from clones and from seeds in 2010 and 2011. Collected alfalfa populations were affected significantly in most observed traits over two years period. The populations of Akyurt 1.2.3, Kizilcahamam 1.2., Gudul 1, Kazan 1.2., Cankaya 1, Sincan 2, Çubuk 2, Pursaklar 1, Şereflikochisar 1. 2. 3., Nallıhan 1 had erect growing habit and their annual dry matter yield/plant were very high over the two years. They are going to be evaluated for forage-type alfalfa breeding. Apart, all the other populations are going to be subject to a grazetype alfalfa breeding program in near future, because they showed perfect results when investigate of their pasture characters. The first cut dry matter yield/annual dry matter yield (percentage) was highest on the population of Kalecik 1 (82 per cent). Some of them also had high forage yields, as Golbası 1.2. and Kizilcahamam 1, as well as forage-type. They were growing horizontal, they spread on the surface and under the soil, some of them had rhizomes and they have so many tillers on their crown.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006873.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 169-172]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600220">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Reflexions on agro-pastoralists in the WANA region: Challenges and future priorities]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Ates]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Louhaichi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Resilience]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production system]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Diversification]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Food security]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agropastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Rangeland resources are among the most important – and almost certainly the most neglected – agro ecosystem component in dry areas. They are the largest land-use category, home to the poorest segment of the population, and crucial for millions of small-scale livestock producers. The availability of grazing resources for livestock in the world’s drylands is low and erratic due to the recurrent droughts in which animals can often fall victim. The insufficient feed supply has been in decline with widespread degradation of rangelands arising from overgrazing, loss of biodiversity, and human induced global warming. Moreover, the feed gap today is more pronounced as the livestock population has increased substantially as a result of growing demand for animal products in West Asia and North Africa (WANA) region. An important option to compensate the shortage of feed from rangelands is to grow more forage without compromising food security. It is evident that the livestock keepers in the drylands of WANA region can only attain the goal of desirable animal production if the rangelands are adequately managed. However, protection and rehabilitation of degraded rangelands depend upon complicated factors such as land tenure, control of grazing, intensified forage production, and recurrent droughts.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007007.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 511-516]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600221">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Selection of two triticale varieties for forage-end use in Tunisia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Ben Youssef]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Abidi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Jlidi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutritive value]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Winter crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spring crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Triticosecale]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Two new released triticale varieties (one spring type Tcl821 and one winter type, G41) were evaluated for their dry matter yield and nutritive value at three harvesting stages (first node detectable, Z31, late boot, Z50 and soft dough stag, Z85). Both genotypes confirmed their high dry matter yield potential at all stages. The winter triticale was more productive than the spring genotype at all growing stages. G41 presented a prostrate growth habit from emergence to first node detectable stage (Z31) and took much more time to reach that stage. Among the two cultivars, it was the best to be used by grazing or in dual-purpose system at early vegetative growth. At late boot stage (Z50), the winter type produced 9 T DM ha-1 of high quality forage (CP equal to 15 per cent; ADL equal to 3.8 per cent, dOM equal to 60 per cent). The spring triticale Tcl821 produced an equivalent forage quality but with half the yield potential (5 T DM ha-1). At soft dough stage, the spring triticale Tcl821 was as much productive as the winter genotype G41, but it produced a forage with much higher quality as expressed in terms of CP, ME and fibers. The agronomical meanings of the three key harvesting stages were discussed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006876.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 181-185]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600222">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of deficit irrigation on dry matter and sheep production from permanent sown pastures]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Isik]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Ates]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Gunes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.H., Aktas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Keles]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sheep]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A three year study compared pasture and sheep production from permanent sown pastures that were irrigated at four levels in Konya, the Central Anatolia Region of Turkey. Pastures were established in 2007 with Festuca rubra, Poa pratensis, Lolium perenne, Trifolium repens and Lotus corniculatus, and irrigated at 100 per cent, 75 per cent, 50 per cent or 25 per cent of field capacity (FC). Established pastures were grazed rotationally by flocks of weaned lambs between 2008 and 2010. The total annual dry matter production (DMP) (kg per ha) was reduced (P less than 0.01) by decreasing levels of irrigation in each year. Averaged across the years, mean annual DMP was 9.59, 8.78, 7.21 and 4.86 t per ha for FC 100 per cent, 75 per cent, 50 per cent and 25 per cent, respectively. Pastures irrigated at FC 100 per cent and 75 per cent provided equal animal production but total liveweight production (LWP) per ha decreased (P less than 0.01) when pastures irrigated at FC 50 per cent or at lower level in a similar manner in each year of the study.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006938.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 327-331]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600223">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Prediction of the nutritive value of annual forage clovers and serradella by near infrared spectroscopy (NIRS)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Pereira-Crespo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Valladares]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Flores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Resch]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Piñeiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Díaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., González-Arráez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Bande-Castro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[X., Rodriguez-Diz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chemical composition]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NIRS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Feed legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Digestibility]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Near infrared reflectance spectroscopy (NIRS) was evaluated as a tool to estimate organic matter (OM), crude protein (CP), acid detergent fiber (ADF), neutral detergent fiber (NDF), water soluble carbohydrates (WSC), ether extract (EE) contents and in vitro organic matter digestibility (IVOMD) in samples of six annual legumes species (Trifolium incarnatum, T. michelianum, T. resupinatum –ssp. resupinatum and majus–, T. vesiculosum and Ornithopus sativus) grown as winter crops and harvested in different dates in spring. After selecting a collection of 316 samples, calibration equations were developed by modified partial least square regression of the reference values on the spectra records. The best coefficient of determination in cross validation (r2) and range to error ratio (RER) values for OM, CP, ADF, NDF, WSC, EE and IVOMD were 0.71 and 11.8, 0.88 and 12.7, 0.91 and 15.3, 0.97 and 26.0, 0.91 and 20.6, 0.75 and 9.7 and 0.81 and 11.0, respectively. It is concluded that NIRS analysis is an useful tool for the prediction of the nutritive value of the annual forage legumes studied.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006888.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 241-244]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600224">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[New annual legumes as winter crops for intensive forage rotations in Galicia (NW Spain). II – Nutritive Value]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Pereira-Crespo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Valladares]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Flores]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Díaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Resch]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., González-Arráez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Bande-Castro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[X., Rodriguez-Diz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Piñeiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutritive value]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Serradella]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trifolium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Digestibility]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Galicia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crude protein content]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The digestibility and chemical composition values of six species of annual legumes (Crimson clo - ver, Balansa clover, Persian clover –ssp. resupinatum and ssp. majus–, Arrowleaf clover and French serra - della) sown in small plots as a winter monoculture crop in the CIAM research station farm (coastal zone of Galicia, NW Spain) and harvested in the next spring following a silage-cutting strategy is presented in this paper. Forage was given a first cut at two weeks intervals in six harvest dates beginning at mid-March, and a second cut was taken after six weeks of regrowth. Nutritive value, estimated by NIRS, was high in average, and was affected by species and harvest date. For the first and second growth cycles the mean values of in vitro organic matter digestibility (IVOMD, per cent) and crude protein content (CP, per cent dry matter) were, respectively, 73.0 plus minus 3.7 per cent and 71.7 plus minus 2.9 per cent for IVOMD and 17.8 plus minus 3.8 per cent and 18.4 plus minus 2.7 per cent for CP. Forage quality, whilst reducing from the first harvest date, showed a more marked decline after the third harvest date (mid-April). This date could be adequate for ensiling, providing a high-digestibility, protein-rich forage and would fit into an intensive two crops per year rotation with maize as the summer crop.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006890.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 251-255]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600225">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Quality and dry matter yield of triticale forage in winter and late-spring in Southwestern Spain]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Rodrigo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.J., Poblaciones]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Pinheiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Maças]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Olea]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Santamaría]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., García-White]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Extensive husbandry]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dehesa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Silvopastoral systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Livestock]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Special soil and climate conditions of the dehesa ecosystem in the south west of Spain have an influence in herbaceous biomass production, causing moments with a lack of feed for extensive livestock along the year. In this paper the possibility to introduce triticale crop for a double use (by grazing or cutting in winter and cut at late spring) to cover winter and summer deficiencies in animal feed, has been studied. Triticale varieties were, var. Fronteira, var. Alter and two experimental cultivars from the Portuguese National Agricultural Research Institute, called INIA 1 and INIA 2. As control, a variety of Italian ryegrass, was used. The experiment was carried out in a dehesa in the SW of Spain during three years (2008-09, 2009-10 and 2010-11). On average some triticale cultivar (INIA 1 and INIA 2) biomass yields were similar to the reference treatment one, giving rye-grass the lowest biomass in dry years. Alter and INIA 2 did not show decrease in DM yield when a cut in winter was applied but show an increment in quality (high CP content and low NDF).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006865.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 129-134]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600226">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The fluoride effect (NaF) on germination and yield production of three local species of Poaceae fodder]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Slimani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Boudelaa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ladjama]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Nadjeh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Benkadour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Germination]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chlorophylls]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Growth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Toxicity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fluorides]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sugars]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The effect of fluoride (NaF) of three local species of rye grass (Lolium multiflorum Lamk., tall fescue (Festuca arundinaceae) and red canary grass (Phalaris arundinaceae) was analyzed at the concentration of 0; 10-1M; 10-2 M and 10-3M. The results showed that germination was effected by fluoride pollution. In fact, applying constant level of NaF caused considerable decrease in germinal capacity and power. At the concentration level of NaF solution over 2.33 g.l-1. The process of germination was completely inhibited in the three studied species. Moreover, it is worth mentioning that fluoride was found to greatly affect fescue growth. In contrast, fluoride had a favorable effect on rye grass and reed canary grass growth. Such growth stimulation is explained by an elevation in the respiratory activity. On the other hand, biochemical estimations show that fluoride treatment disturb biosynthesis of both photoreceptor pigments and sugars. Finally, we can conclude that the response of these ecotypes to fluoride pollution seems to be relatively resistant to this type of pollution.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006894.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 271-275]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600227">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of the economic crisis on sheep farming systems: A case study from the north Evros region, Greece]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Manousidis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Abas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ragkos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E.M., Abraham]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z.M., Parissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.P., Kyriazopoulos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farming system]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sheep]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Variable costs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Animal feeding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dairy herds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Extensive and semi-extensive sheep farming constitute the traditional farming systems in the Mediterranean region. These systems are predominantly labor-intensive with relatively low capital requirements, where an essential part of the animal feeding requirements are based on grazing in natural rangelands. The increased market demand for sheep milk and modernization in life-styles has recently resulted in an increase in the intensive sheep farming. The sheep are fed indoors only on purchased or harvested forages produced on-farm and concentrates. Therefore, fixed and variable costs of this system are high. Moreover, the semi-intensive sheep farming system is characterized by grazing in artificial pastures, which reduces the feeding cost. The purpose of this paper is to study the sustainability of the above three sheep farming systems. Technical and economic data from a sample of sheep farms in the north Evros region of Greece were collected in 2011 and analyzed in order to evaluate advantages and disadvantages of each system. The results provide strong evidence that the intensive system has been more adversely affected by the current economic crisis and it is more vulnerable to the potential negative effect of continued volatility of the economy than the semi-extensive ones. This is because the intensive system requires higher variable costs of purchasing harvested forage and concentrates. Although the semiintensive system exhibits high variable costs, its feeding costs were significantly lower than the intensive.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006992.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 439-442]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600228">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Grassland management options under Kyoto Protocol Article 3.4. The Portuguese case study]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Valada]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Teixeira]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Martins]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Ribeiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Domingos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Shrubs]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Carbon sequestration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Non-tillage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Portugal has voluntarily committed to reporting the CO2 emissions and removals resulting from grassland management under Kyoto Protocol Article 3.4. This commitment, together with the fact that a significant proportion of grasslands in Portugal are of low productivity and are located in the regions with higher risk of desertification, brought the context and motivation to promote the expansion of permanent sown biodiverse rich in legumes. These pastures are an innovation from the Biodiversity Engineering that promotes the increase of the soil organic matter and consequent carbon sequestration. Nowadays, this type of pasture represents more than 85 000 ha in Portugal, from which a significant percentage has been supported by the Portuguese Carbon Fund as a way of refunding farmers for the provision of an environmental service. Recently, the Portuguese Carbon Fund has also demonstrated interest in remunerating the farmers willing to control shrub encroachment at pastures through the use of non-invasive techniques that promote soil carbon sequestration. Regarding the biodiverse pastures, a 10 years model of the soil organic matter dynamic shows a carbon sequestration of about 6.5 t CO2.ha-1.yr-1. In the case of the change of practice for shrub control, results from a preliminary model are promising in what concerns the prediction of carbon sequestration.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006830.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 53-56]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600229">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Variation in seed yield and morphological traits in Turkish grass pea (Lathyrus sativus) genotypes]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[U., Basaran]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Mut]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Onal Asci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Gulumser]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Ayan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Seeds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lathyrus sativus]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grass pea]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land races]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this study 51Turkish landraces, 4 ICARDA lines and 1 registered variety of Lathyrus sativus L. were investigated for morphological characters and seed yield. The experiment was carried out in Samsun ecological conditions in 2009 with spring-sown. A high variation was determined among genotypes regarding the investigated characters, especially in seed yield and thousand seed weight. The variation among the Lathyrus sativus genotypes was between 2.82 g per plant and 13.64 g per plant for seed yield and between 5.10 g per plant and 22.89 g per plant for biological yield and between 91.65 g and 167.70 g for thousand seed weight. Many of the landraces had higher seed yield and thousand seed weight than registered cultivar named “Gurbuz 2001”. Correlation analysis showed that biological yield, stem number, pod number per plant and petiole length highly and positively correlated with seed yield.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006868.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 145-148]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600230">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Current trends in the transhumant sheep and goat sector in Greece]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Laga]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ragkos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Skapetas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Mitsopoulos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Kiritsi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Abas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Mazaraki]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Bambidis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Transhumance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Greece]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Goats]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sheep]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The transhumant sheep and goat farming system is mainly characterized by the sustainable use of pastures for animal nutrition, low fixed capital endowments and intensive use of human labor. The system is typical for Greece, although it exhibits a constant decline during the last 30 years. The purpose of this study is to provide a thorough presentation of the current situation of the transhumant sheep and goat farming sector in Greece. Through a survey of all relevant public services, data concerning the number of transhumant farms and animals as well as their movements in 2011 are presented. The survey reveals that transhumant flocks are present in the lowlands of most of the regions in Greece and move towards mountainous rangelands of less favored areas (particularly in Macedonia and Epirus). The distances of the movements vary considerably and can be classified as small (within the boundaries of Prefectures), relatively large (mainly within the boundaries of Regions) and large (mainly intra-regional movements).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007000.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 473-476]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600231">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of herd mobility on the species composition and productivity of plant communities in the northern Mediterranean region of Morocco]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y., Chebli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Mrabet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Chentouf]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rif]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adaptation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biomass]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The study was conducted in two pasture areas in the Moroccan Rif mountains (Akoumi and Bettara) exclusively used by goat’s herds to assess biomass production and botanical composition of major species. To measure plant biomass we used the method of the reference module. Breeders use pasture throughout the year, except on rainy days where they resort to limbing. The shrub, mainly Erica arborea and Arbutus unedo, is the main diet used by goats. In Bettara, breeders are becoming sedentary, where the pastures are overgrazed and dominated by unpalatable plant species, and biomass production is estimated to 934 kg DM per ha. In Akoumi, where breeders are still transhumant, plant biomass largely exceeds that of Bettara (2256 kg DM per ha). A seasonal movement alleviates anthropozoic pressure on pastoral land and allows restoration of palatable species. In fact due to climate change, silvopastoral resources will be less available and of lower quality, mobility of herds is a necessary adaptation strategy to insure sustainability of pastoral resources.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006932.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 303-306]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600232">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Alley cropping as a durable alternative for pasture land development in the drought prone region of Eastern Morocco]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y., Chebli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Mrabet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Chentouf]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Barley]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Alley cropping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean region]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Atriplex nummularia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Eastern region of Morocco, which is under permanent water shortage and recurrent drought, is facing problems of pastoral land degradation that threaten economic livelihoods of resource-poor farmers. In order to diversify the productivity and meet livestock nutritional requirements during feed gap periods, saltbush (Atriplex nummularia) was planted in association with barley (alley cropping). This study was conducted in Tancherfi area in order to assess the socio-economic impact of changes in farming systems using alley cropping. The vegetation parameters (shrub biomass and canopy cover) were measured during three periods. The results showed that biomass and canopy cover of Atriplex nummularia increased by 15% and 10% respectively due to the inclusion of barley. This association had positive effects on soil properties, which improved soil water status. Farmers expressed their satisfaction with this technique that allowed a 38.9% increase in barley grain yield. This result could be explained by the microclimate created by fodder shrubs that benefited barley growth and development. As a conclusion, with active involvement of community alley cropping should be introduced in any policy related to development of pasture lands in eastern region of Morocco.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006994.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 449-452]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600233">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[New approaches for grassland research in a context of climate and socio-economic changes]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., López-Francos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Porqueddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farming systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Socioeconomic environment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rehabilitation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adaptation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean region]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Grassland-based systems are no longer seen exclusively as livestock production enterprises but as multiple use systems with important consequences for the global environment. They are crucial for the protection of ecosystem goods and services, for tourism and for mitigating climate change. Wellmanaged grasslands provide important benefits such as increased water infiltration and retention or improved nutrient cycling, associated with organic matter accumulation in the soil, as well as increased plant growth and species diversity. Thereby, grassland management is also an adaptation strategy for climate change, as it reduces the risks associated with prolonged drought periods and unreliable rains that characterise Mediterranean regions. There is an urgent need to assess the interaction between climate change and grasslands to identify appropriate options that can help farmers to manage forage resources under increasing drought conditions and market globalisation. The challenge is then to improve grassland productivity, pasture persistence and resilience under these constraints. Scientific advances in grassland management and new strategies in plant improvement may undoubtedly contribute to this aim. This publication is the outcome of the 14th Meeting of the FAO-CIHEAM Inter-regional Cooperative Research and Development Sub-Network on Mediterranean Pastures and Fodder Crops titled “New approaches for grassland research in a context of climatic and socio-economic changes” which took place in Samsun (Turkey) from 3 to 6 October 2012, and includes the invited and selected papers presented at the Meeting.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/a102.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Conference Proceedings]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 541]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[14. Meeting of the FAO-CIHEAM Subnetwork on Mediterranean Forages and Fodder Crops on New approaches for grassland research in a context of climate and socio-economic changes]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600234">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Overview on grassland and farming systems in Samsun province]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Acar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Ayan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[O., Tongel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Area]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Turkey]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Samsun]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forages]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Samsun province is one of the important provinces for its high agricultural potential in Turkey. Around 45 per cent of the province total area is suitable for cultivation. Crop production makes 81 per cent of the total agricultural income. However, the average farm size is very small at about 4 hectares. In order to sustain the existence of small enterprises, livestock and the cultivation of forage crops with a higher added value should be developed accordingly. For this purpose, there should be more forage plants in crop rotation systems. High yielding forage crops in irrigable lands and drought-resistant, ever green plants in summer period in non-irrigable sloping lands are necessary to provide the animal feed chain with high energy resources.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006824.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 23-27]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
</ags:resources>