<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ags:resources SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600048">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The use of remote sensing and geographic information systems for irrigation management in Southwest Europe]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., López-Francos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Montesinos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.-P., Berthoumieu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Europe]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical information systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The loss of competitiveness and the abandonment of agricultural activities in many rural areas of Southwest Europe are worsened by problems related to water shortage and the rise in natural hazards such as droughts. Remote sensing and geographic information systems offer a huge potential to improve water management in agriculture, as they are able to provide a great amount of relatively cheap information, which can be automated, and processed and analysed for a wide range of agronomic, hydraulic and hydrological purposes. New developments in ICTs allow the products of those technologies to be easily available for end-users for practical applications. This publication is a result of the TELERIEG project (Use of remote sensing for irrigation practice recommendation and monitoring in the SUDOE space, SOE1-P2-E082, 2009-2011), co-financed by the Programme Interreg IVB-Sudoe of the EU-ERDF, with the participation of 9 beneficiary institutions from France, Portugal and Spain. The final target was to achieve a better environmental protection through more efficient and rational management of water resources in agriculture and a more effective prevention and response against natural risks. The project has generated a vigilance and recommendations system for vast areas. Specifically, data collection, information analysis and decision-making services were developed, based on geographical information systems (GIS) and remote sensing, allowing water users and managers to have timely information and a useful decision-making tool for irrigation water management. The chapters of this book were part of the learning and support materials prepared by the lecturers of the international course on “The use of remote sensing for irrigation management”, organised by the Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Zaragoza in November 2011, with the aim of disseminating the knowledge and tools created by TELERIEG and by other initiatives in the field of the application of remote sensing to agricultural water management. The chapters collect information at different levels: generalities on remote sensing and the theoretical basis of its application to agriculture, methodologies for specific measurements and applications, and field experiences and case studies. The book is accompanied by a DVD containing additional materials which were used for the course, such as presentations, teaching practical materials (images and data), software practicals and the pdf version of the book chapters.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/b67.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Book]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 239]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600049">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The TELERIEG Project]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., López-Francos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[INSPIRE]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[TELERIEG]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Europe]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[SUDOE]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The TELERIEG (The use of remote sensing for irrigation practice, recommendation and monitoring in the SUDOE space, www.telerieg.net), co-financed by the Interreg IVB SUDOE Programme of the European Union, has spent three years of activity with the objective of developing knowledge and tools on the application of remote sensing and geographic information systems for the improvement of irrigation water management and the response to natural risks affecting agriculture in the Southwest of Europe. The main results include an automated image processing that generates daily maps with useful parameters for irrigation management, and a geoportal adapted to the INSPIRE Directive, made up of large databases of agroclimatic and cartographic information, as well as utilities and tools based on geographic information systems and remote sensing allowing users to calculate irrigation requirements at plot scale. A collaboration network has been created of institutions working in the field of remote sensing and irrigation water management, using the most advanced techniques of high resolution images processing for estimation of agronomic parameters at field scales. All these results have been disseminated at local and international scale, covering mainly the project areas of Southwestern Europe but also other Mediterranean countries. The technologies developed by TELERIEG can contribute to improvements in optimization of the agricultural production factors mainly water.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006590.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 7-13]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600050">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Background of TELERIEG project]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.-P., Berthoumieu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Irrigation management is now possible by monitoring plant and soil water status in a special location in a field that is supposed to well represent a larger surface. This place, used as a reference, is often equipped with point sensors (as EnviroScan and others) to measure the precise variation of the available water into the root zone. Completed with weather forecast it enables a decision taking about the best moment and best amount of irrigation, preventing any risk of stress by lack of water or lack of air (brief saturation with anoxia) and reducing diffuse pollution by drainage (see PRECIRIEG project, www.precirieg.net). As it is quite expensive and time consuming to install probes in many locations the TELERIEG (www.telerieg.net) project is trying to reveal the potential of remote sensing tools in order to extend the principles of precise irrigation advice over larger irrigated areas. In this article we describe the different objectives and principal findings that are presented in other papers in this book.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006591.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 15-24]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600051">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Geographic information systems: data versus information. Introduction to remote sensing]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Montesinos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Fernandes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Data]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In a modern society, decision-making process realised by managers or planners must be based on true information which has been obtained from reliable and consistent data. Geographic Information Systems are tools that allows us to convert pre-existing data into information Remote sensing is defined as the ability to obtain information from an object without physical contact with it. Remote sensing term is restricted to all methods that use the reflected or irradiated electromagnetic energy of objects.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006592.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 25-30]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600052">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Generation and interpretation of images]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Montesinos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Digital image processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Information recording]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[A digital image is a representation of a real object using a numerical two-dimensional matrix where each element is called pixel. The digital process is the set of numerical transformations performed on the original matrix to obtain more appropriate representations of the image, depending on applications. Restoration processes are aimed to eliminate the radiometric errors sounds and geometric distortions generated during the compilation and transmission of data. The highlight consists on a set of techniques to improve the visual interpretation of the image. The multitemporal and multispectral character of remote sensing data allows transformations that produce new components or bands of the image.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006593.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 31-36]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600053">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Spanish National Remote Sensing Program, a way to achieve massive use of remote sensing data]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Peces]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Villa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Arozarena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Plaza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.A., Tejeiro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Domenech]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[PNT]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Satellite imagery]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Spanish National Remote Sensing Program (PNT) provides regular coverage of the Spanish territory with current and historical satellite imagery. This imagery is acquired with multi-user licenses for all Spanish Public Institutions, and processed once with geometric and radiometric processing agreed by experts of Spanish scientific community, and it is distributed to all users from Spanish Public Institutions. This way, we promote the massive use of remote sensing data. Spanish imagery is structured in three levels of spatial and temporal resolution: (i) High resolution: Images from 2 to 10 m of spatial resolution in panchromatic mode and from 10 to 30 m in multispectral mode. It is acquired a complete coverage every year with summer images. From 2005 to nowadays SPOT5 satellite is selected to provide that type of resolution. In future, with Spanish high resolution satellite called Ingenio, we will have several annual coverages. (ii) Medium resolution: Images from 10 to 15 m of spatial resolution in panchromatic mode and from 20 to 50 m in multispectral mode. It was planned to acquire at least four coverages every year, but since January 2008 all Landsat5 (TM) imagery captured over Spain is acquired. During 201, as well, Spot4 and Deimos1 images are being acquired. (iii) Low resolution: Multispectral images from 50 to 1000 m of spatial resolution, with a periodicity of 1 or 2 days. MODIS and MERIS sensors are the main source of this type of resolution. Nowadays, in PNT, more than 2000 images are processed every year to obtain derivate products such us georeferenced images, mosaics of images, etc. To reduce the time between the collection of data and the moment the information is available, PNT has designed a storage infrastructure suitable to the volume of information, an appropriate workflow, distribution control and an efficient spreading.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006594.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 37-46]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600054">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Introduction to ILWIS GIS tool]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Montesinos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[ILWIS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[ILWIS for Windows is a Windows-based, integrated GIS and Remote Sensing application consisting of: (i) Display of raster and multiple vector maps in map windows; (ii) Display of tables in table windows; (iii) Interactive retrieval of attribute information, (iv) Image processing facilities, (v) Manipulation of maps in a Map Calculator; (vi) Manipulation of tables in a Table Calculator; (vii) GIS analysis tools and (viii) Script language to perform \'batch\' jobs. With Windows, you can start one operation and keep it running while you start one or more additional applications. This is a sort of multitasking. You may work with both Windows and DOS application programs, you can perform one or more ILWIS calculations in the background and at the same time display maps, run other ILWIS operations, print, etc. http://52north.org/communities/ilwis/.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006595.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 47-52]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600055">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Use of remote sensing for the calculation of biophysical indicators]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Sánchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Pecci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigiolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Telerieg]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NOAA-AVHRR]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Albedo]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evapotranspiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[LST]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[SUDOE]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDVI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In recent years, remote sensing has emerged as one of the most useful tools in agronomy. A series of biophysical indicators can be derived from satellite images and become inputs for decision support systems in irrigation management, crop planning or determination of crop yields, thus achieving a better management of resources. An automated system implemented under the Telerieg project provides these indicators on a daily rate to aid in decision-making.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006596.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 55-63]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600056">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Assessment of vegetation indexes from remote sensing: theoretical basis]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.G., García Galiano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Indicators]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vegetation index]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Uncertainties in agricultural activities due to the scarcity of water and the increase in droughts could be ameliorated by considering early detection and spatio-temporal characterization of water stress conditions at a regional scale from remote sensing. Theoretical aspects of the spatio-temporal assessment of vegetation indexes related with soil moisture, based on remote sensing and meteorological data are presented.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006597.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 65-75]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600057">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Estimation of irrigated crops areas: generation of water demand scenarios]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Montesinos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Fernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Demand]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mapping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vegetation index]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The study of the evolution of agricultural demand is one of the most significant aspects for water management, not only due to the specific weight that it represents inside the global river basin demand, but also to the difficulty to estimate it. The irrigated area map is elaborated from digital processing of available satellite images, and is based in the analysis, interpretation and classification of vegetation index maps, where numerical information is collected and is linked with the photosynthetic activity rate, vegetation cover vigour and vegetation vigour within each crop.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006598.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 79-84]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600058">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Remote sensing based water balance to estimate evapotranspiration and irrigation water requirements. Case study: grape vineyards]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Campos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Boteta]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Balbontín]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Fabião]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Maia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vineyards]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soil water balance]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water requirements]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evapotranspiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vegetation index]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this paper the basis for the incorporation of remote sensing data into a soil water balance through the relationship between the basal crop coefficient (Kcb) and vegetation indices (VI) for grape vineyards is described. The remote sensing soil water balance has been applied in previous studies obtaining accurate estimates of actual evapotranspiration and crop coefficient in grape vineyard, and this methodology is evaluated in order to estimate irrigation necessities in an irrigated vineyard in Albacete, Spain. The model was also applied in vineyards under high deficit irrigation management. The model results: total irrigation necessities, crop evapotranspiration, and water stress coefficient (Ks) are analyzed. The evolution of Ks was compared with experimental measurements of stem water potential ((s). Ks calculated present values between 0.2 and 0.4 during July and August, indicating severe stress levels. The s tendency coincides with the modelled Ks, showing a parallel evolution and values of about -1.4 MPa during the stress period. The evidences presented indicate that Kcb derived from VI overestimate the actual crop coefficient under water stress conditions. In these cases, it is therefore essential to properly estimate the stress coefficient in order to accurately estimate actual crop evapotranspiration and crop coefficient.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006599.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 85-94]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600059">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Models for assessment of actual evapotranspiration from remote sensing: theoretical basis]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.G., García Galiano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Baille]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evapotranspiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDVI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the evaluation of the onset, severity and duration of situations of water stress and droughts, indicators based on processes with intensive use of remote sensing can be used. In the monitoring of agricultural activities as well as the management of water and forest resources, spatio-temporal distributions of information of actual evapotranspiration (ETact) are crucial. This work presents the theoretical aspects of spatio- temporal assessment of ETact process, from remote sensing and meteorological data.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006600.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 95-103]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Otions Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600060">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Estimation of actual evapotranspiration from remote sensing: application in a semiarid region]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.G., García Galiano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., García Cárdenas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evapotranspiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDVI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The potential of remote sensing for the recommendation and monitoring of irrigation practices is irrefutable. GIS have enabled the development of operational spatio-temporal tools for monitoring agricultural activity which can overcome the uncertainty brought about by problems related to water scarcity and increasing drought events. This paper presents an operational methodology for estimating actual evapotranspiration from Landsat images, and its application in the Region of Murcia (Spain).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006601.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 105-117]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600061">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Thermostress. An automatic imaging process for assessing plant water status from thermal photographs]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Jiménez-Bello]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Ballester]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.R., Castel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigliolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Thermography]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Leaf temperature can be used for monitoring plant water status. Nowadays, by means of thermography, canopy temperature can be remotely determined. In this sense, it is crucial to automatically process the images. In the present work, a methodology for the automatic analysis of frontal images taken on individual trees was developed. The camera used in this investigation took at the same time thermal and visible scenes, so it was not necessary to overlap the images. During the processing in batch no operator participated. This was done by means of a non supervised classification of the visible image from which the presence of sky and soil was detected. In case of existence, a mask was performed for the extraction of intermediated pixels to calculate canopy temperature by means of the thermal image. Sunlit and shady leaves could be detected and isolated. Thus, the procedure allowed to separately determine canopy temperature either of the more exposed part of the canopy or of the shaded portion. The methodology developed was validated using images taken in several regulated deficit irrigation trials in persimmon and two citrus trees cultivars (Clementina de Nules and Navel Lane-Late). Overall, results indicated that similar canopy temperatures were calculated either by means of the automatic process or the manual procedure. In addition, differences in midday stem water potential and stomatal conductance among irrigation treatments were associated with differences in canopy temperature in persimmon trees. The procedure here developed here allowed to drastically reduce the time amount used for image analysis also considering that no operator participation was required. Indeed, the tool here proposed will facilitate further investigations in course for assessing the feasibility of using thermography for detecting plant water status in woody perennial crops with discontinuous canopies.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006602.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 121-129]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600062">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The use of multispectral and thermal images as a tool for irrigation scheduling in vineyards]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bellvert]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Girona]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Multispectral imagery]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Leaf water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Thermal imagery]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Multispectral and thermal imagery were studied to evaluate the relationship between grapevine water status and Plant Cell Density index (PCD) and Crop Water Stress index (CWSI). Grapevine water status was determined with a pressure chamber by measuring the leaf water potential (leaf) of 184 grapevines distributed homogeneously within a 11 ha vineyard. Image acquisitions and leaf measures were obtained simultaneously at noon. Results showed that PCD could be useful to discriminate well-watered zones in a vineyard. However the relationship between PCD vs Psi leaf seemed to vary between different zones of the vineyard. This inconvenient did not exist with CWSI. The relationship between Psi leaf and crop-air temperature differential was strong and presented a high coefficient of determination (r2 equal to 0.714; P less than 0.0001) at noon. Accordingly, this methodology showed potential to be used as a tool for irrigation scheduling. Further studies should be directed to explore the convenience of CWSI measured at other moments of the day and the optimal thermal image resolution to obtain the best results.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006603.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 131-137]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600063">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Study of the effects of irrigation on stem water potential and multispectral data obtained from remote sensing systems in woody crops]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Alarcón]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Pérez-Cutillas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Precision agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study is part of the work carried out in experimental plots of different research centres (IMIDA, CEBAS, UPCT and IVIA) that are part of the TELERIEG project, with the aim of improving irrigation methods in irrigated crops in the region of Murcia, significantly contributing to a better management of drought. The work was carried out, on the one hand, on two parcels of citrus fruit (mandarin and grapefruit) where several different irrigation treatments were applied, which generated varying degrees of water stress on the studied trees. Three sources of irrigation water were also used, each one different in nature and quality, in order to study their impact on the development of crops. On the other hand, work was also carried out on a parcel of peach trees, where several different irrigation treatments were applied, which also generated varying degrees of water stress. This variability in tree water status was measured in the field through stem water potential at midday (Psi s), and from the air by capturing images with a multispectral camera to estimate the values of the near-infrared spectrum (NIR) and the normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006604.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 139-146]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600064">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Use of remote sensing and geographic information tools for irrigation management of citrus trees]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Jiménez-Bello]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L.A., Ruiz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Hermosilla]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Recio]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigliolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cover plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The most widely used method for estimating crops water requirements is the FAO approach, which takes into account: (i) climatic variables included in the reference evapotranspiration and (ii) the crop type, characterized by the crop coefficient (Kc). In citrus trees, Kc is mostly function of the tree ground covers (GC). In large areas tree ground covers (GC) can be estimated by means of remote sensing tools, and once tree water needs are calculated, this information can be implemented in geographic information systems. The present article summarizes some of the research conducted in order to estimate citrus water needs in large irrigated areas. It describes first how tree ground covers (GC) can be obtained by using image analysis tools applied to multispectral images. Tree water needs are obtained and they are compared with the real water applications for a case study of citrus water use associations. The results obtained allowed to conclude that the tools developed might be useful for improving irrigation efficiency showing some of the deficiencies currently found in irrigation management of collective water networks.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006605.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 147-159]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600065">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Automated extraction of agronomic parameters in orchard plots from high-resolution imagery]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Recio]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Hermosilla]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L.A., Ruiz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Efficiency]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sensors]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trees]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The availability of high spatial resolution images obtained from aerial and satellite sensors together with the development of new image analysis methods are providing an important impulse to precision agriculture techniques and applications. We describe an automated methodology for the extraction of agronomic parameters from tree orchard plots based on the use of high-resolution remotely sensed imagery, which can be further used to increase the efficiency of irrigation and agricultural plot management in the SUDOE area. These methods are based on parcel-based image analysis, and a variety of parameters are obtained including tree detection, location and counting, planting patterns, tree crown, vegetation cover and others. Since common data and image processing techniques are used, they can be easily implemented in production processes and cover large agricultural areas. The methods are tested on citrus orchard plots located in Valencia (Spain), showing a good performance in particular for adult trees. In addition to the particular use of the ground cover for the estimation of water requirement, these parameters can also be used as support tools for agricultural inventories or database updating, allowing for the reduction of field work and manual interpretation tasks.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006606.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 161-174]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600066">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Thermal infra-red remote sensing for water stress estimation in agriculture]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Labbé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Lebourgeois]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Jolivot]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Marti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vegetation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Monitoring]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Image analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Thermal infrared images can be used to estimate vegetation water content of the plant and thus to locally adapt (precision agriculture) and globally adjust (sustainable management of water resources) irrigation water quantities. Thermal imaging cameras using micro-bolometer sensors loaded on light aerial vehicles are suitable to produce thermal images. These images are helpful for irrigation monitoring if they are: (i) coupled with simultaneous acquisition of images in the visible and near infrared bands; (ii) geometrically corrected to be superimposed with other images; and (iii) radiometrically corrected to take into account the drift of the thermal sensors and the effects of the atmosphere on the measured temperature.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006607.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 175-184]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600067">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Contribution of airborne remote sensing to high-throughput phenotyping of a hybrid apple population in response to soil water constraints]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Virlet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Lebourgeois]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Labbé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.L., Regnard]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imagery]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Malus domestica]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Genetic variation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this study, we developed a remote sensing approach, normally applied to management of crop irrigation, with the purpose of phenotyping a plant population in the field. The experiment was performed on \'Starkrimson\' x \'Granny Smith\' apple progeny (122 hybrids, 4 replicates) at adult stage, cultivated in field on Diaphen platform (INRA Montpellier, France). Airborne images acquisition in RGB and NIR bands permit to compute the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), while differences between tree canopy surface measured by thermal IR imaging (Ts) and air temperature (Ta) made it possible to calculate water stress indices. The Water Deficit Index (WDI), derived from the Crop Water Stress Index (CWSI), was considered for its applicability to discontinuous plant cover. WDI was computed on each individual tree, and focused on its central zone (60 cm diameter buffer). The first results showed significant genotypic effects and drought effects for indices during imposed summer water shortage, without interaction between them. Moreover, this first experiment permits to determine field measurements that are necessary to validate the method, linking image interpretation and tree water status variables.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006608.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 185-191]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600068">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Irrigation decision support system assisted by satellite. Alqueva irrigation scheme case study]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Maia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Boteta]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Fabião]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Santos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Campos]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[EFMA]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[DEMETER]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[TELERIEG]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Decision support systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Earth observation satellites]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[COTR]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[AQUASTAR]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDVI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In irrigated farming systems is important to increase the processes for the rational use of water improvement, to achieve water maximum productivity, respecting the environment. For that, the Irrigation Advisory Services (IAS), included in the Irrigation Extension Services (IES) must be considered a regular instrument for the best irrigation management. To increase the IES efficiency, COTR proposed, firstly, with the development of the AQUASTAR-Alqueva project, and now within the TELERIEG project, to apply the irrigation scheduling methodology developed in the DEMETER project (Calera et al., 2005) to the Alqueva irrigation area (EFMA, Portugal), and based on that, develop the IES, based on Earth observation technologies and other information and communication technologies, which allows near real time to estimates the real crop water use at a large scale. In this work we intend to show the results and the operational side of the irrigation decision support system developed for the Alqueva irrigation scheme.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006609.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 195-201]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600069">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Transpiration and water stress effects on water use, in relation to estimations from NDVI: application in a vineyard in SE Portugal]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.I., Ferreira]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Conceição]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Silvestre]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Fabião]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Portugal]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vitis vinifera]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[NDVI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Remote sensing can give contributions to answer the classical questions in irrigation management: when to irrigate and how much (irrigation depth). In order to compare with estimations partially derived from remote sensing, evapotranspiration (ET) and its components (transpiration, T and soil evaporation, Es) as well as selected water stress indicators were measured in a commercial vineyard with deficit irrigation, in SE Portugal. A combination of micrometeorological, sapflow and microlysimeter methods were used to measure water flux densities. The seasonal results reported (2009) are explored in relation to T obtained from practical models based on meteorological data (reference ET, ETo), crop basal coefficients (Kcb) and stress coefficients (Ks) where the use of the normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is included. Results from stress cycles (2010) confirm the selection of predawn leaf water potential (PLWP) as water tress indicator for the purpose of the analysis. A preliminary conclusion, confirmed later, on the meaning of NDVI in the conditions of this study (-0.2 MPa greater than gt;PLWP greater than -0.7 MPa), suggested that it is not affected by short term but by long term water stress. Kcb measured and estimated from NDVI agreed generally well, with exceptions. The comparison between T measured and estimated from ETo.Kcb.Ks (being Ks obtained from PLWP) highlights the importance of Ks on T estimation. For practical uses, alternative tools to obtain Ks are proposed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006610.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 203-208]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600070">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Contribution of remote sensing in analysis of crop water stress. Case study on durum wheat]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Jolivot]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Labbé]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V., Lebourgeois]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[WDI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Evapotranspiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[S-SEBI]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Precision irrigation requires frequent information on crop conditions spatial and temporal variability. Image-based remote sensing is one promising techniques for precision irrigation management. In this study, we investigated the use of broad band multispectral (visible, near infrared and thermal infrared bands) and thermal airborne imagery for the characterization of water status of durum wheat crop through two indices: the Water Deficit Index (WDI) and the Simplified Surface Energy Balance Index (S-SEBI). Comparisons between these two indices and the ratio between actual and potential evapotranspiration (AET-PET) show that such techniques are promising for precision irrigation management.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006611.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 209-216]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600071">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Application of INSPIRE directive to water management on large irrigation areas]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., López]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Caro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Atenza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Sánchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.M., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.P., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[INSPIRE]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Remote sensing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[OGC]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigated land]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The goal of this paper is to illustrate how INSPIRE can facilitate orientation and advice to calculate the water requirements of crops. These technologies can provide information adapted to specific conditions, updated daily and in an interactive way. These tools permit the integration and management of georeferenced agroclimatic data, soil maps, quality of waters, crop information and technical parameters of a farm. The final objective is to develop a decision support system to facilitate decision-taking processes in a comfortable and generic access on-line, incorporating different techniques and access into GIS data. The information technologies and in a more precise way, the new technologies, applied in different agriculture environments, can introduce important improvements in optimization of the agricultural production factors. Directive 2007/2/EC1 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 14 March 2007 establishing an Infrastructure for Spatial Information in the European Community (INSPIRE) entered into force on the 15th May 2011. INSPIRE lays down general rules to establish an infrastructure for spatial information in Europe for the purposes of Community environmental policies, and policies or activities which may have an impact on the environment. One of the aspects that INSPIRE regulates is the interoperability and harmonization of spatial data sets and services for 34 so-called data themes that are laid down in the three Annexes to the INSPIRE directive. These include land-cover, land-use and weather data.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006612.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 217-222]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600072">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Soil salinity prospects based on the quality of irrigation water used in the Segura Basin]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Alcón]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Atenza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Alarcón]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agriculture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Soil salinity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[WATSUIT]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Segura river]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Watersheds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Geographical Information Systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The main objective of this study was to determine the effect of the quality of irrigation water currently used in various agricultural demand units (ADU) on the soil-water salinity, assessing the effects of its use on crop yields and soils agronomic properties. The current state of the water quality used in all ADUs of the Segura Basin (Spain) was identified through sampling points located in surface and groundwater bodies. The geographical relationship established between water quality and crops in each ADU allowed a prospective analysis of the major agronomic risks of salinity, infiltration, toxicity by undesirable ions and the resulting environmental risks of soil degradation. WATSUIT software was used for each existing relationship between water bodies and ADUs. The results of this study provide geo-referenced knowledge of the current status of water quality and of the problems that its use may cause on the crops and the environment. It is also the starting point in establishing actions to increase the quality of irrigation water improving environmental conservation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006613.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 223-229]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600073">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Radar-aided understanding of semiarid areas: Maximum depression storage and storm motion]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., García-Pintado]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Barbera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Erena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.A., Lopez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V.M., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Cabezas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM - IMIDA - SUDOE Interreg IVB (EU-ERDF)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farmland]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hidrology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flooding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Semiarid zones]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Models]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Weather radar supports the estimation of accurate spatiotemporal rainfall inputs. These may be of great help to hone water management strategies, as those involving irrigation plans or flood risk analyses. If these strategies are supported by simulation models, the radar-based estimates should lead in turn to lower biases in estimates of model parameters and to improved model structures. E.g., flash floods pose a danger for life and property and, in semiarid agricultural areas, have a strong relationship with soil loss processes. Unfortunately, in arid and semiarid environment the runoff generation shows a complex nonlinear behavior with a strong spatiotemporal non-uniformity. Predictions by forecasting models are subject to great uncertainty and better descriptions of physical processes at the watershed scale need to be included into the operational modelling tools. We analyze a convective storm, in a 556 km2 semiarid Mediterranean watershed, with a complex multi-peak response. Radar was instrumental in the understanding and analysis of runoff generation. In the central area, a significant time-variability in the maximum depression storage resulted in the a posteriori model structure, pointing to failures in agricultural terraces and/or protection structures. Sensitivity analysis to storm motion indicates that a partial coverage upstream-moving storm on the infiltrating plane results in greater responses.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-482-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
																				http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/b67/00006614.pdf
																]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 231-239]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Series B: Studies and Research]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.67()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600074">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Probiotic and antioxidant properties of synbiotic yoghurt supplemented with Australian-grown ‘Wonderful’ pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) juice]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Arjmand]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Shamsi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N.P., Shah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Sherkat]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Polyphenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Synbiotic yoghurt]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yoghurt]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Physicochemical properties of the Australian-grown ‘Wonderful’ pomegranate juice (WPJ) including total phenolic compounds (TPC) and antioxidant activity (AA) were determined and compared with four brands of imported pomegranate juices (IPJs). The TPC in WPJ was found to be 2,400 ± 200 mg/l GAE while in the IPJs ranged from 1,000 to 2,800 mg/l GAE. The AA in WPJ was 11.0 ± 1.0 mM/l TEAC and ranged from 5.5 to14.5 mM/l TEAC in IPJs. A synbiotic yoghurt supplemented with different levels of IPJ was developed. Maximum single strength PJ supplementation level with no adverse effects on yoghurt attributes and probiotics viability was found to be 20% in heat-treated milk resulting in a TPC level of 731 ± 69 mg/l GAE in synbiotic yoghurt.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006973.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 295-307]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600075">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Convective and microwave drying influence on the chemical composition, functional properties and sensory quality of pomegranate arils and rind]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calín-Sanchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Figiel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.A., Carbonell-Barrachina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[DPPH]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Peel]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this study was to evaluate the application of: (i) convective drying (50, 60 or 70 degrees C), (ii) vacuum-microwave drying (240, 360 or 480 W) and (iii) a combined method of convective predrying and vacuum-microwave finishing drying in the processing of dehydrated pomegranate arils and rind. The parameters under study included sugars and organic acids contents, total antioxidant activity and total polyphenols content. All parameters were calculated on a dry matter basis and analysis of data showed drying let to a reduction in all the parameters under study; however, the behavior of arils and rind were different. Vacuum-microwave drying at 240 W was the best drying treatment of arils, while rind required softer conditions of convective drying (50 degrees C) and vacuum-microwave drying (240 W). Convective pre-drying and vacuum-microwave finishing drying was not a proper treatment for pomegranate drying.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006964.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 255-259]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600076">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Potential of Spanish sour-sweet pomegranates for juice industry]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calín-Sanchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.A., Carbonell-Barrachina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Volatile compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Industry]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Commercial juices of sweet pomegranates and fresh juices of sour-sweet pomegranates were analysed for organic acids, sugars, antioxidant activity, volatile composition, sensory profile and consumer liking. Organic acids and sugars were analysed by HPLC, while volatiles were extracted using hydrodistillation and analysed by GC-MS and GC-FID. Malic acid was predominant in sweet juices while citric acid predominated in sour-sweet samples. Fructose and glucose were found as the predominant sugars in all juices. The high potential of sour-sweet pomegranate fruits for the juice industry was supported by (i) the high values of positive attributes, such as colour and fresh pomegranate flavour and (ii) the high overall liking of consumers.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006967.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 269-272]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600077">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Authentication of pomegranate juices using their volatile compositions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calín-Sanchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Szychowski]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.A., Carbonell-Barrachina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality controls]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[GC-MS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Volatile compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Certification]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Artificial flavourings]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate juice has gained much popularity mainly because of its health benefits; however, are you completely sure that when you pick up a bottle of juice from a store you are really getting a real pomegranate juice with all its antioxidants and full flavor? This is important especially because usually you are paying a high price for this juice. Pure pomegranate juices and blends (grape, apple, orange, etc.) with other fruits from around the world are under analysis using GC-MS to find a “volatile fingerprint” that allow us to discriminate which products really contain what it is promised in their labels and which ones are just promising much more than they are claiming. Artificial pomegranate aromas being used in the food industry are also being analyzed to find out which are the compounds being intentionally added to juices to pretend they have the unique flavor of fresh pomegranates.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006968.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 273-275]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600078">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[La culture du grenadier (Punica granatum L.) au Maroc]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Haddioui]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Local varieties]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In Morocco, pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) has been considered for long time a secondary fruit tree. In the last years, its culture is extended over different regions in more than 4000 ha. Today,Morocco is one of the world’s important pomegranate production countries. The total production is 58000 tons. It’s well concentrated in the center and the north regions. The total of production is consumed in local markets and very little quantities (less than 0.5 per cent) are exported. Fruits are consumed fresh or processed into juice.Local varieties are numerous and well adapted to agroecological conditions. Their denominations reflect mainly origin area, the shape or the fruit color. Interchange of plant material was very frequent between regions. These varieties are maintained in two germplasm collections in Beni Mellal and Meknès. The local germplasm is characterized by a large diversity. However, little is known about the genetic diversity organization in this crop.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006910.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 79-81]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600079">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Sensory quality of pomegranate products]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.A., Carbonell-Barrachina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Calín-Sanchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Vázquez-Araújo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Chambers I V]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organoleptic analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[New products]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Consumers]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate has become very popular in the last years because of its healthy properties (high antioxidant activity and phenolic compounds content). However, do consumers really know how a fresh pomegranate fruit-juice tastes? In our opinion the answer is clear: no, they do not. Thus, our first task is to explain consumers the main characteristics describing fresh pomegranate fruits; then, they will able to assess whether the products they are buying/consuming come from natural sources. It is evident that the appearance of pomegranate fruits is very appealing and this is the main reason why intense garnet arils are always shown in advertisement. Pomegranate products can be manufactured using fruits from sweet, soursweet or sour cultivars, determining the relative intensities of the basic tastes. However, pomegranate has a big drawback, the low intensity of volatile compounds (aroma). The arils can be described by their basic tastes but not by their aroma; this makes very difficult to judge whether a pomegranate product is natural. In contrast, the rind has strong intensities of attributes such as astringency and toothetch mouthfeel. Without these notes a product will not have any healthy activity because polyphenols are mainly located in the rind. If a pomegranate juice can be described as having high intensities of candy-like and sweet overall, it can be a high success among consumers but it cannot be considered as a natural pomegranate product, and besides it will not have any healthy activity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006963.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 251-254]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600080">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The Pomegranate National Collection of Afghanistan]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.M., Saeedi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Mohammad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.R., Samadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Abdiani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Giordani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collection]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Germplasm]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The Perennial Horticulture Development Project – Afghanistan is a project in support to the Ministry for Agriculture of Afghanistan. The main goal is the strengthening of the perennial horticulture through the development of a highly standardized nursery sector and the adoption of local genetic resources. Pomegranate has been surveyed in a wide area of the Afghan territory and collected during the first phase of the project (2006-2010). The in situ collection holds 60 different labeled and recorded varieties located in various provinces. These accessions have been propagated and planted in year 2009 in two different duplicated ex situ collections. Besides a first characterization of the in situ collected material reported in the PHDP Germplasm "In-Situ" Collection Database, all the clones are being fully characterized and evaluated following international descriptor lists and standards.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006905.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 57-60]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600081">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Breeding Mexican pomegranates to improve productivity and quality and increase versatility of uses]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Mondragón Jacobo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gene banks]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Exports]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Segregation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plant breeding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Germplasm banks]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Domestic markets]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Markets]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is a marginal fruit crop in Mexico, practiced by small farmers and focused on the national market. The Mexican varieties bear during summer, they are probably segregants of Spanish and American pomegranates, obtained through sexual propagation and informal introduction, they are maintained in gardens and family orchards. Mexico also regularly imports pomegranates from USA under the frame of commercial treaties. INIFAP has been supporting a Genetic Resources and Breeding program since 2002 pursuing the following objectives: to obtain new pomegranate cultivars suitable for export – Wonderful type–, to extend the harvest season into fall and to enhance fruit quality, among others. We have characterized the national germplasm and obtained selections adequate to supplement the local market, others with ornamental value and some with outstanding functional properties, advances that will be discussed in this presentation.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006906.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 61-66]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600082">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Reduction of chilling injury of pomegranate by heat treatment before cold storage]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Martínez-Romero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Mirdehghan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.M., Valverde]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Guillén]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Firmness]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Electrolytes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Putrescine]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spermidine]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fatty acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Browning]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranates are highly perishable fruit and sensitive to chilling injury (CI) when stored below 5 degrees C, manifested as skin browning, surface pitting, higher susceptibility to decay and reduction in both internal and external fruit quality. Thus, the aim of this experiment was to study the effect of hot water dip at 45 degrees C for 4 min on reducing CI in pomegranates after storage at 2 degrees C for 15-90 days plus 3 days at 20 degrees C. Pomegranates developed CI, manifested as increases in skin browning and electrolyte leakage, which were highly correlated. The severity of damage in control fruit was related to loss of fatty acids with a concomitant reduction in the ratio of unsaturated/saturated fatty acids during storage. These CI symptoms were slightly, but significantly reduced in heat-treated pomegranates. In addition, the heat treatment induced increases in free putrescine and spermidine during storage. These higher polyamine levels as well as the maintenance of the unsaturated/saturated fatty acid ratio during storage could account for the maintenance of membrane integrity and fluidity and the reduction of CI.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006956.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 241-244]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600083">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The prices in Europe of pomegranates and arils]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Rymon]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Exports]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Prices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Wholesale prices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Imports]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Europe]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[World pomegranates demand increased through the beginning of the 21st century, probably mainly due to the publication of research findings on the fruit's contribution to human health. A lack of dependable national statistics prevents us from estimating world trade. A paired time-series of price data by exporting and importing country in Europe is available, offering useful information to producers, traders and investors. The information allows an analysis of: (i) seasonality of fruit and aril prices by country of origin and European market; (ii) sensitivity of the trade to economic crises such as experienced in 2008; and (iii)estimation of supplier prices and comparison by hemispheres. The results are invaluable for producers andtraders, as well as regional and national plannners.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006901.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 37-41]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600084">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[New insights on the postharvest technologies to maintain the overall quality of pomegranate fruits]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Mirdehghan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Damage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Volatile compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Postharvest technology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Dipping]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is a subtropical fruit and its arils contain a high concentration of sugars, organic acids, vitamins, polysaccharides, and essential minerals. In recent years its antioxidant properties and its effect against degenerative diseases have been claimed, which are attributed to their polyphenol content. Pomegranate, as other tropical and subtropical fruits are sensitive to low temperatures and develop a complex of physiological disorders known as “chilling injury”. The incidence of this physiopathy limits the application of cold storage, the most widely strategy employed for marketing the horticultural produce. Therefore the impact of chilling injury on the agro-food industry has serious economic consequences. In the present work, we provide the different postharvest technologies of an environmentally friendly nature assayed in research or applied in the agro-food industry with the aim of inhibiting or delaying the emergence of chilling injury in sensitive fruits such as pomegranate and the effects of these technologies on the content of bioactive compounds with antioxidant properties.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006941.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 191-193]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600085">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Polyamines applied by immersion or pressure maintain ‘Mollar de Elche’ pomegranate quality stored at chilling temperatures]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Mirdehghan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Zapata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Martínez-Romero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Firmness]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Putrescine]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spermidine]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chilling injury]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Browning]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate fruits (Punica granatum L. cv. ‘Mollar de Elche’) were treated with putrescine (Put)or spermdine (Spd) at 1 mM under pressure-infiltration or immersion prior cold storage at 2 degrees C. Non-treated fruit developed rapidly chilling injury (CI), with main symptoms being skin browning, increased electrolyte leakage and weight loss. During storage losses of firmness and colour and increases in °Brix-acidity ratio and respiration rate were observed. All these changes were significantly delayed by polyamine treatments, with effectiveness being found similar either by pressure-infiltration or by immersion. The reduction of CI severity was correlated to the increased levels of free endogenous Put and Spd in the skin, which could induce acclimation of pomegranate to cold temperature and also a mechanism of protection to CI, with a net increase of the shelf-life. In conclusion, in this paper a novel technology based on the exogenous application of Put or Spd under pressure-infiltration or immersion could induce acclimation of pomegranate to low temperature, and in turn protect the fruit to CI by increasing the levels of endogenous Put and Spd.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006953.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 229-231]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600086">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Regulated deficit irrigation in pomegranate (Punica granatum) trees. Yield and its components]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigliolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Lozoya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Bonet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Nicolás]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Alarcón]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought stress]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Yields]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Disorders]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[An experiment has been carried out during two seasons with the objective of identifying pomegranate yield responses to water restrictions applied during different phenological periods. In mature trees, five irrigation treatments where applied including trees watered at 100 per cent and 50 per cent of tree water needs (ETc) during the entire season, and other three regulated deficit irrigated (RDI) treatments with severe restrictions applied only during certain phenological periods. Results showed that all the deficit irrigated treatments allowed increasing water use efficiency (i.e. yield-water applied). An early season water stress,increased the number of fruit collected at harvest, with the drawaback of reducing fruit weight if restrictions were prolonged during all the season. On the other hand, temporal water restrictions applied in the mid summer lead to a very small effect on final fruit weight. Results indicate the potential that RDI has in Pomegranate trees as a tool to cope with water scarcity in this crop.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006915.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 101-106]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600087">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of calcium chloride dip and 1-methylcyclopropene on quality changes in arils from stored pomegranates]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Aguayo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Jansasithorn]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Kader]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Calcium chloride]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this study was to determine the effect of CaCl2 dips, methylcyclopropene (1-MCP), and the combination of both on quality of extracted arils of ‘Wonderful’ cv. pomegranates. Arils were extracted from whole fruit stored 10 weeks at 7.5 degrees C in air. Treatments consisted of washing arils in chlorinate water (7 degrees C, 100 ppm of NaOCl) (control), dipping arils into CaCl2 (10 g l-1) for 2 min, treating arils with 1-MCP (1μl l-1) during 24 h at 5 degrees C, and the combination of CaCl2 dip and 1-MCP. All treatments were packaged in jars and kept in humidified air flow for up to 12 days at 5 degrees C. The use of CaCl2 or 1-MCP helped to keep a better overall quality and firmness at the end of storage (reduced C2H4 and respiration rates, respectively). All treatments scored above the limit of marketability, indicating the viability of long term storage of whole pomegranate for fresh-cut produce.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006943.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 195-199]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600088">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Usefulness of maximum diurnal trunk shrinkage as a continuous water stress indicators of pomegranate (Punica granatum) trees]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Badal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Bues]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Guerra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Puerto]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Bonet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Perán]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Nicolás]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigliolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stem]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[LVDT]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trees]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[MDS]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Deficit irrigation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this research was to assess the feasibility of using maximum diurnal trunk shrinkage (MDS) obtained by means of LVDT sensors, as a plant water stress indicators for pomegranate trees. The experiment was carried out with mature trees grown in the field under three irrigation regimes: (i) control (well watered trees); (ii) trees continuously deficit irrigated at 50 per cent of the control regime (SDI); and (iii) trees that had a summer water stress cycle being irrigated at 25 per cent of the control rates only in July and August (RDI). Control trees maintained lower MDS values than the SDI ones. In the RDI treatment, as water restrictions began, there was a slow increase in MDS, in correspondence with a decrease in stem water potential (Ψstem). When water was returned at full dosage, the RDI recovered to MDS and Ψstem values similar to the control. However, lower MDS for a given values were observed as the season advanced. The magnitude of differences between well watered and deficit irrigated trees was much larger in the case of MDS than for Ψstem. The tree-to-tree variability of the MDS readings was more than four times higher than for Ψstem.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006919.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 121-128]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600089">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Advances in postharvest and refrigeration techniques in whole and minimally processed pomegranate]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Artés]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Artés-Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mycoses]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Disinfection]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Damage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Controlled atmosphere storage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agrochemicals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Selection]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Packaging]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The varietal selection of pomegranates will improve its sales and, growing in fertile soils, will accumulate more anthocyanins than in poor and saline ones. Pomegranate fruit is quite sensitive to mechanical damages and chilling injuries (CI). To store pomegranates up to 3 months, 5 degrees C and 90-95 per cent RH are recommend because these conditions will limit fungal development, weight loss and CI. Controlled or modified atmospheres, alone or in combination with UV-C light, improve its overall quality. Several curing, intermittent warming and sustainable agro-chemicals (salicylic, acetyl salicylic or oxalic acids, methyl jasmonate or methyl salicylate), before storage at 2 degrees C of ‘Mollar de Elche’ cv, reduce CI and nutrient losses. The minimal processing of the arils generates high added value. In this work the different steps of minimal processing as well as some viable innovative techniques like the use of ‘clean room technology’ are referred. Several sustainable disinfection alternatives to chlorine (UV-C, O3, or peroxyacetic acid), and particular conditions of packaging and distribution to optimize the arils shelf life are recommended. About all these aspects regarding Spanish cvs, relevant contributions are reviewed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006929.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 169-177]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600090">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of oxalic acid treatment on maintaining pomegranate fruit quality and antioxidant potential]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Guillén]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Zapata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Zapata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organic acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this work was to study the effect of pre-storage oxalic acid treatment at three concentrations (2, 4, and 6mM) on pomegranate CI and fruit quality after long-term storage at 2ºC. The CI symptoms were significantly reduced by oxalic acid treatment, especially for the 6 mM concentration. In addition, control pomegranates showed a significant reduction in the content of total phenolics and ascorbic acid as well as in total antioxidant activity (TAA), in both hydrophilic (H-TAA) and lipophilic (L-TAA) fractions after long term storage. However, the application of oxalic acid led to lower losses of total phenolics and significant increase in both ascorbic acid content and H-TAA, whereas L-TAA remained unaffected. Thus, oxalic acid could be a natural promising postharvest treatment to alleviate CI and increase antioxidant potential of pomegranate, by enhancing or maintaining the bioactive compounds.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006951.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 221-223]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600091">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Influence of the temperature in the evolution of the coordinates of color in pomegranate]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F.J., Manera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Colour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The colour quality of many fresh and processed fruits may influence consumer acceptance. Pomegranate acceptability depends on a combination of quality attributes related to physical-chemical and mechanical properties such as rind colour, sugar content, acidity, flavour, etc. This studyrealized at 2009 season, was undertaken to study the evolution of colour parameters with the environmental temperature. The results confirmed a strong influence between the colorimetric coordinates measured during fruit development, maturation and the maximum, mean and minimum temperatures.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006957.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 245-247]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600092">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[A preliminary survey on pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) genotypes localized in Apulia region,Southeastern Italy]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Ferrara]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Cavoski]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Pacifico]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Pacucci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Mondelli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Polyphenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morphology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Italy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Little information is available about the pomegranate genotypes present in Italy and in particular in Apulia (Southeastern region of Italy). A two-year study (2008-2009) was carried out in order to evaluate morphological, organoleptic and chemical parameters of 8 pomegranate genotypes (4 sweet and 4 sour)localized in some small orchards. Significant differences were observed among the 8 genotypes for many of the parameters investigated.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006909.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 75-77]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600093">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Physico-chemical and antioxidant properties of pomegranate genotypes in Greece]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Pantelidis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Drogoudi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Manganaris]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Greece]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Fruit quality attributes and antioxidants contents were compared among 11 Greek omegranate genotypes and the foreign cultivars Wonderful, Akko and Hicaznar, established in two collections in the northern Greece. The heaviest fruit were harvested by Wonderful (474 g), 11021 (400 g), Hicaznar (316 g), and T9 and T10 (mean 366 g). Kallisti had the greatest aril weight (0.472 plus minus 0.015 g), whereas Wonderful had the lowest aril weight (0.260 plus minus 0.025 g). The greatest edible portion percentage (62.3 per cent) and juice percentage (44.7 per cent) were found in the genotype 11019. Total soluble solid content ranged between 15.7 per cent (Kallisti) and 18.3 per cent (11019), and total acid content ranged between 4.8 (Hicaznar) and 22.4 g L-1 (Wonderful). The genotypes T9 and T10 contained the highest total phenol and ascorbate equivalent antioxidant capacity, which were comparable with Hicaznar and Wonderful. Total anthocyanin contents were lower in the Greek, compared with the foreign cultivars. In conclusion Kallisti is a worthy genotype in respect to having relatively great aril weight, fruit size and being soft seeded, and therefore it should be considered for fresh consumption. The genotype 11019 could be worthy for an industrial point due to its high juice content.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006978.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 335-337]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600094">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The Pomegranate, Punica granatum L.:sustainability and improvement of biodiversity in Apulia, Italy]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Russo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Pacucci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Pacifico]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.M.S., Matarrese]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Foods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Culture]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[History]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Biodiversity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutraceuticals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Italy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Nowadays the name and the image of pomegranate are widely used: it can be found as a name in several commercial activities such as banks, agritouristic farms, cultural and sporting associations; its presence in different commercial brands symbolizes \"abundance\". The plant is used for decorating the landscape and the aesthetics of ancient and modern villas, as well as in the dyeing industry and, since ancient times, has been celebrated by Orazio and Virgilio; this plant has been revalued from a pharmaceutical and nutritional point of view (in the Mediterranean diet). Thanks to its nutritional properties and high value of vitamins and antioxidants, it can be included among the nutraceutical products such as citrus fruit and actinidia (for the content in Vitamin C), almonds and other dried fruit (for the presence of Omega 3) and the olive oil (in the prevention of the cardio-vascular diseases).]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006913.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 91-94]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600095">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Usefulness of pomegranate in prostate cancer]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.E., Chéchile Toniolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Neoplasms]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[PSA]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Prostate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is the fruit of the Punica Granatum tree, which grows in Mediterranean countries. Its therapeutic properties have been used to treat different conditions (cardiovascular, neurological, diabetes and cancer) for hundreds of years. Numerous in vitro and in vivo studies have recently shown the antioxidant, anti-inflammatory and anti-tumoral properties of pomegranate. Antiproliferative, proapoptotic, antiangiogenic and inhibition of tumor invasion have been proven in several experimental models of urological tumors such as in prostate cancer. Pomegranate juice has been shown to delay PSA duplication time in patients with biochemical cancer recurrence after initial treatment. Many phase II studies are currently in progress to demonstrate the effectiveness of pomegranate juice in several diseases and in prostate cancer.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006974.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 311-320]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600096">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Acetyl salicylic acid alleviates chilling injury and maintains nutritive and bioactive compounds during cold storage]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.M., Díaz-Mula]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Qualtiy]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Acetylsalicylic acid]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranates are highly perishable and to extend storability the refrigeration is therefore necessary, but this fruit is susceptible to chilling injury (CI) if stored longer at temperatures lower than degrees C. Acetyl salicylic acid (ASA) is present in vegetable tissues, its concentration being below 0.2 mg kg-1 in some fruits. In this experiment the effect of ASA treatments at three concentrations (0.1, 0.5 and 1.0 mM) on pomegranate quality and nutritive and bioactive compounds after storage for 14-84 days at 2 degrees C plus 4 days at 20 degrees C was assayed. Control fruit exhibited more CI symptoms (manifested by pitting and browning) than treated fruit during storage, which were accompanied by increased softening, ion leakage and respiration rate. The ASA treatments were also effective in maintaining higher contents of nutritive (sugars and organic acids) and bioactive compounds (acid, total phenolics and anthocyanins), ascorbic acid and total antioxidant activity. These results suggest that ASA could have potential postharvest application to reduce CI, maintain quality and improve the health benefits of pomegranate fruit consumption by increasing their antioxidant capacity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006950.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 217-219]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600097">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Harvest maturity and postharvest storage condition effects on pomegranate fruit quality]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.S., Sidhu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.C., Díaz-Pérez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., MacLean]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Storage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Controlled atmosphere storage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Harvesting]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Little is known of the postharvest quality and storage potential of locally grown pomegranate cultivars in Georgia, U.S.A. Seven cultivars were harvested at two maturity stages (early and late) and stored either in regular air (RA; 5 degrees C, 90 per cent to 95 per cent R.H.) or in controlled atmosphere (CA; 3 per cent O2, 5 per cent CO2, 5 degrees C, 90 per cent to 95 per cent R.H.) for three months. Fruit were evaluated for physical and physiochemical attributes immediately after removal and after 7 days of keeping the fruit at 21 degrees C. Late harvested fruits had significantly increased total soluble solids (TSS) and anthocyanins content compared to early harvested fruit. CA storage significantly reduced fruit disease compared to RA conditions. Acids degradation was significantly reduced in CA as compared to RA. Juice-weight of 50 arils was increased in CA which is an important consideration for fruit destined for juice production.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006945.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 201-204]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600098">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The pomegranate tree in the world: Its problems and uses]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Hernández, F.]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Legua, P.]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Melgarejo-Sánchez, P.]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Martinez Font, R.]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trees]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marketing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The pomegranate tree has been known since ancient times and has traditionally been cultivated in the Near East, later spreading to the rest of Asia and the Mediterranean. It is now cultivated in all five continents: firstly, because its cultivation offers exceptional prospects, it is profitable, it can be grown in arid regions, it has less hydric requirements than other crop types and it can grow and produce in conditions which would not be possible for other more important fruit trees to do profitably; secondly, because, in the last ten years, it has been found to have properties which can prevent and possibly cure some illnesses. Knowing and obtaining new varieties which can provide crops over a longer period of time and therefore meet market demands better, with quality fruits for different uses, as well as the discovery of its numerous nutritious, pharmacological, functional and cosmetic properties has led to this fruit tree becoming more and more in demand by farmers and its fruits and derived products becoming more used by consumers. Undoubtedly, of all the factors mentioned above which have aroused such a great interest in this crop throughout the world, it is the potential of its fruits to prevent-cure illnesses that has most influenced its cultivation. This factor has led to a great interest for the industrialization of its fruit (juices, tubs of grains, dehydrated seeds, rind, etc.), which has contributed remarkably to the increase of crop areas and a rise in farmers' income. Other products being commercialized are extracts for manufacturing capsules, obtaining oils or for manufacturing cosmetic products. AII these new products are becoming widely accepted among consumers and industrialists who see this species as a new market opportunity. The world surface area dedicated to the cultivation of pomegranate trees is more than 300,000 ha and world production is probably higher than 3,000,000 t; the main production countries being India, Iran, China, Turkey and the USA.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 11-26]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[103]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600099">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Development of an irrigation scheduling recommendation for pomegranate trees (Punica granatum)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Buesa]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Badal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Guerra]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Lozoya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D.S., Intrigliolo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Bonet]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trees]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Irrigation scheduling]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate culture in Spain is concentrated in the south east, where water available is scarce. There is a need for providing growers with some irrigation recommendations for improving water use efficiency. For this purpose, information from indicators of the continuous soil-plant-atmosphere is being used in a commercial drip irrigated pomegranate orchard, for delivering to growers a weekly irrigation recommendation, taking into account the reference evapotranspiration, plant water status determined via stem water potential measurements and the soil water available to plant obtained from capacitance probes that measured soil water content at different depths. Watering recommendations are calculated in order to fulfil crop water requirements and also avoid water percolation. The average annual water application has been around 425 mm. The information obtained has been transferred by means of an experimental crop coefficient (Kc) integrated in a dissemination tool for calculating water crops requirements. Experimental Kc values increased from 0.32 in March to 0.74 in July, decreasing to 0.42 in November.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006923.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 141-145]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600100">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Efficacy and residues of selected insecticides for control of cotton aphid (Aphis gossypii) and mealybug (Planococcus citri) in pomegranates]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Lozoya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Valdés]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Natural enemies]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Aphis gossypii]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Planococcus citri]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pest management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Mealybug (Planococcus citri Risso) and aphids (Aphis gossypii Glover and Aphis punicae Passerini) are the most important pests of pomegranate production in Alicante (Spain). Due to the minor crop status of pomegranates, registered pest control chemicals for this crop are scarce. Experimental field efficacy of new conventional insecticides and alternative sprays against these sucking pests was assessed.Experiments to deal with these pests were carried out in randomized block design with three replications during 2009-2010, in two experimental pomegranate orchards in the Southeastern region of Spain. Other management practices and natural enemies of these pests were identified and quantified during the crop period. Results of the experiments suggest that the population of cotton aphid was resistant to Pirimicarb. New generation insecticides (Imidacloprid, Flonicamid, Acetamiprid) were more effective in controlling aphids. Moderately effective control can be achieved with soap, citrus oil and other tolerance exempt products, or some combination of these, but more than two applications may be necessary. Pesticide residue levels in ripening fruit after treatments were analysed.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006916.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 107-111]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600101">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Pomegranate improvement through clonal selection and hybridization in Elche]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Valdés]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Andreu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Lozoya]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., García]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.L., Badenes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Accessions]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Germplasm]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Spain is one of the most important pomegranate producers and exporters in the Mediterranean Basin. In spite of various pomegranate cultivars grown, sweet and soft seeds ‘Mollar de Elche’ and ‘Valenciana’ are the main varieties-population. This paper reports the activities in progress on pomegranate germplasm and breeding in the last ten years at Valencian Agricultural Research Institute (IVIA) in Elche. A collection of 35 accessions collected from different parts of Alicante was established and characterised. The collection has been implemented with new accessions. Hybridization between ‘Mollar de Elche’ and other foreign varieties was done in order to obtain darker skin and early ripening. Crossbred progenies were selected and they are being examined in an experimental orchard.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006908.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 71-74]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600102">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Diversity of pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) germplasm in Spain]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Accessions]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Characterization]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Twenty-nine pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) accessions were studied to determine the overall degree of polymorphism. Cluster analysis showed a considerable phenotypic and genetic diversity in the local pomegranate germplasm. The cluster analysis produced a dendrogram with four main clusters,showing accessions closely related and simultaneously very different from others. The geographic origin was a determinant criterion for cultivars clustering.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006904.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 53-56]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600103">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Acceptance characteristics of pomegranate juice for four countries: Spain, United States, Estonia, and Thailand]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Koppel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Chambers I V]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Vázquez-Araújo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.A., Carbonell-Barrachina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Suwonsichon]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organoleptic analysis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flavour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Acceptability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Five 100% pomegranate juices, representing various flavor profiles, were evaluated by at least 100 consumers in each country, Thailand, Estonia, Spain, and the USA, to determine which products were liked most by consumers in each country. Flavor of the juices was evaluated by a trained descriptive panel. The results suggest that Estonian, United States, and Thai consumers liked pomegranate juice samples that were sweet, sour, and had other fruity flavor notes, whereas, Spanish consumers liked the sample with fruity, musty/earthy, and vegetative flavors. One sample that was high in sweet aromatics, but also was described by consumers as having “artificial taste” or tasting like a “fruit flavored drink” was liked by some consumers in all countries. The sample that was high in astringency and had fermented and metallic flavors was not liked in any country. Clustering of the consumers showed some split opinions for several samples.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006966.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 265-267]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600104">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[UV-C light and mild hot water for keeping overall quality of fresh-cut pomegranate arils]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Maghoumi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.A., Gómez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Artés-Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y., Mostofi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Zamami]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Artés]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Minimal processing (of food)]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Respiration]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ultraviolet radiation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Safety]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hot water treatment]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Manually extracted pomegranate arils (cv. ‘Mollar de Elche’), chlorine disinfected (100 ppm),rinsed and drained arils (Control) were exposed to either 4.54 kJ m-2 ultraviolet-C light (UV-C) or immersed for 30 s in water at 55 degrees C (HW), packaged in polypropylene (PP) baskets (100 g), sealed on the top and then stored up to 14 days at 5 per centC. The respiration rate (RR), atmosphere composition, titratable acidity (TA), total soluble solids content (TSS), microbial growth and sensory quality were monitored. Passive MAP composition at the steady state was the same (16 kPa O2 plus 5 kPa CO2) independently of the treatment. RR tended to slightly increase during storage being in general slightly lower for the Control (between 1.5 and 1.7 ml CO2 kg-1 h-1). Significant changes were detected for TA which decreased from the initial value (0.19 g citric acid/100 ml) to 0.09, 0.08 and 0.1 g citric acid/100 ml for control, HW and UV-C respectively at the end of storage. From the initial TSS of 15.8 per centB, a slight reduction in HW treatment was found. No noticeable changes in TSS for control and UV-C treatment were found. Mesophilic counts strongly decreased by HW and in a lesser extent by both UV-C and chlorinated water. The same trend was found for molds and yeasts. No Enterobacteriaceae growth was observed in any treatment. Control as well as all HW treated arils were sensory scored as poor, being qualified as unmarketable after 14 days. In contrast arils from UV-C kept well enough their sensory quality and were considered as good, being this treatment reliable for keeping overall quality and safety.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006937.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 179-182]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600105">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Chemical composition of pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) cultivars grown in Croatia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Radunić]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Jukić Špika]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Goreta Ban]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Gadže]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Mac Lean]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Acicity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solubility]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is among the oldest cultivated sub-tropical fruit species in the coastal part of Croatia, traditionally grown in central and southern Dalmatia. More recently, its fruits have gained interest for their nutritional values. The edible part of pomegranate fruit contains considerable amounts of vitamins,polysaccharides, polyphenols and minerals. One of the most important quality characteristics of pomegranate fruit are the arils and juice, which are primarily associated with anthocyanin pigments. Fruit samples of seven domestic pomegranate cultivars (Barski slatki, Ciparski rani, Crveni rani, Dividiš, Konjskizub, Sladun, and Šerbetaš) and wild pomegranate were collected from a productive pomegranate orchard in Metković (Croatia) (43 degrees 01'N 17 degrees 65'E). The results on the main fruit quality traits (total soluble solids, total acidity, total sugar contents, total phenolic content, antioxidant activity and anthocyanins content) indicated significant statistical differences among cultivars.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006912.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 87-89]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600106">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Pomegranate fruit ripening: nutritional and bioactive compounds]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ripening]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organic acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Harvesting time]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sugars]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate fruit undergoes several biochemical changes during growth and ripening on tree leading to the fruit to reach an optimal quality at full ripening stage. These changes are increase in sugar concentration (glucose and fructose), diminution in total acidity (citric and malic acids) and increase in anthocyanin concentration. In addition an increase occurs in antioxidant activity which reaches values higher than those found in other fruits of the Mediterranean diet. However, important differences are found among cultivars in these parameters responsible for organoleptic, nutritive and functional properties of pomegranate fruit and thus, cultivar is an important factor determining fruit quality. In addition, pomegranate is a perishable fruit having limited storage possibilities, due to the occurrence of several alterations due to mechanical damage during harvesting and packaging or during storage, such as dehydration, over-ripening (leading to flavor alterations and decreases of antioxidant properties), decay incidence and chilling injury(CI). CI damage appears when fruits are transferred to 20 degrees C after storage at temperatures lower than 5°C and are manifested as pitting, with purple color, desiccation and skin browning, which can reach the carpelar membranes and arils. Then, proper harvesting, handling and storage conditions should be chosen to preserve pomegranate fruit quality attributes from tree to table.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006928.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 165-168]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600107">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Reduction of chilling injury and maintenance of fruit quality after pre-storage salicylic acid application on Iranian pomegranates]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Serrano]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.M., Díaz-Mula]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.M., Valverde]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chilling damage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Electrolytes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Salicylic acid]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is one of the most popular fruit in Iran being consumed as fresh arils. However, pomegranates are highly perishable fruit due to weight losses, decay and mainly chilling injury symptoms (CI) when stored below 5 degrees C. With the aim to reduce CI in pomegranate (Punica granatum cv. Malas Saveh), the fruits were treated with salicylic acid (SA) at different concentrations (0.7, 1.4 or 2.0 mM), then stored at the temperature of 2 degrees C for 3 months (to stimulate low temperature damage). SA treatments, especially at 2 mM concentration, were highly effective in reducing CI and electrolyte leakage in the husk of pomegranate, as well as the ascorbic acid loss compared with that observed in control fruit. In addition, no significant changes were observed in total soluble solids and total acidity, during storage for any treatments, with the only exception of total acidity in 1.4 mM SA-treated, which was rather high. Results found here showed that PAL activity increased during prolonged cold storage although the SA-treatment reduced those increases.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006952.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 225-227]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600108">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Analysis of the production structure and crop costs of pomegranates in Spain]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Fernández-Zamudio]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J., Bartual]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Melián]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production structure]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The importance of the pomegranate is growing with increasing worldwide consumer demand,which is stimulated due to this fruits are considered a functional food, its technological improvements in processing and conservation and a wide range of new industrial uses of the fruit (packed arils, juices and extracts). The increased significance of this fruit in world trade is stimulating improvements in farmingtechniques and commercialization. This paper reviews the production structure of pomegranates in Spain,highlighting both the more favorable and limiting aspects. An analysis of the costs of pomegranate production at representative farms in Alicante province has been performed in order to identify more direct inputs into the economy of the farms which can contribute to their viability and continuity in the medium term. The first finding to be emphasized is that variable costs alone account for over 80 per cent of total costs.Labor is the largest cost (over 32 per cent of total costs), mainly due to the operations of pruning, thinning and harvesting. The irrigation water cost is over 17 per cent due to the high average price of this natural resource in the area. The current average prices in the two main Spanish pomegranate varieties (‘Mollar de Elche’ and ‘Valenciana’) exceed the minimum threshold to offset the costs.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006900.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 33-36]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600109">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Economic prospects of pomegranate growing in the Spanish Mediterranean region]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.D., De Miguel]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Melián]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Fernández-Zamudio]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Economic trends]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Spain]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean region]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The objective of this paper is to analyze origin price trends, as well as to determine the profitability of Spanish pomegranate farms through the evaluation of investments. This analysis is performed in parallel with mandarin, since citrus is one of the main tree crops with which it competes and shares territory. Although farmers in the Spanish Mediterranean have preferred to choose citrus in recent decades,its drop in value is encouraging the choice of alternative tree crops, and there will be areas, like the one studied here, where the interest in species with more favorable prospects, such as the pomegranate, will increase. This is possible if demand grows, supported by the notion that it is a healthy or functional food.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006899.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 29-32]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600110">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The Argentinean experience in the cultivation of 1000 ha of pomegranates (5 provinces. Test of varieties and management of crop]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.F., Zavala]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Cozza]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Genetics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Argentina]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Varieties]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Israel]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crops]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In the year 2007 the commercial pomegranate plantation at scale started in Argentina destined for exportation. At present, the pomegranate project has 1000 hectares implanted in different latitudes, in provinces such as Salta, San Juan, Córdoba, Entre Ríos and Formosa, where the nursery is located. The Genetics is Israeli in its origin for the open varieties like Wonderful clones 100 and 101, Acco and, other varieties have Royalty such as Emek, Kamel, Shany Yonay and Shir; the first two varieties are the ones that are commercially planted in greater proportions. The crops are managed with densities of 416 plants per hectare, with drip irrigation and fertirrigation and plastic mulching over the line. The fertilization used is basically N, P and K. The plants are pruned and are shaped as an open vase multitrunk without trellising systems. The expected time for harvest is March April at its peak. This year 2011 the first commercial harvests have started.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006903.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 47-50]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600111">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of chemicals on control of fruit cracking in pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) var. Ganesh]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.K., Sheikh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Manjula]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chemicals]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit cracking]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[During drought period, strengthened tissue develops in xylem and phloem and loss their ability to divide and enlarge. If after a dry spell (April-May) water supply is increased the meristematic tissue quickly resumes growth but the strengthened tissue does not, and owing to differential growth rate, tissues ruptures appear. Hypertrophy of lenticels may be caused or promoted greatly by retarded transpiration accompanied by plentiful water supply to the regions of hypertrophy. Heavy summer rains (April-May) causes fruit cracking if the plants were previously under severe water stress, because the skin get hardened and the arils are filled-up with water. If 25 per cent available soil moisture is maintained during summer, then fruit cracking will be less. Calcium is a cell binding material, and spraying of calcium chloride (1 kg per 100 l water) or calcium ammonium nitrate (2 kg per 100 l of water) reduces fruit cracking. Dry heat accomplished by dry hot wind at the time of fruit ripening in pomegranate was the main cause of cracking: during the rapid flesh growth, temperatures higher than 38 degrees C combined with less than 60 per cent humidity favoured cracking. Sharp fluctuation in day and night temperatures coupled with heavy irrigation after dry spell also cause cracking. Nutrients like boron, zinc, calcium, copper, molybdenum manganese and potash are involve in physiological processes during fruit growth period, and theirs deficiencies cause cracking. Boron and copper help to increase the growth rate by stimulating enzymatic action in the peripheral tissue which otherwise could not be due to their inherent deficiency in the area. Boron application may probably help in translocation of sugars and synthesis of cell wall.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006921.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 133-135]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600112">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The cultivation of Pomegramate cv. Wonderful in Chile]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Franck]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Growth]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Wonderful]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Chile]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultivation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The pomegranate plantations in Chile have increased exponentially in the last decade taking fresh pomegranate exports from 200 t per year in 2007 to 2500 t per year in 2010. Practically 100 per cent of the pomegranate production in Chile was based on the Wonderful variety which fulfils the requirements of intense red colour of the skin and the flesh inside demanded by the destination markets supplied by Chile: Europe and Russia. This flourishing industry in Chile has faced several challenges related to appropriate planting areas, growing and post-harvest techniques for fruit destined for export and industrialisation and to the large proportion of fruit unsuitable for export. The presentation will detail these challenges as well as the technical advances in cv. Wonderful growing that have been made thanks to the collaboration between producers, exporters and research centres in Chile.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006914.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 97-99]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600113">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of different periods and levels of water deficit on physiological, productive and quality parameters of pomegranate cv. Wonderful fruits]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Franck]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Alfaro]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Kremer]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Opazo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Mundaca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Wonderful]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Physiology]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drought]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is a crop tolerant to water deficit and is suitable in areas of water scarcity. This work presents results from a three year study on different levels of water deficit applied at the beginning,end or during the growth period of the pomegranate cv. Wonderful fruit under full production and young plants raised in 1 m3 containers. Over this period the following parameters were measured: gas exchange, chlorophyll fluorescence, soil and xylem water potential, solar radiation intercept, osmotic adjustment and fruit and shoot growth. Fruit weight, yield and size were determined at harvest. The results help determining controlled water stress thresholds and periods for the production of fresh fruit.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006922.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 137-140]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600114">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Morphological and physiological characteristics in pomegranate cultivars with different yields]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Drogoudi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Pantelidis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Manganaris]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Leaf area index]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stomata]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Gases]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water potential]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[hermaphroditism]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Leaves]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Variations in yield, percentage of hermaphrodite flowers, leaf mass to area ratio, leaf area, stomatal density, leaf gas-exchange and stem water potential (Ψstem) characteristics were studied in four pomegranate accessions. Yield was greatest in 11005 and Kallisti, compared with 11019 and 11021 accessions. Similarly, percentage of hermaphrodite flowers was greatest in 11005, followed by Kallisti which may be related with greater yields. In addition 11005 had highest photosynthetic rate and leaf area, but leaf mass:area was lowest. Intrinsic water use efficiency was highest, and stomatal conductance and transpiration were usually lowest in 11005 and Kallisti, a characteristic that may enable water conservation. Significant greater stomatal density was also found in Kallisti, which may suggest for a flexible stomata regulation to water deficit conditions. There were no significant differences among the studied genotypes in Ψstem.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006907.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 67-69]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600115">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Characterization of six varieties of Moroccan pomegranate]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Haddioui]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Hmid]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Hanine]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Characterization]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This study evaluated the characteristics of six pomegranate varieties (“Sefri”, “Ounk Hman”, “Ruby”,“Rouge Marrakech”, “Bouaâdime” and “Jaune Marrakech”), being all indigenous to four provinces in Morocco where the species shows high variability. A morphological and organoleptic characterisation of the fruits and of the edible portion of the seeds were investigated. Some chemical characteristics of the juice, including total soluble solids, pH, acidity, crude fiber and maturity index, were assessed. The results of the study reveal that the Moroccan varieties present an average top weight to 430g per fruit and one big caliber. The assessment of pomegranate chemical compositions implies the great potential of Moroccan cultivars for both fresh market and fruit processing.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006911.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 83-86]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600116">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Optimization of pomegranate jam preservation conditions]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Legua]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[J.J., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Martínez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Hernández]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Storage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Jams]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Colour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[One of the most important parameters to which consumers are sensitive when selecting jams is the color. Anthocyanin and colour development of pomegranate jams made from ‘Mollar’ cultivar were analysed during five months. Different temperatures (5 degrees C and 25 degrees C) and light exposures (daylight and darkness) were tested during storage. Also the influence of pectin on jam preparation was evaluated. The results concluded that high methoxy pectins yielded better pomegranate jams because of their high a star values (34 per cent higher than low methoxy ones). Optimal storage conditions were achieved at 5 degrees C and no light exposure at all.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006969.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 277-281]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600117">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[II International Symposium on the Pomegranate]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidant capacity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Plant breeding]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Marketing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Health]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultivation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[These Proceedings include 63 scientific papers presented at the II International Symposium on the Pomegranate, held in Madrid (Spain) from 19 to 21 October 2011. Production and commerce of pomegranate and its derived products have experienced significant growth everywhere in the world. Progress has been made in cultivation techniques and some traditional problems have been solved, although new problems such as Xanthomonas axonopodis attacks constitute a present threat. New public and private institutions in different countries are working to improve the production and quality of the pomegranate, and new varieties are being commercialized. The cultivar is a determining factor in issues related to nutritional composition and bioactive compounds with antioxidant activity. At the same time, significant advances in postharvest technologies have been made in the past years, specially focused on the use of technologies with natural compounds of great efficiency in maintaining the quality and safety of pomegranate fruit during prolonged storage periods. Special importance is attached to the advance in the industrialization processes through the technologies for processing ready-to-eat arils. In the past years, new protocols for quality evaluation using sensory analysis have been developed. With respect to the relationship between pomegranate and health, recent clinical studies report that pomegranate juice or extract can reduce the progression of prostate cancer, although more studies are needed to confirm these experimental results.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/a103.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Conference Proceedings]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 337]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En, Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[2. International Symposium on the Pomegranate]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600118">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Évolution et stabilité d’un jus fonctionnel à base de grenade et de kaki]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo-Sánchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Melgarejo Juan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.A., Sánchez]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[L., Valory]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Ignatieva]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Saura]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Martí]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Vitamin C]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Lemons]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Health foods]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kaki]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[La conception de ce produit, """"""gran and GO"""""", résulte de la combinaison de plusieurs développements technologiques innovants : la production de jus clarifié de grenade (Punica granatum L.) de diverses cultivars, le développement d’un jus industriel clarifié de kaki (Diospyros kaki L.) non astringent, l’utilisation, en tant qu’acidulant, d’un jus de citron (Citrus limón (L.) Burm.) clarifié par filtration tangentielle pour compenser la sensation sucrée, astringente et légèrement amère des premiers jus cités précédemment. De plus, des nanoparticules de flavonoïdes d’agrumes ont été employées pour éviter la détérioration de la vitamine C (dernière technologie en expérimentation pour augmenter la solubilité des extraits végétales). L’objectif de cette étude est de déterminer l’évolution et la stabilité des paramètres physico-chimiques et des propriétés nutritionnelles durant l’essai de stockage accéléré de 7 jours à 45 degrees C. Avec la finalité d’estimer la vie utile d’un jus fonctionnel à base de grenade et de kaki.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006970.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 283-286]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600119">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Evolution of sugars and organic acids patterns during the elaboration of pomegranate varietal wines]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Mena-Parreño]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Gironés-Vilaplana]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Martí]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., García-Viguera]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Organic acids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fermentation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Winemaking]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sugars]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is usually earmarked for arils fresh consumption and also used by food industry for the elaboration of juices and jams. Pomegranate wine constitutes a new alternative for the use by producers of second qualities and over-ripe fruits of this typical Mediterranean crop, with the subsequent environmental benefits. Hence, with the aim of developing new pomegranate-derived drinks, the evolution of sugars and organic acids patterns from different varieties throughout the winemaking stages was assessed. Noticeable changes were occurred for these compounds during wine elaboration, especially along fermentation period. In addition, a significant role of the cultivar used in the organic acids profile was noted.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006971.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 287-290]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600120">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Chilling injury is reduced and the content of bioactive compounds enhanced by methyl salicylate treatment]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Zapata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Guillén]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Martínez-Romero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Methyl salicylate (MeSa) is a volatile plant compound having a role in plant defense-mechanism as signal molecule. Some evidences have shown that MeSA could indirectly provide protection against chilling damage (CI). Thus, given than pomegranate fruits are sensitive to CI, the effect of MeSa treatments (at 0.01 and 0.1 mM) on reducing the incidence of CI was analyzed. Control pomegranates exhibited CI symptoms manifested by pitting and browning when fruits were stored at 20 degrees C after cold storage, the severity being enhanced as storage time advanced. The CI symptoms, as well as softening and increase in electrolyte leakage (EL), were significantly reduced by MeSa treatments, without significant differences among 0.01 and 0.1 mM doses. In addition, total phenolic and anhocyanin concentration and antioxidant activity were higher in arils from MeSa treated fruits than in those from controls. In conclusion in this paper we report the positive effect of MeSa on reducing CI of pomegranate fruits stored at chilling temperatures, which was accompanied by reduced softening and EL, showing a protective role on cell membranes and for increases in bioactive compounds and their related antioxidant activity have been found.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006954.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 233-236]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600121">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effect of drying process on phenolic compounds and antioxidant capacity of pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) fry flowers]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Reynoso Camacho]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.P., Meillón Alcántara]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.I., Servin Uribe]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Mondragón Jacobo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidant capacity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flowers]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Drying]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The pomegranate (Punica granatum L.) is an important medicinal plant. It has been reported that phenolic compounds contained in the flowers have antioxidant potential. The objective was to determine the concentration of total phenolics and antioxidant capacity of three selections of pomegranate flower dried under different conditions. The highest phenolic content and antioxidant capacity was observed in the orange colored flowers dried at room temperature. Compared to red and dark red flowers, the dark red showed higher anthocyanins. The room temperature and oven drying processes preserved a higher content of phenols compared to sun drying. The results showed that orange pomegranate flowers dried at room temperature could be used for the preparation of antioxidant beverages.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006977.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 331-334]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600122">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Methyl jasmonate treatment reduces chilling injury and improves antioxidant activity]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Castillo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Martínez-Romero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Guillén]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Sayyari]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P.J., Zapata]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Anthocyanins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Methyl jasmonate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Methyl jasmonate (MeJa) is an endogenous plant growth substance that regulates many aspects of plant development and growth, including chilling injury (CI) stress. Then, taking into account that pomegranate fruits are susceptible to CI, the main objective of this paper was to study the effect of MeJa on pomegranate fruit quality attributes during storage under chilling conditions. Pomegranates were treated after harvest with MeJa at two concentrations (0.01 and 0.1 mM), and then stored under chilling temperature for 84 days. Control fruits exhibited CI symptoms, manifested by pitting and browning, the severity being enhanced as storage time advanced, which were accompanied by softening and increase in electrolyte leakage (EL). The CI symptoms were significantly reduced by MeJa treatments, and total phenolic and anthocyanin concentration increased. Total antioxidant activity decreased in control arils, while increases occurred in arils from MeJa treated fruits. Results suggest that MeJa treatment has potential postharvest applications to reduce CI, maintain quality and improving the health benefits of pomegranate fruit consumption by increasing their content in bioactive compounds and antioxidant capacity.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006955.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 237-239]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600123">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Contrôle intégré d’Aphis punicae Passerini en grenadier dans la région du Tadla (Maroc)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Fakhour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tadla]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pests of plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Aphis punicae]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The work to identify pests associated with the pomegranate in Tadla generated a list of the main species encountered during the study period. Among these pests, the aphid Aphis punicae is the most important and destructive. This pest could cause heavy yield losses, reaching in some cases 24 tons per ha in the absence of chemical intervention. Plant protection systems on the basis of the threshold of intervention can lead to avoid a few systematic treatments applied by farmers in the region against these pests.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006925.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 151-154]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600124">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[La culture du grenadier dans la région du Tadla (Maroc)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Fakhour]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tadla]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Morocco]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cultivation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The main objective of this study is to contribute to a better knowledge of the pomegranate sector in the region of Tadla (Morocco), through a technico-economical analysis of the various stages of development and marketing of the fruits. The expected outputs of this diagnosis is a better knowledge of the cultivation methods, the comprehension of their reasoning and the identification of the problems limiting the development of the sector and the productivity of the orchards. This study will help in defining research topics that will be taken into consideration by the regional development agencies and nongovernmental organization in their plans of action.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006924.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 147-149]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600125">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Changes in some free sugars and phenolic contents of pomegranate fruits (Punica granatum L.) in three development stages]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Gozlekci]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[E., Kafkas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Ercisli]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[HPLC]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sugars]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this study, some free sugars and phenolic contents at three development stages (immature, unripe and full ripe) of pomegranate cv. Hicaznar fruits grown in Antalya, Turkey were determined. While total sugar contents showed a regular increment, total phenol content decreased from the immature fruit to full ripe fruit. The predominant sugars quantified were fructose and glucose, while sucrose was minor sugar in all development stages. Fructose contents in immature fruits to mature fruits varied from 3.53 to 5.78 g per 100g fresh weight basis, while glucose contents varied from 3.44 to 6.37 g per 100g fresh weight. On the other hand, sucrose contents varied from 0.21 to 0.41 g per 100g fresh weight. On the contrary to sugars, the lowest levels of total phenolics and flavanoids were determined in full ripe fruits. Results indicate that both free sugars and phenolic contents of pomegranate were strongly influenced by development stages.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006946.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 205-208]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600126">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Influence of pasteurization treatment and storage in antioxidant activity of pomegranate juice]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Vegara]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Funes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Mena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Martí]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Saura]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Storage]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pasteurization]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The combination of time and temperature of pasteurization treatments and storage conditions are important factors in the degradation of the organoleptic and nutritional properties and bioactive compounds of pomegranate juice. Therefore, the influence of pasteurization (high and low temperature) and storage conditions (refrigerated and room temperature) on the variation of the antioxidant capacity of processed juice was evaluated. The analysis of the results indicates that cloudy juice does not suffers loss of antioxidant activity due to pasteurization. However, in the clarified juice the antioxidant activity loss due to the pasteurization treatments was between 20-25 per cent. None of the juices studied showed loss of antioxidant capacity due to storage time.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006975.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 321-323]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600127">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Influence of pasteurization treatment and storage in the red colour and microbiological stability of pomegranate juice]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Vegara]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Funes]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Mena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Martí]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[D., Saura]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Valero]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Colour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Temperature]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Stability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pasteurization]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The combination of time and temperature of pasteurization treatments and storage conditions are critical in the degradation of the organoleptic and microbiological stability of juice. Therefore, the influence of pasteurization (high and low temperature) and storage conditions (refrigerated and room temperature) on the variation of the red color and microbiological stability of processed juice was evaluated. Both pasteurization treatments were effective in reducing microbial load and keeping the juice stable over time. However, storage temperatures had been decisive, because the juices stored at 25 degrees C had lost 70-80 per cent of its original red color.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006972.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 291-293]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600128">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Inhibition of carob moth damage using Ferula assafoetida essential oil in pomegranate orchards of Iran]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Goldansaz]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Talaei]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Poorjavad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y.H., Dehghani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Iran]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ectomyelois ceratoniae]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicinal plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Behaviour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Reproduction]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Ferula assafoetida]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The carob moth, Ectomyelois ceratoniae is a polyphagus insect pest worldwide. In Iran it is the key pest of pomegranate and alternates to conventional insecticides are being developed. The essential oil of Ferula assafoetida was tested in four pomegranate orchards. In each garden 10 trees were treated with three concentrations of oil. The number of rotten fruits per tree that fell to the ground were counted and removed every 2 weeks during the season. Furthermore, the percentage of rotten fruits per tree at the harvest time was calculated. All three concentrations of the essential oil significantly reduced fruit infestation by carob moth (P less than 0.001). However, the 1:1 dose of the oil caused fruits to be scorched. The reduction in infestation may be due to: (i) a direct repellent effect of the oil on the adult carob moth, or (ii) a disruption of mating by volatile compounds emitted by the essential oil.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006920.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 129-131]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600129">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of salicylic acid, jasmonic acid and calcium chloride treatments on reduction of chilling injury in pomegranate fruit]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Mirdehghan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Ghotbi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Dashti]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phenolic compounds]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Browning]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this experiment was to investigate the effects of salicylic acid, jasmonic acid and calcium chloride on reduction of chilling injury in pomegranate fruits cvs. ،Malas Yazdi, and ،Malas Ashkezar. Salicylic acid (1 and 2 mM from source of acetyl salicylic acid), jasmonic acid (0.3 and 0.4 mM from source of n-propyl dihydrojasmonate), calcium (1 and 2 per cent from source of calcium chloride) and control (distilled water) were used as treatment. After the treatments fruits were stored in cold storage at 1.5 oC plus minus 0.5 and 85 plus minus 5 per cent relative humidity for 2 months. The results revealed that treatments with salicylic acid (SA), jasmonic acid (JA) and calcium chloride (CaCl2) significantly reduced the percentage of chilling injury of pomegranate fruits. The lowest chilling injury was observed in 0.4 mM of JA-treated fruits and the highest one was for untreated fruits. Treatments of fruits with 0.3 mM JA and 2 mM SA increased the electrolyte leakage of fruits but it was not significantly affected by other treatments. It was also showed that treatments of fruits with SA, JA and CaCl2 had no significant effect on pH, ripening index, but the total soluble solids of fruit juices was increased. The results evidenced that pomegranate fruits treated with 2 mM SA had the lowest ascorbic acid, but it was not significant difference between other treatments and untreated fruits. In conclusion, cultivar of ،Malas Ashkezar, exhibited higher tolerance to cold storage compared to ،Malas Yazdi,, therefore cultivar of ،Malas Ashkezar, recommended to keep in cold storage for long time.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006948.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 209-215]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600130">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Preharvest foliar application of methyl jasmonate,salicylic acid and potassium sulfate on improving the quality of pomegranate fruit]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.H., Mirdehghan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Vatanparast]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.R., Karimi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.H., Vazifeshenas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Functional disorders]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Recently, a pomegranate physiological disorder called ‘aril browning’ or ‘aril paleness’ in which a part or all of the arils show discoloration, affect the quality of fruit and such fruits are not suitable for consumption. The present research design to evaluate the effects of jasmonates, salicilates and potassium nutrient on reducing this disorders and improving fruit quality. Ten treatments including salicylic acid (0.3, 0.6 and 0.9 mM), methyl jasmonate (0.5, 1 and 2 mM) potassium sulfate (0.5, 1 and 1.5 per cent) and distilled water (control), were sprayed on pomegranate tree 10 and 45 days after full bloom and after harvest. Different parameters related to quality of fruit were measured. The obtained results indicated that salicylic acid could improve the total acidity, TSS, chroma and hue angel of skin and b star index of arils. Although the phenolic content of arils increased in all treatment compare to control, the differences were not significant. The highest antioxidant activity was observed in the 1.5 per cent potassium sulfate treatment and the differences with the control were significant.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006939.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 183-189]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600131">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Status and management of anthracnose of pomegranate in Karnataka State of India]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V.B., Nargund]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Jayalakshmi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V.I., Venagi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A.S., Byadgi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R.V., Patil]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Colletotrichum gloeosporioides]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fungicides]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Karnataka]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[India]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate is extensively cultivated around the Mediterranean and other parts of world including India. It is regarded as the \"Fruit of Paradise\".The most popular varieties in India are Ganesh, Mridula, Arakta, Bhagwa (Kesar). Successful cultivation of pomegranate in recent years has met with different problems such as pests and diseases. Among the various fungal diseases, anthracnose, caused by Colletotrichum gloeosporioides (Penz.) Penz. and Sacc., is one of the most serious disease of pomegranate, remaining latent in early stages of fruit development and reducing fruit quality to a greater extent. Propagules of pathogen cause lesions and decay of the fruit. The study was carried out in Karnataka State (India). The survey on the disease in the field showed the extent of anthracnose affecting the crop and quality of the fruits in different locations. The disease was widespread particularly in rainy season/high moisture conditions and incidence and severity disease were higher in Bagalkot district, followed by Koppal,Bijapur Gadag and Raichur districts. Studies on cultural, morphological, and physiological features of the pathogen showed maximum growth on Potato dextrose broth on the 12th day after incubation at 27 plus minus 1 degree C. C. gloeosporioides exhibited diversity with respect to cultural characters like type of the growth, mycelial colour, pigmentation and sporulation with maximum growth on Potato dextrose agar. The different days of incubation of culture filtrates of C. gloeosporioides differed in their action to inhibit the seed germination,root and shoot elongation of sorghum seeds and induction of phytotoxic symptoms on tomato seedlings. Among the tested fungicides, bioagents and botanicals, iprobenfos, propiconazole, carbendazim plus mancozeb and T. viride were superior in inhibiting the mycelial growth of the fungus in vitro. carbendazim plus mancozeb at 0.3 per cent and propiconazole at 0.1 per cent concentration were effective in reducing the percent disease index of anthracnose under field conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006918.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 117-120]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600132">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Threat of bacterial blight on pomegranate in India – Mitigation by an integrated approach]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V.I., Benagi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M.R., Ravikumar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[V.B., Nargund]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Epidemics]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Integrated disease management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Xanthomonas axonopodis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[India]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegrante (Punica granatum L.), so called “fruit of paradise” is one of the major fruit crops of arid region. It is mainly grown in states of Maharashtra, Karnataka, Andhra Pradesh and Tamil Nadu.Bacterial blight of pomegranate, caused by Xanthomonas axonopodis pv. Punicae, considered to be a minor disease, was reported as bacterial leaf spot in the 1950s. At present this disease is observed on leaf,stem and on fruits, and has been responsible for the removing of many orchards in south India. Recently this disease was also observed in Rajasthan. A survey was conducted in North Karnataka during 2008-09 and 2009-10. Disease severity on the trees was 29.8 and 19.3 per cent during 2008-09 and 2009-10 respectively. The disease was very severe in Mrig bahar (severity of 20.8 per cent). Demonstrations were conducted for three years (2008-09 to 2010-11) in farmers’ fields over 6 locations involving various components like selection of hasta bahar treatment, proper training, sanitation, use of micro nutrients, use of organics and use of antibiotics along with copper compounds. The results indicated that before adopting the orchard integrated control management measures, the observed severity on the trees was up to 69 per cent, and it was brought down to 3.0 per cent in orchards where measures were adopted over three years. The average yield levels were 10 tons per hectare in demonstration plots. In the orchards, with nor integrated control, the disease severity on trees was up to 33.1 per cent with average yield levels of 5.2 tons per hectare. Hence yield increased 4.8 tons, which worth Rs. 4.8 lakhs (1 lakh equal to 105), when compared to non-adopted orchards.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006917.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 113-116]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600133">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Main pomegranate phytochemicals and their contribution to the antioxidant potencies of pomegranate juice]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[W., Elfalleh]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Yahia]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ferchichi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Antioxidant capacity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Phytochemistry]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Punica granatum]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[This research aims to screen the main phytochemicals and their antioxidant capacities from juice of some pomegranate cultivars from southern Tunisian. Total polyphenols, flavonoids, anthocyanins and hydrolysable tannins were determined by using classical spectrophotometric methods. Free radical scavenging activities were determined by DPPH and ABTS tests. Antioxidant capacities were determined by FRAP and ORAC methods. Results showed that the antioxidant potency of pomegranate extracts was correlated with their phenolic contents. In particular the highest correlations were reported between DPPH (as IC50) and respectively total flavonoids (r equal to -0.960), anthocyanins (r equal to -0.866) and total polyphenols (r equial to - 0.788). Therefore both total flavonoids and total anthocyanins showed high correlation to FRAP and ORAC assays. All of these findings confirm the differential contributions of pomegranate phytochemicals to the antioxidant potencies of pomegranate juice. The richness of pomegranate juice with antioxidants might encourage for the development of antioxidant function dietary food.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006976.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 325-329]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600134">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[A comprehensive industrialization of the processing of the pomegranate fruit. The key to its economic viability]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y., Sarig]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Galili]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruit juices]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Freezing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The past 10 years have witnessed major changes in the pomegranate industry. Specifically, a worldwide significant increase in the pomegranate planted area, an increase in fruit production, an increase in export quantities and an increase in the stored and processed fruit. Two factors are primarily responsible for these changes: (i) an increasing demand for the pomegranate fruit driven by a substantial body of published results of research on the characteristics of the pomegranate fruit, suggesting that the fruit has both, antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties, helping reduce the risk of prostate cancer and artery plaque. And (ii), the unique development of a machine for automatic extraction of the arils, thus, facilitating the use of ready–to-eat arils and/or development of various postharvest processing lines, such as juice and wine production and development of various pharmaceutical and nutraceutical and cosmetic products derived from the arils kernels. While the current increase in fruit production continues and more “players” are joining in, there is no guarantee that the economic viability of the pomegranate industry is ensured. In fact, past experience have shown that if increased production is not matched by a similar increase in demand, prices of the fruit are liable to come down; competition will increase; small growers will be forced out of business and we shall witness (as seen in the past) uprooting of existing orchards with declined economy. The pomegranate industry is still undergoing a process of evolution from specialty to commercial crop. Thus, to ensure its sustained economy, a system approach has to be adopted addressing all the factors associated with the industrialization of the processing. Unfortunately, many growers do not even make use of existing technologies and do not initiate R and D to develop new processing technologies addressing the unique characteristics of the pomegranate fruit. Thus, for example, the arils extracting machine is yet not fully commercialized. Likewise, the unique freezing technology is still not fully utilized and very little is done to develop commercial products from the various components of the fruit, such as: the arils, the rind, the arils kernels and the juice. The potential is high, but unless a system approach is adopted,the fruit will remain a minor crop globally]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006902.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 43-46]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600135">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[The pomegranate industry in China – Current status and future challenges]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Y., Sarig]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Galili]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Processing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[China]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Arils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The pomegranate, one of the oldest fruits known to man, was originally thought to be a native to China. Actually, it was brought to China through the Silk Road during the Tang Dynasty (600-900 BCE). The current production is estimated as 1,600,000 tones and the planted area of 110,000 Ha. Although the pomegranate adopts itself to a variety of climatic conditions and pomegranate can be found in many parts of China , the major orchards in China are in the provinces of Sichuan, Chongqing, Shandong, Shaanxi and Henan. Other provinces where pomegranate is produced (although on a smaller scale) include the provinces of Xinjiang, Hebei, Guangdong and Yunnan. There are over 200 different varieties of pomegranate in China, which vary from province to province, with a range of weights, from 300-1200gr, a scale of colors from light green to deep red and a range of skin thicknesses and kernels hardness (from soft to hard kernels). They also vary in their sugar content and other ingredients in the arils and the rind. The vast size of China constitutes, both, its potential strength, but also the source of its difficulties, which is reflected also in the Chinese pomegranate industry. Although China is one of the world’s biggest producer of pomegranate (the biggest, according to some sources), its methods of cultivation resembles a gardening art rather than modern agriculture. Although some significant changes were introduced in recent years, agriculture in China is still characterized by labor intensiveness and small scale and it is a far cry from modern horticultural methods. The current situation is characterized by rather primitive methods of irrigation, lack of adequate facilities for sorting, sizing, packing, transportation and storage especially, cold and CA storage, which results in a relatively low quality of the product and inconsistency in the quality. The fruit is marketed, almost exclusively, in local markets because the current quality can’t meet the competitive market economy requirements. China’s rapid growth and structural changes, while resolving many problems, have also given rise to new challenges. Nevertheless, China has the capacity to meet these challenges. With the proper guidelines, including training, technology transfer and acquisition of know-how and modern equipment its potential can be realized.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006965.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 261-264]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600136">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Besoins en eau du grenadier cultivé sous les conditions de la plaine du Tadla (Maroc)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Messaoudi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Segmani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Khatib]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tadla]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fruits]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quality]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Water requirements]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Acreage dedicated to pomegranates in Tadla plain (Morocco) is estimated in more than 1400 ha. Pomegranate orchards are mainly irrigated by submersion. Therefore, water consumption is very high. This study aimed at estimating water requirements under the conditions of this area and evaluating the effects of different drip irrigation strategies on tree developpement and yield parameters. Five drip irrigation strategies were compared namely 60 per cent ETc, 80 per cent ETc, 100 per cent ETc, 120 per cent ETc and the own farm drip irrigation strategy. Daily mean ETc was calculated by using the Penman-Monteith formula for a period of 11 years. Results suggested that drip irrigation based on 120 per cent ETc conditions constitutes the optimal drip irrigation strategy when vegetative growth, fruit yield parameters and water consumption are considered.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006927.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 159-162]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600137">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effets de quelques pulvérisations foliaires sur l’éclatement des grenades sous les conditions du Tadla (Maroc)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Messaoudi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[Z., Il-Idrissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Khatib]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza, Spain; Universidad Miguel Hernández,, Elche, Spain]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tadla]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Calcium]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Division]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Kaolin]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pomegranates]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Pomegranate cv Sefri occupies more than 70 per cent of the total acreage dedicated to this fruit specie in Tadla plain (Morocco). However, fruit splitting does not allow a suitable economical valorization of the pomegranate production in this area. This work aimed at studying the effect of three foliar products namely Fertibore, Ferticalcium and Cutisan on yield parameters and fruit cracking of Sefri pomegranates. Four treatments, namely control (untreated trees), Fertibore 15 per cent (200 cm3 per 100 l), Ferticalcium 11.5 per cent (200 cm3 per 100 l) and Cutisan (2 kg per ha) were compared according to a completely randomized block design. Highest fruit weight was recorded under Ferticalcium treatment while fruit bark weight and thickness was improved by the three products. Total aril mass and arils width were improved by the three products. Fruit juice volume was improved by Cutisan and Fertibore while total soluble solid was not affected. The three products reduced pomegranates splitting.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[
					http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a103/00006926.pdf
				]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-501-5]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 155-158]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[Fr]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.103()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600138">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Development of agro forestry areas in Northern Algeria to improve pastoral production]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Abdelguerfi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Laouar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[K., Abbas]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., M'Hammedi Bouzina]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[T., Madani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Agroforestry systems]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Development]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Resowing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In Algeria, the exploitation for livestock breeding of grazing land sloping, gaps in the forests, and some marginal lands, can be of substantial interest. Indeed, these spaces, including catchment areas of dams extending over 3 million hectares, can improve feed production. Currently, forage productivity of scrubs and forest rangelands varies from one region to another depending on environmental conditions (rainfall, exposure, soil, etc.), animal pressure and botanical composition of vegetation. Considering the chronic deficit of forage, and to improve pastoral production, we propose the development of some agroforestry areas in northern Algeria with natural re-seeding of legumes, such as annual Medicago, some Trifolium, Hedysarum, Onobrychis, and Scorpiurus species. The choice of species and mixtures of species should take into account the ecological conditions and the adaptation of plant species. In this context, a list of suitable plant species is proposed according to soil and climatic conditions.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006935.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 319-322]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600139">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Secondary compounds characterization in some autochtonous species from a North-Eastern region of Tunisia]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Bettaieb]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[N., Moujahed]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Ksouri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Flavonoids]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Polyphenols]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Essential oils]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Tannins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Saponins]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Several native species were collected in the region of Zaghouan (eastern-north of Tunisia, semi-arid) in order to evaluate their chemical diversity for an eventual animal use context, during the period of spring 2011. Some secondary compounds were determined by colorimetric quantification in leaves and twigs. Essential oils from these species were extracted by hydro-distillation and then analyzed using gas chromatography technique, coupled with mass spectrometry (GC per MS). Results showed that among the studied species, Myrtus communis presented the highest total polyphenol (101.3 mg GAE per g DM), while Artemisia herba-alba and Ruta Chalepensis were the lowest ones (13.2 and 13.7 mg GAE per g DM respectively). Condensed tannin content in Juniperus phoenicea (43.8 mg CE per g DM) was largely higher than in all the other species, in which it ranged approximately between 1 and 5 mg per g DM. In addition, saponin content was the utmost in J. phoenicea (25.2 mg per g DM) as compared to the others species, where it varied between almost 6 and 13 mg per g DM. The amount of flavonoids varied widely between 28.6 and 5.1 mg per g DM in Mentha pelagium and M. communis respectively. Essential oils of all species were composed of wide pools of identified components. For instance, the main compounds were 1.8-cineol in Rosmarinus officinalis (39 per cent), thymol (61.3 per cent) in Thymus vulgaris, and carvacrol (64.8 per cent) in A. herba-alba. It was concluded that the vegetal diversity in the studied area presented a consequent chemical diversity, available for animals as fed in grazing or in housing conditions. These bioactive molecules, mainly essential oils, may be used for their antimicrobial actions to improve animal health and performance. In this connection, in vitro studies are currently carried out in our]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006960.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 371-374]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600140">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Impacts of climate change on the small ruminants farming systems in north western Tunisia and adaptation tools]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Brahmi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Khaldi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Jaouad]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Hicheri]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Touati]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Rkhissi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Ifaoui]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G., Khaldi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Farming system]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate change]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Adaptation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Susstainability]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Small ruminants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Studies on the national adaptation strategy of Tunisian agriculture to climate change reveal that this phenomenon will have serious implications on water resources, ecosystems and agro-systems by 2030. Successive droughts will reduce livestock numbers by 80% in central and southern regions and 20% in the North. In this context, we studied the reaction of the small ruminants farming systems to this critical situation. An investigation has been carried out in the north west of Tunisia (240 small ruminants farms in Jendouba governorate and 151 in Kef governorate). Farms typology results (by PCA) indicate the presence of three farms groups in Kef and three in Jendouba with different farm sizes and flock numbers. The common problem is feed availability. Frequent droughts and over-grazing explain why the involvement of natural pastures and rangelands in animal feed calendars are declining noticeably, justifying the frequent use of transhumance. Large amounts of concentrates are used especially in summer, reducing farmers’ incomes improved by other activities. In forest zones, twigs of trees and shrubs constitute a very good food resource. Farmers practice late weaning to reduce the quantities of concentrates presented to the lambs in order to preserve their farm’s sustainability.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006990.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 427-431]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600141">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Behaviour of some alfalfa populations from algerian oasis]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Chaabena]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Laouar]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Boudebbous]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[I., Cahouki]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Bentebba]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Madani]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Abdelguerfi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Oasis]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Behaviour]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Algeria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Medicago sativa]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Surveys carried out between April and December 2006 at several Saharan farms showed that farmers continue to use local alfalfa seed they buy from other neighbouring farmers even with higher prices than those of introduced varieties. Thus, we have implemented a behaviour test (March 2008) at Hassi Ben Abdallah (800 km Southeast of Algiers) with a Lattice device with 4 blocks (repetitions) for 20 Saharan populations and 13 biometrical parameters (fresh and dry yields, dry matter content, height and diameter of the main stem, number of mowing, …) considered for about three years. The first observation is that nineteen alfalfa populations continue growing in the winter and just one (Guemar) which stop its growing when it’s cold. After an ANOVA test, all parameters have shown a significant or high significant difference except the number of mowing which revealed a non significant difference. Using an ascending hierarchical classification, we obtain three groups of alfalfa populations from algerian oasis according to our biometric parameters.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006878.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 191-196]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A. Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600142">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Advances in grassland research in the Mediterranean region of Chile]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Del Pozo]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[C., Ovalle]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Crop rotation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nitrogen fixation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legumes]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Cover plants]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Pastures]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Productivity]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The Central Zone of Chile, the only part of South America that presents a Mediterranean climate, has about 5 million hectares of pasture. A large proportion are annual species from the Mediterranean Basin. This article presents a summary of the results of 20 years of research carried out in order to improve productivity of livestock production systems and contribute to the rehabilitation of these degraded agroecosystems. The studies have considered both the collection and domestication of naturalized annual legumes in Chile (Medicago polymorpha) and the assessment of several accessions and cultivars of annual legumes of the genus Trifolium, Medicago, Ornithopis and Biserrula. The works have also considered the design and assessment of pasture mixtures, the evaluation of N fixation in addition to the integration of legumes in crop rotations and as cover crop in vineyards and orchards. Evaluations were performed in a gradient of rainfall between 600 and 1000 annual rainfall on volcanic soils (Andisols) and Entisols derived from granitic rocks. The productivity and persistence of B. pelecinus in the interior dryland and O. compressus in the Andean foothill are clearly superior to other annual legumes (M. polymorpha or T. subterraneum) seeded in those areas. The use of legume mixture is also highly recommended due to their higher productivity and persistence compared to monospecific pastures. The amount of N2 fixed by annual legumes is closely related to the shoot dry matter production of the pasture, and the rate is 18-20 kg shoot N fixed per ton shoot DM accumulated. Finally, annual legumes contribute to the N nutrition of wheat or grapevines in a Mediterranean environment.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00007010.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 527-531]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600143">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Effects of grazing on the traits of a potential fire in a Sardinian wooded pasture]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Franca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Sanna]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S., Nieddu]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.A., Re]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[G.V., Pintus]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Ventura]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[P., Duce]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Salis]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[B., Arca]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Fires]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Management]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grazing]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Solid fuels]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Sardinia]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Mediterranean rural landscapes are often characterized by a complex matrix of grasslands, open wooded pastures, shrubland and broadleaf forests, and are affected by a considerable frequency of fire ignitions. Whatever the causes and the interested landscape structure, the risk of burning is related with the fuel biomass. This paper would clear the role of grazers in reducing the fire risk within 2000 ha of a typical Mediterranean Quercus spp. forest, by a modelling approach, based on FARSITE simulator, able to estimate the probability of burning, and the severity of the fires. Fuel biomass samples were collected at the start and the end of the fire season in 23 representative sites, in order to define the spatial variation of the herbaceous fuel model in grazed and non grazed conditions. Ungrazed conditions were simulated placing exclosure cages in each site. The study allowed to assess the effect of the grazing abandonment on the fire behavior. Fuel reduction strategies tested by the simulator permitted to define the role of grazers in the fire prevention plan.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006933.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 307-311]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600144">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Seasonal change of the mineral concentrations of gall oak (Quercus infectoria) and Christ’s-thorn (Paliurus spina-christi)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Gökkus]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Özaslan-Parlak]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Parlak]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Paliurus spina-christi]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Quercus infectoria]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Nutrients]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Trace elements]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[Gall oak and Christ’s-thorn are common in the Mediterranean flora of Turkey and significant forage source for goats in spring, summer and fall. Both species are consumed preferably by the goats. Therefore, to obtain information about the feeding values of these species and reveal cause of the goats preferred primarily these species were aimed in this study by determining the change of nutrient and nonnutrient minerals in these species. In the samples macro and micro elements were determined. Results were analyzed statistically by repeated experimental design. Generally, seasonal variation of minerals of both shrubs was similar. While N, P, K, S, Cu and Zn decreased regularly from spring to fall, Ca, Mn and Na increased. Mg did not alter significantly. In gall oak, B increased from spring to fall and decreased in Christ’s-thorn from spring to summer. Although Zn amount of gall oak had non-significant change seasonally, it was high for Christ’s-thorn in spring but low in the other seasons. The shrubs contained sufficient macro and micro nutrients, except for S, Cu and Zn, to supply the needs of the goats in every season.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006949.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 355-359]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600145">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Climate change and grasslands: impacts, adaptation and mitigation]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Hopkins]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Mediterranean zone]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Climate]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Greenhouse gases]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Animal husbandry]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forages]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The paper reviews recent evidence on climate change and the role of greenhouse gases (GHG). Historical evidence indicates that climate change is not a new phenomenon and Mediterranean ecosystems have shown considerable resilience to past climate changes. The 21st century can be regarded as an era of climate change in which concerns about climate are accompanied by other drivers relating to globalization, food security and energy and sustainability issues. Carbon dioxide enhancement can have positive and negative effects for forage production. Increased temperatures and water deficits in the Mediterranean zone are likely to impact adversely on production, based on modelled outcomes, especially on maximum-production systems, but climate-adapted and regionally diverse systems of agriculture are suggested as being more resilient to climate change impacts. A range of adaptation strategies at both farm level and at policy/ government level are considered as means of enabling grass and forage systems to be maintained in a changing climate. Livestock agriculture contributes to GHG emissions but a range of mitigation measures are considered that can help offset some of these emissions. It is concluded that an integrated approach is required to respond to climate change. Many challenges remain but there are grounds for cautious optimism for future grass and forage-based farming in the Mediterranean zone.The paper reviews recent evidence on climate change and the role of greenhouse gases (GHG). Historical evidence indicates that climate change is not a new phenomenon and Mediterranean ecosystems have shown considerable resilience to past climate changes. The 21st century can be regarded as an era of climate change in which concerns about climate are accompanied by other drivers relating to globalization, food security and energy and sustainability issues. Carbon dioxide enhancement can have positive and negative effects for forage production. Increased temperatures and water deficits in the Mediterranean zone are likely to impact adversely on production, based on modelled outcomes, especially on maximum-production systems, but climate-adapted and regionally diverse systems of agriculture are suggested as being more resilient to climate change impacts. A range of adaptation strategies at both farm level and at policy/ government level are considered as means of enabling grass and forage systems to be maintained in a changing climate. Livestock agriculture contributes to GHG emissions but a range of mitigation measures are considered that can help offset some of these emissions. It is concluded that an integrated approach is required to respond to climate change. Many challenges remain but there are grounds for cautious optimism for future grass and forage-based farming in the Mediterranean zone.The paper reviews recent evidence on climate change and the role of greenhouse gases (GHG). Historical evidence indicates that climate change is not a new phenomenon and Mediterranean ecosystems have shown considerable resilience to past climate changes. The 21st century can be regarded as an era of climate change in which concerns about climate are accompanied by other drivers relating to globalization, food security and energy and sustainability issues. Carbon dioxide enhancement can have positive and negative effects for forage production. Increased temperatures and water deficits in the Mediterranean zone are likely to impact adversely on production, based on modelled outcomes, especially on maximum-production systems, but climate-adapted and regionally diverse systems of agriculture are suggested as being more resilient to climate change impacts. A range of adaptation strategies at both farm level and at policy/ government level are considered as means of enabling grass and forage systems to be maintained in a changing climate. Livestock agriculture contributes to GHG emissions but a range of mitigation measures are considered that can help offset some of these emissions. It is concluded that an integrated approach is required to respond to climate change. Many challenges remain but there are grounds for cautious optimism for future grass and forage-based farming in the Mediterranean zone.The paper reviews recent evidence on climate change and the role of greenhouse gases (GHG). Historical evidence indicates that climate change is not a new phenomenon and Mediterranean ecosystems have shown considerable resilience to past climate changes. The 21st century can be regarded as an era of climate change in which concerns about climate are accompanied by other drivers relating to globalization, food security and energy and sustainability issues. Carbon dioxide enhancement can have positive and negative effects for forage production. Increased temperatures and water deficits in the Mediterranean zone are likely to impact adversely on production, based on modelled outcomes, especially on maximum-production systems, but climate-adap]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006828.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 37-46]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600146">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[An overview of fodder resources and animal production in Turkey]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Koc]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[M., Tan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H.I., Erkovan]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Rangelands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Forage production]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Turkey]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Animal husbandry]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering feed quality are especially important challenges. Finally producers have to be trained on animal feeding and raising and rangelands management.In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering feed quality are especially important challenges. Finally producers have to be trained on animal feeding and raising and rangelands management.In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering feed quality are especially important challenges. Finally producers have to be trained on animal feeding and raising and rangelands management.In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering feed quality are especially important challenges. Finally producers have to be trained on animal feeding and raising and rangelands management.In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering feed quality are especially important challenges. Finally producers have to be trained on animal feeding and raising and rangelands management.In this paper, roughage resources of Turkey were reviewed. Problems and recommendations were discussed for sustainable animal production in the country. Hay production and forage crops acreage have increased significantly last two decades owing to governmental incentives but there is still gap in sufficient quality forage in the country. The forage gap is mainly compensated with cereal straw which is too far to meet animal maintenance need. Some serious measurements such as regulation of grazing season, grazing capacity and selection of proper animal species for rangelands are needed. With respect to forage crops production, solving seed problems and marketing, and determining roughage prices considering f]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006823.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 15-22]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
<ags:resource ags:ARN="QC2015600147">
	<dc:title><![CDATA[Management of common pool resources: Cases of collective grasslands, inventory and characterization of their management in the region of Hadj Mechri, Laghouat (Algeria)]]></dc:title>
	<dc:creator>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[A., Mouhous]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[S.A., Kadi]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[R., Hammouda]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[H., Guermah]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
		<ags:creatorPersonal><![CDATA[F., Djellal]]></ags:creatorPersonal>
	</dc:creator>
	<dc:publisher>
		<ags:publisherName><![CDATA[CIHEAM-IAMZ, Zaragoza (Spain), Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun (Turkey)]]></ags:publisherName>
	</dc:publisher>
	<dc:date><dcterms:dateIssued><![CDATA[2012]]></dcterms:dateIssued></dc:date>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Grasslands]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Degradation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Hadj Mechri]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Collective ownership]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:subject><![CDATA[Legislation]]></dc:subject>
	<dc:description><dcterms:abstract><![CDATA[The aim of this study is to identify collective grasslands in the region of Hadj Mechri (in Laghouat region, Algeria) and to characterize their operating modes. The results showed different legal status (Arch, domanial and municipal) and different degradation levels of collective grassland managed by two operating modes, namely the collective mode and individual mode. The use of these collective grasslands was limited only to sedentary agro-pastoralists which are installed in the periphery. When operating mode is individual, it means that there was a tacit division of the collective grassland between the agro-pastoralists concerned.]]></dcterms:abstract>
	</dc:description>
	<dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI"><![CDATA[http://om.ciheam.org/om/pdf/a102/00006959.pdf]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:identifier scheme="ags:ISBN"><![CDATA[2-85352-490-6]]></dc:identifier>
	<dc:type><![CDATA[Journal Article]]></dc:type>
	<dc:format><dcterms:extent><![CDATA[p. 367-370]]></dcterms:extent></dc:format>
	<dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1"><![CDATA[En]]></dc:language>
	<ags:citation>
		<ags:citationTitle><![CDATA[Options Méditerranéennes. Séries A: Mediterranean Seminars]]></ags:citationTitle>
		<ags:citationNumber><![CDATA[v.102()]]></ags:citationNumber>
	</ags:citation>
</ags:resource>
</ags:resources>