<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
  <ags:resource ags:ARN="RU2015C03803">
    <dc:title xml:lang="ru">Тенденции роста сосны обыкновенной и ели европейской на северо-западе РФ как индикатор возможных изменений климата</dc:title>
    <dc:title xml:lang="en">
      <dcterms:alternative>Scots pine and Norway spruce growth trends in North-West Russia as an indicator of possible climate changes</dcterms:alternative>
    </dc:title>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorPersonal>Alekseev A.S.</ags:creatorPersonal>
    </dc:creator>
    <ags:creatorConference>International scientific conference Innovation and technologies in forestry</ags:creatorConference>
    <dc:creator>
      <ags:creatorCorporate>Saint Petersburg Forestry Research Institute</ags:creatorCorporate>
    </dc:creator>
    <dc:date>
      <dcterms:dateIssued scheme="dcterms:W3CDTF">2011-</dcterms:dateIssued>
    </dc:date>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K01</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K10</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K11</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K50</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectClassification scheme="ags:ASC">K70</ags:subjectClassification>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">Diameter increment</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC" xml:lang="en">climate change</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_34812</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:subject>
      <ags:subjectThesaurus scheme="ags:AGROVOC">http://aims.fao.org/aos/agrovoc/c_1666</ags:subjectThesaurus>
    </dc:subject>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="ru">Изучены долговременные тенденции роста сосны обыкновенной, произрастающей на границе своего естественного ареала на северо-западе Кольского полуострова (Мурманская обл.), а также сосны обыкновенной и ели европейской на территории Ленинградской области. Основу анализа составляют дендрохронологические данные о ширине годичных слоев. Для изучения процессов роста в совокупностях деревьев в зависимости от состояния внешней среды обитания использован специальный метод удаления возрастного тренда из дендрохронологических рядов, в результате чего появляется возможность для биологической индикации возможных региональных изменений климата. Показано наличие достоверной тенденции к увеличению прироста у деревьев сосны обыкновенной на Кольском полуострове и ее отсутствие у древостоев сосны обыкновенной и ели европейской в Ленинградской области. Построены кривые хода роста по диаметру древостоев и проведен их сравнительный анализ. Обсуждаются полученные результаты.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:description>
      <dcterms:abstract xml:lang="en">Growth trends of Scots pine at its northernmost extent may be an indicator of changes in the carbon cycle of terrestrial forest ecosystems. Using a method which removed age trends from the data, a time-series analysis of annual radial increment in wood over the last few decades comparatively with the period of last registered warming with maximum in the 1930-40 revealed elevated growth. This increased growth occurred despite a decrease in temperature after about 1940 and significant air pollution. Growth trends are unstable in time and took place together with growing oscillations of Scots pine trees radial increment.
The most probable reasons for a marked increase in radial increment growth of Scots pine in this region are climate warming and higher levels of carbon dioxide. Together these may produce a synergetic effect.
By the same method Scots pine and Norway spruce trees growing in Leningrad region was tested on elevation trend in radial increment. For this region no growth trends was re-vealed both for Scots pine and Norway spruce.</dcterms:abstract>
    </dc:description>
    <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">http://www.spb-niilh.ru/pdf/innovations/innovations_2011_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
    <dc:type>Conference Paper</dc:type>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">ru</dc:language>
    <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">en</dc:language>
  </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>