<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Comparative evaluation of the nutritional quality of corn, sorghum and millet ogi prepared by a modified traditional technique</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Oyarekua</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M.A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Science Technology Department, Federal Polytechnic, Ado–Ekiti, Ekiti State, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Eleyinmi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A.F.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Food Science and Technology Dept, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Ondo State, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Ogi was prepared from corn (Zea mays), sorghum (Sorghum vulgare) and millet (Eleusine coracana) by a modified traditional process, dry milled, packaged and subjected to proximate, mineral and amino acid analyses. Crude protein content of the traditional ogi flour ranged from 4.12 (millet ogi) to 5.93% (sorghum ogi) while ogi from the modified process had values between 7.92 (millet ogi) and 10.78% (corn ogi). Significant increases (P&lt; 0.05) were recorded in the lipid, ash and mineral composition of modified ogi flours with increase ranging between 16–92% for minerals. Nutrient contents were highest in modified corn ogi (MCO) for P, Na, K, Ca and Fe, in modified millet ogi (MMO) for Mg (986 mg kg-1) and Mn (11.6 mg kg-1) and in MSO (modified sorghum ogi) for Cu (10.7 mg kg-1) and Zn (53.5 mg kg-1). The mineral ratios for Ca/P (0.01–0.17) and Ca/Mg (0.11–1.09) were significantly lower than the recommended standard (1), the only exception being traditional sorghum ogi (1.09). Gross energy calculated for the ogi flours was comparable and did not appear to be influenced by the modification introduced. Proportion of the total energy due to protein and utilisable energy due to protein was highest in MCO (10 and 6% respectively). MSO had the highest total essential amino acids (TEAA) (721.9 mg g-1 cp), total sulphur AA (91.3 mg g-1 cp), arginine (91.5 mg g-1 cp) and predicted biological value (P-BV) (7.06). P-BV and predicted protein efficiency ratio for MCO, MMO and MSO were 6.73 and 4.06, 6.47 and 1.62, and 7.06 and 0.27 respectively.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>94</start>
          <end>99</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2004</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2004-issue_2/f16.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>