<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>In vitro propagation and microrhizome induction in Zingiber cassumunar (Roxb.) – an antioxidant-rich medicinal plant</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Chirangini</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">P.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Manipur University, Imphal-795003, India.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Sharma</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">G. J.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Manipur University, Imphal-795003, India.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Rhizomatous buds of Zingiber cassumunar Roxb. – a medicinally important aromatic herb – were cultured on Murashige and Skoog medium supplemented with plant growth regulators for inducing microshoots. Explants inoculated in 4.44 µM 6- benzylaminopurine (BAP) showed 100% response giving both multiple shoots (70%) and single shoots (30%). However, single shoots were induced in higher percentage (80%) in 2.32 µM kinetin supplemented medium. The most effective media for multiplication of microshoots were MS media fortified with 0.54 µM α-naphthalene acetic acid (NAA) and 4.44 µM BAP and 2.69 µM NAA and 4.44 µM BAP producing at the rate of 8 microshoots per explant. Microrhizomes were observed at the base of all in vitro derived shoots cultured on the media supplemented with a range of sucrose concentration (3-9%) within eight weeks of incubation. The best responses in terms of number (up to 6 microrhizomes per culture tube) were obtained in the media supplemented with 7 and 9% sucrose. Average fresh weight of 0.81g was observed in MS medium supplemented with 5% sucrose.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>139</start>
          <end>142</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_1/a6.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>