<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effect of cattle manure application on pod yield and yield indices of okra (Abelmoschus esculentus L. Moench) in a semi-arid sub-tropical environment</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ogunlela</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Vincent B.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Crop Science, University of Zimbabwe, P O Box MP 167, Mt. Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe. Corresponding author and Current address: Department of Agronomy, Institute for Agricultural Research,  Ahmadu Bello University, PMB 1044, Zaria, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Masarirambi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Michael T.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Crop Science, University of Zimbabwe, P O Box MP 167, Mt. Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Makuza</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Stanley M.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Animal Science,University of Zimbabwe, P O Box MP 167, Mt. Pleasant, Harare, Zimbabwe.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The effects of cattle manure rate and time of application on okra yield and yield indices were studied at Harare, Zimbabwe during two cropping seasons (2000-2002). The treatments were factorial combinations of four cattle manure rates (0, 6, 12 and 18 t ha-¹) and two application timings (4 and 8 weeks after planting). The experiment was a randomized complete block design with four replications. Both cumulative green pod count and yield were increased by manure application up to 12 t ha-¹ in 2000 and 6 t ha-¹ in 2001. Yield values for the best manure rates were 131 and 123% of those for the control in 2000 and 2001 respectively. Average green pod weight and length were increased by manure application in one year only (2000). Application of manure 6 t ha-¹ gave the highest dry pod weight while 12 t ha -¹ produced the highest weight of seeds pod -¹. Parameters were generally not influenced by time of manure application or rate x timing interaction. Leaf Ca was slightly higher for earlier applied manure and for 6 and 12 t ha-¹ than for no manure or 18 t ha-¹. Pod N was also slightly higher for earlier manure application than for the later application. The best manure rate would vary with manure quality. However, application of manure 6 t ha-¹ as early as possible in the cropping season appears to be best for okra production in semi-arid Zimbabwe.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>125</start>
          <end>129</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_1/a2.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>