<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Adsorption isotherms and heat of sorption of fresh and preosmosed oven-dried bananas</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Falade</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">K.O.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Food Technology, University of Ibadan,. P. O. Box 9508 U I Post Office Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Awoyele</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">O.O.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Food Technology, University of Ibadan,. P. O. Box 9508 U I Post Office Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Three banana varieties (Omini Red, Cavendish and Cooking banana) were transversely cut into 10 mm slices, pretreated in sucrose solution of 52, 60 and 68°B and maintained at 25°C for 12 hours. Both fresh and preosmosed banana slices were subsequently oven-dried at 60°C for 72 hours. Adsorption isotherms of fresh and preosmosed oven-dried banana slices were determined at 20 and 40°C using gravimetric–static method. Suitability of eight sorption models in describing the adsorption data was tested. Moreover, isosteric heat of sorption of both fresh and preosmosed oven-dried bananas was determined using Clausius–Clapeyron equation. Adsorption isotherms of fresh and preosmosed oven-dried banana slices gave type I (J–shaped) isotherms. Isotherms were affected by temperature and pretreatment sucrose solution concentration. Crossing of isotherms occurred at aw~0.55-0.70. Among the eight models, tested, Guggenheim-Anderson-de Boer (GAB) model gave the best fit. Calculated GAB monolayer moisture (Mm) content (9.80–20.8% d.b.) decreased with increase in temperature. Generally GAB Mm content increased with increase in total solids (%) content of preosmosed banana slices. Isosteric heat of sorption increased with decreased moisture content in banana slices.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>97</start>
          <end>102</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_1/f17.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>