<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Can reflective ground cover enhance fruit quality and colouration?</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Funke</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Kerstin</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Obstversuchsanlage Klein-Altendorf, Universität Bonn, Meckenheimer Str. 42, D-53359 Rheinbach, Germany.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Blanke</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Obstversuchsanlage Klein-Altendorf, Universität Bonn, Meckenheimer Str. 42, D-53359 Rheinbach, Germany.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>White reflective ground cover was spread in mid September on the grass strips on both sides of the tree rows of seven-year-old cv. Braeburn apple on M9 rootstock to improve light utilisation in the orchard. Apple trees in uncovered grass strips served as controls. The maturity and quality parameters [fruit size, fruit firmness (10.4 kg cm-²), starch breakdown (score 4) and sugar content (12.6%)] of the late-ripening, bi-coloured cv. Braeburn apple fruit at harvest were unaffected by the reflective ground cover. White reflective ground cover on the grass strips improved light utilisation in the orchard in terms of fruit colouration, particularly for the lower part of the tree close to the reflective ground cover and the inner, tree-facing and down-facing, otherwise shaded sides of the apple fruit. The improved fruit colouration with reflective ground cover is attributed to increased light utilisation in the orchard. The present work showed that effective enhancement of fruit colouration with retention of good fruit quality is possible, if reflective ground cover is spread as late as mid September, i.e. only four weeks prior to harvest, in the tree alleys of the late ripening, bi-coloured cv. Braeburn apple.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>203</start>
          <end>206</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_1/a20.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>