<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Assessment of the environment-related problems and prospects of vegetable production in peri–urban areas of Lagos State, Nigeria</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Oladoja</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M.A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago – Iwoye, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Akinbile</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">L.A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Development, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Adisa</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">B.O.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Extension and Rural Sociology, Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago – Iwoye, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The study attempted to assess the environment-related problems and prospects of vegetable production in peri–urban areas of Lagos state, Nigeria. A total of 120 farmers were interviewed. Data collected were analyzed using frequency, percentages and Pearson product moment correlation coefficient. Frequency distribution showed that majority of the respondents was within the age of 36–55 years (75%); 87.5% were literate, 71.67% of them were members of groups, 91.67% of the farmers sampled favoured the suitability of the alluvial soil high in organic manure in the vegetable production. The hypotheses testing showed that age does not have significant relationship with vegetable production while household size, farming experience and farm size do have significant relationship with vegetable production. Education and vegetable production were negatively significant but related. Sequel to the findings of the study, it is recommended that government should give serious considerations to the promotion of this business enterprise and necessary incentive should be made available to encourage the farmers to practice vegetable production.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>271</start>
          <end>275</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_3_4/e15.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>