<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Expanding the uses of phane, a nutritionally rich local food in Southern Africa</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ohiokpehai</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Omo</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Tropical Soil Biology and Fertility Institute, The International Center for Tropical Agriculture (TSBF – CIAT), P.O. Box 30677-00100 UN Avenue, Gigiri, Nairobi, Kenya.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Dried mophane worms (phane) are a common but small part of the diet in Botswana. Proximate analysis of phane showed it to be a very good food source, with high protein content (approximately 50%) and a significant amount of fat (approximately 15%). The traditional method of preparing phane, which is degutting, cooking, salting and drying, should produce a product suitable for long-term storage. Therefore, we explored several ways to use phane as a high protein food component, with a view to promote its use year round. The most promising of these was the addition of phane to weaning food. Sorghum was mixed with phane at a ratio of 80:20 to give a protein mixture of about 18%, and with ditloo, bambara nuts and phane at 40:40:20 (sorghum:ditloo:phane) to give a protein content of about 20%. In the case of weaning food, microbiological quality becomes especially important. It was found that phane purchased from street vendors in Botswana was contaminated with coliforms/faecal coliforms at levels that might be acceptable when the phane was to be cooked further, but unacceptable for infant food. Therefore, a post-processing method to reduce these organisms to acceptable levels was tested.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>26</start>
          <end>32</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_3_4/f7.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>