<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Biochemical implications of the consumption of Zonocerus variegatus, (Orthoptera: Pyrgomorphidae) and Cirina forda Westwood (Lepidoptera: Saturnidae)</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ogunleye</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">R. F.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Zoology, University Ado Ekiti, Ado-Ekiti, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Biochemical implications of the consumption of two insect species, Zonocerus variegatus (Orthoptera:Pyrgomorphidae) and Cirina forda (Lepidoptera Saturnidae), were evaluated in laboratory experiments. Proximate and mineral analysis showed that the insect species had high contents of protein and essential minerals. Powder of processed C. forda caterpillars and Z. variegatus adults was used as replacement for fishmeal in experimental diets of albino rats. Three groups (control and 2 experimental groups) of ten wealing rats were fed for a period of five weeks.Thereafter, the rats were taken to the laboratory for the evaluation of total protein, glucose and cholesterol level in blood. The blood cholesterol level of rats fed with C. forda and Z. variegatus (1.33 and 1.18 mmol/l) was lower than in control group (1.48 mmol/l). Protein levels of blood serum for rats fed with Z. variegatus and C. forda (66±3.4 and 67.5±2.3 g/l) were higher than in control rats (63±2.3 g/l). The glucose level in blood of experimental rats fed with Z. variegatus and C. forda (6.75±0.4 and 3.48±0.3 mmol/l) was also lower than in control (8.4±0.2 mmol/l).</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>23</start>
          <end>25</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_3_4/f6.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>