<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Chemical composition and antibacterial and antimutagenic activity of Tunisian Rosmarinus officinalis L. oil from Kasrine</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Marzouk</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Zohra</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratoire de Biologie Végétale, Faculté de Pharmacie, Monastir, Rue Avicenne 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Neffati</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Aicha</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratoire de Biochimie, Faculté de Pharmacie, Monastir, Rue Avicenne 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Marzouk</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Belsem</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Institut Supérieur de Biotechnologie, Monastir, Rue Tahar Haddad 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Chraief</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Imed</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratoire de Biochimie, Faculté de Médecine, Monastir, Rue Avicenne 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Fathia</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Khemiss</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratoire de Physiologie Humaine, Faculté de Médecine Dentaire, Monastir, Rue Avicenne 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ghedira</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Leila Chekir</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratoire de Biologie Cellulaire et Moléculaire, Faculté de Médecine Dentaire, Monastir, Rue Avicenne 5000 Monastir, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Boukef</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Kamel</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Centre National de Transfusion Sanguine, Bab-Sadoun, Tunis, Tunisie.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The first aim of this study was to describe in detail the chemical composition of Tunisian Rosmarinus officinalis L. essential oil (EO) from Kasrine. The second aim was to test its antibacterial and antimutagenic activities. EOs were extracted from rosemary leaves by hydrodistillation using a Clevenger-type apparatus. The chemical analysis was carried out by using gas chromatography and mass spectrometry (GC-MS). Forty chemical compounds were identified in EOs. The quantitative composition of EOs differs between geographical sources.The antimicrobial activity was evaluated against five pathogenic bacterial strains: Gram-negative Escherichia coli and Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Gram-positive Staphylococcus aureus, Staphylococcus epidermidis and Micrococcus luteus. All EOs were dissolved in Tween-80. The minimum inhibitory concentrations (MIC) and the minimum bactericidal concentrations (MBC) were determined by sub-culture at TSA agar plates which were incubated at 37°C during 18- 24 h. The antimutagenic effect was tested by Ames test on Salmonella typhimurium TA97. Rosemary EOs had a good antimicrobial activity against all bacteria tested, E. coli being the most sensitive. EOs can be suggested as an antimutagenic agent. The antibacterial and antimutagenic activities are not related only to major compounds but also to the minor components of rosemary EOs. Rosemary oil can be used as an antimicrobial agent in hospitals by pulverisation or in soaps and in foods such as fish, meat, milk and its derivatives. Regular use of honey based on rosemary might help to treat chronic bacterial infections or cancer.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>61</start>
          <end>65</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_3_4/f14.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>