<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of N fertilization on the vegetative growth of passion fruit (Passiflora edulis f. flavicarpa) seedlings</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Aiyelaagbe</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">I. O. O.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Horticulture, University of Agriculture PMB 2240 Abeokuta, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Fagbayide</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">J. A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agronomy, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Makinde</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A. I.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agronomy, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The effects of N fertilization on the growth and dry matter production of juvenile-transition phase of yellow passion fruit plants were investigated in pot experiments conducted in 1996 and 2002/2003. The study covered the juvenile and transition stages of growth. In the first trial, the plants received N at rates equivalent to 30-120 kg ha-1. In the second trial, the plants received N at rates equivalent to 60-480 kg ha-1. In both trials, no N pots served as control. In the first trial, application of N 30-120 kg ha-1 had no consistent effects on the growth and dry matter accumulation by the passion fruit plants compared with control. In the second trial, the effects of N 0-120 kg ha-1 on vine length, number of leaves, leaf area, number of branches and dry matter production were similar to those observed in the earlier trial. However, application of N 240 or 480 kg ha-1 consistently significantly enhanced vine length, number of leaves, leaf area, number of branches and total dry matter accumulation of the plants. Except for number of branches, the effects of N 240 kg ha-1 on other growth parameters were often not significantly different from those of N 480 kg ha-1. Since, number of branches is positively related to fruit yield, thus N 480 kg ha-1 which produced the largest number of branches is considered the optimum N rate for the vegetative growth of yellow passion fruit during the juvenile and transition stages of growth.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>62</start>
          <end>64</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_3_4/a1.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>