<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Relative susceptibility of some local and elite rice varieties to the rice weevil, Sitophilus oryzae L. (Coleoptera: Curculionidae)</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ashamo</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Michael O.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Biology, Federal University of Technology,P. M. B. 704, Akure, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Studies on the relative susceptibility of some local and elite rice varieties to the rice weevil, Sitophilus oryzae L., were carried out in the laboratory under ambient temperature of 28±2°C and relative humidity of 75±5%. The exotic or elite varieties of rice tested included ITA 257, ITA 150, ITA 117, ITA 128, ITA 315, ITA212, ITA 222, ITA 306, ITA 230, Cisadene, Aroso (Caprice, which was brought in from Thailand) while the indigenous or local varieties included Igbimo and Otiripo. The infestation was done with 4 males and 8 females for each 10 g of each variety and then replicated three times. A control without weevils was also set up. The greatest number of adult emergence (55.00), weight loss (14.60%) and highest percentage grain damage (20.38%) occurred in variety ITA 117 (elite) and least adult emergence (9.00), weight loss (3.82%) and percentage grain damage (3.62%) occurred in ITA 212 (elite). The index of susceptibility (SI) showed that variety ITA 117 was the most susceptible with SI=10.8 while ITA 212 was the least susceptible of all the 13 varieties with SI=5.5. The local varieties (Igbimo and Otiripo) were less susceptible to S. oryzae than some of the elite varieties such as ITA257, ITA150, ITA128, ITA315, ITA222, ITA306, ITA230 and Cisadene.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>249</start>
          <end>252</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_1/e3.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>