<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Polyphenolics and minerals composition of selected browse tree species leaves native to north-western Tanzania traditional fodder banks</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Rubanza</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Chrispinus D.K.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratory of Animal Science, Faculty of Life and Environmental Science,Shimane University, Matsue, Shimane 690-8504, Japan. Tanzania Forestry Research Institute (TAFORI), P.O Box 1257, Shinyanga, Tanzania.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Shem</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Martin N.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Animal Science and Production, Sokoine University of Agriculture,P.O Box 3004, Morogoro, Tanzania.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ichinohe</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Toshiyoshi</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratory of Animal Science, Faculty of Life and Environmental Science,Shimane University, Matsue, Shimane 690-8504, Japan.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Fujihara</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Tsutomu</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratory of Animal Science, Faculty of Life and Environmental Science,Shimane University, Matsue, Shimane 690-8504, Japan.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Utilisation of browse tree fodder supplements in ruminant feeding in the tropics is limited by lack of information on their nutritive potential. A study was conducted to screen leaves of six browse species (Acacia sieberiana, Boscia spp., Grewia spp., Lonchocarpus capassa, Pithecellobium dulce and Salvadora persica) for potential chemical composition, total extractable phenolics (TEP) and tannins (TET) and concentration of minerals, using chemical assays. The species had high levels of crude protein (CP) that varied among the species from 153 to 231 g kg-1 DM in Grewia spp. And Boscia spp., respectively. Acacia sieberiana had the highest neutral detergent fibre (NDF) (475 vs. 323 g kg-1 DM; P. dulce), acid detergent fibre (ADF) (393 vs. 191 g kg-1 DM; Grewia spp.) and acid detergent lignin (ADL) (196 vs. 71 g kg-1 DM; S. persica). The browse species had low levels of TEP (1.1- 8.1) and TET (0.25-7.1 g kg-1 DM). Concentration of Ca, P, Mg and S varied among the species from 13.8-55.1, 3.2-4.9, 2.4-6.2 and 1.6-30.6 g kg-1 DM, respectively. The forages contained low to moderate levels of most micro minerals. Copper varied among the species from 5.1 (S. persica) to 9.6 mg kg-1 DM (L. capassa). The species had excessive levels of Mo (93.4-234.1 mg kg-1 DM) and Fe (126-851 mg kg-1 DM). Grewia spp. had the lowest Mn (44.7 vs. 306 mg kg-1 DM; L. capassa). Content of Zn varied among the species from 10.2 (S. persica) to 34.7 mg kg-1 DM (L. capassa). Boscia spp. and Grewia spp. had the lowest concentration of Co (0.29 vs. 0.61 mg kg-1 DM; S. persica). Low levels of TEP and TET could be regarded beneficial by preventing excessive N-loss and by promoting by-pass protein to the lower gastro-intestinal tract. The species could be used as protein and mineral supplements for ruminants in the tropics due to their high levels of CP, Ca, P, S, Mn and Co. Low concentrations of Cu and Zn of these feeds could be limiting in ruminant feeding.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>328</start>
          <end>332</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_1/e18.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>