<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Revisión del cultivo de esciénidos en el mundo, con especial atención a la corvina Argyrosomus regius (Asso, 1801)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, M. T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pastor, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Grau, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alconchel, J. I</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Leal, R.F. (Ricardo Félix)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cárdenas, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Sciaenidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>tasa de crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor conversión de alimento</dc:subject><dc:description>Interest in culture of sciaenid fishes has grown rapidly in recent years. The present paper reviews the literature on several species belonging to Sciaenidae, cultured around the world: red drum Sciaenops ocellatus (L., 1766), Japanese meagre or mulloway Argyrosomus japonicus (Temminck y Schlegel, 1843), shi drum Umbrina cirrosa (L., 1758), and meagre Argyrosomus regius (Asso, 1801). The meagre is a commercially important fish species whose distribution extends along the Eastern Atlantic coast and the Mediterranean Sea. Experiments carried out in sea cages and indoor tanks have shown similar results in growth rate, but the food conversion rate was higher in cages (2,73) than in tanks (13,88).</dc:description><dc:description>El interés por el cultivo de peces esciénidos se ha visto incrementado en los últimos años. Se realiza aquí una revisión bibliográfica de cultivos de varias especies de la familia Sciaenidae en el mundo: corvinón ocelado Sciaenops ocellatus (L., 1766), corvina japonesa Argyrosomus japonicus (Temminck y Schlegel, 1843), verrugato Umbrina cirrosa (L., 1758) y corvina Argyrosomus regius (Asso, 1801). La corvina ha adquirido una importancia comercial notable, y se distribuye a lo largo de las costas del Atlántico y el Mediterráneo. Experiencias de cultivo en jaulas y tanques demostraron similares índices de crecimiento, obteniéndose, sin embargo, un mejor factor de conversión del alimento en jaulas (2,73) que en tanques (13,88).</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1379</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>