<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Problemas importantes relacionados con la protección y recuperación del esturión atlántico Acipenser sturio L., 1758</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Holčík, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:22Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:22Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Distribución</dc:subject><dc:subject>morfología</dc:subject><dc:subject>genoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>taxonomía</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecología</dc:subject><dc:subject>recuperación</dc:subject><dc:description>Analysis of existing data and information show that the present status of the Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser sturio L., 1758, is much more complex than that of any other sturgeon worldwide. The name A. sturio includes 9-12 geographically, and probably also reproductively, isolated populations with disrupted gene flow. If so, and if there are both morphological and genome differences among them, then this name is used to designate several distinct species. Restoration programmes for the particular geographic area in which the Atlantic sturgeon has been known must be based on the stocking of offspring of the same genome from ancestors coming from the same geographic area. The stocking of specimens from other geographic areas would be similar to introduction of an exotic species sensu stricto, resulting in wide-ranging, unexpected and irreversible consequences. Therefore, the ultimate decision on such stocking has to be preceded by careful and scientifically sound analyses of the intended action. Any final solution to this problem needs close international co-operation and financial support from the countries concerned.</dc:description><dc:description>El análisis de los datos e informaciones existentes muestra que el estado actual del esturión atlántico Acipenser sturio L., 1758 es mucho más complejo que el de cualquier otra especie de esturión en todo el mundo. El nombre A. sturio comprende 9-12 poblaciones geográficamente, y probablemente también reproductivamente, aisladas con una corriente interrumpida de genes. Si es realmente así, y entre estas poblaciones existen diferencias tanto morfológicas como genómicas, este nombre denomina entonces varias especies distintas. Los programas de recuperación para un área geográfica particular en la que A. sturio ha sido conocido tienen que estar basados en la repoblación con descendientes con idéntico genoma de ancestros procedentes de la misma región geográfica. La repoblación con ejemplares de una región geográfica diferente significaría la introducción de una especie exótica sensu stricto, resultando una ampliación de su rango, con consecuencias imprevistas e irreversibles. Por eso, la decisión final sobre tal repoblación tiene que basarse en un análisis cuidadoso y científicamente sólido de la acción proyectada. Cualquier solución final de este problema exige una estrecha colaboración internacional y también el apoyo económico de los países involucrados.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>