<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Use of lectins to characterise genetic variability and geographic differentiation in natural populations of Thunnus alalunga (Bonn. 1788)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Rodas, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrizabalaga, H. (Haritz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nieto, B. (Blanca)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Costas, E. (Eduardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:19:00Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:19:00Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002</dcterms:issued><dc:description>New tools from cell and molecular biology can be used to implement the knowledge of fish&#13;
biology and fisheries. In this sense, we suggest that the use of lectins can be an understandable&#13;
procedure to study population structure of fishes. Lectins are proteins or glycoproteins of nonimmune&#13;
origin that agglutinate cells and/or precipitate complex carbohydrates. Several lectins&#13;
behave like blood group antibodies and can be used as specific gene markers. We characterise&#13;
blood groups of Thunnus alalunga worldwide populations under a population genetics point of&#13;
view using lectins. Fishes from several populations of Mediterranean Sea, Atlantic, Pacific and&#13;
Indian Oceans were captured and 5 mL blood was obtained from each fish. Each fish was&#13;
treated with 8 FITC-labelled lectins. The binding activity of the lectins was detected using a&#13;
fluorescence assay. Several statistical procedures of populations genetics were employed to&#13;
analyse genetic variability, geographic differentiation, and genetic distance showing that: i)&#13;
there is genetic variability within Thunnus alalunga populations, ii) we detect highly&#13;
significant heterogeneity among populations, and considerable geographic differentiation, iii)&#13;
Mediterranean population is quite distant of North Atlantic population, iv) North and South&#13;
Atlantic populations are extremely distant, v) Pacific population is the most distant from the&#13;
others , vi) Gulf of Guinea and South Atlantic populations are distant, vii) Gulf of Guinea and&#13;
North Atlantic are proximate, viii) Indian and South Atlantic populations are also proximate.</dc:description><dc:description>De nouveaux moyens fournis par la biologie cellulaire et moléculaire peuvent servir à&#13;
appliquer les connaissances sur la biologie et la pêche du poisson. A cet égard, nous&#13;
suggérons que l'utilisation des lectines peut constituer un processus raisonnable pour étudier&#13;
la structure des stocks de poisson. Les lectines sont des protéines ou des glycoprotéines&#13;
d'origine non-immunitaire qui agglutinent les cellules et/ou précipitent les carbohydrates&#13;
complexes. Plusieurs lectines se comportent comme des anticorps de groupes sanguins et&#13;
peuvent servir de marqueurs génétiques spécifiques. Nous identifions les groupes sanguins des&#13;
populations globales de Thunnus alalunga du point de vue de la génétique des populations au&#13;
moyen de lectines. Des poissons de plusieurs stocks de la Méditerranée, de l'Atlantique, du&#13;
Pacifique et de l'océan Indien ont été capturés, et 5 ml de leur sang a été prélevé. Chacun de ces poissons a été traité avec des lectines dénommées 8 FITC. L'activité agglutinante des&#13;
lectines a été détectée au moyen de tests de fluorescence. Plusieurs processus statistiques de&#13;
génétique des populations ont été employées pour analyser la variabilité générique, la&#13;
différentiation géographique et l'écartement génétique, d'où: i) il existe une variabilité&#13;
génétique su sein des populations de Thunnus alalunga, ii) nous détectons un degré très&#13;
significatif d'hétérogénéité entre les populations, et une différentiation géographique&#13;
considérable, iii) la population méditerranéenne se démarque assez de la population nordatlantique,&#13;
iv) les populations du nord et du sud de l'Atlantique sont extrêmement distinctes, v)&#13;
la population du Pacifique est celle qui se différencie le plus des autres, vi) les populations du golfe de Guinée et de l'Atlantique sud sont distinctes, vii) les populations du golfe de Guinée et&#13;
de l'Atlantique nord sont proches, viii) les populations de l'océan Indien et de l'Atlantique sud&#13;
sont également proches.</dc:description><dc:description>Las nuevas herramientas de biología molecular y celular se pueden utilizar para implementar el&#13;
conocimiento de la biología de los peces y de la pesca. En este sentido, proponemos la utilización&#13;
de lectinas como procedimiento comprensible para estudiar la estructura de población de los&#13;
peces. Las lectinas son proteínas o glucoproteínas de origen no inmune que aglutinan células o&#13;
precipitan carbohidratos complejos. Muchas lectinas se comportan como anticuerpos de grupos&#13;
sanguíneos y pueden utilizarse como marcadores genéticos específicos. Hemos identificado grupos&#13;
sanguíneos de poblaciones de Thunnus alalunga de todo el mundo desde el punto de vista de&#13;
genética de poblaciones mediante lectinas. Se capturaron peces de varias poblaciones del mar&#13;
Mediterráneo y de los océanos Atlántico, Pacífico e Índico y se les extrajo 5 mL de sangre a cada&#13;
uno. Se trató a cada pez con lectinas marcadas con FITC 8. La actividad aglutinante de la lectina&#13;
se detectó utilizando fluorimetrías. Se emplearon varios procedimientos estadísticos de genética&#13;
de poblaciones para analizar la variabilidad genética, diferenciación geográfica y distancia&#13;
genética, que mostraron que: i) existe una variabilidad genética dentro de las poblaciones de&#13;
Thunnus alalunga; ii) detectamos una heterogeneidad muy significativa entre las poblaciones y&#13;
una considerable diferenciación geográfica; iii) la población mediterránea se distancia bastante&#13;
de la población del Atlántico Norte, iv) las poblaciones del Atlántico norte y sur son&#13;
extremadamente distantes; v) La población del Pacífico es la que presenta una mayor distancia&#13;
con respecto a las demás; vi) las poblaciones del Atlántico Sur y del Golfo de Guinea son&#13;
distantes; vii) las poblaciones del Golfo de Guinea y el Atlántico norte son próximas; viii) las poblaciones del Índico y el Atlántico sur también son próximas.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1660</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>López-Rodas, V., H. Arrizabalaga, B. Nieto, A. González-Garcés, E. Costas. 2002. Use of lectins to characterise genetic variability and geographic differentiation in natural populations of Thunnus alalunga (Bonn. 1788). Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 54 (5): 1495-1507.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>