<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Primeros resultados sobre la dieta de los jóvenes esturiones atlánticos Acipenser sturio L., 1758 en el estuario del Gironda</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Brosse, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lepage, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Dumont, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Alimentación</dc:subject><dc:subject>juveniles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Francia</dc:subject><dc:subject>fauna de invertebrados</dc:subject><dc:description>Very little is known about the diet of the European sturgeon Acipenser sturio L., 1758 in its natural environment. For juveniles, improved knowledge in this field could lead towards the determination of the species's major feeding habitats in the estuary, in order to then improve their preservation or protection. From May 1998 to March 1999, the stomach contents of 61 juveniles were collected by gastric lavage. The fish were caught during monthly trawling campaigns to monitor sturgeon migration in the Gironde estuary (southwestern France). Specimens were mainly caught during spring and summer in two areas of increased abundance. The gastric lavage method used had been previously tested on Siberian sturgeon Acipenser baerii Brandt, 1869 in captivity. Twelve taxa of prey were found. The highest proportions in number identified consisted of polychaetes, mainly represented by Heteromastus filiformis (Claparede, 1864) in zone 7 and Polydora Bosc, 1802 sp. in zone 1. Crustaceans were the second most abundant group of prey.</dc:description><dc:description>Se conoce muy poco sobre la dieta del esturión atlántico Acipenser sturio L., 1758 en su medio natural. Para los juveniles, un conocimiento mejorado en este campo podía conducir hacia la determinación de los principales hábitats alimentarios de la especie en el estuario, como preámbulo para su mejor preservación y conservación. Entre mayo de 1998 y marzo de 1999 fueron recogidos los contenidos estomacales de 61 juveniles por lavado gástrico. Los peces fueron capturados durante las campañas mensuales de pesca de arrastre para el seguimiento de la migración del esturión en el estuario del Gironda (suroeste de Francia). Los ejemplares fueron capturados principalmente en primavera y verano en dos áreas de alta abundancia. El método de lavado gástrico utilizado fue probado previamente en cautividad con esturión siberiano Acipenser baerii Brandt, 1869. Se encontraron presas de doce taxones. Las proporciones más altas en número correspondieron a poliquetos, principalmente representados por Heteromastus filiformis (Claparede, 1864) en la zona 7 y Polydora Bosc, 1802 sp. en la zona 1. Los crustáceos fueron el segundo grupo de presas más abundante.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1307</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>