<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">REPRODOTT Final Report (Reproduction of the Bluefin Tuna in Captivity -&#13;
feasibility study for the domestication of Thunnus thynnus)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Reprodott</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-01-11T09:28:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-11T09:28:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus thynnus</dc:subject><dc:subject>atún rojo</dc:subject><dc:subject>bluefin tuna</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproducción</dc:subject><dc:subject>acuicultura</dc:subject><dc:subject>aquaculture</dc:subject><dc:subject>spawning</dc:subject><dc:description>Informe final</dc:description><dc:description>In 2003 a 40-months-long research project supported by the European Commission, REPRODOTT (Q5RS-2002-01355), was initiated aimed at studying the feasibility to achieve reproduction of BFT in captivity conditions. The project draws on the exceptional opportunity to combine forces between an international group of scientists and commercial 'growing out' facilities for BFT to provide an in-depth study of the reproduction of BFT in captivity, thereby providing a strategic feasibility study for the domestication of this species. &#13;
&#13;
The controlled reproduction is a crucial step on the road to domesticating a wild species. The project studied the hormonal regulation on gonadal development, maturation of gametes, spawning and fecundity, and finally developed suitable methods to control the reproduction of the BFT. The availability of captive broodstock allowed an increase in knowledge from the input of reproductive cues to recruitment determinism in the wild. This will allow better management of the resource in a global sense. &#13;
&#13;
The overall objective of this project was to improve our understanding of the reproductive physiology of BFT as the basis to develop a suitable methodology for the control of its reproduction in captivity, in order to establish a sustainable aquaculture.&#13;
&#13;
Four main specific objectives of the project were:&#13;
&#13;
1) To improve the knowledge of the reproductive biology of the species in captivity and compare this with wild populations, in order to develop an aquaculture farming technology for the BFT&#13;
&#13;
2) To assess the capability of BFT broodstock to mature and spawn in captivity&#13;
&#13;
3) To obtain viable eggs from BFT breeders and bring them to hatching must be assessed and found to be feasible&#13;
&#13;
4) To develop handling techniques for routine operations in BFT aquaculture, including setting up safe and effective anaesthesia procedures, designing adequate transportation systems for live fish, developing egg collection devices for cage-reared BFT, and employing non-invasive methods for the assessment of BFT sex and maturation status.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
Main results&#13;
&#13;
1) Has improved our knowledge of the Reproductive Biology of Atlantic bluefin tuna (BFT), Thunnus thynnus thynnus, both in captive and under wild conditions, throughout the Mediterranean area.&#13;
&#13;
a) An extensive database has been generated from the BFT populations studied composed of biometric indices, histological features of the gonads, levels of reproductive hormones, characteristics of gametes and stress parameters.  Thus, providing the necessary basis to characterize the reproductive biology of BFT and their performance in wild and captive conditions.&#13;
&#13;
b) New tools and procedures have been developed that may facilitate further in depth  studies on  BFT reproduction&#13;
&#13;
2) Assessed the capability of captive BFT broodstock to mature and spawn in captivity.&#13;
&#13;
Several behavioral studies, histological and hormonal analyses carried out in two consecutive years on the reproductive status of captive breeders, kept in floating cage for over two years, have produced consistent results, which clearly indicate that BFT are able to mature and spawn in captive conditions.    &#13;
&#13;
3) Assessed the feasibility of obtaining viable eggs from BFT breeders and brought them to hatching.&#13;
&#13;
The development of a suitable hormonal delivery system and its implantation procedure, and the lessons acquired after two years of attempts to control the BFT reproductions have resulted in the successful production of eggs, which were then brought to hatching. &#13;
&#13;
4) Developed handling techniques for routine operations in BFT aquaculture&#13;
&#13;
Some progresses was made in the setting up of anesthesia procedures, transportation systems, the design of egg collectors for rearing cages, employment of non-invasive techniques for sex and maturity assessment, and for conducting behavioral studies through echo-sounding and data logger tagging.&#13;
&#13;
Benefit- beneficiairies&#13;
&#13;
REPRODOTT’s results might serve as a scientific support to policies, be of help to solve some environmental concerns regarding the survival of BFT populations in the Mediterranean, contributes to the sustainability of the tuna farming industry, and last but not least be of interest and with applicability to scientist, mainly fish physiologists and particularly those working with BFT.&#13;
 &#13;
The project deals with several aspects concerning the Common Fisheries Policy. Particularly conservation and management of fisheries stock, aquaculture, environment, food hygiene and socio-economics issues. It is expected that the outputs of the project can contribute to the implementation of the EU common Fishery Policy and be of help for the compliance of its regulations. In particular, by providing with scientific and technical advice for updating and improving the actual legislation concerning the sustainable exploitation of this highly migratory finfish species. Thus, the extensive data base generated by the project with biological information about BFT brood stock at different location throughout the Mediterranean basin might be of interest not only because of its scientific value, but also for management and conservation purposes&#13;
&#13;
REPRODOTT has demonstrated that BFT is able to mature and spawn in captivity and also is feasible to obtain viable eggs and sperm for successful fertilization and consequently larvae. This, in turn, is the first step at controlling the whole life cycle of this species in captivity and for a future mass rearing of the species, as happens in other marine finfish aquaculture species such as seabass and seabreams. The first time ever successful used of hormonal induction of BFT and the acquisition of viable eggs and larvae can be considered as a major scientific breakthrough that might contributes to the development of a real self-sustained BFT aquaculture industry in the Mediterranean.  &#13;
&#13;
	Furthermore, the project consortium are convinced that this result represents one of the last chances to save the species by establishing the possibility of raising domesticated fish in captivity which in turns allow the regulation of tuna fishing intensity to manage the endangered wild stocks for the share benefits of future generations. Moreover, potential supply of larvae may provide biological material for future needs in understanding BFT biology.&#13;
&#13;
Scientists working on fish physiology, particularly those on BFT; as well as aquaculturists can also benefit from the suitable handling procedures developed for BFT. Apart from that, very useful tools have been developed for fish reproduction studies that could be later used for other scientists working on reproductive physiology on the same species or use a model for other finfish species. Moreover, the production of a suitable hormonal implant for inducing spawning of BFT might have applicability to other tuna species and large marine finfish.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Anon (2007). REPRODOTT Final Report (Reproduction of the Bluefin Tuna in Captivity - feasibility study for the domestication of Thunnus thynnus). 220 pp.</dc:identifier><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>