<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Cultivo de almeja japonesa Ruditapes philippinarum (Adamsampersand Reeve, 1850) a altas densidades de siembra y en zona intermareal</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Royo, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Quintero, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hurtado Burgos, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hurtado Cancelo, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:15Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:15Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Cobertura mareal</dc:subject><dc:subject>crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>mortalidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>almeja</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes philippinarum</dc:subject><dc:description>Growth and mortality were estimated in the culture of Manila seed clams Ruditapes philippinarum (Adamsampersand Reeve, 1850) from a hatchery. The culture was been carried out in two 1.50 m x 26.00 m plots, located between higher water (HLW) and lower low water (LLW) in an intertidal zone, at densities from 1 000 to 1 500 indiv/m².  Statistical analysis indicates that growth was not homogenous after a year, for the 1 000 and 1 500 indiv/ m² densities; the inter-individual differences found for these two extremes were 23.69 and 8.51 %, respectively. However, no significant differences in total growth were found for these two densities. Our results indicate that the intertidal zone could be more effectively used for the culture of this species.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ha estimado el crecimiento y la mortalidad en un cultivo de almeja japonesa Ruditapes philippinarum (Adamsampersand Reeve, 1850) con semilla procedente de criadero. El cultivo se ha llevado a cabo en dos calles paralelas de 1,50 m x 26,00 m situadas en la zona intermareal, perpendicularmente a la orilla, en niveles comprendidos entre los de bajamar de marea viva y bajamar de marea muerta, a densidades de 1 000 y 1 500 indiv/m².  El análisis estadístico pone de manifiesto que, transcurrido un año, el crecimiento no ha sido homogéneo, y entre los dos extremos de las calles de cultivo las diferencias fueron de 23,69 y 8,51 % para las densidades 1 000 y 1 500 indiv/m², respectivamente. Sin embargo, no se aprecian diferencias significativas en el crecimiento general en ambas densidades. Los resultados estimados justifican un mejor aprovechamiento de la zona intermareal para el cultivo de este tipo de almejas.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>