<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Mortalidad embrionaria por canibalismo en la anchoíta argentina Engraulis anchoita Hubbs y Marini, 1935</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pájaro, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez, R. P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Aubone, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:32Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:32Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Canibalismo</dc:subject><dc:subject>anchoíta argentina</dc:subject><dc:subject>Engraulis anchoita</dc:subject><dc:subject>huevos</dc:subject><dc:subject>depredación</dc:subject><dc:subject>zooplancton</dc:subject><dc:description>The Argentine anchovy Engraulis anchoita Hubbs and Marini, 1935, is, in terms of biomass, the greatest fish resource in the Southwest Atlantic. It plays a key role in the Argentine fisheries as trophic support for several commercially exploited species. Argentine anchovy migrate to their coastal spawning grounds during spring and summer; and at least two populations co-exist in the spawning- area: the northern, or Buenos Aires, population (from 33° LS to -41° LS) and the southern, or Patagonian, population (from 41° LS to -48° LS). From a trophic standpoint, this a poor habitat for such a large number of anchovies, and copepods predominate amont their prey organisms to findings from our analysis of stomach contents.  No relationship was found between consumption and density of plankton eggs; however, in the northern population, there was evidence of an increase in cannibalism as mezooplancton density decreased. Regarding the number of eggs ingested, we estimated a mean value of 10.0 eggs/fish (standard desviation: 5.04) and 0.8 (s.d.: 0.44) eggs/fish (s.d.e.: = 0.44) for the Buenos Aires and Patagonian populations, respectively. The mean number of anchovy eggs per stomach was 14.1 (s.d. 7.9) for nocturnal samples and 1.0 (s.d.: 0.4) for daytime samples. Consumption of eggs over a 12 h feeding period was estimated to have caused 27 % of the total eggs mortality for the Buenos Aires stock and 1-2 % for the Patagonian stock. Our results indicate that intraespecific predation on eggs by anchovy adults represents a high percentage of the total embryonic mortality, especially in areas where other food resources are scarce.</dc:description><dc:description>La anchoíta argentina Engraulis anchoita Hubbs y Marini, 1935, el recurso pesquero de mayor biomasa del Atlántico sudoccidental, constituye una especie clave en el ecosistema pesquero del Mar Argentino como alimento de varias especies explotadas comercialmente. La anchoíta migra al hábitat costero en primavera, donde se lleva a cabo la puesta. Dos poblaciones, al menos, habitan el área reproductiva en esa época del año: la población bonaerense (33°-41° S) Y la población patagónica (41°-48° S).  Desde el punto de vista trófico, dicho hábitat es pobre para los numerosos cardúmenes de anchoíta, con predominio de los copépodos entre los organismos presa, observación que también puso de manifiesto el análisis de los contenidos estomacales.  No se encontró una relación entre el número de huevos consumidos y la densidad de huevos en el plancton, aunque sí se hallaron, en la población bonaerense, evidencias del aumento del canibalismo junto con la disminución en la densidad de mesozooplancton.  En cuanto al número de huevos ingeridos por canibalismo, se determinaron valores medios de 10,0 (desviación estándar: 5,04) y 0,8 huevos/pez (d. e.: 0,44) para las poblaciones bonaerense y patagónica respectivamente. Por otra parte el canibalismo se produjo principalmente en horas diurnas, con. 14,1 huevos/pez (d. e.: 7,9) frente a 1,0 (d.e.: 0,4) para las horas nocturnas. La mortalidad embrionaria natural diaria por canibalismo, considerando un periodo de alimentación de 12 horas, fue de 27 % para la población bonaerense y de 1-2 % para la población patagónica.  Los resultados obtenidos permiten concluir que la depredación intraespecífica sobre los estadios embrionarios de la anchoíta argentina puede llegar a representar un porcentaje importante de la mortalidad natural embrionaria total, especialmente en zonas con escaso alimento disponible.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1417</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1998. 14 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>