<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="fra">Commentaires sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus Alalunga) Nord- Atlantique</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Antoine, L. (Loïc)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T09:21:34Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T09:21:34Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1982</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This document updates the catch and effort data by  age classes of the Spanish and French &#13;
surface fisheries.  Recruitment indices are discussed; recruitment was calculated by using &#13;
cohort analyses and its relation with a parental stock indicator is also updated. The conclusicn is that the state of the North Atlantic stock is disturbing.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document met à jour les données d'effort et de capture par classe d'âge des pêcheries de surface espagnole et française. Les indices de recrutement sont &#13;
commentés; le recrutement a été calculé au moyen d'analyses de cohorte, et sa relation avec un &#13;
indicateur du stock parental est remise à jour. La conclusion&#13;
est que l'état du stock nord-atlantique ne semble pas inspirer d'inquiétude.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento actualiza los datos de esfuerzo y captura, por clases de edad, de las pesquerias de superficie españolas y francesas. Se comentan los indices de reclutamiento, calculados por medio del análisis de cohortes y se actualiza su relación con un &#13;
índice del stock de adultos. Se llega a la conclusión de que la situación del stock del Atlántico Norte no parece inspirar inquietud.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Antoine, L., A. González-Garcés. 1982. Commentaires sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus Alalunga) Nord- Atlantique . Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 17 (2): 263-268</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>