<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Vertical distribution of fish larvae in the Canaries-African coastal transition zone, in summer</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, J.M</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández León, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barton, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2012-12-10T13:43:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-12-10T13:43:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-12-10</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Fish larvae</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vertical distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>African coastal transition zone</dc:subject><dc:subject>NW African upwelling</dc:subject><dc:description>13 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables.-- Printed version published Jul 2006.</dc:description><dc:description>This study reports the vertical distribution of fish larvae during the 1999 summer upwelling season in the Canaries-African Coastal Transition Zone (the Canaries-ACTZ). The transition between the African coastal upwelling and the typical subtropical offshore conditions is a region of intense mesoscale activity that supports a larval fish population dominated by African neritic species. During the study, the thermal stratification extended almost to the surface everywhere, and the surface mixed layer was typically shallow or non-existent. Upwelling occurred on the African shelf in a limited coastal sub-area of our sampling. The vertical distributions of the entire larval fish population, as well as of individual species, were independent of the seasonal thermocline. Fish larvae and mesozooplankton were concentrated at intermediate depths regardless of the thermocline position, probably because of its weak signature and spatial and temporal variability. Day/night vertical distributions suggest that some species did not perform diel vertical migration (DVM), whereas others showed either type I DVM or type II DVM. The opposing DVM patterns of different species compensate for each other resulting in no net DVM for the larval fish population as a whole.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0025-3162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1000</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodriguez, J.M., Hernandez-Leon, S., Barton, E.D., 2006. Vertical distribution of fish larvae in the Canaries-African coastal transition zone in summer. Marine Biology 149(4), 885-897</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>