<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">The Integrated Assessment as the main goal for achieving an Ecosystem Approach to Management in the Western European Shelf Seas</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Andonegi, E. (Eider)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Beggs, S. (Steven)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Borges, M.F. (Maria Fatima)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Laffargue, P. (Pascal)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Llope, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Reid, D. (Dave)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-23T13:32:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-23T13:32:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-15</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Providing regional integrated ecosystem assessments (IEA) is a key challenge identified in the ICES Strategic Plan (2014-2018). IEAs are seen as a fundamental link between advice and ecosystem science inachieving Ecosystem Based Management (EBM).While EBM is not a new concept, difficulties in achieving such an ambitious goal have been highlighted by the extensive work conducted in this area. The implementation of new regulation policies, such as the Marine Strategy Framework Directive (MSFD) and the reformed Common Fisheries Policy (CFP) in Europe,have challenged the scientific community to rapidly react  despite these difficulties and provide scientific advice to support management decisions concerning these policies.&#13;
RegionalICES groups have been tasked with developing methods and tools for IEA in their corresponding ecoregions; this is the case of the Working Group on Ecosystem Assessment of Western European Shelf Seas (WGEAWESS). The role of this group is to implement, and test tools and methods for the advisory process, focusing on the North Atlantic European continental shelf, including Celtic Seas, Bay of Biscay and Iberian Waters.   &#13;
In this presentation we show the progress made within this WG during its initial three years of activity, in relation to some of the terms of reference already addressed. An adaptation of the ODEMM framework has been selected as a tool for identifying a) links between components, processes, pressures and states, and b) gaps in data availability and indicator implementation. Some preliminary results of a first IEA exercise will also been shownwith emphasis onthe MSFD descriptors D1 (biological diversity) and D4 (food webs).</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES Annual Science Conference 2014. (15/09/2014 - 19/09/2014. A Coruña (Spain)). 2014. ICES CM 2014/3940 C:05. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES CM 2014/3940 C:05</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20192</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>