<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Length Distributions and Recruitment Index of Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis) in Flemish Cap (Division 3M) in 1993-1998, as Inferred from Stomach Contents Analysis of Cod (Gadus morhua), Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides) and Thorny Skate (Raja radiata)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Marín, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Río-Iglesias, J.L. (José Luis) del</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-10T09:42:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-10T09:42:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1999</dcterms:issued><dc:description>From stomachs of cod (Gadus morhua), Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides) and thorny skate&#13;
(Raja radiata) sampled in the fishing surveys carried out in Flemish Cap in July from 1993 to 1998, the importance&#13;
in diet, predator-prey relationship and length frequency of northern shrimp (Pandalus borealis) were evaluated.&#13;
These three species prey on different lengths of northern shrimp as a function of their feeding habits and the overlap&#13;
in their ranges of vertical distribution with that of their prey. The ability of these predators to sample different sizes&#13;
of northern shrimp allows the observation of the annual progression of strong year classes of this prey and the&#13;
estimate of its recruitment at age 2 from its frequency of occurrence in cod stomach contents from 1989 to 1997.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1694</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodríguez Marín, E., J.L. del Río. 1999. Length Distributions and Recruitment Index of Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis) in Flemish Cap (Division 3M) in 1993-1998, as Inferred from Stomach Contents Analysis of Cod (Gadus morhua), Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides) and Thorny Skate (Raja radiata). NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 99/73, Serial Nº N4144: 14p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>