<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A preliminary examination of differential survey trends in recent years between the Canadian Spring and EU-Spain surveys for 3NO cod</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rideout, R. (Rick)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Troncoso, D.M. (Diana María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Costas, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Morgan, J. (Joanne)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-17T13:43:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-17T13:43:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Results of the EU-Spain survey in Divs. 3NO are not used as input to the current ADAPT assessment model for 3NO cod but make an interesting comparison to the Canadian Spring survey since they occur at approximately the same time of year. The two surveys exhibit differences in both abundance and biomass trends in recent years, with the EU-Spain survey results indicating some relatively strong signs of stock growth since 2007 but the Canadian spring survey showing little to no sign of stock growth. Results did not change when analyses of the Canadian survey were restricted only to strata located all or partially within the NRA. An examination of distribution plots for the two surveys suggests that a lower density of fishing sets in the NRA by the Canadian Spring survey relative to the EU-Spain survey might be at least partially responsible for the differential trends between the two survey time series in recent years. However, because the EU-Spain survey covers only a small portion of the stock area, the observed trends for this survey can not be considered indicative of the entire stock. Differences in the length distribution of the catches were also evident in some years.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1723</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rideout, R.M., D. González-Troncoso, F. González-Costas, M.J. Morgan. 2013. A preliminary examination of differential survey trends in recent years between the Canadian Spring and EU-Spain surveys for 3NO cod. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 13/043, Serial Nº N6198: 11p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>