<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Assessing the responses of exploited marine populations in a context of rapid climate change: the case of blackspot seabream from Strait of Gibraltar.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Báez, J.C. (José Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías-López, A.D. (Ángel David)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Castro de, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez-Gesteira, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gimeno, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Real, R</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:31:56Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:31:56Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Arctic Oscillation, Blackspot seabream, Climate, Fisheries collapse, North Atlantic Oscillation,</dc:subject><dc:description>Assessing the response of exploited marine populations in a context of rapid climate change: the case of&#13;
blackspot seabream from the Strait of Gibraltar.—&#13;
There is a growing concern over the decline of fisheries and&#13;
the possibility of the decline becoming worse due to climate change. Studies on&#13;
small–scale fisheries&#13;
could help&#13;
to improve our understanding of the effect of climate on the ecology of exploited stocks. The Strait of Gibraltar&#13;
is an important fishery ground for artisanal fleets.&#13;
In this area, b&#13;
lackspot seabream (&#13;
Pagellus bogaraveo&#13;
) is&#13;
the main species targeted by artisanal fisheries&#13;
in view of its relevance in landed weight.&#13;
The aims of this&#13;
study were to explore the possible effects of two atmospheric oscillations, the North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO)&#13;
and the Arctic Oscillation (AO), on the capture of blackspot seabream in the Strait of Gibraltar, to determine&#13;
their association with oceanographic conditions, and to improve our knowledge about the possible effects of&#13;
climate change on fisheries ecology so that fishery management can be improved. We used two types of data&#13;
from different sources: (i) landings per unit of effort reported from a second working group between Morocco&#13;
and Spain on&#13;
Pagellus bogaraveo&#13;
in the Gibraltar Strait area,&#13;
for the period 1983–2011&#13;
, and (ii) the recorded&#13;
blackspot seabream landings obtained from the annual fisheries statistics published by the&#13;
Junta de Andalucía&#13;
(Andalusian Regional Government). Our results indicate that the long–term landing of blackspot seabream in&#13;
the Strait of Gibraltar is closely associated with atmospheric oscillations. Thus, prolonged periods of positive&#13;
trends in the NAO and AO could favour high fishery yields. In contrast, negative trends in NAO and AO could&#13;
drastically reduce yield.</dc:description><dc:identifier>1578-665X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Animal Biodiversity and Conservation, 37(1). 2014: 1-13</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20324</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>