<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Larval growth and development of the smooth clam Callista chione (Mollusca: Bivalvia) under laboratory conditions</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez-Larruscain, J. (Josu)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Fernández, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gairín, J.I. (Joan Ignasi)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T11:37:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T11:37:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2011</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Callista chione</dc:subject><dc:subject>development</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>larvae</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:description>This study describes the first data on larval development and growth of the smooth clam Callista chione under two different temperature regimes (19 and 23 ºC). The mean diameter of the oocytes was 89.5 ± 0.7 µm. After seven days, the mean length of D-shaped larvae was 132.9 ± 7.8 µm at 19 ºC and 148.38 ± 12.74 µm at 23 ºC. Metamorphosis took place between days 32 and 39. Differences in length associated with different culture temperatures were statistically significant on days 11, 13, and 20. At 23 ºC, larvae reached a length of 175.15 µm within 11 days, whilst during the same period they reached 137.88 µm at 19 ºC (a difference in growth of 39%); however, survival rate was higher at 19 ºC (8%) than at 23 ºC (2%).</dc:description><dc:description>Este trabajo describe los primeros datos sobre el desarrollo y el crecimiento larvario del almejón de sangre Callista chione bajo dos regímenes diferentes de temperatura (19 y 23 ºC). El diámetro medio de los ovocitos observado fue de 89.5 ± 0.7 µm. Después de siete días, el tamaño medio de las larvas D fue de 132.9 ± 7.8 µm a 19 ºC y 148.38 ± 12.74 µm a 23 ºC. La metamorfosis se llevó a cabo entre los días 32 y 39. Las diferencias de longitud asociadas a las diferentes temperaturas de cultivo fueron estadísticamente significativas en los días 11, 13 y 20. A 23 ºC las larvas alcanzaron una longitud de 175.15 µm a los 11 días, mientras que durante el mismo periodo alcanzaron 137.88 µm a 19 ºC (una diferencia en el crecimiento de 39%); sin embargo, la tasa de supervivencia fue mayor a 19 ºC (8%) que a 23 ºC (2%).</dc:description><dc:identifier>DOI 10.7773/cm.v37i3.1902</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Ciencias Marinas (2011), 37(3): 271-277</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>