<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Spawning biomass variation in Atlantic Cod (Gadus morhua) in Flemish Cap in Relation to Changes in Growth and Maturation</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Saborido-Rey, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Junquera, S. (Susana)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-14T09:04:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-14T09:04:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1999</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>biomass</dc:subject><dc:subject>cod</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flemish Cap</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>maturity</dc:subject><dc:description>Drastic changes in both age- and length-at-maturity of cod (Gadus morhua) on Flemish&#13;
Cap have been observed during this decade. In the present paper, growth by cohort in this&#13;
period was analyzed and compared with the observed trend in maturation. Different cohorts&#13;
displayed different growth rates, the strongest 1990 year-class showing fastest growth.&#13;
The compensatory response to lower population density alone did not explain the decline&#13;
in both age- and size-at-maturity. Strong changes in fishing pressure during the period&#13;
could have provoked a size-selectivity for early maturity, i.e. genetic selection. An estimate&#13;
of the spawning biomass, accounting for the corresponding size-at-age distributions, on a&#13;
cohort basis is given. The influence of changes in spawning biomass and spawning stock&#13;
biomass age structure on the probability of future stock rebuilding is also discussed. It is&#13;
shown a low spawning biomass composed of young and recruited females will hardly&#13;
rebuild the stock to historical levels.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1706</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Saborido-Rey, F., S. Junquera. 1999. Spawning biomass variation in Atlantic Cod (Gadus morhua) in Flemish Cap in Relation to Changes in Growth and Maturation. J. Northw. Atl. Fish. Sci., vol. 25: 83-90</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>