<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="fra">Considerations sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus alalunga) de l'Atlantique Nord, d'apres les données des flotilles franco-espagnoles</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Antoine, L. (Loïc)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T08:44:05Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T08:44:05Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1983</dcterms:issued><dc:description>During the last ten years, fishing effort of Spanish baitboats has remained relatively constant. &#13;
Effort of Spanish trollers seems to have stabilized for the last six years after naving decreased; &#13;
French trollers show a distinct decrease in&#13;
effort in the iast four years.  Although not showing as clear a decrease as in 1975, the CPUE is nevertheless decreasing after the peak reached in 1979. &#13;
Recruitment indices have also been decreasing since 1979. A change in the availability of the fish, &#13;
due to certain hydrologic conditions, could be the&#13;
reason for this decrease, as well as a true decrease in recruitment.  Nevertheless, the stock does not seem to be in danger.</dc:description><dc:description>Au cours des dernières années,  l'effort de  pêche des canneurs espagnols est resté relativement constant. Celui des ligneurs espagnols semble stabilisé &#13;
depuis six ans après avoir baissé; les ligneurs français montrent une nette diminution de leur &#13;
effort depuis quatre ans. Sans montrer un fléchissement aussi net qu'en 1975, la PUE est dependant &#13;
en diminution depuis&#13;
le maximum atteint en 1979. Les   indices du recrutement   sont également en diminution &#13;
depuis 1979. Une modification de la disponibilité des poissons, due à des conditions hydrologiques &#13;
particulières pourrait en être la raison, autant qu'une baisse réelle du recrutement. Néanmoins, le &#13;
stock ne semble pas en danger.</dc:description><dc:description>El esfuerzo de pesca de los barcos españoles de cebo, ha permanecido  relativamente  constante &#13;
durante  los diez. últimos años. El correspondiente a los barcos  españoles  de curricán, parece   &#13;
estar   estabilizado después de seis años de haberse producido  una disminución.  Los barcos  &#13;
franceses de curricán muestran un claro descenso de su esfuerzo desde hace cuatro años. Sin &#13;
mostrar una disminución tan clara como en 197S, la CPUE está, sin embargo, en descenso desde la &#13;
cota máxima alcanzada  en  1979.  Los  índices de reclutamiento   se encuentran en  disminución desde 1979. Esta situación podría deberse a una modificación de la disponibilidad de &#13;
los peces, derivada de condiciones hidrológicas  especiales, así como de una disminución real &#13;
del reclutamiento.  Sin embargo, el stock no parece encontrarse&#13;
en peligro.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1653</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Antoine, L., A. G. Garcés. 1983. Considerations sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus alalunga) de l'Atlantique Nord, d'apres les données des flotilles franco-espagnoles. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 18 (2): 411-420</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>