<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Glucógeno sintasa del tejido del manto de Mytilus galloprovincialis Lamarck, 1819</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz Muñoz, Y.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Suárez Alonso, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>San Juan Serrano, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:15Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:15Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007-08-30T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucógeno sintasa</dc:subject><dc:subject>características cinéticas</dc:subject><dc:description>Glycogen synthase (GS) from Mytilus galloprovincialis Lamarck, 1819 mantle tissue is primarily in G6P-dependent form, whose activity is four times that of the G6P-independent form. Both forms present higher activity to pH: 7, but the D-form mantains 60 % of its maximum activity at extreme pH values, whereas that of the I-form drops to 25 %. The optimum temperature is 30-35 ºC for both forms, but the I-form is more stable between 30 and 40 ºC. Kinetic data on both enzymatic forms indicate the existence of cooperative effects with regard to the substrate and effector. The I-form affinity constant for the substrate UDPG is 1.9-2.3 mM and that of the D-form is 0.9-1.3 mM. Moreover, the D-form shows an activation constant for the efector G6P of 5.2-5.6 mM.</dc:description><dc:description>La enzima glucógeno sintasa del tejido del manto de Mytilus galloprovincialis Lamarck, 1819 se encuentra principalmente en su forma dependiente (D) de G6P, con una actividad cuatro veces mayor que la forma independiente (I) de G6P. Ambas formas presentan la mayor actividad a pH:7, pero la forma D mantiene el 60 % de su actividad a valores extremos de pH, donde la forma I disminuye la suya al 25 %. La temperatura óptima está entre 30 y 35 ºC en ambos casos, pero la forma I es más estable entre 30 y 40 ºC. Los datos cinéticos de ambas formas enzimáticas indican la existencia de efectos cooperativos respecto al sustrato y el efector. La constante de afinidad de la forma I para el sustrato UDPG es 1,9-2,3 mM y la de la D es 0,9-1,3 mM. La forma D muestra, además, una constante de activación de 5,2-5,6 mM para el efector G6P.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2007. 23 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>