<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Engorde de pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797 en jaulas flotantes alimentado exclusivamente con boga Boops boops (L., 1758) de descarte de la acuicultura</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Socorro, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Roo, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-López, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Guirao, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Reyes, T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Palacios, H.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Izquierdo, M. S.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Jaulas</dc:subject><dc:subject>cefalópodos</dc:subject><dc:subject>engorde de pulpo</dc:subject><dc:subject>alimentación</dc:subject><dc:description>The first two experiences of ongrowing the octopus Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797, fed solely on fish of low commercial value, such as discarded bogue Boops boops (L., 1758) accidentally reared in seabream Sparus aurata L., 1758 culture cages, were carried out in the Canary Islands. The present study was made in a floating cage of galvanized mesh, divided vertically into two semi-cages. In a first experiment, individuals of two different initial average sizes were compared: 1.5 kg and 2.3 kg, both stocked at a density of 11 kg/m³. They were reared for 57 days, obtaining octopus of 2.643 kg from the 1.5 kg group, and of 3.812 kg from the 2.3 kg group. The survival rate was 91 % for the initially smaller group, and 82 % for the larger group. Density of individuals was increased in a second experience, in which the initial sizes were smaller, 1.0 kg and 0.8 kg, in each semi-cage. This second experience was carried out for 81 days, and the final weight of the octopus was 3.111 kg for the 1 kg group and 3.052 kg for the 0.8 kg group, with a survival rate of 44 % for the former and 50 % for the latter. The use of bogue as a single feed was found to be enough to sustain good growth in octopus cage rearing. Best results in terms of specific growth rate and average daily growth were obtained in the lowest size group, 0.8 kg of initial weight, with a SGR of 1.65 %, whereas the smallest rates of growth (SGR of 0.86 %) were in octopus of 2.337 kg of initial weight.</dc:description><dc:description>Las dos primeras experiencias de engorde de pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797 utilizando como único alimento peces de bajo valor comercial, como boga Boops boops (L., 1758), introducidos accidentalmente en las jaulas de engorde de dorada Sparus aurata L., 1758, se llevaron a cabo en las islas Canarias. El estudio se realizó en una jaula flotante de malla galvanizada, dividida verticalmente en dos mitades. En una primera experiencia se engordaron ejemplares con tamaños medios iniciales diferentes, 1,5 kg y 2,3 kg, en ambos casos a la densidad de 11 kg/m³. El engorde se realizó durante 57 días, obteniéndose al final individuos de 2,64 kg y 3,81 kg, respectivamente, con supervivencias del 91 % y el 82 %, también respectivamente. La densidad inicial fue incrementada en una segunda experiencia, donde se partió de tamaños inferiores a 1,0 kg y 0,8 kg en las semijaulas y que se prolongó durante 81 días; en ella, los pulpos alcanzaron un peso final de 3,11 kg y 3,05 kg, con una supervivencia del 44 y 50 %, respectivamente. La utilización de boga de descarte de acuicultura como único alimento en jaulas de engorde de pulpo parece proporcionar un buen crecimiento a este molusco. Los mejores resultados en términos de crecimiento específico (SGR) y crecimiento diario (IPD) fueron obtenidos en los ejemplares de menor tamaño inicial (0,8 kg), con un SGR de 1,65 %, mientras que las menores tasas de SGR (0,86 %) se registraron en ejemplares mayores de 2,34 kg de peso inicial.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1391</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>