<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Comparative cryopreservation study of trochophore larvae from two species of bivalves: Pacific oyster (Crassostrea gigas) and Blue mussel (Mytilus galloprovincialis)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Paredes, E. (Estefanía)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bellas-Bereijo, J.D. (Juan Domingo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Adams, S.L. (Serean)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:50:05Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:50:05Z</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Oysters and mussels are among the most farmed species in aquaculture industry around the world. The aim of this study was to test the toxicity of cryoprotective agents to trochophore larvae from two different species of bivalves and develop an improved cryopreservation protocol to ensure greater efficiency in the development of cryopreserved trochophores (14 h old oyster larvae and 20 h old mussel larvae) to normal D-larvae for future developments of hatchery spat production. The cryopreservation protocol producing the best results for oyster trochophores (60.0 ± 6.7% normal D-larvae) was obtained by holding at 0 °C for 5 min then cooling at 1 °C min(-1) to -10 °C and holding for 5 min before cooling at 0.5 °C to -35 °C, holding 5 min and then plunging into liquid nitrogen (LN), using 10% ethylene glycol. For mussel experiments, no significant differences were found when cooling at 0.5 °C min(-1) or at 1 °C min(-1) for CPA combinations with 10% ethylene glycol and at 0.5 °C min(-1). Using these combinations, around half of trochophores were able to develop to normal D-larvae post-thawing (48.9 ± 7.6% normal D-larvae).</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1855</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Cryobiology, 67, 3. 2014: 274-279</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cryobiol.2013.08.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>6517</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>