<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A Preliminary Investigation of the Efficiency of Canadian and Spanish Survey Bottom Trawls on the Southern Grand Bank</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Walsh, S.J. (Stephen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Paz, X. (Xabier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Durán-Muñoz, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-10-31T09:24:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-10-31T09:24:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-06</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Preliminary analysis of the capture efficiency of the bottom trawls used by Canada and Spain in surveys of the&#13;
Grand Bank was conducted using a variant of the logistic model to analyse a series of comparative fishing data.&#13;
Within the Canadian comparative data of the old and new survey trawls, the new survey trawl was less efficient for&#13;
larger cod and yellowtail flounder but not so for American plaice. However, there is some uncertainty in capture&#13;
probability for larger fish because of a sparse catches in the data. The Spanish survey trawl is more efficient than the&#13;
new Canadian survey trawl because of the use of longer sweep lines, which increase catchability in plaice and&#13;
yellowtail flounder. The logistic model did not fit the data well, in particular for yellowtail flounder. Further analysis&#13;
is suggested which may offer more insight into modelling and interpretation of the capture efficiency of these survey&#13;
trawls.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1573</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Walsh, Stephen J. et al. 2001. A Preliminary Investigation of the Efficiency of Canadian and Spanish Survey Bottom Trawls on the Southern Grand Bank. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 01/74, Serial Nº N4453: 18p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>