<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Interspecific Introgression in Cetaceans: DNA Markers Reveal Post-F1 Status of a Pilot Whale</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Miralles, L. (Laura)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lens-Lourido, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Folgar, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Carrillo, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín, V. (Vidal)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mikkelsen, B. (Bjarni)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Vázquez, E. (Eva)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-10-07T09:01:16Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-10-07T09:01:16Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-19</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Visual species identification of cetacean strandings is difficult, especially when dead specimens are degraded and/or species&#13;
are morphologically similar. The two recognised pilot whale species (Globicephala melas and Globicephala macrorhynchus)&#13;
are sympatric in the North Atlantic Ocean. These species are very similar in external appearance and their morphometric&#13;
characteristics partially overlap; thus visual identification is not always reliable. Genetic species identification ensures correct&#13;
identification of specimens. Here we have employed one mitochondrial (D-Loop region) and eight nuclear loci&#13;
(microsatellites) as genetic markers to identify six stranded pilot whales found in Galicia (Northwest Spain), one of them of&#13;
ambiguous phenotype. DNA analyses yielded positive amplification of all loci and enabled species identification. Nuclear&#13;
microsatellite DNA genotypes revealed mixed ancestry for one individual, identified as a post-F1 interspecific hybrid&#13;
employing two different Bayesian methods. From the mitochondrial sequence the maternal species was Globicephala melas.&#13;
This is the first hybrid documented between Globicephala melas and G. macrorhynchus, and the first post-F1 hybrid&#13;
genetically identified between cetaceans, revealing interspecific genetic introgression in marine mammals. We propose to&#13;
add nuclear loci to genetic databases for cetacean species identification in order to detect hybrid individuals.</dc:description><dc:identifier>doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0069511</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1556</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Miralles L, Lens S, Rodrı´guez-Folgar A, Carrillo M, Martı´n V, et al. (2013) Interspecific Introgression in Cetaceans: DNA Markers Reveal Post-F1 Status of a Pilot Whale. PLoS ONE 8(8): e69511. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0069511</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>