<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Diagénesis temprana en carbonatos biogénicos de aguas someras y templadas (bahía de Cádiz y plataforma continental adyacente)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Santos, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Calle, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López Tirado, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gutiérrez-Mas, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Bastero, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago-Duport, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Carbonatos biogénicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>neomorfismo</dc:subject><dc:subject>minerales autigénicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>ambientes diagenéticos</dc:subject><dc:description>Because of the chemical reactivity of biogenic carbonates in shallow waters, there is increasing interest in those early diagenesis processes that imply an alteration or variation of the composition of original material. This paper presents the preliminary results of a study concerning the compositional variations that have taken place in the skeletons or skeletal remains of bryozoans and echinoids. This variation, which includes an aragonite-calcite transformation, has been checked by means of the Rietveld method, using the Fullprof program. This transformation is caused by an in situ dissolution-recrystallisation process, due to aragonite's metastability. Moreover, the presence of specific authigenic minerals helps to delimit early diagenetic processes, which are, in turn, indicative of the path and the extension of the diagenetic reactions that take place in the sediment column.</dc:description><dc:description>Debido a que los carbonatos biogénicos de aguas someras son químicamente muy reactivos, existe cada vez mayor interés por conocer los procesos de diagénesis temprana que conllevan una alteración o modificación de la composición del material original. En este trabajo se presentan los resultados iniciales sobre las variaciones de composición que han tenido lugar en los caparazones o restos del esqueleto de equinodermos y briozoos. Esa variación, incluida la transformación aragonito-calcita, ha sido chequeada mediante el método Rietveld, programa Fullprof. Dicha transformación ocurre por un proceso de disolución-recristalización debida a la metaestabilidad del aragonito. Además, la presencia de una asociación de minerales neoformados implica procesos diagenéticos tempranos indicativos de las reacciones que tienen lugar en la columna del sedimento.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1505</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>