<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Intra-pituitary relationship of follicle stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone during pubertal development in Atlantic bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Berkovich, N.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Corriero, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Santamaria, N.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mylonas, C.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vassallo-Agius, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>de-la-G치ndara, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Meiri-Ashkenazi, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Zlatnikov, V.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gordin, H.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bridges, C.R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rosenfeld, H.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanogr치fico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T09:29:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Atlantic bluefin tuna</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dot-blot-immunoassay</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gonadotropins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Puberty</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sexual dimorphism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fish reproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>tuna</dc:subject><dc:description>As part of the endeavor aiming at the domestication of Atlantic bluefin tuna (BFT; Thunnus thynnus), first&#13;
sexual maturity in captivity was studied by documenting its occurrence and by characterizing the key&#13;
hormones of the reproductive axis: follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) and luteinizing hormone (LH).&#13;
The full length sequence encoding for the related hormone b-subunits, bftFSHb and bftLHb, were determined,&#13;
revealing two bftFSHb mRNA variants, differing in their 50 untranslated region.&#13;
A quantitative immuno-dot-blot assay to measure pituitary FSH content in BFT was developed and validated&#13;
enabling, for the first time in this species, data sets for both LH and FSH to be compared. The&#13;
expression and accumulation patterns of LH in the pituitary showed a steady increase of this hormone,&#13;
concomitant with fish age, reaching higher levels in adult females compared to males of the same age&#13;
class. Conversely, the pituitary FSH levels were elevated only in 2Y and adult fish. The pituitary FSH to&#13;
LH ratio was consistently higher (&gt;1) in immature than in maturing or pubertal fish, resembling the situation&#13;
in mammals. Nevertheless, the results suggest that a rise in the LH storage level above a minimum&#13;
threshold may be an indicator of the onset of puberty in BFT females. The higher pituitary LH levels in&#13;
adult females over males may further support this notion.&#13;
In contrast three year-old (3Y) males were pubertal while cognate females were still immature. However,&#13;
it is not yet clear whether the advanced puberty in the 3Y males was a general feature typifying wild&#13;
BFT populations or was induced by the culture conditions. Future studies testing the effects of captivity&#13;
and hormonal treatments on precocious maturity may allow for improved handling of this species in a&#13;
controlled environment which would lead to more cost-efficient farming.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0016-6480</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2480</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>General and Comparative Endocrinology, 194. 2013: 10-23</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2013.08.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20269</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribuci칩n-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 Espa침a</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>