<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Geomorphological characteristics of Pipoca mud volcano linked to recent geological processes in the Gulf of Cadiz continental margin</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Palomino, D. (Desirée)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>IV Congress of Marine Sciences</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03T18:55:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03T18:55:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Mud volcanoes are conical edifices formed by the vertical migration of muddy sediments and fluids&#13;
(hydrocarbons and brines) that are extruded by successive emissions. Mud breccia is the distinctive&#13;
material of these volcanoes which is composed by clasts of varied lithologies embedded in a clayey matrix.&#13;
This material is pushed out by the central diatrema of the cone and gives rise to mud flows that&#13;
slide down the flanks of the edifice. These volcanoes are very common in the middle and upper slope&#13;
of the Gulf of Cadiz. They are placed over buried diapiric structures and are associated to faults that&#13;
facilitate the fluid escape (Fern´andez-Puga et al. 2007). The aim of this communication is to study the&#13;
seafloor morphology and the sub-superficial characteristics of the Pipoca mud volcano, its interaction&#13;
with the water masses hydrodynamic and the recent geological processes (tectonics, sedimentary, diapirism)&#13;
that have occurred in the zone. This work has been developed in the framework of the LIFE+&#13;
INDEMARES/CHICA Project.&#13;
It has been analyzed data obtained during the oceanographic cruise INDEMARES/CHICA0412 onboard&#13;
R/V “Ram´on Margalef” that was carried out in the area named Shallow Field of Fluids Expulsion (SFFE)&#13;
in the middle slope of the continental margin of the Gulf of Cadiz. The acquired information comprised:&#13;
bathymetric data from a Kongsberg Simrad EM-710 multibeam echosounder (70 to 100kHz); and a very&#13;
high-resolution seismic system TOPAS PS018, working with a primary frequency from 16 to 20kHz and&#13;
a secondary frequency ranginf from 0,5 to 4 kHz.&#13;
The Pipoca mud volcano is situated in the SFFE, to the west of the Guadalquivir diapiric ridge and to&#13;
the north of Huelva channel (Hern´andez-Molina et al. 2006). It shows a sub-conical shape with an&#13;
elliptic base as an ENE-WSW direction. The major semiaxis has a length of 2.89 km and the minor&#13;
semiaxis of 1.1 km. The summit is dome shaped and is located at 503m water depth. A large mud flow&#13;
is observed from the summit to 762 m water depth crossing the volcano southwestward and interrupting&#13;
the Huelva channel. On the mud flow surface, six superimposed lobes have been mapped indicating that&#13;
the venting processes and the formation of mud flows have took place in different stages. To the SE, it&#13;
is characterized by a plastered contouritic deposits that ascend the volcano flank. Very high-resolution&#13;
seismic profiles reveal chaotic-to-transparent units with faults that break the contouritic deposits and&#13;
are interpreted as slides. Some slide scars can be seen in the contourite-volcano limit. The slides have&#13;
been occurred in different episodes and the deposits are buried between sediment layers of sub-parallels&#13;
reflectors. Two large depressions, with areas of 2 and 5 km2 respectively, are located to the north and&#13;
northwest of the volcano. They have a sub-circular plan view shape and their edges show approximately&#13;
vertical walls that end on a low-gradient flat bottom surfaces. The bottom of the depressions is slightly&#13;
tilted to the NNE, where both reach the maximum depth, and parallel reflectors are observed which&#13;
appear abruptly truncated in the very high-resolution seismic profiles.&#13;
In this sector of the Gulf of Cadiz, the Mediterranean Outflow Water (MOW) flows with the same direction&#13;
SE-NW as the Huelva channel (Hern´andez-Molina, et al., 2006) reaching current velocities that range between 0,20 and 0,40 m/s at the southeastern flank of the Pipoca mud volcano and between 0,10&#13;
and 0,20 m/s in the northwestern depression zone (Fern´andez-Salas et al. 2012). The interaction of the&#13;
current with the volcanic edifice generates an increase of the erosion in the southeastern zone of its base.&#13;
It could be the trigger mechanism of mass transport processes observed in this zone. These mass transport&#13;
deposits appear buried and intercalated with units of subparallel reflectors of contouritic deposits.&#13;
Plastered contouritic deposits, possibly generated by the currents, are therefore emplaced over old mass&#13;
transport deposits giving rise to a low slope surface. Whereas in the NW zone, there is a countercurrent&#13;
generating eddies and vortex with minor speed intensity. In this zone, the two main depressions are generated&#13;
by the non-consistency of the sediments related to the lack of interstitial fluids and the presence of&#13;
normal faults which drive the fluid migration could produce also the collapse of the surface. The elongated&#13;
shape of the eastward depression could be also explained by a major influence of the erosion by&#13;
currents that are favored by eddies and vortex of the MOW. Besides, slide generated deposits have been&#13;
observed along the walls of the depressions that would be also a consequence of this current effect. In the&#13;
southeastern flank of Pipoca dense crinoid beds of mediterranean affinity (Leptometra phalangium) occur&#13;
due to the nature of the water mass (MOW) and also the stronger currents that favour the availability&#13;
of particles for these suspension feeders that are indicative of productive waters.</dc:description><dc:identifier>978-84-697-0471-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Book of Abstracts submitted to the IV Congress of Marine Sciences.. IV Congress of Marine Sciences (ed.). IV Congress of Marine Sciences. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (España). 2014. 2 pp: 462-463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20447</dc:identifier><dc:type>bookPart</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>