<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Distribución y composición de la materia particulada en suspensión del margen portugués norte</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Oliveira, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodrigues, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jouanneau, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Weber, O.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alveirinho-Dias, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vitorino, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Materia en suspensión</dc:subject><dc:subject>capas nefeloides</dc:subject><dc:subject>plataforma continental</dc:subject><dc:subject>margen portugués</dc:subject><dc:description>On the North Atlantic continental margins, the Portuguese continental shelf has a singular morphology and hydrology. These characteristics are reflected in the sedimentary processes that occur on the continental shelf and in deeper areas. The main objective of the present paper is to review the nature, spatial distribution and dynamics of suspended particulate matter (SPM) on the continental shelf north of 41° N, in winter conditions. The data were collected during the Corrente da Vertente (CORVET) cruise sponsored by the Portuguese Hydrographic Institute in November 1996. During the cruise, hydrographic data (conductivity, temperature, and nephelometry) were obtained along transepts perpendicular to bathymetric contours. At most of these stations, suspended sediment samples were also collected from near-bottom turbid water (the bottom nepheloid layer, BNL) and from the surface turbid water (-5 m). SPM over the shelf consists of inorganic particles, skeletal biogenic particles and organic debris. Inorganic matter is dominated ( 60 %) by fine silt particles (  15 μm) in the inner shelf near river mouths, although in the middle-to-outer shelf biogenic debris prevails in coarser particles (greater than 28 μm). Currents and waves induce resuspension events, which are clearly shown by concentration fluctuations in the BNL. These events are greatly intensified during storms. The nephelometrical distribution near the bottom can reflect this events with a rise of the values in the middle shelf far away from the river inputs. Near the continental slope, the BNL nourish the intermediate nepheloid layer (INL). The nourishment increases during storm events, showing the importance of these events to the transport of particles to deeper areas.</dc:description><dc:description>La plataforma continental portuguesa, situada en el ámbito más vasto del margen continental del Atlántico norte, puede ser considerada como única a causa de sus características morfológicas e hidrológicas. Estas características se reflejan en los procesos sedimentarios que ocurren tanto en la plataforma continental como en las áreas más profundas. El objetivo principal de este trabajo es caracterizar el tipo, la distribución espacial y la dinámica de la materia particulada en suspensión de la plataforma continental situada al norte de 41° N, en condiciones invernales. Los datos fueron obtenidos en el mes de noviembre de 1996 durante la misión CORVET (Corrente da Vertente) promovida por el Instituto Hidrográfico de la Marina Portuguesa, según secciones perpendiculares a la costa. Las muestras de materia en suspensión fueron obtenidas a 5 m de la superficie y en cercanía del fondo. El análisis de las muestras indica que la materia particulada en suspensión de la plataforma continental está constituida esencialmente por partículas terrígenas, bioclastos siliciosos y calcáreos, así como de otros detritos orgánicos. Cerca de la desembocadura de los ríos, más del 60 % de la materia terrígena está compuesta de partículas finas (  15 μm); en cambio, en el resto de la plataforma los bioclastos son dominantes y presentan, generalmente, dimensiones superiores ( 28 μm).  Las corrientes y las olas inducen periodos de resuspensión de las partículas sedimentarias más finas localizadas en la plataforma media. Este fenómeno, ilustrado por las variaciones de concentración de la capa nefeloide de fondo, es particularmente intenso durante las tormentas, alimentando entonces una capa nefeloide intermediaria que circula cerca del borde de la plataforma.  Los valores observados muestran la importancia de los periodos energéticos en el traslado de las partículas de la plataforma continental hacia los sectores más profundos.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1518</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>