<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis, Kroyer) from EU-Spain Bottom Trawl Survey 2013 in NAFO Div. 3LNO</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Casas-Sánchez, J.M. (José Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Román-Marcote, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Teruel-Gómez, J. (Josefina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramilo-Rivero, G. (Guadalupe)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-14T13:45:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-14T13:45:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The Spanish Institute of Oceanography carried out in 2013 two bottom trawl surveys in the NAFO Regulatory Area in Division 3NO and 3L during the months of June and August respectively. The results on Northern shrimp (Pandalus borealis) are presented and compared with those from previous surveys from the same series. Although in 2013 the shrimp catch (8.955 kg.) and estimated biomass (37.711 t.) in 3NO increased to 2011 level, the low values recorded confirm the decrease in the importance of shrimp catches from 2004. Similarly, in 3L Division, northern shrimp indices increased with respect to 2012 (62%) but remains at low level. Estimated biomass increased from 2003-2006; then, the values of these indices declined in 2007 (about 10%) and increased again in 2008 up to its historical maximum (149 265 t.). In 2009 is initiated a downward trend decreasing up to lowest values in 2012 in the survey series. In 2013 the biomass estimated 17 438 t. in 3L and 38 t. in 3NO were between the lowest in the Spanish surveys series.&#13;
Catch results from the surveys and data analysis are discussed in this paper.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1713</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Casas, J.M., E. Román, J. Teruel, G. Ramilo. 2013. Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis, Kroyer) from EU-Spain Bottom Trawl Survey 2013 in NAFO Div. 3LNO. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 13/063, Serial Nº N6225: 12p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>