<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Decadal variability in chlorophyll and primary production off NW Spain.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Bode, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Anadón, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Morán, X.A.G. (Xosé Ánxelu Gutiérrez)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Teira, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Varela-Rodríguez, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-28T06:32:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-28T06:32:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2011-08-30</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>primary production</dc:subject><dc:subject>phytoplankton</dc:subject><dc:subject>plankton</dc:subject><dc:subject>upwelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galicia</dc:subject><dc:description>Proyectos RADIALES (IEO), REFORZA&#13;
(PGIDIT06RMA60401PR)y HERCULES (09MMA027604PR)de la Xunta de Galicia y ANILE (CTM2009-08396) del Plan nacional de I+D+i</dc:description><dc:description>Long-term variability of phytoplankton biomass (chlorophyll a) and primary production&#13;
(carbon fixation) in relation to changes in climatic and oceanographic factors was analysed for&#13;
oceanic and shelf waters of the north and northwest Iberian Peninsula. Changes related to stratification&#13;
in the water column and upwelling intensity were specifically addressed. The time series include&#13;
measurements of primary production and biomass over 19 yr. Seasonally, the main mode of temporal&#13;
variability of the series is the occurrence of phytoplankton blooms during the winter-spring and summer-&#13;
autumn transition periods. On the northwestern coast (Galicia), the blooms are more frequent&#13;
and attain higher biomass and production values than on the northern coast (Mar Cantábrico) due to&#13;
the longer duration and higher intensity of upwelling in the former region. Even for the longest series&#13;
there is no significant long-term trend in biomass, but primary production increased in Galicia and&#13;
decreased in the Mar Cantábrico at nearly equivalent rates when considering monthly series. The&#13;
lagged relationships between external factors and phytoplankton biomass and production suggest&#13;
non-linear interactions between phytoplankton and climate. Neither the increase in surface stratification&#13;
nor the decrease in upwelling intensity has negatively affected primary production in this region&#13;
following consistent and systematic patterns. Changes in the amount and proportions of nutrients&#13;
during winter water-mass formation, and an increased use of nutrients remineralised in situ, are proposed&#13;
as the main causes of decadal variability in primary production in this region.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2077</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Climate Research, 48. 2011: 293-305</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.3354/cr00935</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20044</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>