<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Benefits of probiotic administration on growth and performance along metamorphosis and weaning of Senegalese sole (Solea senegalensis)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Lobo, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Tapia-Paniagua, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moreno-Ventas, X.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alarcón, F.J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balebona, M.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moriñigo, M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-de-la-Banda, I. (Inés)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Santander</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:33:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:33:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Solea senegalensis</dc:subject><dc:subject>larviculture</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>gut microbiota</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shewanella</dc:subject><dc:subject>Probiotics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Digestive enzymes</dc:subject><dc:description>Suitable nutrition at ﬁrst feeding in marine ﬁsh larvae is an important factor for successful larval and juvenile&#13;
rearing. In this way probiotic supplementation may contribute to better face the habitual stress of metamorphosis&#13;
and weaning at early sole stages. The aimof this study was to optimize Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11 administration&#13;
to Senegalese sole (Solea senegalensis) at early stages of development. For this purpose, we studied the&#13;
inﬂuence of a short pulse of S. putrefaciens Pdp11 (10–30 dah) on growth performance, gut microbiota modulation,&#13;
digestive enzymes activities and body composition. These probiotic bacteria were incorporated using&#13;
Artemia as live vector (2.5 × 10&#13;
7&#13;
cfu mL&#13;
−1&#13;
) and supplied to sole specimens in a co-feeding regime (Gemma,&#13;
Skretting) by triplicate. S. putrefaciens Pdp11 colonized larval gut being present from23 to 119 dah. Probiotic supply&#13;
signiﬁcantly modulated larval and fry gut microbiota. A PCA analysis including all the parameters analyzed&#13;
strongly associated S. putrefaciens Pdp11 presence with a higher ﬁsh growth, a higher digestive proteolytic activity&#13;
level and a ﬁsh body composition modulation along S. senegalensis rearing. In addition less size variability was&#13;
obtained frommetamorphosis until the end of weaning. In conclusion a short pulse of S. putrefaciens Pdp11 (10–&#13;
30 dah) seems sufﬁcient to obtain a suitable microbial modulation involved in a better growth performance and&#13;
body composition that suggests a great potential for sole aquaculture production.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2627</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquaculture, 433. 2014: 183-195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20379</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>closedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>