<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Depuración de la navaja Ensis arcuatus (Jeffreys, 1865) y el longueirón Ensis siliqua (L., 1758) (Solenacea)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>López, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Darriba, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Miranda, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:32Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:32Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Escherichia coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>coliformes fecales</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salmonella spp</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of this study is to evaluate a specific method for the depuration of the razor clams Ensis arcuatus (Jeffreys, 1865) and Ensis siliqua (L., 1758), aimed a obtaining an optimal quality in the depurated product. The presence of Salmonella spp. and levels of Escherichia coli and faecal coliforms were monitored before and during the process of depuration. These results show the importance not only of a previous selection of the damaged specimens, but also of banding the razor clams in groups of 20 specimens and placing them horizontally in cages. In all cases, less than 21 hours are needed in order to reach the legal levels required for human consumption.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se evalúa un método de depuración para la navaja Ensis arcuatus (Jeffreys, 1865) y el longueirón Ensis siliqua (L., 1758) de fácil aplicación en las depuradoras comerciales y verificando que garantice una calidad óptima de los ejemplares al final del proceso. La presencia de Salmonella spp. y los niveles de Escherichia coli y de coliformes fecales son registrados antes y durante el proceso de depuración. Los resultados muestran la importancia de la selección previa de individuos no dañados y la eficacia de la colocación en posición horizontal de los especímenes en grupos de 20 individuos atados. En todos los casos se necesitaron menos de 21 h para alcanzar los niveles permitidos para el consumo humano.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1414</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>