<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A comparative study of the United States and Spanish longline fleets targetting swordfish in the Atlantic Ocean North of 40º N latitude</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Hoey, J. (John)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mejuto-García, J. (Jaime)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Martínez, S. (Sergio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Conser, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of the Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-11T13:34:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-11T13:34:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1988</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Harvesting characteristics (size composition and catch rates) of the U. S. and Spanish fleets are &#13;
examined in light of gear and operating (time-area) practices latitude and    between in the north Atlantic  between 40° and 50° north 20° and 50° west longitude, The two fleets have approached and overlapped operations in  this area between 1983 and 1985. During 1986 the degree of &#13;
overlap continued to increase.</dc:description><dc:description>Se examinan las características (composición por tallas y   tasas de capturas) de la captura de &#13;
las flotas española y estadounidense, a la luz de los artes empleados y del tipo de operación &#13;
llevada a cabo (tiempo-zona) en el Atlántico Norte, entre 40 - 50º de latitud Norte y  20- 50º &#13;
grados de longitud Oeste. Las operaciones de ambas flotas han estado bastante cerca nas y   se     &#13;
han solapado en esta zona durante el periodo 1983-85. En 1986 cont1nuó en aumento el grado de &#13;
solapamiento.</dc:description><dc:description>Les caractéristiques d'exploitation (composition de taille et taux de capture) des flottilles &#13;
américaine et espagnole sont examinées  à la lumière des    engins    et    méthodes     normalement   &#13;
 employés    dans    l'Atlantique    nord     entre&#13;
40º et 50°N de latitude, et 20º et 50ºW de longitude. La pêche de ces deux flottille s'est &#13;
rapprochée, et même recoupée, dans ce secteur entre 1983 et&#13;
1985. En 1986, le degré de chevauchement a continué de s'accroitre.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1609</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Hoey, J. et al. 1988. A comparative study of the United States and Spanish longline fleets targetting swordfish in the Atlantic Ocean North of 40º N latitude. Col.Vol.Sci.Pap. ICCAT, 27 : 230-239</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>