<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Division 3M Northern shrimp (Pandalus borealis) - Interim Monitoring Update</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Casas-Sánchez, J.M. (José Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T09:12:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T09:12:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This document updates some of the indices for northern shrimp (Pandalus borealis) harvested within NAFO Divisions 3M. The assessment for this resource was completed, within Scientific Council during autumn 2011. Scientific Council recommended that the fishing mortality for 2013 be set as close to zero as possible. Now, the low indices of biomass estimated in the 2012 EU summer survey, where the stock size was well below Blim proxy, confirm the depletion of the stock after several years of downward trend, even though the levels of exploitation have been low since 2005 and close to zero in 2011 and 2012, due to the moratorium initiated in 2011. The biomass estimates (EU survey summer 1988-2012) are updated within this report. In the 2011 EU survey the 3M total and female biomass index were 1041t and 850 t respectively. These indexes were around 37% lower than last year and the lowest values in the EU survey series. As previous years, the sharp decline of shrimp biomass in Flemish Cap was associated with a high level of the cod stock. This unfavorable situation confirms the recommendation carried out within Scientific Council during autumn 2011.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1703</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>NAFO Scientific Council Research (SCR) Documents, NAFO SCR Doc. 12/42 Serial Nº N6075. 2012: 1-11</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>5512</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>