<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Scleractinia off Canary Islands Seamounts</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brito, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T13:10:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T13:10:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>scleractinia</dc:subject><dc:subject>banco de La Concepción</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amanay</dc:subject><dc:subject>El Banquete</dc:subject><dc:subject>montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomasa</dc:subject><dc:subject>abundancia</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecosistemas marinos vulnerables</dc:subject><dc:subject>organismos indicadores</dc:subject><dc:subject>seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomass</dc:subject><dc:subject>abundance</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulnerable marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>indicator organisms</dc:subject><dc:description>South of Fuerteventura (Amanay and El Banquete banks) and La Concepción bank (north of Lanzarote)&#13;
are the areas chosen to be depicted at Canary Islands in the frame of INDEMARES project. The main&#13;
aim of the project was to end up with an inventory and mapping of habitats and fisheries footprint off the&#13;
study area, information which would let the administrations to establish a new Natura 2000 area, trying&#13;
to reconcile protection of biodiversity with artisanal local economic activities. Methodology approach&#13;
complies with a multidisciplinary perspective, having described the area from geological, oceanographic,&#13;
biological and fisheries points of view. Several surveys have taken place since 2009 to 2013 at Amanay,&#13;
El Banquete and La Concepción waters. Data from VMS (Vessel Monitoring System) were used,&#13;
combined with interviews to users (fishers), sampling at landing points and onboard observation&#13;
programs, to describe the fishery uses in the area.&#13;
The sets were made with two direct samplers, benthic dredge and beam trawl, between 60 and 1597 m&#13;
depth, haul duration of 5 and 15 minutes long, respectively. The sampling within the project has yielded&#13;
results that allow a comprehensive overview on the distribution and biodiversity of Scleractinia off&#13;
seamounts. In each station total invertebrates catch was separated to specific level, counted and&#13;
weighted.&#13;
The order Scleractinia (Cnidaria, Anthozoa, Hexacorallia) is one of the cnidarian groups with greater&#13;
biodiversity and abundance within benthic communities. Total Scleractinia biomass collected is 1 950&#13;
g, a total of 334 organisms (individuals and colonies). The 37% of the abundance belonging to&#13;
Caryophyllidae, 27% Dendrophyllidae, 22% Flabellidae and 12% Deltocyathidae. Another Families&#13;
present are Oculinidae, Faviidae and Astrocoenidae (2%). 44% of biomass is due to the family&#13;
Caryophyllidae, 25% to Flabellidae and 22% to Dendrophyllidae, being these the three more prominent&#13;
groups. It’s very important the appearance of species considered as VME (Vulnerable Marine&#13;
Ecosystems) indicator organisms –Lophelia pertusa (Linnaeus, 1758), Madrepora oculata Linnaeus,&#13;
1758, Anomocora fecunda (Pourtalès, 1871), Solenosmilia variabilis Duncan, 1873 and Dendrophyllia&#13;
cornigera (Lamarck, 1816)-, the 60% of biomass, and other habitat structuring species as Flabellum&#13;
(Flabellum) chunii (24% of the biomass).</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2598</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón (España)). 2014. 1.11, Pág. 25. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1.11, Pág. 25</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20351</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>