<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Influencia del tamaño y la concentración de alimento sobre las tasas de aclaramiento e ingestión de la almeja Ruditapes decussatus (Linnaeus, 1758)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez-Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Albentosa-Verdú, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:41Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:41Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Ingestión</dc:subject><dc:subject>aclaramiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentración de alimento</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:description>The impact of food concentration (C) and water flow on the clearance (TA) and ingestion (TI) rates of the clam Ruditapes decussates (Linnaeus, 1758) was studied, using different-sized specimens. We found no relationship between C and TA, whereas there was a significant relationship between C and TI (TI = 24.757 + 0.576 C). The relationship between TA and the clams' live weight (PV) was also significant (TA = 4.292 PV0.683). A close relationship between PV and TI was found only when food availability (AD), a parameter that includes food concentration and flow, was constant. When it was not, the equation  TI = 64.089 + 0.015 PV + 0.546 AD  appears to explain 96.1% of TI variability.</dc:description><dc:description>Se estudia el efecto de la concentración de alimento (C) y el flujo sobre las tasas de aclaramiento (TA) e ingestión (TI) de Ruditapes decussatus (Linnaeus, 1758) con ejemplares de diferentes tamaños. En esta especie no se observa relación entre C y TA, mientras que entre TI y C la relación es significativa: TI = 24,757 + 0,576 C. Igualmente es significativa la relación entre TA y el peso vivo (PV): TA = 4,292 PV0,683. PV y TI guardan una estrecha relación sólo en caso de que el alimento disponible (AD), variable que engloba la concentración de alimento y el flujo, se mantenga constante. En caso contrario, se propone la utilización de la ecuación  TI = 64,089 + 0,015 PV + 0,546 AD que explica el 96,1 % de la variabilidad de TI.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>