<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Population dynamic and trophic position of mysid community demonstrates its key role for nursery function in a temperate estuary</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Vilas, C. (César)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rubio, E. (Elena)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cañavate, J.P. (José Pedro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Van Bergeijk, S. (Stef)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Ortegón, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Baldó, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Drake, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:48:34Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:48:34Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-20</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-12</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Guadalquivir Estuary is a main nursery ground of marine goal species for Gulf of Cadiz fisheries. It is a well-mixed temperate estuary with horizontal salinity gradient and clear seasonal water temperature trend. Mysid community with Mesopodopsis slabberi, Neomysis integer and Rhopalophthalmus tartessicus make up to over 80% of total macrofauna biomass in the estuary. Life history, population structure, secondary production, trophic level and community spatio-temporal dynamic were unravelled combining analysis of long term 16y monitoring data with 2y of in depth population analysis and trophic biomarker studies. Results show a key trophic role in food web, a seasonal trend showing density peaks ( 23, 3 and 6 mg/m3, respectively) in spring-summer and winter marine coastward migration. Despite being euryhaline, the three species of showed unevenly spatial distribution, being salinity the variable best explaining structure changes of mysid assemblage. Inter- and intra-specific euryhalinity differences both for prey and predators seem to determine the entire spatial estuarine community distribution. High secondary production (P/B rates 38.2, 10.3 and 10.7) and food web studies confirm key role of mysids transferring energy up to juveniles (fish and crustaceans) arriving yearly in spring to their nursery area.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ECSA 54: Coastal systems under change: tuning assessment and management tools. (12/05/2014 - 20/05/2014. Sesimbra (Portugal)). . ECSA 54. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ECSA 54</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20016</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>