<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Estuarine mysids are key prey for anchovy juveniles</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Baldó, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vilas, C. (César)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Ortegón, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Drake, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:29:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:29:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-16</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-12</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Previous studies on feeding habits of European anchovy Engraulis encrasicolus, carried out in open sea, described it as a strictly zooplanktivorous species, being copepods their main prey from larvae to adults. Nevertheless the analysis of the stomach contents of a total of 1160 individuals (from 18 to 131 mm total length) collected monthly (from February 1998 to January 1999) at the Guadalquivir estuary (SW Spain) revealed that estuarine myisds play an important role in their diet. Inside the estuary, the smallest individuals analysed (postlarvae) fed mainly on copepods, but as they grew into juveniles they shifted to mysisd. In fact, estuarine mysids represented 76% of dietary composition, in terms of biomass, of juveniles (total length &gt; 40 mm), being Mesopodopsis slabberi the main prey species (46%). During last 16 years, from June 1997 to date, abundance of anchovy and mysids have been monitored by monthly sampling in the estuary. This time series has pointed out the role of the estuary as an important nursery ground for anchovy. The seasonal coincidence of maximal anchovy and mysid densities suggests that food availability may be a principal factor influencing that nursery function.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ECSA 54: Coastal systems under change: tuning assessment and management tools. (12/05/2014 - 16/05/2014. Sesimbra (Portugal)). . ECSA 54. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ECSA 54</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20014</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>