<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Shifts between gelatinous and crustacean plankton in a coastal upwellin region</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Bode, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Ossorio-Costa, M.T. (María Teresa)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Miranda, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz-Villarreal, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-25T12:10:09Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-25T12:10:09Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-09</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Climate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copepods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jellyfish</dc:subject><dc:subject>Planktivorous fish</dc:subject><dc:subject>Time-series</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tunicates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Upwelling</dc:subject><dc:description>proyectos RADIALES (IEO) y EURO-BASIN (Ref. 264933, 7FP)</dc:description><dc:description>Variability in the dominance of copepods vs. gelatinous plankton was analysed using monthly time-series covering the last 55 years and&#13;
related to changes in climatic, oceanographic, and fishery conditions in the upwelling region of Galicia (NW Spain). Seasonality was&#13;
generally the main component of variability in all groups, both along the coast and in the nearby ocean, but no common long-term&#13;
trend was found. Coastal copepods increased since the early 1990s, and gelatinous plankton increased in the ocean during the 1980s.&#13;
Different trends were found for gelatinous plankton in two coastal sites, characterized by increases in either medusae or tunicates. In&#13;
all series, multiyear periods of relative dominance of gelatinous vs. copepod plankton were evident. In general, copepod periods were&#13;
observed in positive phases of the main modes of regional climatic variability. Conversely, gelatinous periods occurred during negative&#13;
climatic phases. However, the low correlations between gelatinous plankton and climatic, oceanographic, or fishery variables suggest&#13;
that local factors play a major role in their proliferations.</dc:description><dc:identifier>10.1093/icesjms/fss193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1734</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES Journal Of Marine Science, 70(5). 2013: 934-942</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>