<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Un modelo de advección-difusión para explicar anomalías térmicas en el cabo de Trafalgar</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Vargas, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarhan, T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lafuente, J.G.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cano-Lucaya, N. (Natalio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:09Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:09Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Advección-difusión</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrientes de marea</dc:subject><dc:subject>topografía</dc:subject><dc:description>The authors describe an almost permanent thermal anomaly, with low surface-temperature values, off Cape Trafalgar. The existence of strong tidal currents in the alongshore direction, and the local offshore orientation of isobaths at this point, support the hypothesis of vertical forcing by interaction between the barotropic tide and topography. This is simplified for modelisation as the pass of a tidal current over a ridge, which is considered uniform in the crossshore direction. A bidimensional model in finite differences is developed to reproduce the main features observed experimentally. The combined effects of advection (both vertical and horizontal) and diffusion appear to be very important. The model is sensitive to the assumed values of thermal diffusion coefficients and their depth dependence, as well as to heat flux through the sea surface. To have realistic values for these parameters, a unidimensional diffusion model aimed at reproducing the mixed layer and thermocline observed in this area during summer has been developed. Heat flux and diffusion coefficients are adjustment parameters of the model, and, once determined, they are introduced in the 2-D advection-diffusion model. Results from simulation seem to be in good agreement with CTD observations, confirming our initial hypothesis.</dc:description><dc:description>Se describe una anomalía térmica caracterizada por bajas temperaturas superficiales frente al cabo de Trafalgar. Debido a que la orientación de las isóbatas en esta área es casi perpendicular a la costa y a que existen fuertes corrientes de marea a lo largo de ella, se desarrolla la hipótesis de que la interacción entre las corrientes de marea y la topografía son los mecanismos responsables de esta anomalía. Para revisar esta hipótesis se desarrolla en el presente trabajo un modelo de advección-difusión que estudia el efecto del paso de una corriente de marea sobre un obstáculo. El modelo es sensible a ciertos parámetros, como los coeficientes de difusión térmica y el flujo de calor en la superficie del mar. Por ello desarrollamos un modelo monodimensional que reproduce la formación de la capa de mezcla y la termoclina estacional usando estos parámetros como parámetros de ajuste. Una vez encontrados los valores adecuados, son introducidos en el modelo de advección-difusión. Los resultados obtenidos parecen estar de acuerdo con los datos experimentales.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1216</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>