<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Utilización de distintos sistemas de engorde en el cultivo de vieira Pecten maximus (L., 1758), zamburiña Mimachlamys varia (L., 1758) y volandeira Aequipecten opercularis (L., 1758) en Andalucía (España)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Canoura, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Campos, M. J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López, F. J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Saavedra, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Pectínidos</dc:subject><dc:subject>crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>supervivencia</dc:subject><dc:subject>cestas</dc:subject><dc:subject>bolsas colectoras</dc:subject><dc:subject>encordado</dc:subject><dc:subject>semillero</dc:subject><dc:description>A study was carried out on the growth of three different species of scallops -king scallop Pecten maximus (L., 1758), black scallop Mimachlamys varia (L., 1758), and queen scallop Aequipecten opercularis (L., 1758)- in suspended culture using different growout systems: trays and bags for all three species, the hung ropes technique for black scallop, and nursery culture for king scallop. Von Bertalanffy's equation  Lt = L∞ (1 - e -k(t-t0)) was used to analyse growth, measured in shell height (mm).  The best growout system from a biological standpoint, is that of oyster trays, where all three species showed the fastest growth. Growth was also found to be greater in terms of the largest attainable size in Pecten maximus. For black scallop and queen scallop, it is necessary to use collector bags when the unattached spat measure less than 5 mm. Moreover, the bags are easier to handle and less expensive than trays, making them the method of choice during the early stages of this culture. The use of the hung ropes technique for the growout of black scallop seems to be a good system, resulting in a growth parameter of k = 0.89.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ha estudiado el crecimiento de la vieira Pecten maximus (L., 1758), la zamburiña Mimachlamys varia (L., 1758) y la volandeira Aequipecten opercularis (L., 1758) cultivadas en suspensión con distintos sistemas de engorde: cestas y bolsas para las tres especies, encordado para la zamburiña y semillero para la vieira. Para analizar el crecimiento en altura (mm) se ha utilizado la ecuación de Von Bertalanffy:  Lt = L∞ (1 - e -k(t-t0))  El mejor sistema de engorde desde un punto de vista biológico lo constituyen las cestas ostrícolas, pues produce en las tres especies un crecimiento más rápido. Este crecimiento ha sido también superior en talla máxima alcanzable para el caso de la vieira. Para la zamburiña y la volandeira la utilización de las bolsas se hace necesaria cuando la semilla despegada tiene menos de 5 mm; por otra parte, las bolsas son más manejables y más baratas que las cestas, siendo aconsejables en las primeras fases del cultivo. La utilización de la técnica de encordado para el engorde de la zamburiña parece ser un buen sistema con una constante de crecimiento de 0,89.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1399</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>