<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Wild or not. That is the question. Microsatellites and the reproductive failure in cultures Solea senegalensis</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez, A. (Andrea)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nande, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Blázquez-Fernández, B. (Blanca)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Peleteiro-Alonso, J.B. (José Benito)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T15:31:10Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T15:31:10Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-17</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-14</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Senegalese sole (Solea senegalensis) is a species of great interest in aquaculture because it has a high commercial value and a fast development of eggs. The reproduction of Senegalese sole in captivity has been studied since the early 1980s (Rodriguez et al., 1982). While F1 females were shown to be able to produce fertilized eggs from natural spawning as long as they were accompanied by wild males (Mañanos, 2011), failure of F1 males to display normal courtship behaviour has been demonstrated (Carazo et al., 2009). The reason for this failure remains unclear and therefore, research in this subject is paramount to overcome this bottleneck in S. senegalensis culture. We have designed an experiment using two broodstocks maintained since 2010 in the aquaculture facilities of the Oceanographic center of Vigo, one of them (T1) constituted by wild females together with wild and F1 males and the other (T2) constituted by F1 females together with wild and F1 males. One year later we obtained a successful spawn in T2. The main goal of this research was to test whether the male responsible for this spawn was F1.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2529</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquaculture Europe. (14/10/2014 - 17/10/2014. Donostia-San Sebastián (Spain)). . Abstract ID# 385. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Abstract ID# 385</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20295</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>