<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Application of age-length-keys to estimate catch-at-age for the North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus alalunga) stock</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Zárate-Vidal, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Cabello-Ródenas, M.C. (María Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:03:17Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:03:17Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus alalunga</dc:subject><dc:subject>albacore</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface fishery</dc:subject><dc:subject>age-length-keys</dc:subject><dc:subject>age composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>North Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:description>This document presents the results of applying two different methods to estimate catch-at-age&#13;
for North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus alalunga). The Spanish albacore surface fishery size&#13;
frequency data from 2003 to 2005 have been analyzed by means of MULTIFAN and age-lengthkeys&#13;
(ALKs) have been derived from readings of sections obtained from sampled dorsal spiny&#13;
rays of catch landed.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document présente les résultats de l’application de deux méthodes différentes visant à&#13;
estimer la prise par âge pour le germon de l’Atlantique Nord (Thunnus alalunga). Les données&#13;
de fréquences de tailles de la pêcherie de surface espagnole ciblant le germon de 2003 à 2005&#13;
ont été analysées à l’aide de MULTIFAN et des clefs âge-taille ont été calculées (ALKs)&#13;
d’après la lecture des sections obtenues des rayons épineux de la dorsale échantillonnées de la&#13;
prise débarquée.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento presenta los resultados de aplicar dos métodos distintos para estimar la&#13;
captura por edad del atún blanco del Atlántico norte. La distribución por talla de las capturas&#13;
comerciales de las flotas españolas de superficie fue analizada con MULTIFAN. Las claves&#13;
talla edad fueron obtenidas por medio de la lectura de secciones de radios espinosos&#13;
muestreados a partir de las capturas comerciales.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1673</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Ortiz de Zárate, V., X. Valeiras, C. Rodríguez-Cabello, M. Ruiz. 2007. Application of age-length-keys to estimate catch-at-age for the North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus alalunga) stock. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 60 (2): 428-436</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>