<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis, Kroyer) from Spanish Bottom Trawl Survey 2012 in NAFO Div. 3LNO</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Casas-Sánchez, J.M. (José Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Román-Marcote, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Teruel-Gómez, J. (Josefina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramilo-Rivero, G. (Guadalupe)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T09:26:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T09:26:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The Spanish Institute of Oceanography carried out in 2012 two bottom trawl surveys in the NAFO Regulatory Area in Division 3NO and 3L during the months of June and August respectively. The results on Northern shrimp (Pandalus borealis) are presented and compared with those from previous surveys from the same series. In 2012 the catch (0.923 kg.) and estimated biomass (3.864 t.) confirm the decrease of shrimp importance from 2004 in 3NO. In 3L Division, northern shrimp indices show consecutive and drastic declines (55.7% with respect to 2011) and confirm the downward trend initiated in 2009. Estimated biomass increased from 2003-2006; then, the values of these indices declined in 2007 (about 10%) and increased again in 2008 up to its historical maximum (149265 t.). In 2012 the biomass estimated 10784 t. in 3L and 4 t. in 3NO were the lowest in the Spanish surveys series.&#13;
Catch results from the surveys and data analysis are discussed in this paper.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Casas, J.M., E. Román, J. Teruel, G. Ramilo. 2012. Northern Shrimp (Pandalus borealis, Kroyer) from Spanish Bottom Trawl Survey 2012 in NAFO Div. 3LNO. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 12/56, Serial Nº N6118: 12p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>