<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Caracterización cromosómica del pez sapo Halobatrachus didactylus (Schneider, 1801) (Teleostei: Batrachoididae) mediante hibridación in situ de fluorescencia</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Merlo, M. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cross, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarasquete, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Palazón-Fernández, J. L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rebordinos, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Halobatrachus didactylus</dc:subject><dc:subject>genes ribosomales</dc:subject><dc:subject>secuencia telomérica</dc:subject><dc:subject>repeticiones GATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>hibridación in situ de fluorescencia</dc:subject><dc:subject>FISH</dc:subject><dc:description>Halobatrachus didactylus (Schneider, 1801) has a chromosome number of 2n = 46 (8 metacentrics, 12 submetacentrics and 26 acrocentrics). Specimens studied were collected from waters of the Bay of Cadiz. Chromosome preparations were made from the cephalic portion of the kidney. The telomeric probe hybridized on the terminal position of all toadfish chromosomes. (GATA)n hybridized preferentially on the subcentromeric region of only one submetacentric chromosome pair, although additional weak signals dispersed throughout the chromosomes were found. Major ribosomal genes were also located on a submetacentric pair, but at a telomeric position. Finally, the 5S rDNA probe produced a hybridization pattern similar to the GATA probe. These results provide interesting information which describes chromosomal markers that may be of utility for the management of natural populations of this species.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ha realizado la caracterización cromosómica de Halobatrachus didactylus (Schneider, 1801) mediante la localización de diferentes secuencias repetidas en sus cromosomas. Los especímenes utilizados fueron capturados en aguas de la bahía de Cádiz. Las preparaciones cromosómicas se realizaron de la porción cefálica del riñón. La sonda telomérica hibridó en posición terminal de todos los cromosomas del pez sapo. (GATA)n hibridó preferentemente en la región subcentromérica de un par cromosómico submetacéntrico; se encontraron señales adicionales más débiles. Los genes ribosomales mayores también fueron localizados en un par submetacéntrico, pero en región telomérica. Finalmente, la sonda 5S rDNA presentó un patrón de hibridación similar a la sonda GATA. Los resultados aportan interesantes datos que describen marcadores cromosómicos que podrían ser de utilidad para la gestión de poblaciones naturales de esta especie.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1390</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>