<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Disponibilidad y consumo de microalgas por parte de Siphonaria pectinata (L., 1758) en un litoral rocoso</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ocaña, T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fa, D.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Siphonaria pectinata</dc:subject><dc:subject>alimentación</dc:subject><dc:subject>microalgas</dc:subject><dc:description>Siphonaria pectinata (L., 1758) is a pulmonate gastropod of the order Basommatophora, which has adopted a lifestyle superficially similar to that of patellogastropod limpets, and is thus often referred to as a «false limpet». In this paper, we present the results of a study investigating microalgal availability and resource utilization by this species in its intertidal habitat, on a rocky shore off Gibraltar (southern Iberian Peninsula).  A number of different experiments are described, which serve to provide an overview of the main food types and their relative availability to this species. These include the sampling of the surface microbial algal film, scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and light microscopy of rock chips and slurry, radular structure, gut contents and faecal pellets.  The results of this study suggest that S. pectinata does not feed on encrusting «hard» algae, but rather uses its fine-toothed radula to graze superficial, soft algae, including spores and emerging germlings. We suggest that such a feeding strategy would allow it to reduce competition with other patellogastropod limpets, which tend to scrape deeper into the rocky substrate while foraging. Possible avenues for further research are discussed.</dc:description><dc:description>Siphonaria pectinata (L., 1758) es un gasterópodo pulmonado del orden Basommatophora que ha adoptado un modo de vida parecido al de los patelogasterópodos o lapas por lo que, a menudo, se le denomina «falsa lapa». En este trabajo presentamos los resultados de un estudio sobre la disponibilidad y la utilización de las microalgas por esta especie, en su hábitat intermareal, en un litoral rocoso de Gibraltar (al sur de la península Ibérica).  Se describen diferentes experimentos que proporcionan una visión general sobre los principales alimentos y su disponibilidad. Estos experimentos incluyen el muestreo de una película de algas microscópicas y microscopía electrónica y óptica de lascas y manchas rocosas, rádulas, contenidos intestinales y heces fecales.  Los resultados sugieren que S. pectinata no se alimenta de algas fuertemente incrustadas sino que más bien utiliza su delicada y dentada rádula para raer las algas blandas superficiales, incluyendo las esporas y las células germinales recién aparecidas. Creemos que esta estrategia de alimentación permite reducir la competencia con otros patelogastrópodos que tienden a raspar el sustrato rocoso más profundo cuando forrajean. Se discuten posibles vías para una futura investigación.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>