<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Effects of mesh size and effort changes on the ibero-atlantic hake (Merluccius merluccius L.) fishery (Div. VIIIc (W) + IXa)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Martínez, S. (Sergio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pereiro-Muñoz, F.J. (Francisco Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cardador, F. (Fátima)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Dinis, M.H.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lima Dias, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-01-23T08:08:37Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-01-23T08:08:37Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1978</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This paper concerns Hake fishery from the North of Galicia (Spain) to the South of&#13;
Portugal. It represents one more attempt in obtaining more informations about the&#13;
exploitation state of hake stock in this area.&#13;
The aim of this study is to assess the immediate and long-term effects in this fishery with different fishing strategies. The models used were the following:&#13;
a) increases in mesh-size: - Gulland (1961), Jones (1974), Ricker (1975),&#13;
Cadima (1976,1978).&#13;
b) increases in mesh-size and changes in fishing effort: - Jones (1974) and&#13;
Ricker (1975).&#13;
To apply such methods we used the data concerning the mean catches (from 1974 to&#13;
1977) belonging to the Galician and Portuguese fleets.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce travail concerne la pêcherie du merlu de la côte nord de la Galice (Espagne),&#13;
jusq'au sud du Portugal.&#13;
Il répresente un essai en plus pour améliorer notre connaissance sur l'état d'exploitation&#13;
du stock du merlu dans cette même region.&#13;
Le but de cet étude c'est l'évaluation des effects immédiats et a long terme sur la&#13;
pêcherie selon des stratégies de peche différentes.&#13;
Les modeles appliqués ont été les suivants:&#13;
a) pour les accroissements des maillages: Gulland (1961), Jones (1974), Ricker&#13;
(1975), Cadima (1976,1978).&#13;
b) pour les variations de l'effort et augmentations des mail lages: Jones (1974)&#13;
et Ricker (1975).&#13;
Pour l'application des méthodes mentionnées, nous avons utilisé les données rélatives&#13;
a la moyenne des captures réalisées par les flotilles espagnole (Galicienne) et&#13;
portugaise, pendant la période 1974-77.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1589</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Iglesias, S. et al. 1978. Effects of mesh size and effort changes on the ibero-atlantic hake (Merluccius merluccius L.) fishery (Div. VIIIc (W) + IXa). ICES CM Documents 1978/G: 39. 14p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>