<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Combining cytogenetics and flow cytometry to the study of the marine dinoflagellate life cycle</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Dapena, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cuadrado, Á. (Ángeles)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bravo, I. (Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Figueroa, R.I. (Rosa Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:41:51Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:41:51Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-26</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-24</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Very few studies have focused on the chromosomal characterization of the different life&#13;
cycle stages of the dinoflagellates, unicellular algae best known for being causative agents of&#13;
the popularly known as “red tides”. These algae, some able to cause human health problems&#13;
through the accumulation of their toxins in bivalve mollusks, grow very fast asexually, causing&#13;
the bloom. However, their high environmental resilience is acquired by their ability to encyst&#13;
as zygotes (sexually). The main difficulty in the study of these organisms life cycle lies in the&#13;
difficulty to take apart the different stages of the cellular cycle (mitotic and meiotic nuclei), and&#13;
of the life cycle (sexual and asexual phases), which are very similar when traditional technics of&#13;
optical microscopy are used. Since it is not possible to obtain a total (100%) sexual induction,&#13;
cultures in which sexuality is induced are a mixture of sexual and asexual stages, which adds&#13;
difficulty to their study. With the objective of analyzing the growth strategies of dinoflagellates&#13;
and characterizing the cellular cycle phases, we designed an experiment in which we monitored&#13;
with image flow cytometry the cellular cycle during mitotic proliferation and during sexual&#13;
induction every 2 h during 3 days. We selected populations according to ploidy, separated&#13;
them with sorting, and stained them with DAPI and with a marker of telomeric sequences.&#13;
The comparative study of these cultures indicates that the life cycle of dinoflagellates could be&#13;
much more complex than the depicted to date</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>VIII Seminario de Citogenética. (24/06/2014 - 26/06/2014. Alcalá de Henares (España)). 2014. . En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7519</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>