<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Current knowledge and pespectives of study on benthic toxic dinoflagellates of the genus Gambierdiscus in the Canary Islands</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fraga, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Riobó, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Franco, J.M. (José Mariano)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-26T11:12:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-26T11:12:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-15</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Gambierdiscus</dc:subject><dc:subject>ciguatera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canarias</dc:subject><dc:description>Species of the dinoflagellate genus Gambierdiscus are the cause of Ciguatera Fish Poisoning which is very common in tropical areas, mainly in the Pacific Ocean and Caribbean Sea. Until 2008 this disease was not reported in the NE Atlantic Ocean, when human intoxications after consumption of local fish have been reported almost yearly in the Canary Islands. Sampling of tidal ponds on rocky shores of this archipelago has revealed an unexpected diversity of the genus Gambierdiscus in the area. Morphological and phylogenetic studies of culture isolates established the presence of at least three different species: G. excentricus (originally described in the Canaries), G. australes, and a third species soon to be formally characterized, with close characteristics to G. polynesiensis and Gambierdiscus sp. type 4 sensu Xu et al (2014). The evaluation of toxicity in these species was performed by mouse bioassay (MBA) and erythrocyte lyses assay (ELA). Additionally, identification of the CTXs congeners will be conducted using liquid chromatography (LC) coupled with high resolution mass spectrometry (HRMS) analyses. Nevertheless, the link between local Gambierdiscus populations and ciguateric fish has not been unambiguously demonstrated. Future studies should focus more efforts on the phylogeography of Gambierdiscus in the Canaries, the distribution and abundance of their populations, and the characterization of toxin profiles in cultures vs those in local fishes to understand if ciguatoxins are accumulated in Canaries waters or other surrounding areas in the Macaronesian region.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2449</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES ASC 2014. (15/09/2014 - 19/09/2014. A Coruña (España)). 2014. -. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20240</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>