<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Uso de marcadores genéticos en el estudio de poblaciones naturales marinas</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rebordinos, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cross, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Crassostrea angulata</dc:subject><dc:subject>aloenzimas</dc:subject><dc:subject>polimorfismo</dc:subject><dc:subject>ostras</dc:subject><dc:description>Crassostrea angulata (Lamarck, 1819), known as the Portuguese oyster, is a species naturally located in the southwest Iberian Peninsula, mainly at river mouths and the heads of estuaries with suitable hard substrates. Genetic data on C. angulata are scarce, and Spanish natural populations (the main beds of the species) have not been studied previously. Electrophoresis is a good detector of variability, and isozyme polymorphisms have been widely used in genetic studies. The present paper reports on the electrophoretic examination of seven allozyme loci at 14 sites located between the mouth of the Guadiana River and the Straits of Gibraltar, which found a high level of genetic variability in terms of average number of alleles (min. of 2.71 and max. of 3.71), polymorphism (P₉₅ &amp;ge; 71.43 %) and mean heterozygosities (H = 0.264). All populations showed a deficit of heterozygotes as well as the genes Lap, Mdh-1, Mdh-2, Me-2, Pgi and Xdh across populations. However, Pgm showed heterozygous excess. Null alleles appeared in Lap and Mdh loci, which could be responsible for this disequilibrium, at least in Mdh, because the increase in frequencies of null alleles was also related to the increase in heterozygote deficit. Values of genetic distance between populations have been used to cluster the populations, and the F-statistics showed a mean FST value across loci of 0.023 and Mdh-1 surveyed the highest value (0.046). At the same time, heterogeneity in allelic frequencies found in all genes indicated genetic differentiation between populations, in spite of the high dispersal of the species, probably due to local selective conditions.</dc:description><dc:description>Crassostrea angulata (Lamarck, 1819), conocida como ostra portuguesa, es una especie que se encuentra localizada en el suroeste de la península Ibérica, principalmente en la desembocadura de los ríos y en la cabecera de estuarios con sustrato duro disponible. Los datos sobre la genética de C. angulata son escasos y las poblaciones naturales de España (la principal fuente de esta especie) no habían sido estudiadas. La electroforesis es un buen detector de la variabilidad, y los polimorfismos isoenzimáticos han sido ampliamente usados en estudios genéticos. Este trabajo está basado en el análisis electroforético de siete loci y catorce puntos de muestreo entre la desembocadura del río Guadiana y el estrecho de Gibraltar y se ha encontrado un alto nivel de variabilidad genética en términos de número medio de alelos (mínimo de 2,71 y máximo de 3,71), polimorfismos (P₉₅ &amp;ge; 71,43 %) y heterocigosis media (H = 0,264). Todas las poblaciones mostraron un déficit de heterocigotos en los genes Lap, Mdh-1, Mdh-2, Me-2, Pgi y Xdh. En cambio, el sistema Pgm mostró un exceso de heterocigotos. Aparecieron alelos nulos en los loci Lap y Mdh que podrían ser los responsables del desequilibrio, al menos, en Mdh debido a que el incremento en la frecuencia de los alelos nulos estaba relacionado con un incremento en el déficit de heterocigotos. Las poblaciones se han agrupado según los valores de distancia genética obtenidos y también se han calculado los estadísticos F, obteniéndose un valor medio de FST en los loci de 0,023; Mdh mostró el valor mayor (0,046). Simultáneamente, la heterogeneidad en las frecuencias alélicas encontradas en todos los genes indicaban diferenciación genética entre las poblaciones, a pesar de la gran dispersión de la especie, probablemente debido a condiciones selectivas locales.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1337</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>