<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Relaciones entre la comunidad de anfípodos y las macroalgas a las que están asociados, en una plataforma rocosa del litoral central de Venezuela</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ayala, Y.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Diversidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>crustáceos</dc:subject><dc:subject>anfípodos</dc:subject><dc:subject>algas</dc:subject><dc:subject>complejidad morfológica</dc:subject><dc:subject>Venezuela</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper examines the relationships between the amphipod community on a rocky shelf off the central Venezuelan coast and seven species of associated algae which are morphologically different: Centroceras clavulatum (C. Agardh, 1822); Enteromorpha intestinalis (Linnaeus, 1753); Gracilaria cervicornis (Turner, 1808-1809); Sargassum platycarpum Montagne, 1856; Padina gymnospora (Kützing, 1859); Ulva fasciata Delile, 1813; and Laurencia filiformis (C. Agardh, 1822). The complexity of each alga was determined using different parameters: biomass (wet and dry weight), displaced volume, weight of sediments attached to the algae matrix, and fractal dimension. A total of 696 specimens were identified, of the species Hyale media (Dana, 1853); H. pygmaea Ruffo, 1950; Ampithoe marcuzzii Ruffo, 1954; Batea carinata Shoemaker, 1926; Bemlos unicornis (Bynum and Fox, 1977); Elasmopus rapax Costa, 1853; and E. pocillimanus (Bate, 1862). The highest species diversity was observed in the algae with the greatest morphological complexity (S. platycarpum and P. gymnospora). Regarding correspondence between the amphipods and the morphological complexity of the different macroalgae, we found that the fractal dimension was the best parameter for explaining the patterns of diversity and abundance of the amphipod species.</dc:description><dc:description>Se han estudiado las relaciones existentes entre la comunidad de anfípodos de una plataforma rocosa y siete especies de macroalgas a las que se asocian y que son morfológicamente diferentes: Centroceras clavulatum (C. Agardh, 1822); Enteromorpha intestinalis (Linnaeus, 1753); Gracilaria cervicornis (Turner, 1808-1809); Sargassum platycarpum Montagne, 1856; Padina gymnospora (Kützing, 1859); Ulva fasciata Delile, 1813 y Laurencia filiformis (C. Agardh, 1822). La complejidad del alga se caracterizó mediante las variables biométricas: biomasa (peso húmedo y seco), volumen desplazado, sedimentos retenidos y dimensión fractal. Se identificaron 696 ejemplares de las especies Hyale media (Dana, 1853); H. pygmaea Ruffo, 1950; Ampithoe marcuzzii Ruffo, 1954; Batea carinata Shoemaker, 1926; Bemlos unicornis (Bynum y Fox, 1977); Elasmopus rapax Costa, 1853 y E. pocillimanus (Bate, 1862). La mayor diversidad se registró en las algas más complejas (S. platycarpum y P. gymnospora). Respecto a la correspondencia entre los anfípodos y la complejidad morfológica de las macroalgas, se ha constatado que, de las diferentes variables biométricas analizadas, la dimensión fractal es la más adecuada para explicar los patrones de diversidad y abundancia de las especies.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1446</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>