<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Posible influencia sobre el comportamiento migratorio del atún rojo (Thunnus thynnus) de las distintas estrategias de marcado electrónico utilizadas en las almadrabas y en jaulas de engorde</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Serna-Ernst, J.M. (José Miguel) de-la</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abascal-Crespo, F.J. (Francisco Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abid, N.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Godoy-Garrido, M.D. (María Dolores)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-17T08:06:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-17T08:06:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Marcado electrónico, Jaulas de engorde, cultivo de atún rojo, marruecos</dc:subject><dc:description>The Spanish Institute of Oceanography has been carrying out diverse research projects since &#13;
1997 on stock structure and on migration patterns of bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus), using the &#13;
method of electronic tagging of adults. The results are provided to the stock assessment process &#13;
of this species that the ICCAT Scientific Committee conducts periodically. The tagging is &#13;
carried out in traps and fattening cages, observing marked differences in the movements of &#13;
tunas that were tagged in the water from those that were brought on board for tagging. In the &#13;
latter case, differences were also observed in the behavior of tunas that were released outside &#13;
the codend of the trap from those that were released together with the rest of the shoal that was &#13;
in the trap. With regard to the tagging and release of tunas in the fattening cages, it was &#13;
observed that the behavior after tagging is related to time the tunas spent in the farming &#13;
installations. The conclusion was reached that this type of tagging affects the natural behavior &#13;
of bluefin tuna in the first phase, after which they continue with their normal biological cycle &#13;
and their return to the natural habitat.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2176</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICCAT Collective Volume of Scientific Papers, SCRS/2012/122. 2012: 427-.434</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20136</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>CC0 1.0 Universal</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>