<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Influence of the oceanographic conditions during spring 2003 on the transport of the Prestige tanker fuel oil to the Galician coast</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Salgado, X.A. (Xosé Antón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Herrera, J.L. (Juan Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Otero-Tranchero, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Soriano-Sanz, J.A. (José Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Pola, C. (César)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Soto, C. (Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-06T12:41:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-06T12:41:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2006</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Prestige oil spill</dc:subject><dc:subject>PAHs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wind and density-driven circulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iberian current</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iberian poleward current</dc:subject><dc:description>Hydrographic data collected during the cruise HIDROPRESTIGE were combined with meteorological and dynamic data provided&#13;
by remote sensors and drifting/moored buoys, to describe the surface circulation of the Northern Iberian basin in March–April 2003. Sea&#13;
surface winds transported the floating Prestige oil slicks from the sinking area to the continental slope off the Rías Baixas in 1/2 month:&#13;
the surface current intensity was 2% of the wind intensity and it was rotated clockwise 5  from the wind direction. Mesoscale cyclonic and&#13;
anticyclonic structures west of 10º W increased the residence time of oil patches in the Northern Iberian basin, as compared with the&#13;
expected southwards flow of the Iberian current (IC). On the other hand, the Iberian poleward current (IPC) formed a marked surface&#13;
front with coastal waters, preventing the entry of fuel oil into the rías. PAHs in the surface layer during the cruise were &lt;0.5 ug L- 1,&#13;
except in the Galicia bank ( 1 ug L- 1; where the Prestige tanker was still leaking) and the vicinity of Cape Fisterra ( 1.5 ug L -1; where&#13;
the convergence front between the IPC and coastal waters vanished).</dc:description><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.marpolbul.2005.09.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Álvarez-Salgado, X.A., J.L. Herrera, J. Gago, P. Otero, J.A. Soriano, C.G. Pola, C. García-Soto. 2006. Influence of the oceanographic conditions during spring 2003 on the transport of the Prestige tanker fuel oil to the Galician coast. Mar. Pol. Bul., 53 (5-7): 239-249</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>