<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Balance energético en la almeja Ruditapes decussatus (Linnaeus, 1758)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez-Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Albentosa-Verdú, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Balance energético</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentración de alimento</dc:subject><dc:subject>tamaño</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of food ingestion and clam size on absorption efficiency, absorption rate and oxygen consumption of the clam Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758) was studied. Absorption efficiency (AE) was related to the ingestion rate (IR) following the non-lineal equation  AE = 0.836 + e-0.64/IR     (P   0.01; n = 26; r² = 0.321)  No significant relationship as found between AE and clam live weight, whereas there was a relationship between absorption rate (AR) and IR, following the expression  AR = 0.8248 IR - 0.0344     (P   0.001; n = 26; r² = 0.964)  The maintenance food ration for a 2 g (live weight) clam was estimated as 1.528 J/h, equivalent to a daily food ration of 0.08 mg organic matter/g clam live weight.</dc:description><dc:description>Se estudia el efecto de la ingestión de alimento y el tamaño de las almejas sobre la eficiencia de absorción, la tasa de absorción y el consumo de oxígeno de Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758). La eficiencia de absorción (EA) se relaciona con la tasa de ingestión (TI) siguiendo el modelo no lineal  EA = 0,836 + e-0,64/TI (P   0,01; n = 26; r² = 0,321)  Entre EA y el peso vivo de las almejas no existe una relación significativa, mientras que sí la hay entre la tasa de absorción (TA) y TI, y responde a la ecuación  TA = 0,8248 TI - 0,0344     (P   0,001; n = 26; r² = 0,964) La ración de mantenimiento de una almeja de 2 g de peso vivo es de 1,528 J/h, que se corresponde con una dieta diaria de 0,08 mg de materia orgánica por gramo de peso vivo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1243</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>