<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Persistence and Variation on the Groundfish Assemblages on Flemish Cap (NAFO Divisions 3M): 2004-2013</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira Gassent, A. (Adriana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Paz, X. (Xabier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Troncoso, D.M. (Diana María)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T11:20:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T11:20:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-12</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-30</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Data from the EU (Spain-Portugal) bottom trawl surveys in the Division 3M of the NAFO Regulatory Area (2004-2013) were analyzed to examine patterns on this zone of groundfish assemblage structure and diversity in relation to depth. 1699 hauls between 129 and 1460 m in depth were carried out. We focused on the 29 most abundant species, which made up 87.5% of the catch in terms of biomass. &#13;
&#13;
Assemblage structure was strongly correlated with depth. For the most part, changes in assemblages seem to be fairly continuous, although there were more abrupt changes at 600 m. Three main assemblages were identified. A shallow assemblage was found in the shelf. Assemblage I (Shallow) comprises the strata with depths lesser than 250 m and include American plaice (Hippoglossoides platessoides), witch flounder (Glyptocephalus cynoglossus) and Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua). Assemblage II (Intermediate) includes the strata with depths between 251 and 600 m and comprises Acadian redfish (Sebastes fasciatus), Arctic eelpout (Lycodes reticulates), thorny skate (Amblyraja radiata), longfin hake (Phycis chesteri), deepwater redfish (Sebastes mentella), spinytail skate (Bathyraja spinicauda) and Northern wolffish (Anarichas denticulatus). Three species are present in the two first assemblages: Atlantic wolffish (Anarichas lupus), golden redfish (Sebastes marinus) and spotted wolffish (Anarichas minor). Assemblage III (Deep) contains the depth strata greater than 601 m. Marlin-spike (Nezumia bairdii), scaly dragonfish (Stomias boa), Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides), sloane’s viperfish (Chaulonius sloani), black dogfish (Centroscyllium fabricii), Snubnosed spiny eel (Notacanthus chemitzii), roughhead grenadier (Macrourus berglax), roundnose grenadier (Coryphaenoides rupestris), blue antimora (Antimora rostrata), threadfin rockling (Gaidropsarus ensis), bean’s sawtoothed eel (Serrivomer beanii), Northern cutthroat eel (Syphanobranchus kaupii), lanternfish (Lampanyctus sp), vahls’s eelpout (Lycodes vahlii), Arctic skate (Amblyraja hyperborea) and Demon catshark (Apristurus sp) formed Assemblage III. Despite dramatic changes in biomass and abundance of the species in the area, the boundaries and composition of the assemblages seem to be similar to the period before the collapse. Extending depth range to 1460 m, no another boundaries were found. Although some changes were evident, the main ones were replacements of the dominant species in several assemblages and bathymetric range extension of distribution of some species. Acadian redfish and golden redfish appear to be the dominant species in the shallowest assemblage instead of Atlantic cod that were dominant in the period before the collapse in the area; redfish is the dominant species in the second shallow and intermediate assemblages.&#13;
&#13;
Diversity appears inversely related to biomass in the different assemblages. Despite the collapse in some species and the permanent fishing activity target to the North Shrimp (Pandalus borealis), redfish (Sebastes spp) and Greenland halibut, the overall pattern of demersal fish assemblages remains similar over time. This pattern is similar in other Atlantic areas; it indicates that changes in the fish populations in Northwest Atlantic have been produced on a large scale and are not limited to specific areas.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Consejo Científico de NAFO. (30/05/2014 - 12/06/2014. Halifax (Canadá)). 2014. NAFO SCR 14/009, Serial Number N6299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>NAFO SCR 14/009, Serial Number N6299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20281</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>