<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Zonas de interés para cultivos marinos: identificación y gestión para el desarrollo ordenado de la acuicultura en Andalucía</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías, J. C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>del Castillo, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Villarías, R. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gaiteiro, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Acuicultura marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>Andalucía</dc:subject><dc:subject>zonificación</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIG</dc:subject><dc:subject>gestión</dc:subject><dc:subject>ordenación</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study was carried out in order to establish a general framework of aquaculture planning and management, as well as to support marine aquaculture development, in Andalusia. A total of four studies were performed, two of them off-shore and two in-shore, with the collaboration of other Spanish regional and national authorities. After identifying, studying, and mapping the different parameters involved, a cartographic database using a Geographical Information System (GIS) was prepared, where both off-shore and terrestrial zones for aquaculture development can be identified. These results will make it possible to assess the suitability of the different areas studied, taking into account the levels of compatibility between aquaculture, administrative regulations, and also the physical-chemical characteristics of each zone.  As a result, this database can be used as a useful planning tool for both the public administration and the private sector when scouting for new farm sites in the future, thus contributing to the development of the marine aquaculture sector.</dc:description><dc:description>El objetivo ha sido establecer una planificación general de la acuicultura marina para favorecer su evolución en la región de Andalucía. Se han desarrollado un total de cuatro estudios, dos de ellos en mar abierto y los otros dos en áreas de dominio público marítimo terrestre. Para esta investigación se ha contando con la colaboración de las diferentes administraciones nacionales y regionales con competencias en las zonas estudiadas. Tras obtener y analizar los datos recopilados en las distintas demarcaciones, los resultados obtenidos han sido introducidos en un sistema de información geográfica (SIG), de manera que se han podido representar las condiciones administrativas y ambientales de los emplazamientos estudiados para definir el grado de interés que dichas zonas presentan para la acuicultura marina.  Como resultado se ha obtenido una herramienta de planificación útil no solo para la administración pública, también para el sector privado, que busca nuevos espacios para el cultivo, contribuyendo de esta forma al desarrollo de la acuicultura marina en Andalucía.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1343</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>