<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="fra">Commentaires sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus alalunga) Nord-Atlantique en 1980</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Antoine, L. (Loïc)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T09:54:38Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T09:54:38Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1981</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This document updates the previous study made by Bard and González-Garcés (1980). The data of the French-Spanish&#13;
surface fishery are complete up to 1979; the age composition table of catches including the &#13;
longline catches from 1978 are also updated.&#13;
A decrease in fishing effort of the surface fishery is noted, as well as a probable tendency for a &#13;
decrease in long­ line effort.&#13;
The estímate of recruitment was made with the help of multi-cohort analysis method developed by &#13;
Lauree (1980). A&#13;
comparison is made with the changes in the CPUE of the "bonites" of the French liners. In the two cases, the recruitment shows&#13;
a stability with a tendency to increase, since 1972.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document met à jour l'étude précédemment faite par BARD et GONZALEZ GARCES (1980). Les données &#13;
sur la pecherie de surface franco-espagnole sont complétées jusqu'a 1979; le tableau démogra­phique des captures incluant les captures palangrières de 1978 a également été mis à jour.&#13;
On note une baisse de l'effort de peche de la pecherie de surface, et une tendance probable à la baisse de l'effort palangrier.&#13;
L'estimation du recrutement a été menée a l'aide de la méthode d'analyse pluricohorte mise au point par LAUREC (1980). Une comparaison est faite avec l'évolution de la C.P.U.E. des "boni­tes'' des ligneurs français. Dans les deux cas, le recrutement montre une stabilité, avec une tendance à &#13;
augmenter, depuis 1972.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento actualiza el estudio anteriormente efectua­do por Bard y Conzalez Garcés (1980). Los datos referentes a la pesquería de superficie &#13;
franco-española están completos hasta 1979; el cuadro demográfico de capturas, que incluye las&#13;
capturas por palangre durante 1978, han sido igualmente puestos al día.&#13;
Se observa una disminución en el esfuerzo de pesca de la pesquería de superficie y una probable tendencia a la baja del esfuerzo palangrero.&#13;
El cálculo del reclutamiento ha sido efectuado con el método de análisis de cohortes múltiples, actualizado por Lauree (1980). Existe una comparación &#13;
hecha con la evolución de la&#13;
CPUE, de los bonitos pescados con curricán por los franceses. En ambos casos, el reclutamiento es &#13;
estable, con tendencia a aumentar, desde 1972.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1656</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Antoine, L., A. González-Garcés. 1981. Commentaires sur l'etat du stock de germon (Thunnus alalunga) Nord-Atlantique en 1980. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 15 (2): 222-231</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>