<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Análisis de la pesquería española de pez espada, Xiphias Gladius, entre los años 1973 y 1981</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rey-Salgado, J.C. (Juan Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:52:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:52:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1983</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In this paper the Spanish swordfish fishery data between 1973 and 1981 are revised.&#13;
Information about this fishery in 1981 is provided and&#13;
trends in the mean weight of individuals (1975-1981) and CPUE are analyzed for these last nine &#13;
years.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent document passe en revue les données de la pêcherie espagnole d'espadon pour la période 1973-81.&#13;
Des informations sont également fournies sur cette pêcherie pour l'année 1981, et une analyse des tendances des poids moyens individuels de 1975 a  1981, ainsi que de la CPUE des neuf dernieres années, est effectuée.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se hace una revisión de los datos de la pesquería española de pez espada entre los años 1973 - 1981.&#13;
Se da asimismo, información sobre dicha pesqueria en 1981 y  se hace un análisis de las tendencias de &#13;
los pesos medios individuales de 1975 a 1981 y  de las CPUE de los útimos 9 años.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Garcés, A.G. and J.C. Rey. 1983. Análisis de la pesquería española de pez espada, Xiphias Gladius, entre los años 1973 y 1981. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 18 (3): 622-628</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>