<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Densidad y hábitos alimentarios de Oreaster reticulatus (Linnaeus, 1758) (Echinodermata, Asteroidea) en praderas de fanerógamas marinas de Venezuela</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Villamarín-Pérez, M.A. (María Amelia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Penchaszadeh, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Atienza, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Densidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitos alimentarios</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oreaster reticulatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Asteroidea</dc:subject><dc:subject>Venezuela</dc:subject><dc:description>We determined the density and size ranges of individuals of the asteroid Oreaster reticulatus (Linnaeus, 1758) from three populations off the Venezuelan coast. Individuals were collected by hand, visually inspecting 100 m² quadrates in the localities of Caño León (N = 10), Las Luisas (N = 24), and Mochima (N = 5). In the field, each individual was turned upside down, in order to determine the condition of the asteroid's stomach (everted vs retracted), and to describe the substrate to which they were associated. Individuals were preserved and their gut contents were analyzed in the laboratory. Oreaster reticulatus (L., 1758) was found 65 % of the times on silt and in areas with low seagrass densities. At Las Luisas, the density of the asteroid was 0.0075 indiv/ m². However, in Caño León and Mochima, densities were at least one or two orders of magnitude higher, reaching 0.072 indiv/m² and 0.2 indiv/m², respectively. Size ranged between 4 and 9.3 cm at Las Luisas; 7.8 and 12.6 cm at Caño León; and 8.5 and 16.5 cm at Mochima. Of the 55 asteroids studied in Caño León, 63.64 % had the stomach everted on the silty substrate. Of these, 14.28 % were feeding on a colonial tunicate, and 71.34 %, on a filamentous alga. Spines of sea urchins were found in 19.05 % of all the specimens collected in Mochima. Previous observations, from laboratory experiments, have shown individuals of Oreaster reticulatus actively predating upon individuals of Lytechinus variegatus (Lamarck, 1818).</dc:description><dc:description>Con la finalidad de determinar la densidad y talla del asteroideo Oreaster reticulatus (Linnaeus, 1758) presente en tres localidades de fanerógamas de Venezuela, se realizaron cuadrículas de 100 m² en las estaciones de Caño León (10), Las Luisas (24) y Mochima (5). La dieta de O. reticulatus (L., 1758) se determinó levantando cada uno de los ejemplares conseguidos y observando si el estómago se encontraba evertido y la naturaleza del sustrato. El asteroideo se encontró un 65 % de las veces sobre sedimento o en áreas de poca vegetación. La densidad en la localidad de Las Luisas fue de 0,0075 indiv/m², siendo un orden de magnitud mayor en Caño León (0,072 indiv/m²), mientras que Mochima presentó las mayores densidades (0,2 indiv/m²). De las 55 estrellas estudiadas en Caño León, un 63,64 % tenía el estómago evertido sobre el sedimento, mientras que un 12,73 % lo tenía sobre las hojas de las fanerógamas. En Mochima, un 14,28 % de los ejemplares se alimentaba de sedimento, un 14,28 % lo hacía sobre un tunicado colonial y un 71,34 % estaba sobre algas filamentosas. Del total observado en Mochima un 19,05 % presentaba espinas de erizos envueltas en el estómago. En laboratorio se realizaron experiencias de depredación sobre el erizo Lytechinus variegatus (Lamarck, 1818), comprobándose depredación activa sobre el mismo, en un periodo aproximado de 6 horas. La talla (radio mayor) de O. reticulatus osciló entre 4 y 9,3 cm en Las Luisas, entre 7,8 y 12,6 cm en Caño León y entre 8,5 y 16,5 cm en Mochima.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1311</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2001. 17 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>