<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Cetacean-fishery interactions in Galicia (NW Spain): results and management implications of a face-to-face interview survey of local fishers</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Goetz, S. (Sabine)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Read, F.L. (Fiona)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Santos, M.B. (María Begoña)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pita, C. (Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pierce, G.J. (Graham)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:50:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:50:07Z</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Galicia (NW Spain) is an important fishing region with a high potential for cetacean–fishery interactions. Cetacean depredation on catch&#13;
and damage to fishing gear can potentially lead to substantial economic loss for fishers, while cetacean bycatch raises conservation concerns.&#13;
With the aim of gathering information on the types and scale of interactions and of suggesting possible management strategies, we&#13;
conducted face-to-face interviews with fishers in local fishing harbours, in particular to identify specific problematic interactions and to&#13;
quantify the level of economic loss and bycatch rates associated with these interactions. We found that cetacean–fishery interactions&#13;
are frequent, although damage to catch and fishing gear by cetaceans was mostly reported as small. Nevertheless, substantial economic&#13;
loss can result fromcommon bottlenose dolphins (Tursiops truncatus) damaging coastal gillnets and from short-beaked common dolphins&#13;
(Delphinus delphis) scattering fish in purse-seine fisheries. Cetacean bycatch mortality was reported to be highest for trawls and set gillnets,&#13;
and probably exceeds sustainable levels for local common and bottlenose dolphin populations. Although interviewdata may be biased due&#13;
to the perceptions of interviewees, and therefore should be interpreted with care, the methodology allowed us to covermultiple sites and&#13;
fisheries within a reasonable time frame. Minimizing cetacean–fishery interactions requires the implementation of case-specific management&#13;
strategies with the active participation of fishers. For set gillnet and purse-seine fisheries, the use of acoustic deterrent devices&#13;
(pingers) may prevent cetaceans from approaching and getting trapped in the nets. For trawl fisheries, where bycatch appears to be particularly&#13;
high at night in water depths of 100–300 m, possible solutions include the implementation of time/area closures and the relocation&#13;
of some fishing effort to deeper waters.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1867</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES Journal Of Marine Science, 71, 3. 2014: 604-617</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1093/icesjms/fst149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>6729</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>