<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Reproducción y fecundidad de la faneca Trisopterus luscus (Linnaeus, 1758) (Pisces, Gadidae) en la región central del mar Cantábrico</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Merayo, C. R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Reproducción</dc:subject><dc:subject>maduración sexual</dc:subject><dc:subject>fecundidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>trisopterus luscus</dc:subject><dc:subject>faneca</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper studies the reproduction of the bib Trisopterus luscus (Linnaeus, 1758) of the coast of Asturias (northern Spain), taking into account its size and age at first maturity, spawning season and fecundity. Spawning takes place from December to April. The first-maturity length and age were 220 mm and 1.7 years for females, and 234 mm and 1.8 years for males. Throughout the spawning season of this species, several oocyte batches undergo asynchronous development, which makes fecundity estimation difficult. Total fecundity was related to size, weight of the eviscerated fish, weight of the gonads, and age. Correlations were significant in all cases. The equation which best predicts total fecundity is log F = 1.1561 + 2.7056 log LT; r = 0.88.</dc:description><dc:description>Se examinó la reproducción de la faneca Trisopterus luscus (Linnaeus, 1758) de las costas de Asturias, teniendo en cuenta la talla de primera maduración sexual, la época de freza y la fecundidad. La freza tiene lugar entre diciembre y abril. Las tallas y edades de primera maduración fueron 220 mm y 1,7 años en las hembras y 234 mm, y 1,8 años en los machos. El desarrollo de los oocitos es asincrónico lo cual dificulta la estimación de la fecundidad. Se relacionó la fecundidad total con la talla, peso del pez eviscerado, peso de las gónadas y edad, obteniéndose correlaciones significativas en todos los casos. La ecuación que mejor predice la fecundidad total es log F = 1,1561 + 2,7056 log LT; r = 0,88.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1504</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1996. 12 (1)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>