<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Indicadores del estado nutricional de larvas de rodaballo Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Paulsen, H.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Poulsen, N. E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Estévez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Olmedo-Herrero, M. (Mercedes)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Korsgaard, B.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lavens, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Burkhardt-Holm, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-05-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Larva</dc:subject><dc:subject>nutrición</dc:subject><dc:subject>inanición</dc:subject><dc:subject>rodaballo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scophthalmus maximus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Psetta maxima</dc:subject><dc:description>Se han analizado diferentes indicadores del estado nutricional de larvas de rodaballo Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758) alimentadas de hasta 53 días de edad y se han comparado con los de otras larvas sometidas a condiciones de inanición. Los indicadores estudiados fueron longitud, peso seco, condición relativa larvaria, diámetro del otolito, histología digestiva de las larvas, contenido en ácidos grasos, ácido ascórbico, RNA, DNA Y proteínas. Los procesos de inanición se llevaron a cabo a los 3, 9, 16, 23 Y 27 días de edad y los análisis de estas larvas fueron comparados con los de larvas alimentadas de las mismas edades. Durante las primeras 24 horas de inanición, las goticulas lipídicas en las células epiteliales desaparecen por completo del intestino. Después, la condición relativa disminuye aproximadamente el 5% por día y el diámetro relativo del otolito se incrementa en el 5% por día. Se producen también disminuciones en el peso seco, el contenido proteico, los niveles de ácidos grasos 18:1Ω-9, 20:5Ω-3 (EPA) y los de otros ácidos grasos altamente insaturados (Ω-3 HUFA), y en la relación RNA/DNA. Sin embargo, la mayoría de los indicadores investigados muestran una alta variación, incluso entre las distintas experiencias de cultivo realizadas, por lo que se concluye que las gotículas de lípidos en las células epiteliales del intestino, la condición relativa y el diámetro relativo del otolito son las únicas variables que pueden ser útiles para detectar un proceso de inanición en larvas de rodaballo.</dc:description><dc:description>Nutritional status indicators of larvae of turbot Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758) were investigated in feeding and starving turbot larvae from hatching up to an age of 53 days. The study included the whole-larvae parameters of length, dry weight and relative condition; the organ-related characteristics otolith diameter and intestinal histology; and the biochemical indicators fatty acids, ascorbic acid, RNA, DNA and total protein. Starvation was started at day 3, 9, 16, 23 and 27, and starved larvae were compared with feeding larvae from the same rearing group. After onset of starvation, lipid droplets in the intestinal epithelial cells disappeared within 24 h. Later; the influence of starvation also became apparent in most of the other indicators studied. Relative condition decreased by about 5%/day and relative otolith diameter increased by about 5%/day. A histologically observed total disappearance of chylomicrons and lipid droplets in the intestinal epithelial cells was in accordance with a drop in dry weight, protein content, and the fatty acids 18:1Ω-9, 20:5Ω-3 (EPA) and Ω-3 HUFA (Highly Unsaturated Fatty Acids), as well as the RNA/DNA ratio in starved larvae. However, most of the indicators studied showed such a high variation between individual rearing groups that only the parameters lipid droplets in intestinal epithelial cells, relative condition and relative otolith diameter seem useful for detecting starvation in turbot larvae.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1484</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1998. 14 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>