<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Modelos de variación de la composición bioquímica de Mesopodopsis slabberi (Van Beneden, 1861) (Crustacea: Mysidacea)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Azeiteiro, U.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fonseca, J.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pastorinho, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Morgado, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Marques, J. C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Composición bioquímica</dc:subject><dc:subject>estuarios</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mesopodopsis slabberi</dc:subject><dc:description>In order to assess the patterns of variation in the biochemical composition of Mesopodopsis slabberi (Van Beneden, 1861) in a temperate estuary, we determined the protein, carbohydrate, chitin and lipid contents of freshly caught immature individuals (juveniles), adult males, and adult females during two annual cycles. Statistical analysis (anova) revealed significant differences in the biochemical components between months and development stages for the months analysed. All of the biochemical components showed significant differences between months. Environmental and trophic conditions were the main processes determining seasonal patterns of variation in biochemical composition. The results of complementary experiments carried out to estimate the effects of starvation on biochemical composition showed that the process of starvation consumed mostly carbohydrates, and also that these compounds, together with lipids, were the most affected during the refeeding period. Our findings also indicate that all body reserves were almost fully replenished during refeeding, except for carbohydrates and lipids in adult females and immature individuals (juveniles) and protein content in immature individuals (juveniles). These results indicate that responses to fasting in M. slabberi may be dependent on individual development stages, an observation that is corroborated by the significant differences in the biochemical components observed between development stages for the months analysed. Reproduction was also found to influence patterns of variation in biochemical composition.</dc:description><dc:description>Para evaluar los modelos de variación de la composición bioquímica de Mesopodopsis slabberi (Van Beneden, 1861) en un estuario templado, determinamos los contenidos en proteínas, hidratos de carbono, quitina y lípidos de individuos inmaduros (juveniles) recién cogidos, y de machos y hembras adultos, durante dos ciclos anuales. Los análisis estadísticos (anova) revelaron, para los meses analizados, diferencias significativas en las composiciones bioquímicas entre los meses y los estados de desarrollo. Todos los componentes bioquímicos mostraron diferencias significativas entre meses. Los factores ambientales y tróficos fueron los principales procesos que determinaron los modelos estacionales de variación en la composición bioquímica. Los resultados de los experimentos complementarios, realizados para determinar los efectos de la inanición sobre la composición bioquímica, pusieron de manifiesto que los procesos de inanición consumen, fundamentalmente, hidratos de carbono, y, también, que estos compuestos, junto con los lípidos, son los más afectados durante el periodo de vuelta a la alimentación. Nuestros descubrimientos indicaron también que todas las reservas corporales son casi completamente repuestas durante la vuelta a la alimentación, excepto los hidratos de carbono y los lípidos en las hembras adultas y en los inmaduros (juveniles), y el contenido en proteínas en los juveniles. Estos resultados indican que las respuestas al ayuno de M. slabberi podrían depender del estado de desarrollo individual, observación que es corroborada por las diferencias significativas observadas, en los componentes bioquímicos y para los meses analizados, entre los distintos estados de desarrollo. Se encontró también que la reproducción tenía influencia sobre los modelos de variación de la composición bioquímica.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1537</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>