<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">La fiscalidad en el sector español de la acuicultura</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Argente-Álvarez, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Vegazo, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz-Molina, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Acuicultura</dc:subject><dc:subject>fiscalidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>liderazgo en costes</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRPF</dc:subject><dc:subject>modalidad de estimación del beneficio</dc:subject><dc:description>Cost leadership is one of the strategies that the Spanish industry must follow in order to remain competitive. Its implementation requires paying special attention to the tax issues, among others, due to their impact on the final cost of the product and, consequently, its market potential. Income taxes are a source of great concern to the aquaculture sector, as is usually the case within any industry. Among the many different aspects of taxation that are of special interest to this sector, two have recently received a great deal of attention: the impact of stock assessment on profit estimates, and the possible inclusion of the mussel farming in the Spanish income tax system's so-called objective estimation regime. Therefore, the present paper's analysis focuses on these two issues.</dc:description><dc:description>El liderazgo en costes es una estrategia obligada en el sector acuícola español, y su implantación requiere dedicar atención especial al ámbito tributario, entre otros, por su incidencia en el coste final del producto y en la capacidad competitiva. La fiscalidad es un aspecto que provoca una preocupación profunda en este sector, como en cualquier sector económico en general. De los distintos, y no escasos, aspectos de la fiscalidad que suscitan interés, quizá dos de ellos han inquietado especialmente: la incidencia de la valoración de existencias en la determinación del beneficio y la posible inclusión del sector mejillonero en el régimen de estimación objetiva del impuesto sobre la renta de las personas físicas (IRPF). Por ello se han seleccionado dichos temas como centro de análisis del presente trabajo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>