<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Hábitos alimentarios de los lenguados Solea vulgaris Quensel, 1806 y Solea senegalensis Kaup, 1858 en el bajo estuario del río Guadiana (el Algarve) (sur de Portugal): Primeros resultados</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Sá, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bexiga, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vieira, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Veiga, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Erzini, K.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Contenido estomacal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solea</dc:subject><dc:subject>lenguados</dc:subject><dc:subject>Guadiana</dc:subject><dc:subject>estuario</dc:subject><dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject><dc:description>The feeding habits of two major species of sole, the common sole Solea vulgaris Quensel, 1806 and the Senegalese sole Solea senegalensis Kaup, 1858 were studied in the lower estuary of the Guadiana River (Algarve, southern Portugal). An evaluation of the number, weight, and feeding coefficient of prey types showed that S. vulgaris feed on a limited variety of prey (only Polychaeta and Tanaidacea) and present low-intensity feeding activity, with small differences in diet between seasons. S. senegalensis also have a low-diversity diet (with only one more taxa, Amphipoda), but exhibit more intense feeding activity which varies seasonally, although with little seasonal variation in the relative importance of the main preys. The diet composition of these two species suggests feeding specialization.</dc:description><dc:description>Se han examinado los hábitos alimentarios de dos especies importantes de lenguado, Solea vulgaris Quensel, 1806 y Solea senegalensis Kaup, 1858, en el bajo estuario del río Guadiana (en el Algarve, sur de Portugal). La actividad depredadora de S. vulgaris es escasa y la variedad de sus presas limitada (únicamente poliquetos y tanaidaceos), con una ligera variación estacional de la dieta. S. senegalensis también se alimenta de una variedad reducida de presas, aunque con un taxón más (anfípodos), y tiene una actividad depredadora mayor, que varía estacionalmente, aunque no hay variaciones en la importancia relativa de la presa con la estación del año. La composición de la dieta de estas dos especies sugiere la especialización de su alimentación.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>