<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Hydrographic features and dynamics of blue whiting, mackerel and horse mackerel in the bay of biscay, 1994-1996. A multidisciplinary study on sefos.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Porteiro-Lago, C. (Carmen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cabanas-López, J.M. (José Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valdés-Santurio, L. (Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Carrera-López, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Franco-Fernández, C. (Concha)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lavín, A. (Alicia)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-20T12:52:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-20T12:52:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1996</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Hydrographic and climatic conditions have been found to be one of the most important factors that&#13;
can influence the distnbution and behaviour of adults, juveniles and early stages of fish. This&#13;
relationship, which has been pointed out by several authors, is also the main objective ofthe SEFOS&#13;
project, which studies the relationship between the distnbutions and migrations of commercially&#13;
important fish species and the oceanography of the European shelf edge. Within this framework, the&#13;
Bay of Biscay presents special oceanographic and climatic conditions that could intluence the&#13;
aggregations of food and larvae in retention areas throughout this zone, which is one of the most&#13;
important nursery areas for several fish species and seasonal migrations of blue whiting, horse&#13;
mackerel and mackerel&#13;
This paper presents the results of a multidisciplinary study of the relationship between the&#13;
oceanographic conditions ofthe Bay ofBiscay and the distribution ofboth early stages - eggs and&#13;
larvae - and adult fish ofhorse mackerel, mackerel and blue whiting for the period 1994-1996.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Porteiro, C. et al. 1996.Hydrographic features and dynamics of blue whiting, mackerel and horse mackerel in the bay of biscay, 1994-1996. A multidisciplinary study on sefos. ICES CM Doc. 1996/S:13: 29p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>