<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Utilización de biotransformados de Laminaria saccharina (L.) Lamouroux en la alimentación de la semilla de la almeja Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez-Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Salinas, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fuertes-Roig, M.C. (María del Carmen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Biotransformado</dc:subject><dc:subject>células detríticas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laminaria saccharina</dc:subject><dc:subject>alimentación</dc:subject><dc:subject>cultivo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:description>A production technique for single cell detritus (SCD) from Laminaria saccharina (L.) Lamouroux was developed based on the sequential action of two enzymes, endoglucanases and cellulases, and two bacteria isolated in our laboratories: CECT-5255 and CECT-5256, which have high levels of cellobiosic, proteolytic and alginolytic activity. Using this technique, L. saccharina meal is transformed into a suspension of algal cells and detritus of less than 20 m in diameter, which can easily be filtered and digested by bivalve molluscs.  A feeding trial carried out with Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758) seed clams showed that L. saccharina SCD, when used as their sole diet, got 40 % of the seed growth achieved with a microalgal diet (control diet). When the SCD was used in a mixed diet, it could substitute up to 90 % of the microalgae, with comparable or even higher growth rates than exclusive microalgal diets.</dc:description><dc:description>En este estudio se desarrolla una técnica de producción de biotransformados de Laminaria saccharina (L.) Lamouroux basada en la acción secuencial de enzimas (endoglucanasas y celulasas) y dos bacterias aisladas en laboratorios del Instituto Español de Oceanografía: las cepas códigos CECT-5255 y CECT-5256 de la CECT, que presentan una alta actividad celobiósica, proteolítica y alginolítica. Con dicha técnica, la harina de L. saccharina se transforma en una suspensión de células libres y detritos algales de tamaño inferior a 20 m, perfectamente capturables y digeribles por los moluscos bivalvos.  Los diversos ensayos realizados en la alimentación de semilla de la almeja Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758) ponen de manifiesto que con este biotransformado de L. saccharina, utilizado como único alimento, se obtienen crecimientos de alrededor del 40 % del logrado con fitoplancton. Si se mezcla con fitoplancton, puede sustituir hasta el 90 % del alimento vivo obteniéndose crecimientos equivalentes, incluso superiores, a los de las dietas algales puras.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1394</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>