<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A first approach to assess the impact of bottom trawling over Vulnerable Marine Ecosystems on the High Seas of the Southwest Atlantic</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez-Portela, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Yepes, J. (Juan)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cristobo, J. (Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Muñoz-Recio, A. (Araceli)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Parra-Descalzo, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ríos, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Río-Iglesias, J.L. (José Luis) del</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Tel, E. (Elena)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Polonio-Povedano, V. (Virginia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Patrocinio, T. (Teodoro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vilela, R. (Raúl)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Barba, M.J. (María José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Marín, P. (Pedro)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>InTech</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-20T12:16:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-20T12:16:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Benthos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bottom trawl</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fishing activities</dc:subject><dc:subject>High seas</dc:subject><dc:subject>SW Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vulnerable marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:description>This study deals with ongoing concerns over the effects of bottom trawling on benthic vulnerable marine ecosystems on the high seas of the Southwest Atlantic. The collected information during five multidisciplinary research cruises led to the identification of areas where the presence of vulnerable organisms was considered significant in the southern part of the study area. Great densities and biomass of octocorals, sponges, colonial scleractinians (Bathelia candida) and big hydrocorals (Errina spp., Cheiloporidion pulvinatum, Sporadopora sp. and Stylaster densicaulis), considered indicators of vulnerable ecosystem, were found at intermediate depths (401- 1000 m), whereas shallow waters (&lt;400 m) presented the lowest biomass, abundance and diversity of species. In deeper strata (1001-1500 m), the pennatulid octocorals (Order PENNATULACEA) were the most abundant amongst benthic cnidarians. A list of the most common species of cold-water corals and deep-water sponges collected during the research cruises is presented. As the presence of this type of sensitive organisms was mainly observed at depths deeper than those where bottom trawling takes place, we can preliminarily conclude that current fishing activities of Spanish trawlers operating in the area have low impact on them. Further research is needed to determine if the lack of sensitive species in shallow waters (&lt;400 m) is an effect of persistent bottom trawling by international fleets for over 50 years.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Biodiversity in Ecosystems - Linking Structure and Function. Blanco, J. (Juan); Yueh-Hsin, L. (Lo) (ed.). InTech. Rijeka (Croatia). 2014. 350 pp: 1-25</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20005</dc:identifier><dc:type>bookPart</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>