<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Edad y crecimiento de la chopa Spondyliosoma cantharus (Linnaeus, 1758) (Sparidae) en las islas Canarias</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Lorenzo-Nespereira, J.M.ª</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Pajuelo, J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Chopa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spondyliosoma cantharus</dc:subject><dc:subject>islas Canarias</dc:subject><dc:subject>edad</dc:subject><dc:subject>crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:description>The authors determined the age and growth of black seabream Spondyliosoma cantharus (Linnaeus, 1758) caught off the Canary Islands, using the otolith interpretation method. Annual rings are clear in the otolith cross-sections. Two rings, one associated with fast-growing periods (summer) and the other with slow-growing periods (winter) are deposited each year on the otoliths. The specimens ranged from 9.4 cm - 38.6 cm in total length, with ages of 0-9 years. Individuals grew quickly until the third year of life, at which they had reached more than 50 % of their maximum length. The Von Bertalanffy growth curve parameters were: L∞ = 44.09 cm, K = 0.23 year⁻¹, and t0 = -0.34 years. The growth found for this sample of black seabream is very similar to that reported for the species in other regions.</dc:description><dc:description>Se determinan la edad y el crecimiento de la chopa Spondyliosoma cantharus (Linnaeus, 1758) de las islas Canarias por interpretación de los anillos visibles en los otolitos. Los anillos de crecimiento anuales se observan con claridad en las secciones transversales de los otolitos. Cada año se forman dos anillos, uno de crecimiento rápido en los meses de verano y otro de crecimiento lento durante el periodo invernal. Los ejemplares, de tallas que oscilan desde 9,4 hasta 38,6 cm de longitud total, presentan edades comprendidas entre 0 y 9 años. El crecimiento de los individuos es rápido durante los primeros años de vida, alcanzando al tercero más de la mitad de su talla máxima. Los parámetros de la curva de crecimiento de Von Bertanlanffy son: L∞ = 44,09 cm, K = 0,23 años⁻¹ y t0 = -0,34 años. El crecimiento de la chopa en las islas Canarias es similar al observado para la misma especie en otras regiones.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1533</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1997. 13 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>