<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Programa de recuperación para Acipenser sturio L., 1758: la propuesta alemana</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Kirschbaum, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gessner, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:24Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Recuperación</dc:subject><dc:subject>declive</dc:subject><dc:subject>stock de cría</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitat</dc:subject><dc:subject>gestión del agua</dc:subject><dc:description>Acipenser sturio L., 1758 was a prevalent species of the fish communities in all major German rivers' waters until the end of the 19th century. Since then, the population sizes decreased rapidly due to overfishing, pollution, and hydro-construction, and the last remaining population was observed in the Eider River until the 1960s. Recently, specimens have been observed in German waters only rarely. Until the end of the 1980s, neither politicians nor ecologists considered reestablishment measures feasible in Germany. In 1994, joint activities of scientists and aquaculturists led to the foundation of the Society to Save the Sturgeon (A. sturio L.), aimed at co-ordinating the A. sturio restoration measures in Germany. A federal programme was initiated, supporting in part the various subprojects dealing with this matter. Under a scientific co-operation agreement with France's Cemagref, the Institute of Freshwater Ecology and Inland Fisheries (IGB) in Berlin received, in May 1996, juvenile A. sturio for the establishment of a broodstock, as an ex-situ measure to save the species. The IGB also carries out research on various aspects of A. sturio biology. Together with the Cemagref, genetic analyses of remaining populations and specimens are conducted as a basis for a long-term breeding programme. The broodstock development is carried out in co-operation with the Research Institute for Agriculture and Fisheries of Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, where experiments with model species are performed within the framework of the programme. Evaluation measures for the restoration of A. sturio in the Odra and Elbe Rivers are carried out by the Society in collaboration with the Institute for Inland Fisheries of Poland. Additionally morphometric and meristic studies are conducted at the University of Rostock to characterise the species. The evaluation of the remaining populations in other European regions, in particular Romania and Georgia, is considered an important element for its future development. International co-operation in general is an essential aspect of future attempts to save the species.</dc:description><dc:description>Acipenser sturio L., 1758 fue una especie frecuente en las comunidades de peces en las aguas de todos los grandes ríos alemanes hasta finales del siglo XIX. Desde entonces, los tamaños de las poblaciones disminuyeron rápidamente debido a sobrepesca, contaminación y obras hidráulicas, y la última población superviviente fue observada en el río Eider hasta la década de los sesenta. Recientemente, sólo raramente han sido observados ejemplares en aguas alemanas. Hasta finales de los ochenta, ni políticos ni ecologistas consideraron posibles las medidas de recuperación en Alemania. En 1994 las actividades conjuntas de científicos y acuicultores llevaron a la fundación de la Sociedad para Salvar el Esturión (A. sturio L.), aspirante a coordinar las medidas de recuperación de A. sturio en ese país. Se inició un programa federal, financiando en parte distintos subproyectos. Bajo un acuerdo científico de cooperación con Cemagref de Francia, el Instituto de Ecología Dulceacuícola y Pescas Interiores (IGB) de Berlín recibió, en mayo de 1996, juveniles de A. sturio para el establecimiento de un stock de cría, como una medida ex-situ para salvar a la especie. El IGB también investiga sobre varios aspectos de la biología de A. sturio; colabora con Cemagref en la realización de análisis genéticos de las poblaciones y de ejemplares remanentes como base para un programa de cría a largo plazo. El desarrollo del stock de cría se lleva a cabo en cooperación con el Instituto de Investigación para Agricultura y Pesca de Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, donde se realizan estudios experimentales con especies modelo dentro del marco del programa. Las medidas de evaluación para la recuperación de A. sturio en los ríos Oder y Elba se establecen por la Sociedad para Salvar el Esturión en colaboración con el Instituto de Pescas Interiores de Polonia. Adicionalmente se llevan a cabo estudios morfométricos y merísticos en la Universidad de Rostock para caracterizar a la especie. La evaluación de las poblaciones remanentes en otras regiones europeas, particularmente en Rumania y Georgia, se considera un elemento importante para su futuro desarrollo. La cooperación internacional en general es un aspecto esencial de los intentos futuros para salvar a la especie.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1347</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>