<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Edad y crecimiento del besugo americano Beryx splendens Lowe, 1834 (Osteichthyes, Berycidae) en aguas de las islas Canarias</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rico, V.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lorenzo, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Santana, J. I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, J. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Edad</dc:subject><dc:subject>crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>besugo americano</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beryx splendens</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atlántico centro-oriental</dc:subject><dc:subject>Canarias</dc:subject><dc:description>Age and growth of the alfonsino Beryx splendens Lowe, 1 834 off the Canary Islands were studied, based on otoliths readings of 643 individuals, ranging from 182 to 389 mm in fork length (Lf) and from 120 to 1 396 g in total weight, caught in waters of the Canary archipelago between March 1996 and July 1998. The fork length-total weight relationships were described using the parameters: a = 1.2 ˟  10-5 and b = 3.12. Whole otoliths show clear growth rings. Two rings, one opaque and one hyaline, are laid down each year on the otoliths. The opaque ring is formed between May and October and the hyaline one between November and April. Individual ages ranged from 1 to 9 years. The Von Bertalanffy growth equation was characterised by the parameters: L∞ = 445.1 mm Fl, k = 0.15 years-1, and t0 = -3.41 years.</dc:description><dc:description>En el presente trabajo se aborda el estudio de la edad y crecimiento del besugo americano Beryx splendens Lowe, 1834 en Canarias mediante la interpretación de otolitos. Se analizaron 643 ejemplares con tamaños comprendidos entre 182 y 389 mm de longitud furcal (Lf) y entre 120 y 1 396 g de peso total, capturados en aguas del archipiélago entre marzo de 1996 y julio de 1998. La relación longitud furcal-peso total resultó estar caracterizada por los siguientes parámetros: a = 1,2 x 10-5; b = 3,12. Los anillos de crecimiento se observan con claridad en los otolitos enteros. Cada año se forman dos anillos, uno opaco entre los meses de mayo y octubre, y otro hialino entre noviembre y abril. La edad de los ejemplares examinados osciló entre 1 y 9 años. La ecuación de crecimiento en longitud de Von Bertalanffy fue definida por los parámetros siguientes: L∞ = 445,1 mm Lf; k = 0,15 años-1; t0 = -3,41 años.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2001. 17 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>