<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">By-catch composition of the striped soldier shrimp Plesionika edwardsii (Crustace: Decapoda: Pandalidae) experimental fishery in the Cape Verde Islands</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Triay-Portella, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Martín, V.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martins, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almeida, N</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Monteiro, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Correia, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Lorenzo, J.G. (José Gustavo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Santana, J.I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pajuelo, J.G.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lorenzo, J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, J.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:59:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:59:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>By-catch</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plesionika edwardsii</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cape Verde Islands</dc:subject><dc:subject>Experimental fisheries</dc:subject><dc:description>This work focuses on the by-catch composition of Plesionika edwardsii experimental fishery in the Cape&#13;
Verde Islands. Obtaining information on abundance, composition and lifecycle of species involved in this&#13;
potential fishery is useful, in order to ensure its sustainable development under an ecosystem approach.&#13;
The first step towards this goal is the description of catches.&#13;
Four 15-day research surveys were conducted on board the R/V Prof. Ignacio Lozano: April 2010 (S˜ao&#13;
Vicente and Santa Luzia islands), November 2011 (Santiago island), March 2012 (Boa Vista island,)&#13;
and July 2012 (Sal and S˜ao Nicolau islands). The working depths were between 66 and 458 m depth.&#13;
A standardized innovative fishing gear was used, so-called multiple semi-floating shrimp traps. Each&#13;
fishing line was composed by 40-65 traps operating around 2.4 m above the seafloor, using Decapterus&#13;
macarellus (Carangidae) as unique bait of the traps.&#13;
Multiple semi-floating shrimp traps is a passive fishing system that allows catch and release sea significant&#13;
part of the unwanted catches, as in the case of Chondrichthyes or Anguilliformes, reducing the&#13;
fishing impact on non-target species.&#13;
The main by-catch was composed of 53 species belonging to three groups including Chondrichthyes&#13;
(three families and three species), Crustacea (11 families and 19 species) and Osteichthyes (15 families&#13;
and 29 species). Plesionika edwardsii, the target species of this fishery, represented 97.8% of&#13;
the catch in terms of abundance and 40.1% in biomass. By-catch represented 59.9% of total catch in&#13;
terms of biomass. Osteichthyes (87.5%) were the dominant group and was represented by the following&#13;
main families; Sparidae (33.9%), Moridae (32.5%), Muraenidae (32.5%), Scorpaenidae (9.9%) and&#13;
Tetraodontidae (9.8%). Chondrichthyes (11.6%) were composed by Centrophoridae (65.3%) and Triakidae&#13;
(34.1%). Finally, Crustacea (1.9%) were chiefly composed by Pandalidae (79.1%). However,&#13;
different families represented by specific species were found to be dominant around each island. Sparidae&#13;
were the dominant family represented by Pagellus acarne (46.2% of total by-catch) at S˜ao Vicente,&#13;
and by Dentex macrophthalmus (42.6%) at Boa Vista. Tetraodontidae with Sphoeroides pachygaster&#13;
(25.9%) and Sparidae with P. acarne (25.1%) were the co-dominant families in the by-catch around&#13;
Santa Luzia. Muraenidae were the dominant family represented by Gymnothorax polygonius (69.4%)&#13;
at Sal, and by Muraena helena (63.4%) at S˜ao Nicolau. Finally, Scorpaenidae with Pontinus kuhlii&#13;
(22.3%) and Moridae with Physiculus cyanostrophus (22.1%) were the co-dominant families of the bycatch&#13;
around Santiago.&#13;
Acknowledgements: This study is part of the PROACTIVA 1-2 (2009-2012) and MARPROF-CV&#13;
(2010-2014) projects, in the framework of the Canary Islands Government and UE PCT MAC 2007-&#13;
2013 programmes respectively.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2595</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV International Symposium of Marine Sciencies. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (España)). 2014. Pag. 481. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Pag. 481</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20348</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>