<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Analysis of the effect of atmospheric oscillations on physical condition of pre–reproductive bluefin tuna from the Strait of Gibraltar</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Báez, J.C. (José Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías-López, A.D. (Ángel David)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Castro de, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez-Gesteira, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gimeno, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Real, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T10:36:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T10:36:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Arctic Oscillation, Atmospheric Oscillations, Clime, North Atlantic Oscillation, Fisheries, Tuna</dc:subject><dc:description>Analysis of the effect of atmospheric oscillations on physical condition of pre–reproductive bluefin tuna from&#13;
the Strait of Gibraltar&#13;
.— The aim of this study was to explore the possible effects of atmospheric oscillations:&#13;
North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) and Arctic Oscillation (AO), on the physical condition of bluefin tuna (&#13;
Thunnus&#13;
thynnus&#13;
). We estimated a fitness ratio from 3,501 pairs of length–weight data based on bluefin tuna caught in&#13;
bait–boat fisheries before the spawning season (January, February and March), for each length class and year.&#13;
In order to obtain a single fitness ratio (K–mean) per year we determined the average for all length classes.&#13;
We also evaluated&#13;
Le Cren’s condition index (K&#13;
LC&#13;
).&#13;
We observed significant positive correlations between the&#13;
atmospheric oscillations and both physical condition indexes. In the case of K–mean, the AO explained 75%&#13;
of the observed variability. Regarding K&#13;
LC&#13;
, the NAO explained approximately 73% of the observed variability,&#13;
while the AO explained 70% of the observed variability. The increase in physical conditions of bluefin tuna&#13;
in association with positive atmospheric oscillations could be mediated by the increase in the prevalence of&#13;
strong trade winds. We concluded that the increase in the prevalence of strong westerly winds, mediated by&#13;
a positive AO or NAO, favours the trip from the Atlantic to the Mediterranean by reducing energy costs due&#13;
to migration and by increasing the supply of nutrients at the surface by the mixing of deep water and surface&#13;
water in local areas such as the Strait of Gibraltar.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Animal Biodiversity and Conservation, 36(2). 2013: 225-233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20315</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>