<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A possible relation between sardine fisheries and oceanographic conditions in NW Spanish  coastal waters</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cabanas-López, J.M. (José Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Porteiro-Lago, C. (Carmen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Varela-Rozados, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-19T10:20:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-19T10:20:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1989</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The NW of&#13;
more often&#13;
the shelf&#13;
sardine in&#13;
Spain is influenced by episodic upwelling which occurs&#13;
between March and October. The consequent enrichment of&#13;
waters is the origin of a very important fishery for&#13;
the area.&#13;
Eggs and larval survival is directly related to the oceanograph¡c&#13;
conditions between the date of birth and recruitment. Laryal&#13;
survival seems to be related essentially to weak upwelling&#13;
conditions since they favour the non-dispersion of eggs (larvae)&#13;
and allow growth of medium sized phytoplankters as suitable food.&#13;
On the other hand, strpng upwelling causes dispersion of eggs&#13;
(larvae) and favours growth of very large phytoplankton specles,&#13;
mainly diatoms, that are thought to be un-suitable food for&#13;
larvae. However, strong upwelling conditions are favorable for&#13;
sardine adults, since the large phytoplankters growing during&#13;
these upwelling events were found to be the main food supply, as&#13;
shown by the study of stomach contents.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Cabanas, J.M. ; Porteiro, C. ; Varela, M. 1989. A possible relation between sardine fisheries and oceanographic conditions in NW Spanish  coastal waters. ICES CM Doc. 1989/H:18: 7p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>