<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">An Assessment of American Plaice (Hippoglossoides platessoides) in NAFO Division 3M</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Alpoim, R. (Ricardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Troncoso, D.M. (Diana María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Avila-de-Melo, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T06:33:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T06:33:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-12</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-30</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The present assessment evaluates the status of the 3M American plaice stock. The catch at age matrix, EU survey&#13;
abundance at age and the respective mean weights were updated. The XSA and a VPA-type Bayesian model were&#13;
applied to this stock, but the XSA presented unrealistic results. The surveys and models indicate that the stock&#13;
suffered a continuous decline, even with catches kept at a low level since 1996. A general decrease is observed in&#13;
the biomass and abundance estimated by the several surveys. The EU survey and VPA-type Bayesian model&#13;
indicates only poor recruitment from 1991 to 2005 year class. SSB recorded a minimum in 2009, in recent years&#13;
SSB indices increase with the income of the strong 2006 year class in the SSB but in 2013 this increase seems to&#13;
halt mainly as there were fewer older fish (ages 16+). There are no changes in the perception of the stock status from&#13;
last assessment (2011). This stock continues to be in a poor condition, despite the apparent improvement of the&#13;
recruitment since 2006 (mainly due to the 2006 year class). Although the level of catches is low since 1996, this&#13;
stock has been kept at a low level.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Consejo Científico de NAFO. (30/05/2014 - 12/06/2014. Halifax (Canadá)). 2014. NAFO SCR Doc. 14/036, Serial Number N6332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>NAFO SCR Doc. 14/036, Serial Number N6332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20355</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>