<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Biological Reference Points for Cod Div. 3NO</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Costas, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Troncoso, D.M. (Diana María)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-17T13:24:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-17T13:24:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In 2011 Fisheries Commission Working Group of Fishery Managers and Scientists on Conservation Plans and Rebuilding Strategies (WGFMS-CPRS) reviewed the cod 3NO Conservation Plan and Rebuilding Strategy (CPRS) and proposed a new one that was approved by the Fisheries Commission in 2011. The new reference points values approved for the 3NO cod CPRS were the following: Blim = 60,000 t, Bisr = 120,000 t, Flim = 0.30 and Bmsy = 248,000 t. Concerns were raised on the high uncertainty and the lack of confidence intervals of the reference points. The WGFMS-CPRS agreed that the values of Bisr and Bmsy should be further reviewed by the Scientific Council and the Fisheries Commission.&#13;
In 2012, Scientific Council noted that: the approach used in estimation of the maximum sustainable yield (MSY) reference points may not be advisable in the case of Div. 3NO cod due to the high uncertainty in the stock-recruit relationship for this stock. Scientific Council recommends the use of proxies based on the yield per recruit (YPR) and spawner per recruit (SPR) to estimate the reference points for cod in Div. 3NO. The proxies for the limit references points estimated through YPR were very similar to the Limited reference points approved. However, the Bmsy estimated based on the YPR was different to the Bmsy estimated last year. The aim of this document is to revise the values for the Bmsy references points based on the YPR-SPR. This document presents new Bmsy references points based on the YPR-SPR taking in account same ideas expressed during the 2012 SC meeting.&#13;
It could be proposed a value around F0.1 (0.19) or F35% (0.20) as a possible Ftarget. The reason to choose this value is that a small reduction in the YPR supposes a precautionary level of F that has a very low probability to be higher than Flim = Fmax (less than 5%) and it is similar to SPR F35%. A good candidate for Btarget based on the YPR estimation could be the equilibrium SSB estimated with all the recruitments produced by the SSB bigger than Blim. A good Btarget level could be the equilibrium SSB of the proposed Ftarget (F0.1 or F35% ) estimated with all the recruitments produced by the SSB bigger than Blim. This gives a value around 180,000-185,000 tons. In the cod 3NO case, and taking a similar definition for Bisr as the ICES MSYBtrigger, a Bisr candidate could be a value around 120,000 ton if we take a very low probability (less than 5%) or 135,000 ton if we take a low probability (less 10%). These values came from biomass point which is expected with a low probability in a fully productive stock which is fished at Ftarget proposed.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1721</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González-Costas, F., D. González-Troncoso. 2013. Biological Reference Points for Cod Div. 3NO. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 13/040, Serial Nº N6195: 10p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>