<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Recent changes in the distribution and abundance of marine seaweeds in the north of the Iberian Peninsula and its relation to climate change</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez, B.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Anadón, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Araújo, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arenas, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrontes, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bárbara, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Díez, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Duarte, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández, Á.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Tasende, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gorostiaga, J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Juanes, J.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lafuente, Á.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Peteiro, C. (César)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Puente, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rico, J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Viejo, R.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Santander</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-09T10:00:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-09T10:00:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The Cantabrian coast is an area of special biogeographical interest because the existence of a marked longitudinal gradient, mainly related to the sea surface temperature (SST) and the intensity and frequency of upwellings. Since the late 19th Century, there is scientific evidence on the existence of fluctuating expansion-retraction periods of certain seaweeds, mainly fucoids and laminarians, associated with cooling or warming events. However, since the beginning of the 21st Century, macroalgae have experienced dramatic changes to date unknown. Populations of brown and red algae typical of cold-temperate waters such as Himanthalia elongata, Fucus vesiculosus, F. serratus, Laminaria hyperborea, L. ochroleuca, Saccorhiza polyschides and Chondrus crispus have undergone significant declines in abundance and even disappeared in many localities. Subtidal stands of Gelidium corneum have undergone a decline in biomass and coverage in the warmest part of the thermal gradient (the Basque coast), while populations westward from Cape Peñas (Asturias) are in expansion. In contrast, SST warming may have enhanced the growth of non-native species and algae with warm water affinities such as calcareous algae, Stypocaulon scoparium, Cystoseira tamariscifolia and Bifurcaria bifurcata. In Galicia, westem area characterized by colder waters, the response of vegetation is more heterogeneous, varying between locations and habitats. Models of distributions based on future climate scenarios suggest massive declines of several canopy species along the Cantabrian coast. The disappearance or decline of these habitat-forming macrophytes may have severe consequences on the functioning of the ecosystem. Increases in SST, air temperature, irradiance, intensity and frequency of storm waves and transparency of coastal waters, in combination with a reduction of upwelling frequency and intensity could be factors involved in those changes detected in macroalgae distribution. In addition, in some cases, the resilience of sorne macroalgae, can be compromised by human pressures (i.e. waste discharges, exploitation), accelerating their decline.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XIV International Symposium on Oceanography of the Bay of Biscay. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Bordeaux, France). 2014. ISOBAY. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ISOBAY</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20079</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>