<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Caracterización elemental de la concha vestigial del pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Napoleão, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pinheiro, T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sousa Reis, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Microprobetas nucleares</dc:subject><dc:subject>concha vestigial</dc:subject><dc:subject>microelementos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Octopus vulgaris</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study represents the first elemental distribution and composition characterization of the vestigial shell in Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797. Ten specimens of O. vulgaris were collected monthly between January and July 2002, on the central coast of Portugal. Using nuclear microscopy, Rutherford Backscattering Spectrometry (RBS) and Particle Induced X-ray Emission (PIXE) techniques, it was found that along vestigial shell transversal sections, the elemental concentrations were differential. Most striking were those of P, Ca, S, and Cl. At the core of the vestigial shell, high concentration levels of Ca and P were determined, declining towards the periphery. Also, trace concentrations of elements such as Fe, Cu and Zn were found to be higher in the external rings than the inner regions. Future complementary studies of vestigial shell chemical composition, as well as histology studies, are necessary to gain better understanding of the vestigial shell microstructure.</dc:description><dc:description>Se presenta la primera caracterización de la distribución elemental y de la composición de la concha vestigial del pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797. Diez muestras de O. vulgaris fueron recogidas mensualmente, entre enero y julio del 2002, en la costa central de Portugal. Utilizando microscopía electrónica, técnicas de espectrometría Rutherford de refracción (RBS) y emisión de rayos X inducida por partículas (PIXE), se pudieron encontrar, a lo largo de las secciones transversales de la concha vestigial, diferencias en las concentraciones elementales, en particular en las de P, Ca, S, y Cl. En el núcleo de la concha vestigial, se pudieron determinar altas concentraciones de Ca y P, que se iban reduciendo hacia la periferia. Asimismo, se encontraron microelementos, como el Fe, Cu y el Zn, a concentraciones que eran mayores en los anillos externos que en las regiones internas. Para una mejor comprensión de la microestructura de la concha vestigial, es necesario llevar a cabo estudios complementarios a éste, y también estudios histológicos.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1250</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>