<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Densidad, biometría y proporción de sexos de Solen marginatus (Pulteney, 1799) (Mollusca: Bivalvia) en la ría del Eo (noroeste de España)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Remacha-Triviño, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Bivalvos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solenidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>navajas</dc:subject><dc:subject>densidad</dc:subject><dc:subject>morfometría</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zostera</dc:subject><dc:description>Data on the density, biometry and sex ratio of the razor clam Solen marginatus (Pulteney, 1799) are presented. Sampling was performed on the natural beds of Reme and La Reguerira, located in Eo ria, the largest inlet of Asturias region (northwest of Spain). The species was found to be widely distributed along both beds, with no significant differences in density among the different areas compared. The mean density of the species was 31 indiv m-2. Power regression: shell length vs. drained weight, was found to be the most suitable fit. Areas covered by the phanerogam Zostera marina were the most densely inhabited. S. marginatus is diecious, being distributed according to a sex ratio of 1:1. No hermaphrodite specimens were found.</dc:description><dc:description>Se investiga la densidad, biometría y proporción de sexos de Solen marginatus (Pulteney, 1799) en los bancos naturales de Reme y La Regueira situados en la ría del Eo, el mayor estuario del Principado de Asturias (noroeste de España). La especie se encuentra ampliamente distribuida a lo largo de ambos bancos, sin existir diferencias significativas entre las distintas áreas comparadas. S. marginatus presenta una densidad media de 31 indiv m-2. El mejor ajuste biométrico de la relación longitud de valvas versus peso escurrido corresponde a la regresión potencial. Las áreas cubiertas por la fanerógama marina Zostera marina son las más densamente pobladas. S. marginatus es una especie dioica, distribuida según una proporción de sexos 1:1. No se encontraron individuos hermafroditas.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>