<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Yield-per-recruit analysis of North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus Alalunga)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Weber, E. (Ed)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T09:45:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T09:45:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1985</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In this paper, a new North Atlantic albacore demographic table is presentad, based on a surface &#13;
catch-by age revision and new longline catch-by-age data.&#13;
With the demographic table, a cohort analysis was applied for the 1959-1971 cohorts, and &#13;
recruitment for the population and fishing mortality for each fishery were obtained. Based on &#13;
these data, a yield-per­ recruit analyais was done.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document présente un nouveau tableau dêmographique pour le germon&#13;
de  l'Atlantique  nord,   basé  sur  la  révision  des  prises  de  surface  par  âge&#13;
et de nouvelles príses palangrières par âge.&#13;
A  partir  de ce  nouveau   tableau   démographique,   une   analyse   de   cohortes a été &#13;
appliquée aux cohortes de 1959-1971, et le recrutement de la population et  la  mortalité  &#13;
par   pêche  de  chacune  des  pêcheries  ont  été obtenus. Une analyse de rendement par recrue a &#13;
été effectuée en se basant sur ces données.</dc:description><dc:description>En este documento se presenta una nueva tabla demográfica del rabil del Atlántico Norte, basada en &#13;
captura de superficie mediante revisión de la edad y una nueva captura con palangre por edad.&#13;
Con esta tabla demográfica, se aplicó un análisis de cohortes para&#13;
las cohortes de 1959-1971, obteniéndose el reclutamiento de la población y mortalidad por pesca &#13;
para cada pesquería. Basándose en estos datos, se&#13;
efectuó un análisis de rendimiento por recluta.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González-Garcés, A., E. Weber. 1985. Yield-per-recruit analysis of North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus Alalunga). Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 23 (2): 307-318</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>