<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A review of Mediterranean albacore (Thunnus alalunga) biology and growth studies</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Quelle-Eijo, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Zárate-Vidal, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lastra-Luque, P. (Patricia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:47:52Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:47:52Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2011</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Mediterranean stock</dc:subject><dc:subject>albacore</dc:subject><dc:subject>length-weight relationship</dc:subject><dc:subject>age determination</dc:subject><dc:subject>spine section ageing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thunnus alalunga</dc:subject><dc:description>Growth parameters are used to estimate catch-at-age data which is required as an input to&#13;
many stock assessment models. In the case of Mediterranean albacore stock no assessment has&#13;
ever done (ICCAT, 2009). This study presents growth information based on spine section&#13;
interpretation of annual time marks. A preliminary age-length key is presented for males,&#13;
females and two sexes combined, based on 249 albacore (Thunnus alalunga, Bonn.1788) spine&#13;
samples caught around the Balearic Islands and Western Mediterranean sea between June and&#13;
November from 2004 thru 2006. The albacore length ranged from 52 cm to 94 cm for females&#13;
and from 53 cm to 96 cm for males. Available length-weight data for 138 males and 162&#13;
females was analysed separately. New estimates presented in this study were compared with&#13;
assumed biological length-weight relationship for Mediterranean albacore stock. As well, mean&#13;
length by age estimates derived from the age-length-key obtained by reading fin ray section&#13;
were compared with other studies that used hard parts to age Mediterranean albacore.</dc:description><dc:description>Des paramètres de croissance sont utilisés pour estimer les données de prise par âge requis en&#13;
tant que valeur d’entrée pour de nombreux modèles d’évaluation des stocks. Dans le cas du&#13;
stock de germon de la Méditerranée, aucune évaluation n’a jamais été réalisée (ICCAT 2009).&#13;
Cette étude présente des informations relatives à la croissance en se fondant sur&#13;
l’interprétation des sections des épines des marques annuelles. Une clé âge-taille provisoire est&#13;
présentée pour les mâles, les femelles ainsi que pour les deux sexes combinés, reposant sur 249&#13;
échantillonnages d’épines de germons (Thunnus alalunga, Bonn, 1788) capturés dans les&#13;
environs des îles Baléares et de la Méditerranée occidentale entre le mois de juin et de&#13;
novembre 2004 jusqu’en 2006. La taille du germon oscillait entre 52 et 94 cm dans le cas des&#13;
femelles et entre 53 et 96 cm dans le cas des mâles. Les données disponibles de longueur-poids&#13;
des 138 mâles et 162 femelles ont été analysées séparément. De nouvelles estimations&#13;
présentées dans cette étude ont été comparées à la relation biologique postulée longueur-poids&#13;
du stock de germon de la Méditerranée. De plus, les estimations moyennes de la longueur par&#13;
âge (dérivées de la clé âge-longueur) obtenues sur la base de la lecture de la section du rayon&#13;
de la nageoire ont été comparées avec d’autres études qui ont recours à des pièces dures pour&#13;
déterminer l’âge du germon de la Méditerranée.</dc:description><dc:description>Se utilizan los parámetros de crecimiento para estimar los datos de captura por edad que se&#13;
requieren como entradas para muchos modelos de evaluación de stock. En el caso del stock de&#13;
atún blanco del Mediterráneo, no se ha realizado nunca una evaluación (ICCAT, 2009). Este&#13;
estudio presenta información sobre crecimiento basada en la interpretación de marcas anuales&#13;
de secciones de espinas. Se presenta una clave edad-longitud provisional para los machos, las&#13;
hembras y ambos sexos combinados basada en 249 muestras de espinas de atún blanco&#13;
(Thunnus alalunga, Bonn. 1788) capturado alrededor de las islas Baleares y en el&#13;
Mediterráneo occidental entre junio y noviembre de 2004 hasta 2006, inclusive. La longitud del&#13;
atún blanco oscilaba entre 52 cm y 94 cm para las hembras y entre 53 cm y 96 cm para los&#13;
machos. Los datos disponibles de longitud-peso para 138 machos y 162 hembras fueron&#13;
analizados por separado. Las nuevas estimaciones presentadas en este estudio se compararon&#13;
con la relación biológica longitud-peso asumida para el stock de atún blanco del Mediterráneo. Asimismo, las estimaciones de longitud media por edad derivadas de la clave edad-longitud y&#13;
obtenidas mediante la lectura de secciones de rayos de aleta, se comparan con otros estudios&#13;
que utilizaron partes duras para determinar la edad del atún blanco del Mediterráneo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1675</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Quelle, P., V. Ortiz de Zárate, P.L. Luque, M. Ruiz, X. Valeiras. 2011. A review of Mediterranean albacore (Thunnus alalunga) biology and growth studies. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 66 (5): 1882-1896</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>