<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Note on the observation of recruits of blue shark, Prionace glauca, in near coastal areas of Galicia (NW Spain) during the summer of 2013</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Mejuto-García, J. (Jaime)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Cortés, B. (Blanca)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramos-Cartelle, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abuin, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T11:32:47Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T11:32:47Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-10</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-09</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Blue shark</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nursery grounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coastal areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galicia</dc:subject><dc:description>This note presents a summary of several observations reported during the summer of 2013 regarding the presence of blue shark recruits in near coastal surface waters of NW Galicia, Spain. Although these observations may be considered incidental, they do, however, serve to change the general perception that this oceanic species does not reach littoral zones. Appearances of this species may be sporadic, taking place during particular years or life stages or at very specific times of the year. On the other hand, the presence of recruits in the coastal waters of Galicia during the summer –a sporadic occurrence well known by professional fishers- and the very near coastal observations reported in 2013 suggest that these areas might be a part of the nursery-recruitment grounds of blue shark in the NE Atlantic. This has been observed in other zones of the NE Atlantic where recruits or juvenile have been known to actively seek feeding grounds in areas of upwelling and high productivity during the summer period.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2348</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICCAT. (2013-09 - 2013-10. España). 2014. Collect. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 70(5): 2452-2461 (2014)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Collect. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 70(5): 2452-2461 (2014)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20157</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>