<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Inventory and mapping of habitats and fisheries footprint off “Amanay” and “El Banquete” seamounts (Southern Fuerteventura, Canary Islands). Criteria analysis for the marine protected area establishment</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Díaz, C. (Carolina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Falcón, Jesús Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pascual-Fernández, José Jaime</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Chinea-Mederos, Inés</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bartolomé-Baraza, A. (Aurora)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Jiménez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarralde-Vizuete, R. (Roberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Irusta, José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Díaz-Fernández, Pablo</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brito, Alberto</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:09:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:09:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Fuerteventura</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amanay</dc:subject><dc:subject>El Banquete</dc:subject><dc:subject>Montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ecosistemas marinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Áreas Marinas Protegidas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiversidad marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hidrografía</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geomorfología</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hábitats sensibles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Comunidades bentopelágicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Comunidades endobentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Comunidades epibentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biocenosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Arrecifes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conservación</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pesquerías</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pesquería artesanal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directiva Hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Idoneidad de hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modelización de comunidades e indicadores ecológicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gobernanza</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine Protected Areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sensitive habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endobenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benthopelagic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epibenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reefs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Artisanal fisheries</dc:subject><dc:subject>Habitat suitability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Community and ecologic indicators modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gobernance</dc:subject><dc:description>Sur de Fuerteventura is one of the areas chosen to be depicted in the frame of INDEMARES project.&#13;
The midpoint of the study area is located at 25 km from Fuerteventura and 65 km from Gran Canaria.&#13;
The main aim of the project was to end up with an inventory and mapping of habitats and fisheries&#13;
footprint off the study area, information which would let the administrations to establish a new Natura&#13;
2000 area, trying to reconcile protection of biodiversity with artisanal local economic activities.&#13;
Methodology approach complies with a multidisciplinary perspective, having described the area from&#13;
geological, oceanographic, biological and fisheries points of view. Several surveys have taken place&#13;
since 2009 to 2013 at Amanay and El Banquete waters. Data from VMS (Vessel Monitoring System)&#13;
were used, combined with interviews to users (fishers), sampling at landing points and onboard&#13;
observation programs, to describe the fishery uses in the area.&#13;
Thirteen different types of communities have been identified as “Habitat 1170, Reefs”, following Annex&#13;
1 from Habitats Directive (Council Directive 92/43/CEE) from European Union. All of them have three&#13;
dimensional structure and species with certain size turning these areas into important containers of&#13;
biodiversity and hot spots for shelter. About protected species by Habitats Directive, Centrostephanus&#13;
longispinus (Philippi, 1845) belongs to Annex IV. Chilomycterus reticulatus (Linnaeus, 1758) is included&#13;
in the Canary Islands Catalog of Protected Species as a vulnerable species. Within the Red List of&#13;
Threatened Species of the International Union for the Conservation of Nature, we can find several fishes&#13;
as endangered species, Squatina squatina (Linnaeus, 1758) as critically endangered, while in the area&#13;
can also be found several vulnerable species, special importance have several elasmobranchs species.&#13;
Subsequent studies about deep water white corals Lophelia pertusa (Linnaeus, 1758) and Madrepora&#13;
oculata Linnaeus, 1758, present in the study area, could conclude with these species inclusion in the&#13;
list.&#13;
Fishery activities identified during this study don’t interact with the bottom (tuna fishing with pole lines&#13;
and surface longlines for sworfish), or as the most frequent activity, artisanal hook and line local&#13;
fisheries, has very little impact on the bottom (arose from anchoring).&#13;
Ecological assessment results from values assigned to different community or species features or&#13;
parameters, not always in a quantitative manner, depending on their diverse nature. To use a totally&#13;
aseptic quantitative index is impossible; therefore, an often used tool is to resort to an expert panel&#13;
(group of experts) which members individually assign a value to each of the assessed parameters. This&#13;
solution absorbs bias produced by individual criteria. We established three value levels (low, medium&#13;
and high) for each of the twelve parameters used. After all we end up with a map of an ecological&#13;
assessment index (EAI) which is simple and weighs every parameter equally. Higher EAI is assigned to&#13;
bathial rocky bottoms with anthipatarians, closely followed by Corallium spp deep water coral reefs and&#13;
circalittoral rocky bottoms with Antipathella wollastoni (Gray, 1857). Bathial rocky bottoms with&#13;
Callogorgia verticillata (Pallas, 1766) and circalittoral rocky bottoms with calcareous algae concretions&#13;
and leafy algae have a mid-high EAI.&#13;
We find good collective action preconditions, which explain the capacity of human communities to&#13;
design, implement and enforce designed institutions to resources management and protection. Strong ishermen organizations, leadership among effective users and experience in conservation initiatives&#13;
and an a priori willing attitude are present. A proper step-zero at Sur de Fuerteventura marine protected&#13;
area will be provided by sharing available scientific information with users, public report and open and&#13;
full consultation about the protection possibilities, giving time to assimilation, involving local&#13;
stakeholders, and finding coordination among institutions and security bodies to ensure protection&#13;
measures enforcement.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2569</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón). 2014. 6.5. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>6.5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20322</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>