<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Biological Information on deep water Rose Shrimp Parapenaeus longirostris and Southern Pink Shrimpo Farfantepenaeus notialis in Mauritanian waters</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Isarch, E. (Eva); Romero, Z. (Zeneida); Expósito, P. (Pablo); Barro, S. (Sergio) and Sobrino, I. (Ignacio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T08:28:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T08:28:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-27</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-18</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Biological information, Parapenaeus longirostris, Farfantepenaeus notilais, Mauritanian fishing ground</dc:subject><dc:description>The deep-water rose shrimp Parapenaeus longirostris (Lucas, 1846) and the Southern pink shrimp Farfantepenaeus notialis (Pérez Farfante, 1967) have traditionally been the target species for the shrimper Spanish fleet operating in the Mauritanian fishing ground. In spite of their commercial interest, there is a general lack of knowledge about biological aspects referring to stock identification, growth, reproduction, alimentation, length structure, and natural mortality of these species. However, population and biological information is needed for stock assessment and management measures aiming a proper exploitation pattern and conservation of the exploited species. The first difficulty encountered for assessment refers to the accurate identification of biological stocks, which are currently assessed on a national basis whereas many of them are supposed to be transboundary. The scarcity of available biological information about the species in the area makes that stocks of P. longirostris and F. notialis, evaluated into the framework of the CECAF Working Group of Demersal Resources (North) have to be defined arbitrarily for assessment purposes, within the geographical limits of the countries where they are exploited. Therefore, one stock of P. longirostris and one stock of F. notialis are considered in Guinea-Bissau, without any biological base. As a consequence, many attempted assessments have to be rejected because of poor data and/or the uncertainty of the stock identity. &#13;
This work aims is to collect and analyzing the available information about different population and biological aspects of P. longirostris and F. notialis, the main target shrimp species in Mauritanian waters. This will contribute to a better knowledge of the biology of the species for assessment and management purposes.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2476</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>FAO/CECAF Working Group on the Assessment of Demersal Resources-North. (18/11/2013 - 27/11/2013. Fuengirola, Spain). . FAO/CECAF Workng Group</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>FAO/CECAF Workng Group</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20265</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>