<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Efecto de la temperatura y el cuidado materno sobre el desarrollo embrionario del pulpo comun (Octopus vulgaris)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Nande, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rosas, C. (Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Estévez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodrigues-dos-Santos-Domingues, P.M. (Pedro Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-29T11:33:03Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-29T11:33:03Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-09-25</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-09-23</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This work presents a study on the effects of two temperatures (14ºC and 18ºC) and incubation (artificial vs&#13;
.&#13;
female care) on the&#13;
embryonic development of&#13;
Octopus vulgaris&#13;
. Results showed that type of incubation does not affect the embryonic development.&#13;
For that reason data obtained from embryos incubated both artificial and by female were grouped. Temperature had a marked eff&#13;
ect&#13;
on embryonic development time of&#13;
O. vulgari&#13;
s&#13;
. At 18ºC, embryonic development was of 40 days, while at 14ºC it was of 64 days.&#13;
Temperature of 14 and 18°C were in the tolerance range of the species without affecting the morphological characteristics of&#13;
hatchlings. Results showed that temperature modu&#13;
lated in a different form the embryonic development, at least until stage XV&#13;
where embryos maintained at 18°C showed values of eggs and embryo length lower than observed in embryos maintained at 14°C.&#13;
t&#13;
he fact that there were no differences between hatchli&#13;
ngs maintained at both experimental temperatures demonstrates that&#13;
O.&#13;
vulgaris&#13;
embryos can be favored if spawn occurs at relatively low but increasing temperatures, which contributes to a shorter&#13;
planktonic life that will impact into the settle.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se realizó el estudio sobre el desarrollo embrionario del pulpo común a 14ºC&#13;
y a&#13;
18ºC&#13;
y el efecto del cuidado&#13;
materno. Los resultados muestran que la temperatura tiene un efecto marcado en el tiempo de desarrollo y que el cuidado mater&#13;
no&#13;
no&#13;
afecta al desarrollo embrionario. A 18°C el tiempo de desarrollo fue de 40 días y a 14°C el tiempo de desarrollo fue de 64 dí&#13;
as. A&#13;
18°C, se alcanzaron las estadios de Naef antes que a 14°C. Del mismo modo, el índice de desarrollo (DI) indica que caracterí&#13;
sticas&#13;
de diferenciación embrionaria fueron alcanzadas siempre antes a 18°C que a 14°C. Al final del desarrollo embrionario, no hubo&#13;
diferencias en la longitud de&#13;
l&#13;
huevo, para los dos supuestos. Sin embargo, el aumento de longitud del huevo fue más evidente y&#13;
visible cuando el embrión se comenzó a formar&#13;
y con valores mayores a 14ºC que a 18ºC&#13;
.&#13;
L&#13;
a longitud de embriones, la longitud del&#13;
brazo, el diámetro del ojo,&#13;
el&#13;
peso del vitelo y el peso del huevo fue similar (p&gt; 0,05) para ambas temperaturas, independientemente&#13;
del cuidado materno, al final del período de desarrollo embrionario. Del mismo modo, no hubo diferencias en el peso ni en&#13;
embriones ni en paralarvas reci&#13;
én eclosionadas a las dos temperaturas ni con cuidado materno ni sin el</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2088</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XIV Congreso Nacional de Acuicultura. (23/09/2013 - 25/09/2013. Gijón (España)). 2013. -. En: Libro de resumenes XIV Congreso Nacional de Acuicultura, . 2013: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20054</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>