<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Influence of food concentration on the physiological energetics and growth of Ostrea edulis larvae</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Beiras, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Springer</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-05-14T13:49:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-05-14T13:49:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1994-09</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>food concentration</dc:subject><dc:subject>physiological energetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>larvae growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ostrea edulis</dc:subject><dc:description>article</dc:description><dc:description>Feeding, respiration and growth rates of oyster (Ostrea edulis L.) larvae reared at five food levels were measured throughout the entire larval period. Energy budgets were derived as a function of alga (Isochrysis galbana Parke) food concentration. Ingestion rate (IR, cells h-1) and oxygen consumption rate ( VO2 , nl h-1) were almost isometric functions of larval size [ash-free dry weight, (AFDW, μg)], characterized by the equations: IR=803.9 AFDW1.13 and VO2 =4.85 AFDW1.09. Ingested ration was directly correlated to cell concentration up to a maximum at 200 cells μl-1, with further increases failing to support higher ingestion rates. Likewise, growth rate linearly increased with food ration up to 100 cells μl-1 (max. growth efficiency,K 1=25%) and reached a maximum at 200 cells μl-1 (growth rate=5.6 μm d-1), with further increases in food not supporting significantly faster growth. Maintenance ration was 2 to 3% daily dry weight (DW); optimum ration increased during larval development from 5 to 20% DW; maximum ration was 20% DW. During larval rearing, an increasing feeding schedule of 50, 100 and 200 cells μl-1 from Days 0, 5 and 10, respectively, is recommended.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0025-3162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1078</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Beiras, R. and Pérez Camacho, A. (1994). Influence of food concentration on the physiological energetics and growth of Ostrea edulis larvae. Marine Biology, 120: 427-435</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>