<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">MAPPING THE SPAIN´S EXCLUSIVE ECONOMIC ZONE IN THE GALICIAN MARGIN</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez-Ballesteros, M. (María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Aller, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Dávila, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Carbó, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Somoza, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Druet-Vélez, M. (María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez-Espinosa, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Catalán, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Muñoz, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>León, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Sede Central IEO</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T09:24:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T09:24:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>ZEEE, Galician Margin</dc:subject><dc:description>MAPPING THE SPAIN´S EXCLUSIVE ECONOMIC ZONE IN THE GALICIAN MARGIN&#13;
&#13;
Gómez Ballesteros, M.1(*), González-Aller, J-D. 2, Martín Dávila, J. 3, Carbó, A., 4, Somoza, L. 5,   Druet, M. 1, Martínez-Espinosa, S. 2, Catalán, M. 3, Muñoz, A. 4, León, R 5&#13;
1 Instituto Español de Oceanografía / C/. Corazón de María, 8, 28020 Madrid&#13;
2 Instituto Hidrográfico de la Marina / Pl. San Severiano, 3, 11007 Cádiz&#13;
3 Real Observatorio de la Armada, C/. Cecilio Pujazón s/n 11100Cádiz&#13;
4 Universidad Complutense de Madrid / Av Séneca, 2, 28040 Madrid&#13;
5 Instituto Geológico y Minero de España, Calle de Ríos Rosas, 23, 28003 Madrid&#13;
&#13;
(*)Corresponding Author: maria.gomez@md.ieo.es&#13;
&#13;
In the context of the Hydrographic and	 Oceanographic Research of the Spain´s Exclusive Economic program (ZEEE), operated jointly by Instituto Hidrográfico de la Marina (IHM) and Real Observatorio de la Armada (ROA) working in close collaboration with the Instituto Español de Oceanografía (IEO), Universidad Complutense de Madrid (UCM) and Instituto Geológico y Minero de España (IGME) have conducted seven oceanographic cruises in Galician waters (EEZ -01 -02 ZEE , ZEE -03, ZEE -06 -07 ZEE , ZEE- ZEE- 08 and 09). The main objective of the Spain´s Exclusive Economic Zone project is mapping the seafloor, carrying out a systematic bathymetric survey of the 200 miles that comprise this area. In addition, as secondary objectives were performed acquiring that complement other geophysical parameters characterizing the seafloor and seabed from the knowledge of other variables such as the Terrestrial Magnetic Field , Terrestrial Gravity field, sound velocity and seabed internal structure.&#13;
&#13;
For the acquisition of detailed and accurate information during these cruises, carried on board the BIO Hespérides, high-resolution geophysical techniques were used to compile the data and the bathymetry of the region was mapped using a multibeam system during which 100 per cent coverage was obtained. At the same time high-resolution parametric seismic reflection profiles, as well as gravity and magnetic, were also recorded in the survey areas. These systems provide data on bathymetry, quality seafloor, acoustics backscatter , gravimetry, magnetometry and subsurface structure and require the use of precise positioning techniques, so were used in conjunction with GPSD and inertial navigation systems.&#13;
&#13;
As a result of these oceanographic researches and post-processing, analysis and interpretation of the whole acquired data, a synthesis of 6 maps were published with 1:500.000 scale and corresponding to Bathymetric map, Geomorphology map, Geomagnetic Anomaly map, Bouguer and Free Air Anomaly maps and backscatter map.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
REFERENCIAS&#13;
J. Martín Davila, M. Catalán, M. Larrán, Sección de Hidrografía del IHM, A. Carbó, A. Muñoz-Martín, JL Granja, P. Llanes, L. Somoza, R. León, F.J. Gonzalez, M. Gómez-Ballesteros, M. Druet, and J. Acosta, 2014: Zona Económica Exclusiva Española (ZEEE): Margen Continental Gallego. Mapas Generales de batimetría, de anomalías Geomagnéticas, Graviméwtricas de Aire Libre y Bpouguer, Geomorfológico y Mosaico de Imágenes de Reflectividad (E. 1:500.000). Ministerio de Defensa. Secretaria General Técnica, NIPO: 083-12-230-3, DL: M-39518-2012</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2613</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Congreso de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas (Gran Canaria)). 2014. -. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20365</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>