<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Temporal trends od Cd, Cu, Hg, Pb and Zn in mussels (Mytilus galloprovincialis) from the Spanish North-Atlantic coast 1991-1999</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Besada, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fumega, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vaamonde, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T09:29:47Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heavy metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pollution monitoring</dc:subject><dc:subject>trends</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spain</dc:subject><dc:subject>JAMP</dc:subject><dc:description>Temporal trends for heavy metals  (Cd, Cu, Hg, Pb and Zn) in mussel ( Mytilus galloprovincialis) from the Galician&#13;
and Cantabrian areas in Spain, where samples were yearly collected from 1991 to 1999, are presented. This study was carried out by the Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo of the Instituto Español de Oceanografía  (I.E.O.) as part of the Spanish contribution to the Joint Assessment and Monitoring Programme  (JAMP) of the OSPAR Convention. The&#13;
experimental work and subsequent statistical treatment, following OSPAR procedures and guidelines, are described.&#13;
In order to carry out the statistical treatment of the data, median values of the different shell length classes were used for each contaminant, year and area. The Kendall t-b correlation coefficient was used with the purpose of&#13;
demonstrating the existence of a downward significant temporal trend in the pollution levels, according to the advice of ICES Working Group on Statistical Aspects of Environmental Monitoring. A decrease of copper levels was&#13;
detected in Vigo, Pontevedra and Arosa, of mercury in Pontevedra and A Coruña, of lead in Vigo, Pontevedra, A&#13;
Coruña and Bilbao and of zinc in Pontevedra and A Coruña. However, a cadmium positive trend was registered at Ria de Vigo. No significant trends were detected in the other cases.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2556</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>The Science of the Total Environment, 288. 2002: 239-253</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0048-9697(01)01010-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20310</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>