<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">The treatment with the probiotic Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11 of sepecimens of Solea senegalensis exposed to high stocking densities to enhance their resistance to disease</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Tapia-Paniagua, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vidal, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lobo, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Prieto-Álamo, M.J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jurado, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cordero, H.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cerezuela, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-de-la-Banda, I. (Inés)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Esteban, M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balebona, M.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moriñigo, M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Santander</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:35:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:35:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Solea senegalensis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>Density</dc:subject><dc:subject>Probiotic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pdp11</dc:subject><dc:description>Aquaculture industry exposes ﬁsh to acute stress events, such as high stocking density, and a link between&#13;
stress and higher susceptibility to diseases has been concluded. Several studies have demonstrated&#13;
increased stress tolerance of ﬁsh treated with probiotics, but the mechanisms involved have not&#13;
been elucidated. Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11 is a strain isolated from healthy gilthead seabream&#13;
(Sparus aurata L.) and it is considered as probiotics. The aim of this study was to evaluate the effect of the&#13;
dietary administration of this probiotics on the stress tolerance of Solea senegalensis specimens farmed&#13;
under high stocking density (PHD) compared to a group fed a commercial diet and farmed under the&#13;
same conditions (CHD). In addition, during the experiment, a natural infectious outbreak due to Vibrio&#13;
species affected ﬁsh farmed under crowding conditions. Changes in the microbiota and histology of&#13;
intestine and in the transcription of immune response genes were evaluated at 19 and 30 days of the&#13;
experiment. Mortality was observed after 9 days of the beginning of the experiment in CHD and PHD&#13;
groups, it being higher in the CHD group. Fish farmed under crowding stress showed reduced expression&#13;
of genes at 19 day probiotic feeding. On the contrary, a signiﬁcant increase in immune related gene&#13;
expression was detected in CHD ﬁsh at 30 day, whereas the gene expression in ﬁsh from PHD group was&#13;
very similar to that showed in specimens fed and farmed with the conventional conditions. In addition,&#13;
the dietary administration of S. putrefaciens Pdp11 produced an important modulation of the intestinal&#13;
microbiota, which was signiﬁcantly correlated with the high number of goblet cells detected in ﬁsh fed&#13;
the probiotic diet.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2629</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Fish &amp; Shellfish immunology, 41. 2014: 209-221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20381</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>closedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>