<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Comparative study of gonadal development of&#13;
Ruditapes philippinarum (Adams and Reeve) and Ruditapes decussatus (L.) (Mollusca: Bivalvia): Influence of temperature</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Fernández, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T13:11:05Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T13:11:05Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>gonadal development</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>histology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes philippinarum</dc:subject><dc:subject>hermaphroditism</dc:subject><dc:description>Laboratory experiments were used to study the influence of temperature on the reproductive behaviour of two&#13;
species of clam, Ruditapes decussatus and Ruditapes philippinarum, during their adaptation to the temperature conditions of&#13;
Galician coastal waters. In both species the rate of gonadal development was directly related to the increase in temperature.&#13;
At 14ºC the reproductive behaviour was similar, both species needing over 2 months to mature. At 18ºC, the rate of gonadal&#13;
development of R. philippinarum was greater than that of R. decussatus. Nevertheless, the results of this study confirm that&#13;
both species have adapted perfectly to the temperature conditions of the Galician Rias, though certain differences between&#13;
the reproductive behaviour of these species were detected. R. philippinarum accumulates oocytes prior to their partial or total&#13;
emission, while in the case of R. decussatus gametes are liberated continuously. In the early phases of its development, the&#13;
gonad of R. philippinarum is highly heterogeneous in nature, with up to 3 reproductive states being present at the same time,&#13;
while in R. decussatus gonadal development is much more uniform. Another major difference concerns the phenomenon of&#13;
reabsorption, common in R. philippinarum but very rare in R. decussatus. These characteristics may well result in a greater&#13;
reproductive activity in R. philippinarum than in R. decussatus, and a longer reproduction period in the former. They may&#13;
also represent a certain advantage for the adaptation of the foreign species (R. philippinarum) over the native species (R.&#13;
decussatus) to the temperature conditions of the Galician Rias.</dc:description><dc:description>Se llevaron a cabo experiencias de&#13;
laboratorio para estudiar la influencia de la temperatura en el comportamiento reproductivo de dos especies de almeja, R.&#13;
philippinarum y R. decussatus, en su adaptación a las condiciones térmicas en las costas de Galicia. En ambas especies la&#13;
tasa de desarrollo gonadal está directamente relacionada con el incremento de temperatura. A 14ºC el comportamiento reproductivo&#13;
es similar y ambas especies necesitan cerca de 2 meses para madurar. A 18ºC, la tasa de desarrollo gonadal de R.&#13;
philippinarum es mayor que en R. decussatus. No obstante, los resultados de este estudio confirman que ambas especies se&#13;
han adaptado perfectamente a las condiciones térmicas de las rías de Galicia, si bien, se detectan ciertas diferencias en su&#13;
comportamiento reproductivo. Así, mientras R. philippinarum acumula ovocitos antes de su emisión parcial o total, en el&#13;
caso e R. decussatus los gametos se liberan continuamente. En las primeras fases de su desarrollo, el aspecto de la gónada&#13;
de R. philippinarum es muy heterogéneo, presentándose hasta 3 estados reproductivos simultáneamente, mientras que en R.&#13;
decussatus el desarrollo gonadal es bastante más uniforme. Otra diferencia concierne al fenómeno de la reabsorción, común&#13;
en R. philippinarum, pero muy raro en R. decussatus. Estas características pueden sustentar una mayor actividad reproductiva&#13;
en R. philippinarum comparado con R. decussatus, y un mayor periodo reproductivo en el caso de la primera. Ello puede&#13;
también representar una cierta ventaje adaptativa, de la especie foráneas (R. philippinarum) frente la especie nativa (R. decussatus),&#13;
a las condiciones térmicas de las rías de Galicia.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0214-8358</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Scienta Marina 71(3) 2007: 471-484</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>