<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Large-scale meridional and zonal variability in the nitrogen isotopic composition of plankton in the Atlantic Ocean</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Marañón, E. (Emilio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bode, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-25T12:34:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-25T12:34:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-20</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>plankton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trichodesmium</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen fixation</dc:subject><dc:subject>ocean</dc:subject><dc:subject>subtropical</dc:subject><dc:description>The zonal (ca. 15º-40ºW along 26-29ºN) and meridional (ca. 30ºN-30ºS along 28º-29ºW) variability of δ15N of suspended particles and zooplankton (&gt;40 µm) was studied to assess the influence of nitrogen fixation in the isotopic budget of the tropical and subtropical Atlantic ocean. Two cruises were conducted in October-November 2007 and April-May 2008 comprising a zonal and meridional transect each. In the region between 30º-15ºN, the concurrently measured nitrogen fixation was insufficient to explain the consistent patch of suspended particles with δ15N &lt; 2‰ and points to a significant contribution of atmospheric deposition of light nitrogen to the isotopic budget. The equatorial region (15ºN-10ºS) is subject to intense nitrogen fixation, which, according to a two-end-member mixing model, may explain 40-60% of the observed δ15N in suspended particles and 3-30% in zooplankton. In the South region between 10ºS-30ºS, low values (&lt;4‰) were measured in suspended particles and zooplankton during 2008. The values of δ15N of suspended particles suggest that nitrogen fixation, which is usually low (&lt;10 µmol N m−2 d−1), may represent 50-60% of phytoplankton nitrogen in this region. Hence, diazotrophy in the South Atlantic may be more important than previously thought.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0142-7873</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2066</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Plankton Research, 36. 2014: 1060-1073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1093/plankt/fbu041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20033</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>