<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Report of the 2006 ICCAT workshop for  bluefin tuna direct ageing</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Marín, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Clear, N. (Naomi)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cort-Basilio, J.L. (José Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Megalofonou, P. (Persefoni)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Neilson, J.D. (John D.)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Neves dos Santos, M. (Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Olafsdottir, D. (Droplaug)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Cabello-Ródenas, M.C. (María Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:41:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:41:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Bluefin tuna</dc:subject><dc:subject>age determination</dc:subject><dc:subject>ageing comparison</dc:subject><dc:subject>validation</dc:subject><dc:subject>otoliths</dc:subject><dc:subject>vertebrae spines</dc:subject><dc:description>This report provides the presentations, discussions and conclusions from the ICCAT bluefin&#13;
tuna workshop for direct ageing held in Santander, Spain, in April 2006. The report&#13;
summarizes the ageing criteria used in the past and the agreements on future age determination&#13;
based on otoliths, vertebrae and spines. Advantages and disadvantages of each calcified&#13;
structure for ageing and border interpretation were discussed. It was considered that bluefin&#13;
tuna age interpretation becomes very difficult from age ten onwards using the whole vertebra&#13;
and the spine sections methods, but this last technique continues to be useful for older ages.&#13;
Otolith sections can be used for the whole age range. Participants agreed that none of these&#13;
three structures could be excluded from routine ageing because otoliths are not easily&#13;
available. Age estimations within the same structure and between different structures of the&#13;
same specimen were compared for several readers. Better precision was found between spine&#13;
readers compared to vertebra and otolith readers. Good age agreement was also achieved&#13;
between readers of spines and vertebrae from the same bluefin for ages less than 12 years.&#13;
Preliminary results from radiocarbon assays on otoliths were presented at the workshop and&#13;
gave promising outcomes for bluefin tuna age validation. Also, these suggested that bluefin&#13;
tuna can live longer than had previously been established and that a review is needed of the&#13;
currently used asymptotic size and growth rate for both stocks. Another important contribution&#13;
of the workshop was a manual for age interpretation.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent rapport recueille les présentations, discussions et conclusions de l’Atelier de&#13;
l’ICCAT chargé de la détermination directe de l’âge du thon rouge, tenu à Santander&#13;
(Espagne) au mois d’avril 2006. Le rapport résume les critères employés par le passé pour&#13;
interpréter l’âge et les accords pour la détermination future de l’âge à partir des otolithes,&#13;
vertèbres et épines. L’Atelier a discuté des avantages et des inconvénients de chaque structure&#13;
calcifiée pour déterminer l’âge et l’interprétation du type de bord. On a abordé la difficulté de&#13;
l’interprétation de l’âge des thons de plus de 10 ans au moyen de la vertèbre entière et des&#13;
sections des épines, bien que cette dernière méthode continue d’être utile pour les âges&#13;
avancés. Les sections d’otolithes peuvent être employées pour toute la gamme d’âges. Les&#13;
participants ont convenu qu’aucune de ces trois structures ne doit être exclue pour&#13;
l’interprétation de l’âge parce qu’il n’est pas toujours possible d’obtenir des otolithes. On a&#13;
comparé les lectures de l’âge à l’intérieur de la même structure et entre différentes structures&#13;
du même exemplaire pour divers lecteurs. On a obtenu une plus grande précision parmi les&#13;
lecteurs d’épines que parmi les lecteurs de vertèbres et d’otolithes. On a également obtenu un&#13;
bon accord entre les lecteurs d’épines et de vertèbres originaires du même exemplaire pour les&#13;
âges inférieurs à 12 ans. Les résultats préliminaires des essais de radiocarbone dans les&#13;
otolithes ont été présentés à l’Atelier, offrant de bonnes perspectives pour son utilisation dans la validation de l’âge. Ces résultats indiquent aussi que le thon rouge a une plus grande&#13;
longévité que ce qui avait été auparavant établi et qu’il est nécessaire de réviser la longueur&#13;
asymptotique et le taux de croissance actuellement utilisés. L’élaboration d’un manuel aux fins&#13;
de l’interprétation de l’âge a constitué une autre contribution importante de l’Atelier.</dc:description><dc:description>Este informe recoge las presentaciones, discusiones y conclusiones del congreso de ICCAT&#13;
para la determinación directa de la edad de atún rojo, celebrado en Santander, España, en&#13;
abril de 2006. El informe resume los criterios empleados en el pasado para interpretar la edad&#13;
y los acuerdos para la determinación futura de la edad a partir de otolitos, vértebras y espinas.&#13;
Se discutieron las ventajas y los inconvenientes de cada estructura calcificada para determinar&#13;
la edad y la interpretación del tipo borde. Se planteó la dificultad en la interpretación de la&#13;
edad de atunes mayores de 10 años utilizando la vértebra entera y las secciones de espinas, no&#13;
obstante este último método continúa siendo útil para edades mayores. Las secciones de&#13;
otolitos pueden ser empleadas para todo el rango de edades. Los participantes acordaron que&#13;
ninguna de estas tres estructuras deben excluirse para la interpretación de la edad porque no&#13;
siempre es posible obtener los otolitos. Se compararon las lecturas de edad dentro de la misma&#13;
estructura y entre diferentes estructuras del mismo ejemplar para varios lectores. Se obtuvo&#13;
una mayor precisión entre lectores de espinas comparada con las obtenidas por los lectores de&#13;
vértebras y otolitos. También se obtuvo un buen acuerdo entre lectores de espinas y vértebras&#13;
procedentes del mismo ejemplar para edades menores de 12 años. Los resultados preliminares&#13;
de las pruebas de radiocarbono en otolitos fueron presentados en el congreso, proporcionando&#13;
buenas expectativas para su uso en la validación de la edad. Estos resultados también indican&#13;
que el atún rojo es más longevo de lo que se consideraba y que es necesaria una revisión de la&#13;
longitud asintótica y de la tasa de crecimiento empleadas actualmente. Otra importante&#13;
contribución del congreso fue la elaboración de un manual para la interpretación de la edad.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1681</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodríguez-Marín, E., N. Clear, J.L. Cort, P. Megalofonou, J.D. Neilson, M. Neves dos Santos, D. Olafsdottir, C. Rodríguez-Cabello, M. Ruiz, J. Valeiras. 2007. Report of the 2006 ICCAT workshop for  bluefin tuna direct ageing. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 60 (4): 1349-1392</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>