<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Assessing sea grass meadows condition at  “El Río” Special Area of Conservation off  “La Graciosa e Islotes del Norte de Lanzarote” Marine Reserve</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, Y. (Yulimar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, E.L. (Erika Lucía)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Jiménez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-González, C.L. (Carlos Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Lorenzo, J.G. (José Gustavo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández, M.Á.R. (María de los Ángeles Rodríguez)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:41:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:41:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Cymodosea nodosa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine Reserve</dc:subject><dc:subject>La Graciosa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lanzarote</dc:subject><dc:description>Cymodosea nodosa meadows, known as ‘sebadales’ or ‘manchones’ at Canary Islands, represent EUNIS&#13;
habitat type code A5.5311, called Macaronesian Cymodocea beds. As it’s described at European&#13;
Union Habitats Directive (92/43/CEE) Annex 1, sea grass meadows belong to 1110 Sandbanks which&#13;
are slightly covered by seawater all the time, within Natura 2000 Network.&#13;
Several ‘sebadales’ throughout the archipelago are included in this Network as Special Areas of Conservation.&#13;
Cymodosea nodosa is regionally included within the Canary Islands Protected Species List&#13;
(Ley 4/2010), as a species ‘of interest to ecosystems of Canary Islands”, is usually found at a narrow&#13;
depth range (10 to 20 m of depth) and, on the whole, best structured meadows are settled at sheltered&#13;
bays, away from wave and current beating, flimsier at exposed areas. Deeper meadows are also sparser,&#13;
being C. nodosa replaced by green algae Caulerpa prolifera and Caulerpa racemosa, although mixed&#13;
algae-sea grass meadows are often found at different depths.&#13;
The project Assessment of marine flora (‘sebadal’, ma¨erl, ‘mujo’) of ‘La Graciosa e Islotes del Norte&#13;
de Lanzarote’ Marine Reserve, funded by ‘Viceconsejer´ıa de Pesca y Aguas de la Consejer´ıa de Agricultura,&#13;
Ganader´ıa, Pesca y Aguas’, Canary Islands Government, has had the aim of assessing sea grass&#13;
meadows condition and distribution at ‘El R´ıo’ Natura 2000 Network Special Area of Conservation, the&#13;
channel between La Graciosa and Lanzarote. ‘LA GRACIOSA 1311’ cruise was performed within the&#13;
framework of the project.&#13;
First of all previous information on sea grass shallow distribution (up to a depth of 20 m) in the study&#13;
area was reviewed. Afterwards, a tugged underwater video camera was used onboard of the Marine&#13;
Reserve Surveillance Vessel to update cartographic info performing a grid of sampling stations, covering&#13;
previously known distribution limits and verifying current presence/absence data and density.&#13;
Furthermore, population parameters were obtained in order to assess ‘sebadal’ condition. Fixed stations&#13;
were selected in regards to this process, and methodology applied on them was as follows: five radial&#13;
arranged transects were performed, identifying fragmentation (it estimates meadow continuity regarding&#13;
observed cover), density (mean value of several shoots number counts with 20 x 20 cm grids placed every&#13;
2 m), height (mean value in cm of 10 independent samples by transect) and fish and macroinvertebrate&#13;
species richness for each transect.&#13;
Graphic picture of sea grass density was made depending on two levels: low density level transects ( &#13;
10 shoots/grid ( 50 shoots/m2) and medium density level transects (  10 shoots/grid ( 50 shoots/m2).&#13;
Main study result is an estimate for the study region (‘El R´ıo’) and time of year of Cymodocea nodosa&#13;
population total distribution cover which comes to 1.640.076 m2, including a higher density ‘sebadal’ of&#13;
178.256 m2.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2574</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Congreso de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria). 2014. 2014. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20327</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>