<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Spring-time zooplankton size structure over the continental shelf of the Bay of Biscay</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Vandromme, Pieter</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Huret, Martin</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Urrutia-Lorente, Á. (Ángel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Nuevo-González, G. (Gonzalo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sourisseasu, Marc</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Petitgas, Pierre</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T09:20:17Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>zooplankton, size-structure, LOPC (laser optical plankton counter), Bay of Biscay</dc:subject><dc:description>Linking lower and higher trophic levels requires special focus on the essential role played by&#13;
mid-trophic levels, i.e., the zooplankton. One of the most relevant information regarding zooplankton&#13;
in terms of flux of energy lies in its size structure. In this study, an extensive dataset&#13;
5 of size measurements is presented, covering parts of the western European continental shelf&#13;
and slope, from the Galician coast to the Ushant front, during the springs from 2005 to 2012.&#13;
Zooplankton size spectra were estimated using measurements carried out in situ with the Laser-&#13;
Optical Plankton Counter (LOPC) and with an image analysis of WP2 net samples (200 μm&#13;
mesh size) performed following the ZooScan methodology. The LOPC counts and sizes parti10&#13;
cles within 100–2000 μm of spherical equivalent diameter (ESD), whereas the WP2/ZooScan&#13;
allows counting, sizing and identification of zooplankton from  400 μm ESD. The difference&#13;
between the LOPC (all particles) and the WP2/ZooScan (zooplankton only) was assumed to&#13;
provide the size distribution of non-living particles, whose descriptors were related to a set of&#13;
explanatory variables (including physical, biological and geographic descriptors). A statistical&#13;
15 correction based on these explanatory variables was further applied to the LOPC size distribution&#13;
in order to remove the non-living particles part, and therefore estimate the size distribution&#13;
of zooplankton. This extensive data set provides relevant information about the zooplankton size&#13;
distribution variability, productivity and trophic transfer efficiency in the pelagic ecosystem of&#13;
the Bay of Biscay at a regional and interannual scale.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2479</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Ocean Science, 10. 2014: 2207-2254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>osd-10-2207-2013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20268</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>