<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Stoichiometry of the degradation of dissolved and particulate biogenic organic matter in the NW Iberian upwelling</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Salgado, X.A. (Xosé Antón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nieto-Cid, M. (Mar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brea, S. (Samanta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Castro, C. (Carmen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Doval, M.D. (María Dolores)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Pérez, F. (Fiz)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T12:08:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T12:08:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2006-07-20</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The average composition of the dissolved and particulate products of early&#13;
degradation of marine phytoplankton has been established for the first time in a coastal&#13;
upwelling system using a mixing analysis along isopycnal surfaces combined with a&#13;
stoichiometric model. About 17–18% of the mineralized organic matter is derived&#13;
from the decomposition of organic particulates, and 16–35% is from the dissolved&#13;
organic matter. The remaining 50–70% is derived probably from large fast sinking&#13;
particles. On average, the mineralized material on large particles has the closest&#13;
composition to the Redfield formula. The ratio of dissolved saccharides to dissolved&#13;
organic matter respiration is &gt;40% higher than expected from a material of Redfield&#13;
composition. Finally, the ratio of lipid to particulate organic matter respiration is &gt;80%&#13;
larger than expected from a material of Redfield composition. Regarding the&#13;
decomposition of hard structures, biogenic silica dissolves predominantly in the inner&#13;
shelf, where organic carbon oxidation is more intense, and diatom deposition occurs&#13;
preferentially.</dc:description><dc:identifier>doi: 10.1029/2004JC002473</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1676</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Álvarez-Salgado, X. A., M. Nieto-Cid, J. Gago, S. Brea, C. G. Castro, M. D. Doval, and F. F. Pérez (2006), Stoichiometry of the degradation of dissolved and particulate biogenic organic matter in the NW Iberian upwelling, J. Geophys. Res., 111, C07017</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>