<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Sensitive Habitats and fishing footprint off Canary Islands seamounts Amanay and El Banquete</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Díaz, C. (Carolina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Irusta, José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:03:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:03:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Fuerteventura</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amanay</dc:subject><dc:subject>El Banquete</dc:subject><dc:subject>montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecosistemas marinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>áreas marinas protegidas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversidad marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>hidrografía</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorfología</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitats sensibles</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades bentopelágicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades endobentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades epibentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocenosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrecifes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquerías</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquería artesanal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directiva Hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>idoneidad de hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelización de comunidades e indicadores ecológicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernanza</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine protected areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrography</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitive habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>endobenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>benthopelagic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>epibenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>reefs</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>artisanal fisheries</dc:subject><dc:subject>habitat suitability</dc:subject><dc:subject>community and ecologic indicators modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernance</dc:subject><dc:description>The main objective of the LIFE+ INDEMARES project is to contribute to the protection and sustainable&#13;
use of the biodiversity in the Spanish seas through the identification of valuable areas for the Natura 2000&#13;
Network. The Spanish Institute of Oceanography (IEO) has been in charge of implementing scientific&#13;
surveys to map sensitive habitats of seven of the ten INDEMARES areas, and to determine the fisheries&#13;
footprint over these areas.&#13;
Sur y Oriente de Fuerteventura y Lanzarote is one of the areas chosen to be depicted in the frame of&#13;
INDEMARES project, although the study about benthic habitats and fishery footprint carried by IEO&#13;
has restricted to Amanay and El Banquete Seamounts. El Banquete really is the extension of southern&#13;
continental shelf while Amanay seamount is located at 25 km from Jand´ıa Lighthouse (S of Fuerteventura)&#13;
and 55 km from Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, at the coordinates 28º 07’ Latitude N and 14º 44’&#13;
LongitudeW, both volcanic buildings raise from more than 2,000 m up to their summits at 25-30 m deep,&#13;
separated by a 1.500 m deep channel.&#13;
The biological richness of Amanay and El Banquete seamounts is very influenced by the deep water&#13;
up-welling phenomena, which create a high productivity, attracting a multitude of pelagic species, such&#13;
as cetaceans, turtles, sharks, and tunas looking for food. There is also a high influence from Saharian&#13;
up-welling. Both the seamounts tops and their vicinities are often visited by a large artisanal local fishing&#13;
fleet which profits of their fishery resources; also a rich invertebrate fauna cohabits in their bottoms. In&#13;
general, its main impacts are related to uncontrolled fishing pressure, and maritime navigation. The&#13;
available information on the anthropogenic impact of the area was scarce, and its level of research was&#13;
very poor as well, before INDEMARES project.&#13;
Methodology approach complies with a multidisciplinary perspective, having described the area from&#13;
geological, oceanographic, biological and fisheries points of view. Several surveys have taken place&#13;
since 2009 to 2013 at Amanay and El Banquete waters. Traps, longlines, beam trawls, benthic dredges&#13;
and box corers have been used to sample benthic fauna. These last two, plus EM 3002 multibeam&#13;
echosounder, PS 18 parametric sub bottom profiler, EA600 monobeam sounder, Seapath 200 positioning&#13;
sensor and SV Plus sound velocity calibration sensor were used to make a geophysical study which&#13;
provides a range of environmental factors. CTD was used to depict physical conditions of the water&#13;
column. Finally, different photogrammetric tugged sleds were used to make a great effort of visual&#13;
sampling. Data from VMS (Vessel Monitoring System) were used, combined with interviews to users&#13;
(fishers), landing samplings and scientific observation onboard, to describe the fishery uses in the area.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2582</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Simposio Internacional de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas). 2014. 332. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20335</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>