<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Who are you? Identification of zooplankton species in the Ria de Vigo</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Nande, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Presa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Estévez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T15:46:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T15:46:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-17</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-14</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In the last years, the marine aquaculture research group of the Oceanographic Center in Vigo is endeavoured with completing the life cycle of both, the European hake (Merluccius merluccius) and the Octopus (Octopus vulgaris) using different approaches. One identified bottlenecks for both species is the development stages of larvae and paralarvae which is probably related to nutrition. More research in this field is a key issue to overcome many culture problems.&#13;
As far as we know, feeding larvae/paralarvae with wild zooplankton improves significantly their growth rate and survival. There are two key issues in this research to identify prey preferences for hakes and octopuses, first, to accomplish the molecular identification of zooplankton species present in Ría de Vigo and the second one, the use the sequences obtained to design specific primers for each species and apply them to identify the species present in the stomachs of hake larvae and Octopus paralarvae. The main goal of this research is two identify the natural zooplankton preys from Ría de Vigo using a molecular approach.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquaculture Europe. (14/10/2014 - 17/10/2014. Donostia-San Sebastián (Spain)). . Abstract ID# 438. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Abstract ID# 438</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20299</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>