<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Comparative analysis of the humoral immunity of skin mucus from</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Guardiola, F.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cuesta, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abellán-Martínez, E. (Emilia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Meseguer, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Esteban, M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-04T12:51:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-04T12:51:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1914-06-24</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Skin mucus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humoral immunity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bactericidal activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seawater fish</dc:subject><dc:description>Fish skin mucus contains several immune substances that provide the first line of defence against a broad&#13;
spectrum of pathogens although they are poorly studied to date. Terminal carbohydrate composition and&#13;
levels of total IgM antibodies, several immune-related enzymes (lysozyme, peroxidase, alkaline phosphatase,&#13;
esterases, proteases and antiproteases) as well as the bactericidal activity (against fish pathogenic&#13;
Vibrio harveyi, Vibrio angillarum, Photobacterium damselae and non-pathogenic bacteria Escherichia&#13;
coli, Bacillus subtilis, Shewanella putrefaciens) were identified and measured in the skin mucus of five&#13;
marine teleosts: gilthead seabream (Sparus aurata), European sea bass (Dicentrarchus labrax), shi drum&#13;
(Umbrina cirrosa), common dentex (Dentex dentex) and dusky grouper (Epinephelus marginatus). First,&#13;
lectin binding results suggests that skin mucus contain, in order of abundance, N-acetylneuraminic acid,&#13;
glucose, N-acetyl-glucosamine, N-acetyl-galactosamine, galactose and fucose residues. Second, results&#13;
showed that while some immune activities were very similar in the studied fish (e.g. IgM and lysozyme&#13;
activity) other such as protease, antiprotease, alkaline phosphatase, esterase and peroxidase activities&#13;
varied depending on the fish species. High levels of peroxidase and protease activity were found in&#13;
U. cirrosa respect to the values obtained in the other species while E. marginatus and S. aurata showed the&#13;
highest levels of alkaline phosphatase and esterase activities, respectively. Moreover, skin mucus of&#13;
S. aurata revealed higher bactericidal activity against pathogenic bacteria, contrarily, to what happened&#13;
with non-pathogenic bacteria (E. coli, B. subtilis). Thus, study of the variations in the carbohydrate profile&#13;
and immune-related components of the fish skin mucus could help to understand the fish resistance as&#13;
well as the presence and distribution of pathogens and magnitude of infections, aspects that are of major&#13;
importance for the aquaculture industry.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Fish and Shellfish Immunology, 40. 1914: 24-31</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.fsi.2014.06.018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20070</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>