<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus) tagging survey in the Bay of Biscay in summer 2005</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Marín, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Cabello-Ródenas, M.C. (María Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Quintans, M. (Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrizabalaga, H. (Haritz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Serna-Ernst, J.M. (José Miguel) de-la</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cort-Basilio, J.L. (José Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T13:21:01Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T13:21:01Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2006</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus thynnus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conventional Tagging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Northeast Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:description>A brief summary of the conventional tagging survey carried out during the summer fishing&#13;
season in 2005 in the Bay of Biscay is presented. A total of 1696 juveniles of bluefin tuna have&#13;
been tagged, corresponding to group ages 1 and 2. Two different conventional tags have been&#13;
used. Fifty-one recaptures have been recovered up to date.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent document fournit un résumé de la campagne de marquage conventionnel de thon&#13;
rouge menée au cours de l’été 2005 dans le Golfe de Gascogne. Au total, 1.696 juvéniles de thon&#13;
rouge ont été marqués, correspondant aux groupes d’âge 1 et 2. Deux types distincts de&#13;
marques conventionnelles ont été utilisés. Cinquante-et-une marques ont été récupérées à ce&#13;
jour.</dc:description><dc:description>Se presenta un resumen de la campaña de marcado convencional de atún rojo llevada a cabo&#13;
durante el verano del 2005 en el Golfo de Vizcaya. En total se han marcado 1696 ejemplares de&#13;
1 y 2 años de edad. Se han utilizado dos modelos distintos de marcas convencionales. Hasta la&#13;
fecha se han recapturado cincuenta y un ejemplares.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1670</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodríguez-Marín, E., C. Rodríguez-Cabello, S. Barreiro, M. Quintáns, J. Valeiras, M. Ruiz, H. Arrizabalaga, J.M. de la Serna, J.L. Cort. 2006. Bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus) tagging survey in the Bay of Biscay in summer 2005. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 59 (3): 858-863</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>