<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Aproximación multiescalar al estudio de la ictiofauna del litoral rocoso de Ceuta (España)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Valle, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bayle Sempere, J. T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramos Esplá, A. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Ictiofauna</dc:subject><dc:subject>censos visuales</dc:subject><dc:subject>variabilidad espacial</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:description>The fish population off the coast of Ceuta (Spain) was sampled using visual censuses. Different spatial scales were used. Two sectors were defined, one of them with Mediterranean influence and the other with Atlantic influence. The population's composition showed differences between sectors, due to biogeographic factors, in the structuring of the fish assemblagse. The number of species, the diversity and the biomass presented significant differences only on a smaller spatial scale, due to the rocky habitat's heterogeneity.  On a large spatial scale, the structure of the assemblage was dominated by pelagic wandering species, whereas on a smaller scale, the small-sized sedentary demersal species were more important. The trophic structure showed a predominance of microphages, followed by carnivorous mesophages, due to the exploitation level which the study zone suffers. Our results indicate the coast of Ceuta's potential as a diversity centre for fish fauna.</dc:description><dc:description>Se estudió la ictiofauna litoral de Ceuta mediante censos visuales a varias escalas espaciales. Se diferenciaron dos sectores: uno con influencia mediterránea y otro con influencia atlántica. La composición del poblamiento mostró diferencias entre sectores debidas a factores de índole biogeográfico. El número de especies, la diversidad y la biomasa fueron significativamente diferentes sólo a la escala espacial menor, debido a la heterogeneidad estructural del hábitat.  A gran escala espacial, la estructura del poblamiento estuvo dominada por especies pelágicas errantes, mientras que a escala menor tuvieron más importancia las especies demersales sedentarias de pequeño tamaño. La estructura trófica mostró un predominio de los micrófagos, grupo seguido de los carnívoros mesófagos, como consecuencia directa del nivel de explotación al que se ve sometida la zona de estudio.  Los resultados han mostrado el potencial del litoral ceutí como centro de diversidad de la fauna íctica.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1502</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>