<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="fra">Report of the FAO Working Group on the Assessment of Small pelagic Fish off Northwest Africa. Dakar, Senegal, 21-25 May 2012/Rapport du Groupe de travail FAO/COPACE sur l’évaluation des petits pélagiques au large de l’Afrique nord-occidentale. Dakar, Senegal, 21-25 mai 2012</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>FAO/ García-Isarch, E. (Eva)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T10:26:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T10:26:29Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-05-25</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-05-21</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Small pelagic fish, Northwest Africa</dc:subject><dc:description>The twelfth meeting of the FAO Working Group on the Assessment of Small Pelagic Fish off Northwest Africa&#13;
was held in Dakar, Senegal from 21 to 25 May 2012. Total catch of small pelagic fish for the period 1990 to&#13;
2011 has been fluctuating with an average of around 1.8 million tonnes, with an overall general increasing trend&#13;
since 1994. Although important changes were observed in the abundance and exploitation level for some of the&#13;
stocks, the overall general situation with respect to the state of the different stocks was found to be similar to the&#13;
results of the 2011 Working Group, with the exception of the Atlantic horse mackerel (Trachurus trachurus)&#13;
which this year was considered overexploited. The Cunene horse mackerel (Trachurus trecae) showed some&#13;
improvement and is considered fully exploited. The Small Pelagic Working Group recommends a decrease in&#13;
catch and effort on the horse mackerels stocks to ensure sustainable harvesting of these stocks. The catches of&#13;
round sardinella (Sardinella aurita) are high for the last three years. The Working Group continues to be&#13;
concerned about this stock and considers it is overexploited. The sardine stock in Zone A+B is still considered&#13;
overexploited and the Working Group therefore maintains its recommendation from the previous years that the&#13;
catch should not exceed 400 000 tonnes. Sardine (Sardina pilchardus) in Zone C is not fully exploited. However,&#13;
the stock structure and abundance should be closely monitored by fishery independent methods, and care must&#13;
be taken in the management of sardine in Zone C. Chub mackerel (Scomber japonicus) and anchovy (Engraulis&#13;
encrasicolus) were both considered fully exploited. In the case of anchovy the Working Group recommends that&#13;
effort should not exceed current levels whereas for mackerel it was recommended that catches should not exceed&#13;
250 000 tonnes. Previous assessments have considered bonga (Ethmalosa fimbriata) as a single stock at the&#13;
subregional level. However, recent changes in the exploitation of this species in Mauritania with the subsequent&#13;
large catches make it difficult to assess this species at the subregional level and the group, on a trial basis,&#13;
proceeded to carry out two separate assessment; Unit North–Northern Mauritania and Unit South-Senegal/The&#13;
Gambia respectively. The Working Group recommends that effort should not exceed current levels for the&#13;
northern unit and to decrease the effort on the southern unit.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>FAO Working Group on the Assessment of Small pelagic Fish off Northwest Africa. (21/05/2012 - 25/05/2012. Dakar (Senegal)). . E-ISBN 978-92-5-007751-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>E-ISBN 978-92-5-007751-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20313</dc:identifier><dc:type>report</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>