<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Preparation of single cell detritus from Laminaria saccharina as a hatchery diet for bivalve molluscs</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Salinas, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fuertes, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Springer</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-06-27T07:35:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-06-27T07:35:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2004-12-01</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>biotransformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>single cell detritus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laminaria saccharina</dc:subject><dc:subject>sea weed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>hatchery diet</dc:subject><dc:description>article</dc:description><dc:description>A high-yield technique is described for the elaboration of single cell detritus (SCD) from Laminaria saccharina, based on the sequential action of C1H, enzymes (endoglucanases and cellulases) and 2 bacteria showing a high degree of cellobiotic, proteolytic, and alginolytic activity (CECT 5255 and CECT 5256). Over 85% of dried particles of L. saccharina were transformed into a suspension of free cell and bacterial and detrital particles after 24 hours of bacterial activity with this technique. These particles were less than 20 μm in diameter, constituting a suitable diet for bivalve mollusks. After 72 hours 99% of the total particulate volume consisted of particles less than 20 μm in diameter. Tests of hatchery diets for the seed of clam Ruditapes decussatus revealed increases of 54% and 68% for live weight and length, respectively, when SCD from L. saccharina was used as the sole dietary component compared with a live phytoplankton diet. However, SCD from L. saccharina is not a suitable food for the larvae of R. decussatus.</dc:description><dc:identifier>1436-2236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1113</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Pérez Camacho, A. et al (2004). Preparation of single cell detritus from Laminaria saccharina as a hatchery diet for bivalve molluscs. Marine biotecnology, vol. 6 nº 6 pp: 642-649</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>