<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Length-weight relationships for bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus L.) caught from the Lybian trap fishery in 1999-2002</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>El Tawil, M. (Mohammed)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>El Kabir, N. (Nasir)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Urbina-Gutiérrez, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abad-Casas, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T13:04:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T13:04:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2004</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Bluefin tuna</dc:subject><dc:subject>length-weight relationships</dc:subject><dc:subject>trap fishing</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper reports length-weight relationships for the bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus L.) in the&#13;
Mediterranean. The estimated equations that are based on data from the Libyan trap fishery&#13;
during 1999 to 2002, allow conversions from fork length to round weight.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent document fournit una série de rapports&#13;
lonqueur-poids pour le thon rouge de la Mediterranée. Les équations estimées qui sont basées&#13;
sur les données des pêcherie libyenne de madrague au long de 1999 a 2002, permettent de&#13;
convertir la lonqueur à la fourche en poids totale.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento presenta una serie de relaciones talla-peso&#13;
para el atún rojo en el Mediterráneo. Las ecuaciones estimadas que se basan en datos de la&#13;
pesquería libia de almadraba de 1999 a 2002, permiten realizar conversiones de longitud a la&#13;
furca a peso vivo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>El Tawil, M., N. El Kabir, J.M. Ortiz de Urbina, J. Valeiras, E. Abad. 2004. Length-weight relationships for bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus L.) caught from the Lybian trap fishery in 1999-2002. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 56 (3): 1192-1195</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>