<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Mediciones del transporte sedimentario en suspensión en una playa mesomareal reflectiva en el sur de Portugal</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Taborda, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ciavola, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ferreira, Ó.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alveirinho-Dias, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Sedimento en suspensión</dc:subject><dc:subject>rompientes en voluta</dc:subject><dc:subject>deriva litoral</dc:subject><dc:subject>playa mesotidal</dc:subject><dc:subject>medidas físicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper reports the results obtained in a field experiment carried out on a medium- energy, mesotidal, reflective beach on Culatra Island (southern Portugal). Simultaneous time-series measurements of waves, currents and sediment concentration were taken during 1.5 tidal cycles using a pressure transducer, two bidirectional electromagnetic current-meters and three optical backscatter sensors. Measurements of suspended sediment transport were compared with fluorescent sand tracers. Total longshore sediment fluxes measured with optical techniques and sand tracers were found to give similar results, if their major limitations are considered. The present experiment confirms the different sedimentary behaviours of steep reflective beaches with plunging breakers, as opposed to the low-gradient beaches with spilling breakers where most previous studies have been performed, and supports the idea that one of the major limitations of longshore sediment transport models is their lack of dependency on breaker/beach type.</dc:description><dc:description>Se presentan los resultados de un experimento realizado en una playa reflectiva, mesotidal y de media energía, en la isla de Culatra (sur de Portugal). Se llevaron a cabo mediciones de series temporales de olas, de corrientes y de concentración de sedimento en suspensión durante un ciclo tidal y medio, utilizando un transductor de presión, dos correntímetros bidireccionales electromagnéticos y tres sensores ópticos. Se constató que los resultados de medir los flujos sedimentarios con las técnicas ópticas y con arenas marcadas eran semejantes, teniendo en cuenta las respectivas limitaciones. El presente experimento ha confirmado el desigual comportamiento sedimentario de playas reflectivas con fuerte inclinación y rompiente en voluta, en oposición a las playas con pequeña inclinación y rompiente en derrame, apoyando, pues, la idea de que una de las mayores limitaciones de los modelos de deriva litoral es la ausencia de dependencia en relación al tipo de playa/ rompiente.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>