<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Aplicaciones de la altimetría espacial al estudio de la dinámica oceánica del golfo de Cádiz</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Catalán M., M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Catalán-Pérez-Urquiola, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Altimetría por satélites</dc:subject><dc:subject>geodesia espacial</dc:subject><dc:subject>dinámica oceánica</dc:subject><dc:description>Sea-level records, and their global and local spatio-temporal variations, are related to many oceanographic and geophysical features. The sea surface can also be visualised as the physical representation of the geoid, averaging the sea-surface records over long periods to eliminate the short periods of dynamic perturbation. Over the last ten years, orbit determination improvements have opened up the possibility of using, for ocean dynamic and sea-level variation studies, several altimetric satellites, accurate to the sub-decimetre level (ERS-1, ERS-2, Topex-Poseidon). Of these satellites, Topex-Poseidon makes it possible to measure the sea-level variation over global or regional zones with an accuracy better than 5 cm. This paper presents the results of the sea-surface height measurements from Topex-Poseidon, corrected for wet and dry troposphere range delays, ionosphere delay, sea-state bias, the inverse barometer, loading effects and the oceanic, solid-earth and pole tides. The authors analyse the spatio-temporal stability of the geoid OSU91-a and the mean sea-surface OSUMSS95, comparing the behaviour of the dynamic signal using the two different surfaces along Topex profile 122, which overflies the Atlantic apertures of the Gulf of Cadiz. Long-term analysis has been done over several points located on the Iberian Atlantic continental margin using Topex Poseidon altimeter data collected from October 1992 (cycle 2) to October 1997 (cycle 186). The main findings of the data analysis present a semi-annual variation with peaks in autumn and winter, separated on the order of 20 cm, which could be explained by the seawater temperature seasonal variation and the doubtful use of the inverse barometer model to correct the response of the ocean to changes in atmospheric pressure. Records also show a secular variation in the regional sea level of roughly 3 mm/year, according to historical tide-gauge trends, which could also probably be explained by polar ice melting and a slight warming tendency of the ocean.</dc:description><dc:description>Los registros de la variación espaciotemporal del nivel del mar están relacionados con un gran número de procesos oceanográficos y geofísicos que afectan a la superficie del océano y que pueden representar físicamente la figura del geoide, al eliminarse las variaciones dinámicas de corto periodo una vez promediados los registros sobre largos periodos de tiempo. En el último decenio los desarrollos técnicos y las mejoras en los formalismos de corrección y cálculo de las órbitas han permitido misiones altimétricas de precisión subdecimétrica, especialmente diseñadas para el estudio de la variación del nivel del mar y la dinámica oceánica global y regional (ERS-1, ERS-2, Topex-Poseidon). Una vez corregidos los observables del altímetro conforme propone la Agencia AVISO, se han comparado las precisiones del geoide OSU91-a con la superficie media OSUMSS95, analizando los valores obtenidos en la señal dinámica en el perfil del Topex n1 122, al sobrevolar la zona del Atlántico ibérico.  Los autores presentan los resultados del estudio que han realizado de los datos obtenidos por el satélite Topex-Poseidon entre los ciclos 2 y 186 de sus órbitas (octubre de 1992 y octubre de 1997) en varios puntos del margen continental ibérico.  Los principales resultados presentan una variación, del orden de 20 cm, en el nivel del mar en los bajos de Gorringe de tipo semianual, justificable con la variación de la temperatura de las masas de agua superficiales entre otoño e invierno y un comportamiento inadecuado del modelo de barímetro invertido en las zonas de estudio. Una variación del mismo orden se detecta en el golfo de Cádiz, igualmente justificable por la variación estacional de la temperatura del océano en su superficie. Además de la variación semianual se detecta una variación secular del orden de 2 a 3 mm/año, probablemente de naturaleza global, compatible con los resultados obtenidos con mareógrafos clásicos, justificable por la fusión de hielos en los casquetes polares y un ligero aumento secular de la temperatura de las masas de agua del océano en la zona del margen continental ibérico.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1202</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>