<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Explotación y hábitats del esturión atlántico Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815 en el estuario del río Hudson: lecciones para la conservación de los esturiones</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Bain, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Haley, N.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Peterson, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Waldman, J. R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arend, K.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Pesca</dc:subject><dc:subject>historia natural</dc:subject><dc:subject>recuperación</dc:subject><dc:description>Conservation of the Hudson River population of the sturgeon Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815 has benefitted from the most intensive research programme on any population of the species. We review the history of the fishery for A. oxyrinchus in the Hudson River, and concisely summarise diverse research findings on its life history and habitat use. The fishery for A. oxyrinchus from the Hudson River had one period of very high harvest (pre-1900s), a long period (1900-1979) of minimal harvest and slow population recovery, a period (1980-1992) of restored abundance and high harvest, and finally another decline and suspension of fishing (1996). Sturgeon spawning and early juvenile development occurs in the freshwater portion of the Hudson River, whereas adult and large juvenile sturgeon occupy marine waters, and some of these fish will annually occupy low salinity sites in the Hudson River and other coastal rivers in summer. A. oxyrinchus of the Hudson River are genetically distinct from other populations associated with rivers along the Atlantic coast. Eight different habitats are used during the life cycle of Hudson River A. oxyrinchus, and these are described in physical and temporal terms. The history and biology of the Hudson River A. oxyrinchus suggest three lessons for sturgeon restoration: basic life history knowledge is essential, fishery management is difficult, and regular population monitoring will be needed from the start.</dc:description><dc:description>La conservación de la población del río Hudson de esturión Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815 se ha beneficiado del programa de investigación más intensivo de los proyectados en la preservación de cualquier otra población de la especie. Se revisa aquí la historia de la pesca de A. oxyrinchus en el río Hudson y se resumen concisamente diversos hallazgos de investigación sobre su historia natural y uso del hábitat. La pesca de A. oxyrinchus en el río Hudson tuvo un periodo de muy alta explotación (antes de 1900), un largo periodo de mínima explotación y lenta recuperación poblacional (1900-1979), un periodo de restauración de abundancia y alta explotación (1980-1992) y, finalmente, otro declive y suspensión de la pesca (1996). La puesta del esturión y el desarrollo temprano de los juveniles tienen lugar en el tramo de agua dulce del río Hudson, mientras los adultos y los juveniles grandes ocupan aguas marinas; algunos de estos peces ocuparán anualmente, en verano, lugares de baja salinidad en el Hudson y en otros ríos costeros. La población de A. oxyrinchus del río Hudson es distinta genéticamente de otras poblaciones asociadas con ríos a lo largo de la costa atlántica. Durante su ciclo vital, el A. oxyrinchus del río Hudson utiliza ocho diferentes hábitats, que son descritos en términos físicos y temporales. La historia y la biología de esta especie del río Hudson sugieren tres lecciones para la restauración de los esturiones: es imprescindible el conocimiento básico de la historia natural, la gestión de la pesca es difícil y el seguimiento regular de la población será necesario desde el principio.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1378</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>