<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">VME indicator species collected during exploratory fishing in Macaronesian seamounts</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarralde-Vizuete, R. (Roberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Abellán, L.J. (Luis José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pedrianes, J.R. (Juan Ramón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Agulló-García, J. (Juan)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:27:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:27:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>VME</dc:subject><dc:subject>Macarnesian Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:description>During the second half of 2012, the longline vessel MARANSA completed 13 fishing trips in international&#13;
waters of CECAF Area (Division FAO 34), in nine Seamounts from northeast off Madeira (Lion,&#13;
Ampere, Unicorn, Seine, “Camaguay”, “Cabezos”, Dacia and “Fantasma”) to south off the Canary Islands&#13;
(Eco/Endeavour), between latitudes 19°N and 35°N, using bottom longlines.&#13;
The main target species were demersal species such as Wreckfish (Polyprion americanus) or Splendidalfonsino&#13;
(Beryx splendens).&#13;
An observer on board recorded the bycatch of Vulnerable Marine Ecosystems (VME) indicator species&#13;
in order to evaluate the potential adverse impact of bottom fishing activities on VME and samples of the&#13;
specimens for later identification in the laboratory were stored. The main indicator species found were&#13;
cold-water corals (black corals, scleractinians and gorgonians) and sponges, species broadly associated&#13;
with seamounts.&#13;
The shallower banks, Ampere and Dacia in the north and centre of the area, show the greater biodiversity&#13;
and the higher percentage of presence of VME indicator species (52% and 53% of the sets respectively),&#13;
followed by Endeavour (South of the Canary Islands), 36.4%. In these three banks the species distribution&#13;
is strongly related to depth, finding Antipatharia (mainly Stichopathes sp) and Scleractinia (Dendrophyllia&#13;
cornigera and D. ramea) in shallower depths and Porifera (Neophryssospongia nolitangere,&#13;
Leiodermatium lynceus and Asconema setubalense) in deeper bottoms. Species of the Porifera group are&#13;
present in all banks except of so-called ”Cabezos”.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2590</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV International Symposium of Marine Sciencies. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (España)). 2014. Pag 333. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Pag 333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20343</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>