<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Geomorphology of the Avilés Canyon System, Cantabrian Sea (BayofBiscay)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gómez-Ballesteros, M. (María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Druet-Vélez, M. (María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Muñoz, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rivera, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Delgado, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cristobo, J. (Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Parra-Descalzo, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Alegre-Garralda, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Pola, C. (César)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gallastegui, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Yepes, J. (Juan)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Sede Central IEO</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:20:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:20:50Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Aviles Canyon System, La Gaviera and El Corbiro, Geomorphology, Cantabrian Margin (Bay of Biscay), Multibeam bathymetry, Sediment transport.</dc:subject><dc:description>The Avilés Canyon System (ACS) is a complex, structurally-controlled canyon and valley system constituted by three main canyons of different morphostructural character. They are, from east to west: La Gaviera Canyon, El Corbiro Canyon and Avilés Canyon. In addition to this ACS, a new canyon has been surveyed: Navia Canyon.&#13;
&#13;
We present for the first time a high resolution multibeam map showing with great detail the morphological and structural complexity of this segment of the Cantabrian margin.&#13;
 &#13;
ACS presents a tectonic imprint marked by NW-SE, NNE-SSW and E-W structures. The morphology of their reaches as well as their single mouth, in addition to some rock dredges in their major valleys, demonstrates active down-slope flushing.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
The continental shelf shows a flat, uniform slope with local and well defined rock outcrops south of Aviles Canyon head. Sedimentary zones are limited, showing thin unconsolidated sedimentary cover.&#13;
&#13;
Strong continental margin water dynamics avoid thicker sediment deposition, being littoral sedimentary dynamics responsible for transport to the canyons heads and conduit to the Biscay Abyssal plain. &#13;
&#13;
Biscay Abyssal Plain shows evidence of a strong westward current affecting the surveyed strip of this more than 10 km wide plain. Presence of two parallel deep sea channels, erosive scarps, and erosion of gully divides on the lower slope, may indicate that this is part of the distal fan at the termination of the large turbiditic system fed by Cap Ferret, Capbreton and other large canyons (Santander, Torrelavega, Lastres and Llanes) to the west of ACS.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Deep Sea Research II, 106. 2014: 99-117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.dsr2.2013.09.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20370</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>