<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Histological study of the gonadal development of Ruditapes decussatus (L.) (Mollusca: Bivalvia) and its relationship with available food</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Fernández, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez Camacho, A. (Alejandro)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T12:53:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T12:53:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>food availabiltiy</dc:subject><dc:subject>gonadal development</dc:subject><dc:subject>histology</dc:subject><dc:subject>maturity index</dc:subject><dc:description>This article describes the effects of food availability on the sexual maturation of Ruditapes decussatus&#13;
through histological examination of the gonadal tissue. Three food rations were tested: High (H: 1 mg. organic matter. g&#13;
live weight–1.day-1 of the microalgae Isochrysis galbana clone T-ISO), intermediate (I: 0.5 mg OM g live weight-1 day-1)&#13;
and nutritionally restricted (R: 0.25 mg OM g live weight-1 day-1). The tests were carried out at a constant temperature of&#13;
18ºC for a period of 70 days for diets H and I, and 120 days for diet R. The results showed that in R. decussatus the energy&#13;
from ingestion was mainly channelled to reproductive processes, especially when food was restricted. The clams&#13;
matured sexually under all the conditions tested, both with a somatic growth and with a loss of body mass. The available&#13;
food was directly related to the rate of the gonadal development and with the total quantity of gonad generated. Equally,&#13;
food restrictions limited gonadal recovery after spawning episodes. Food quantity also affected the dry weight of soft tissues&#13;
(DW), which increased with the highest ration (H) and decreased notably with the lowest ration (R). Decreases in&#13;
DW when food was scarce appeared to be more related to loss of reserve tissue rather than to variations in the quantity&#13;
of reproductive tissue.</dc:description><dc:description>Este artículo describe los efectos de la disponibilidad de alimento en la&#13;
maduración sexual de Ruditapes decussatus, a través del examen histológico del tejido gonadal. Se ensayaron tres raciones&#13;
de alimento: Alta (H: 1 mg. materia orgánica. g live weight-1.day-1 de la microalga Isochrysis galbana clone T-ISO),&#13;
intermedia (I: 0.5 mg OM g live weight-1 day-1) y de restricción nutricional (R: 0.25 mg OM g live weight-1 day-1). Los&#13;
ensayos se realizaron a una temperatura constante de 18ºC, y se prolongaron por un periodo de 70 días en el caso de las&#13;
experiencias H e I, y de 120 días en el caso de la experiencia R. Los resultados muestran que en R. decussatus, la energía&#13;
procedente de la ingestión se destina prioritariamente al proceso reproductivo, sobre todo en situaciones de restricción&#13;
alimentaria. De esta forma, las almejas maduran sexualmente bajo todas las condiciones ensayadas, tanto en las&#13;
que determinan un crecimiento somático, como en aquellas que producen una pérdida de masa corporal de las almejas.&#13;
No obstante, el alimento disponible guarda relación directa con la velocidad del desarrollo gonadal y con la cantidad&#13;
total de gónada generada. Igualmente, las restricciones de alimento pueden limitar las recuperaciones gonadales tras los&#13;
episodios de puesta. La cantidad de alimento disponible repercute también en el peso seco de los tejidos blandos (DW),&#13;
que se incrementa en la ración más elevada (H) y disminuye notablemente con la ración más baja (R). Estas caídas en&#13;
el DW cuando escasea el alimento, parecen estar más relacionadas con pérdidas de tejido de reserva que con variaciones&#13;
de la cantidad de tejido reproductivo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Sci.Mar., 69(1) 2005: 87-97</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>