<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Reproducción del atún rojo Thunnus thynnus en jaulas flotantes obtención de puestas masivas mediante implantes hormonales</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>De la Gándara, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortega, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Belmonte, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mylonas, C.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Covès, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bridges, C.R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Prieto, J.R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Viguri, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>XII Congreso Nacional de Acuicultura.Madrid Noviembre de 2009. Libro de resúmenes del XII Congreso Nacional de Acuicultura. Madrid Noviembre de 2009: 542-543</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-05-13T14:31:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-05-13T14:31:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2009-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus thynnus</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproducción</dc:subject><dc:subject>atún rojo</dc:subject><dc:subject>puestas</dc:subject><dc:subject>huevos</dc:subject><dc:subject>acuicultura</dc:subject><dc:description>In the frame of the SELFDOTT project (From capture based to SELF-sustained aquaculture and Domestication Of bluefin tuna, Thunnus thynnus) captive-reared Atlantic bluefin tuna (Thunnus thynnus) (n=15, estimated body weight=90 Kg) maintained for 3 years in captivity in El Gorguel (Cartagena, Spain) were administered a gonadotrophin releasing hormone agonist (GnRHa) implant underwater, during the natural spawning period for this species in the Mediterranean Sea (June). Beginning 48-72 h later, massive spawnings occurred everyday for 17 days, with a daily maximum fecundity of 34 million eggs. Egg collection was accomplished by placing a special curtain around the perimeter of the cage and at 6 m allowed the floating eggs to be maintained within the cage and be collected at night and sunrise with 500 ìm mesh size nets from the surface of the water.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>De la Gándara, F., A. Ortega, A. Belmonte, C.C. Mylonas, D. Covès, C.R. Bridges, J.R. Prieto y J. Viguri. 2009. Reproducción del atún rojo Thunnus thynnus en jaulas flotantes obtención de puestas masivas mediante implantes hormonales.</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>