<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Results for Greenland halibut, American plaice and Atlantic cod of the Spanish survey in NAFO Div. 3NO for the period 1997-2013</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Troncoso, D.M. (Diana María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Román-Marcote, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Paz, X. (Xabier)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T07:41:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T07:41:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-12</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-05-30</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Greenland halibut (Reinhardtius hippoglossoides), American plaice (Hippoglossoides platessoides) and Atlantic cod (Gadus morhua) indices from the bottom trawl survey that Spain carries out in Spring since 1995 in Div. 3NO of the NAFO Regulatory Area are presented. Biomass, stratified mean catches and mean number per tow for the three species are presented since 1997, year in which the survey extended the depth strata. Mean catch per town, length distribution and age distribution are presented for the last five years (2009-2013). Greenland halibut biomass and abundance estimates presented a decreasing trend since 1999, cut in year 2007 with an increase, reaching in 2009 the highest value in the series. In 2011-2013 the biomass drops under the 2008 value. In last years it can be seen a presence of juveniles, mainly in 2004, but the greatest lengths have failed, although in 2009 there is a quite good presence of individuals of ages 6-7 and in 2010 between 5-7. In 2011-2013 the presence of all ages is poor. For American plaice we can see an increasing trend along the whole period, reaching a maximum of mean catch and number in 2006. The greatest recruitment in the presented series occurred in 2004 and we can follow their mode along the years. No good recruitments were seen since then. For Atlantic cod it can be seen a general decreasing in the biomass between 2002 and 2005 and an increasing since then, especially in 2006 and, higher, in 2009-2011, decreasing again since then. For this species, an increase in the recruitment can be seen in 2004 and 2005, and in 2007-2008 the youngest length classes were much over the rest of the length classes. With the 2006 cohort the series reaches the maximum number of its historical values at five years in 2011. There have been no good recruitments since 2009.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2473</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Consejo Científico de NAFO. (30/05/2014 - 12/06/2014. Halifax (Canadá)). 2014. NAFO SCR 14/005, Serial Number N6295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>NAFO SCR 14/005, Serial Number N6295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20262</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>