<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Routine determination of plankton community composition and size structure: a comparison between FlowCAM and light microscopy</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez, Eva</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moyano, Marta</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Urrutia-Lorente, Á. (Ángel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Scharek, R. (Renate)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T06:42:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>abundance; biovolume; biomass; size spectra; diversity; seasonal cycle, light microscopy, FlowCAM</dc:subject><dc:description>Samples from a monthly monitoring programme in the Cantabrian Sea were analysed&#13;
with a FlowCAM-based automated technique. The estimates of abundance,&#13;
biomass size spectra and taxonomic diversity of nano- and microplankton communities&#13;
were compared with those obtained by traditional microscopical analysis of the&#13;
same samples. The structure and abundance of a preserved plankton sample determined&#13;
using FlowCAM showed minimal differences compared with traditional&#13;
microscopical estimates. The effects of sample preservation and inaccuracies in the&#13;
automatic classification are the main causes of discrepancies in the size structure determination&#13;
between the two approaches. However, the synoptic understanding of&#13;
the seasonal variation in the abundance, biomass and diversity obtained from the&#13;
two methods is similar. Our results suggest that the natural variations in the community&#13;
attributes explored are of greater magnitude than the error introduced by the&#13;
methods and that the fully automatic method is adequate to explore these variations.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0142-7873</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Plankton Research, 36(1). 2014: 170-184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1093/plankt/fbt069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20259</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>