<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Metabolic state along a summer north–south transect near the Antarctic Peninsula: a size spectra approach</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Muñoz, C</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gárcia, CM</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lubian, CM</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Urrutia-Lorente, Á. (Ángel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-León, S</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ameneiro, J</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T10:53:41Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-07</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>metabolic rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>plankton</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antarctic Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:subject>size spectra</dc:subject><dc:description>To establish a metabolic state along a north–south transect in Antarctic waters, we approached community respiration (CR) from a combined perspective based on the metabolic theory of ecology (MTE) and the size-scaling of the whole planktonic community. A detailed analysis of a summer integrated multi-trophic normalized biomass size spectra (NBSS), from heterotrophic bacteria to zooplankton, was carried out. To acquire individual size data, different techniques were combined: flow cytometry for smaller fractions (&lt;20 µm of equivalent spherical diameter), FlowCAM for larger nano- and microplankton and scanning and image analysis for the zooplankton fractions. The distribution of the NBSS was linear at all stations (R2 values: 0.87–0.93) but dome-shape features appeared related to phytoplankton cell distribution which are responsible for a large fraction of microbial respiration. Generally, the region showed an autotrophic budget south of the archipelago due to gross primary production (GPP) values up to 2804 mg C m−2 day−1, where salps could significantly contribute to the carbon export flux. Contrastingly, higher CR rates (&gt;1000 mg C m−2 day−1) were found at the northern stations due to a higher phytoplankton respiration activity associated with increasing sea water temperatures and a higher presence of heterotrophic organisms (microheterotrophs, chaetognaths and copepods) resulting in a net heterotrophic metabolic state (GPP/CR &lt; 1).</dc:description><dc:identifier>0142-7873</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2566</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Plankton Research, 36. 2014: 1074-1091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1093/plankt/fbu042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20319</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>