<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Atlantic Cod Predation on Northern shrimp in Flemish Cap (NAFO Div. 3M)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Iglesias, M.C. (María de la Concepción)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Casas-Sánchez, J.M. (José Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T08:33:52Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-13T08:33:52Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The aim of this study is to estimate the predation on shrimp by Atlantic cod in Flemish Cap in the period 2000-2010 and the impact of the cod stock recovery in recent years on the prey stock. Stomach content samples of Atlantic cod were taken in the Flemish Cap survey (NAFO Div. 3M). The analysis was done jointly from all individuals, undifferentiated sexes. They were established four size groups of Atlantic cod with a different predation rate on shrimp: 10-79 cm, 80-89 cm, 90-109 cm and ≥110 cm. Results show a clear increasing trend in the daily consumption of shrimp by cod related with increasing of shrimp biomass. Males and females show the same pattern of consumption of this prey. However consumption changes with the predator size, being highest in individuals over 16 cm to 79 cm. Cod less than 16 cm does not consume shrimp. The maximum consumption of this prey was observed in the period 1999-2008; this period was followed by the fall of this prey biomass in recent years as the cod biomass increased.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1699</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González Iglesias, C., J.M. Casas. 2012. NAFO/ICES pandalus assessment group-october 2012. NAFO Sci. Coun. Res. Doc. 12/55. Serial Nº N6117: 10p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>