<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Cultivo intensivo de paralarvas de pulpo, Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797, en tanques de 9 m³</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Moxica, C. (Covadonga)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Linares, F. (Fátima)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Otero-Pinzas, J.J. (Juan José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Estévez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Conde, F.J. (Francisco Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Pulpo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Octopus vulgaris</dc:subject><dc:subject>cultivo de paralarvas</dc:subject><dc:subject>análisis bioquímicos</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper describes a cultivation system of octopus, Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797, paralarvae in 9 000 l tanks, at a density of 1 paralarva/l. Their diet consisted mainly of Artemia salina (L., 1756), with spider crab, Maja squinado Herbst, 1788, zoeas as a complement. During the two months of cultivation trial, data on temperature, dissolved oxygen, and prey density were recorded. Paralarvae weight was sampled periodically, and analyses of proteins, total lipids, lipid classes and fatty acids of the prey and paralarvae were carried out, as well. At 56 days, the mean weight of the paralarvae was 9.21 mg (dry weight) and they had developed 17-18 suckers on each arm. The final survival rate was 0.2%.</dc:description><dc:description>Este trabajo describe un sistema de cultivo de paralarvas de pulpo, Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797, en tanques de 9 000 litros y a una densidad larvaria de 1 individuo/litro. La dieta principal, Artemia salina (L., 1756), se complementó con zoeas de centolla, Maja squinado Herbst, 1788. Durante los dos meses de cultivo larvario, se controlaron diariamente la temperatura, el oxígeno disuelto, la densidad de presas y se registró el peso de las paralarvas mediante muestreos periódicos. Además, se realizaron análisis de proteínas, lípidos totales, clases de lípidos y ácidos grasos de las presas y de las paralarvas cultivadas. A la edad de 56 días, las paralarvas pesaron 9,21 mg (peso seco) y presentaron 17-18 ventosas en cada brazo. La tasa de supervivencia final fue de 0,2%.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>6013</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>