<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Tagging and recapture activities carried out  by the Spanish Confederation of Responsible Recreational  fishing (ceprr) with the Scientific Coordination  of the Spanish Institute of Oceanography (IEO)  in the Mediterranean (2008-2011)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Godoy-Garrido M.D., Serna-Ernst J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T15:35:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T15:35:21Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Marcado, marcado electrónico, atún rojo, Estrecho de Gibraltar, cebo vivo,pesquerías artesanales, Pesca Deportiva  recreativa responsable</dc:subject><dc:description>During the 2008-2011 period, 1548 specimens of tuna and tuna-like species were tagged by the &#13;
Spanish Confederation of Responsible Recreational Fishing (CEPRR) with the scientific &#13;
coordination of the Spanish Institute of Oceanography (IEO). Of these, 1031 bluefin tuna were &#13;
tagged with conventional tags, whereas 10 other specimens of the same species were tagged &#13;
with pop-up satellite electronic tags in the Mediterranean. Five pop-up electronic tags &#13;
remained on the adult specimens up to 110 days. In this period, the specimens stayed in the &#13;
tagging area except for one of them, which reached Algerian waters in the winter. Similarly, &#13;
333 long-finned tuna and up to 184 specimens belonging to other species such as swordfish, &#13;
little tunny, bonito, frigate tuna and spearfish, were also tagged. Eight bluefin tuna were &#13;
recaptured, including one adult tuna which was found in the same area where it was tagged &#13;
(Balearic Islands) 1343 days after release. A juvenile tuna tagged in the Mediterranean was &#13;
recaptured more than two years after release in the Cantabrian Sea. Over the 2008-2011 &#13;
period, the IEO provided a number of training courses on conventional and electronic tagging &#13;
techniques at the different ports where tournaments and/or tagging and release campaigns &#13;
were carried out. This promoted participation of the CEPRR in the tagging design of the &#13;
GBYP-ICCAT Atlantic-wide Research Programme on Bluefin Tuna, as well as strategic and &#13;
scientific interest.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2335</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Collect. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 68(1):, 68(1). 2012: 133-139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20147</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>