<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Riding the Canary deep poleward undercurrent</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Vélez-Belchí, P. (Pedro)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-Guerra, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Pola, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Machín, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Collins, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T13:22:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T13:22:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Poleward undercurrents are well known features in Eastern Boundary systems. In the California up- welling system (CalCEBS), the poleward flow has been observed along the entire outer continental shelf and upper-slope, (&lt;500m depth) using indirect methods based on geostrophic estimates and also using direct current measurements. The importance of the poleward undercurrents in the CalCEBS, among others, is to maintain its high productivity by means of the transport of equatorial Pacific waters all the way northward to Vancouver Island and the subpolar gyre but there is also concern about the low oxygen concentration of these waters. However, in the case of the Canary Current Eastern Boundary upwelling system (CanCEBS), there are very few observations of the poleward undercurrent. Most of these observations are short-term mooring records, or drifter trajectories of the upper-slope flow. Hence, the importance of the subsurface poleward flow in the CanCEBS has been only hypothesized. Moreover, due to the large differences between the shape of the coastline and topography between the California and the Canary Current system, the results obtained for the CalCEBS are not completely applicable to the CanCEBS. In this study we report the first direct observations of the continuity of the deep poleward flow of the Canary Deep Poleward undercurrent (CdPU) in the North-Africa sector of the CanCEBS, and one of the few direct observations in the North-Africa sector of the Canary Current eastern boundary. The results indicate that the Canary Island archipelago disrupts the deep poleward undercurrent even at depths where the flow is not blocked by the bathymetry. The deep poleward undercurrent flows west around the eastern-most islands and north east of the Conception Bank to rejoin the intermittent branch that follows the African slope in the Lanzarote Passage. This hypothesis is consistent with the AAIW found west of Lanzarote, as far as 17 W. But also, this hypothesis would be coherent with a cyclonic cir- culation associated with the Savage Islands, the Conception bank and the Canary Islands sub basin that would redistribute the AAIW northeast of the Canaries. The poleward flow in the CanCEBS is deeper (&gt;1000m) than the poleward flow in the CalCEBS (&lt;500m). The differences are explored based on the hypothesis that then gradient between the Mediterranean Outflow Waters and the Antartic Intermediate Waters contribute to force the deep flow in the CalCEBS.</dc:description><dc:identifier>ISBN - 10: 84-697-0471-0&#13;
ISBN - 13: 978-84-697-0471-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2651</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Congress of Marine Sciences.. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria). 2014. 60. En: , 1. 2014: 407-407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>60</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20402</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>