<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Parvilucifera sinerae (Alveolata, Myzozoa) is a Generalist Parasitoid of Dinoflagellates</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Garcés, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alacid, E. (Elisabet)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bravo, I. (Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fraga, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Figueroa, R.I. (Rosa Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:42:56Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-12-23</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2030-01-01</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Parvilucifera</dc:subject><dc:subject>parasite</dc:subject><dc:subject>dinoflagellate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apicomplexa</dc:subject><dc:description>This study begins with a description of the infective process in the dinoflagellate type host Alexandrium&#13;
minutum by a strain of the parasitoid, Parvilucifera sinerae, including the morphologies of the various&#13;
dinoflagellate and parasitoid stages during the infection. Then, the susceptibility of 433 microalgal&#13;
strains to P. sinerae infection was studied. The parasitoid was found to be capable of infecting several&#13;
dinoflagellate species of the genera Alexandrium, Coolia, Dinophysis, Fragilidium, Gambierdiscus,&#13;
Gymnodinium, Gyrodinium, Heterocapsa, Kryptoperidinium, Lepidodinium, Ostreopsis, Pentapharsodinium,&#13;
Protoceratium, Scrippsiella, and Woloszynskia. Intra-strain variability was observed as well,&#13;
such that within the same dinoflagellate species some strains were infected whereas others were not.&#13;
Likewise, species of other dinoflagellate genera were not infected, such as Akashiwo, Amphidinium,&#13;
Barrufeta, Bysmatrum, Karenia, Karlodinium, Prorocentrum, and Takayama. Moreover, P. sinerae was&#13;
not able to infect any of the tested haptophyte, diatom, and chlorophyte species. In natural samples&#13;
screened for P. sinerae infectivity, several dinoflagellate species of the genera Alexandrium, Coolia,&#13;
Gonyaulax, Gymnodinium, Phalacroma, Protoperidinium, and Scrippsiella were identified as susceptible.&#13;
Sporangia size was found to be proportional to the size of the host, and variations in the sporangia&#13;
size were observed to influence their maturation time.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Protists, 164. 2012: 245-260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>doi.org/10.1016/j.protis.2012.11.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20015</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>