<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Trends in catch-per-unit-effort, stock biomass and recruitment in the North and Northwest Iberian Atlantic Nephrops stocks</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González Herraiz, I. (Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fariña, A.C. (Antonio Celso)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Fisheries Research -  Elsevier B.V.</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-02-05T11:51:18Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-02-05T11:51:18Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-09-25</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Nephrops norvegicus, landings, CPUE, Long-term trends, stock biomass, recruitment, North and Northwest Iberian Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:description>Nephrops norvegicus is a burrowing decapod with patchy distribution. In the North and Northwest Iberian shelf and upper slope, it is a by-catch species of the bottom trawl mixed fisheries. The International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES) assesses four Nephrops stocks in the area: North Portugal, West and North Galicia and Cantabrian Sea. From&#13;
a relatively buoyant Nephrops fishery in the period 1975–1989, with annual average landings of 1225 t for the entire area, the landings declined substantially to 270 t in 2000. The general trend for the region is a decline of more than 60% in the catch-per-unit-effort in the last decade. These indicators make the status of the Nephrops stocks a matter of concern. In this paper, trends in the time series of Nephrops fishery data are described and evidence from age-based assessment is given of sharp declines in stock biomass and recruitment</dc:description><dc:identifier>0165-7836</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Fariña, A.C. and González Herraiz, I. (2003). Trends in catch-per-unit-effort, stock biomass and recruitment in the North and Northwest Iberian Atlantic Nephorops stocks. Fisheries Research, 65 pp:351-360</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>