<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Short-term dynamics of late winter phytoplankton blooms in a temperate ecpsystem (Central Cantabrian Sea, Southern Bay of Biscay)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez, Eva</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acuña, José Luis</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Álvarez, Marcos</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sostres, Jorge</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-30T06:55:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2009</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>phytoplankton bloom, hydrography, nutrients, PAR, southern Bay of Biscay</dc:subject><dc:description>The Spring Phytoplankton Bloom takes place in the Central Cantabrian Sea (Southern Bay of&#13;
Biscay) from late-winter to spring as a series of blooms with variable biomass accumulation. In&#13;
late-winter of 2004 and 2005, phytoplankton blooms occurred in this area following a change in&#13;
the weather. In order to describe the dynamics of these late-winter blooms, two oceanographic&#13;
cruises which involved high-frequency sampling (every 2–3 days) were carried out. Meteorological&#13;
conditions during the cruises showed similar changes in variables relevant to phytoplankton physiology&#13;
and population dynamics. Before the bloom, phytoplankton started to grow actively when&#13;
underwater photosynthetic active radiation (PAR) increased. However, biomass accumulation did&#13;
not occur until wind, and hence turbulence levels in the water column, decreased. The observations&#13;
presented here suggest that before the onset of a late-winter bloom a preliminary physiological activation&#13;
phase is necessary driven by increased availability of underwater PAR. Afterwards, biomass&#13;
accumulation can take place provided wind-derived water column turbulence decays. The development&#13;
of the bloom is reinforced by the shoaling of the surface mixing layer depth. The timing of&#13;
this sequence of events can be altered by meteorological disturbances, such as an increase of wind&#13;
speed. The composition of the bloom differed across-shelf: phytoplankton larger than 5 mm in&#13;
equivalent spherical diameter (ESD) dominated on the coast and inner shelf, whereas smaller&#13;
phytoplankton (,5 mm ESD) were more important in the oceanic area, markedly when a frontal&#13;
structure separating both domains developed at the mid-shelf.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0142-7873</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2471</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Plankton Research, 31(6). 2009: 601-617</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1093/plankt/fbp012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20260</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>