<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Ausencia de predilección en lábridos y espáridos mediterráneos respecto a dos tipos de hábitat: fondos rocosos y fondos mixtos de praderas de fanerógamas marinas y roca</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Frau, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Deudero, S. (Salud)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cerdeño, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alou, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Peces</dc:subject><dc:subject>censos visuales</dc:subject><dc:subject>nicho</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diplodus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Symphodus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediterráneo</dc:subject><dc:description>Fish species composition, abundance, diversity and niche breadth of Mediterranean littoral communities have been assessed for two types of habitat: rocky bottoms and mixed meadows of Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813 and rocks. Labridae and Sparidae species have been considered to test differences in abundances between both habitats by means of underwater visual census. Data obtained suggests that these fish assemblages are very similar, and there are no significant differences in the niche breadth of both habitats. Differences in physical structure of the habitats are not enough to produce differences in the fish assemblages observed. A high fishing pressure in the study area may be removing the predator fish species, and consequently determining the species composition and abundance for rocky bottoms.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ha estudiado la composición específica, la abundancia, la diversidad y la amplitud de nicho de dos comunidades ícticas mediterráneas mediante censos visuales en dos tipos de hábitat: fondos rocosos y fondos mixtos de Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813 y roca. Se han observado especies de lábridos y espáridos y no se han encontrado diferencias significativas en las variables analizadas de estas comunidades en ambos hábitats. Las diferencias en la estructura física de los dos tipos de hábitat no son suficientes para justificar la aparición de variaciones significativas en las comunidades ícticas estudiadas. Un factor condicionante puede ser la elevada tasa de presión pesquera, que elimina las especies depredadoras y determinaría la composición específica y la abundancia de peces en los fondos rocosos.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1485</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>