<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Efecto de una posible interacción entre el pH y la salinidad sobre el crecimiento de Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Torquemada, Y.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Lizaso, J. L.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Impacto ambiental</dc:subject><dc:subject>desalación</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbono inorgánico</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesocosmos</dc:subject><dc:subject>fanerógamas marinas</dc:subject><dc:description>Reverse osmosis seawater desalination is a steadily growing industry in Mediterranean countries, but little information is available regarding its potential adverse environmental impact. Brine discharge from these plants has high salinity and a relatively low pH. The present paper describes mesocosm experiments carried out to determine the effect of a possible interaction between this simultaneous pH reduction and increase in salinity and the growth of the seagrass Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813. Our results did not show any effect from the interaction between these two factors, although we did detect a significant growth reduction in plants when high salinities and low pH values occurred separately.</dc:description><dc:description>La desalación de aguas marinas mediante ósmosis inversa es una actividad en desarrollo en la cuenca mediterránea cuyos posibles impactos ambientales son poco conocidos. El agua de rechazo de dichas plantas posee una elevada salinidad y un pH relativamente bajo. En el presente trabajo se realizaron experimentos en mesocosmos para estimar el efecto de una posible interacción entre dicho descenso del pH y el incremento de la salinidad sobre el crecimiento de la fanerógama marina Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813. En los resultados obtenidos no se observó un efecto de la interacción entre ambos factores, pero sí una reducción significativa del crecimiento de la planta frente al aumento de la salinidad y al descenso del pH por separado.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1532</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>