<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Effects of the anthropogenics pressures (marine litter) on the coastal ecosystems of the Marine Reserve “Isla de La Graciosa e islotes del norte de Lanzarote”</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, E.L (Erika Lucía)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González, Y. (Yulimar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Jiménez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-González, C.L. (Carlos Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Lorenzo, J.G. (José Gustavo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández, M.Á.R. (María de los Ángeles Rodríguez)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:56:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:56:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Marine Litter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine Reserve</dc:subject><dc:subject>La Graciosa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lanzarote</dc:subject><dc:description>The European Marine Strategy Framework Directive (2008/56/EC) considers marine litter as one of its&#13;
environmental descriptors, requiring the development and standardization of criteria and methodologies&#13;
for its use to test the good environmental status of marine conditions. The assessment of the impact&#13;
caused by litter accumulation in the shoreline lacked specific monitoring planning and had not been&#13;
systematically performed to date in Canary Islands.&#13;
During the project ”Evaluation of the effect of the anthropogenic pressures (marine litter in beaches and&#13;
alteration of shallow seabed by boats anchoring) on the coastal ecosystems of the “Marine Reserve of Isla&#13;
de La Graciosa e islotes del norte de Lanzarote (MRLG)” developed with the financial help of the Canary&#13;
Islands Government (Council of Agriculture, Ranching, Fishing and Waters), two surveys were carried&#13;
out, ”LA GRACIOSA 1310” and “LA GRACIOSA 1311”, both developed at MRLG and its vicinities.&#13;
The aim has been to depict MRLG shoreline and to locate marine litter accumulation points the most,&#13;
contributing with some tools to assess and manage the coastal ecosystems of the marine reserve.&#13;
Total shoreline sampled at both surveys together was 38326 m, 1834 m at Alegranza, 1366 m at Monta˜na&#13;
Clara, 24656 m at La Graciosa Island, and the rest, 10470 m, at the Lanzarote’s shoreline portion bathed&#13;
by MRLG waters. Shoreline sampling was made qualitatively sorting the sampling stations, according&#13;
to litter presence and distribution, by means of a upward numerical coding related to the type of waste&#13;
or garbage found. Moreover, each station was additionally depicted according to the type of substrate as&#13;
well as to the prevailing type of waste, defining what we named “transects”.&#13;
To validate methodology to European standards, a more exhaustive experimental sampling was made&#13;
in four transects identified as high density or high concentration of marine litter, following guidelines&#13;
of a method developed for OSPAR maritime area during the first half of 2000 decade (OSPAR, 2007).&#13;
It involves evaluating the possibilities and needs of adjustment of this methodology to the particular&#13;
conditions of our region (Gonz´alez, et al., 2013 a and b).&#13;
As preliminary results, the spatial distribution of garbage coastal accumulation will be shown in a cartographic&#13;
base, expressed as relative abundance by island, according to a 4 degrees scale (no litter, low,&#13;
medium and high litter presence) and according to the dominant kind of garbage in each transect. An&#13;
example with one of the most densely occupied with trash transects is shown to illustrate a sampling&#13;
method without the requirement of trash collection. This method uses a sampling unit of 1x1 m grid,&#13;
divided in 10x10 cm subgrids. This grid is set parallel to sampling direction repeatedly. Distance between&#13;
grids is determined by a randomizing software. Sampling direction zigzags from sea border to&#13;
beach back shore, making 45° degrees angles. Subgrids occupied by trash are counted once the grid is&#13;
set. Waste is depict and identified following a guide developed for this purpose by OSPAR in 2010.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV International Symposium of Marine Sciencies. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (España)). 2014. Pag 352. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Pag 352</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20333</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>