<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">DNA-barcoding Decapoda and Stomatopoda from West-Africa</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Willassen, E. (Endre)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Isarch, E. (Eva)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>De Matos-Pita, S.S. (Susana)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03T12:35:18Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-23</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-18</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>benthic invertebrates</dc:subject><dc:subject>bar-coding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decapoda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stomatopoda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crustacean</dc:subject><dc:subject>West Africa</dc:subject><dc:description>Knowledge about species biology, distributions, and autecologies is based on accumulated&#13;
information provided by identifying observers from diverse time periods and from sometimes&#13;
somewhat isolated scientific cultures. Traditional taxonomic revisions bear witness of the inherent&#13;
challenges of specimen identification and the efforts to obtain concordant species observations&#13;
that actually refer to the same natural units. “Mislabelled” species is a growing&#13;
concern in population management and food industries.&#13;
There is also an emerging alertness in macro-ecology&#13;
of bias in estimators of species occurrences and in biodiversity&#13;
assessment and modelling due to misidentifications.&#13;
Open access databases with DNA-barcodes are potentially&#13;
powerful tools to discover conflicting identifications&#13;
and may help in species recognition and in harmonizing&#13;
the use of species taxonomies across research&#13;
groups. Barcodes may also give taxonomists alerts&#13;
about a need for integrative re-evaluation of taxa and&#13;
their distributions. Such ideas are the background motivation&#13;
for our DNA-barcoding of benthic animals&#13;
from recent sampling on the West-African shelf conducted&#13;
by the EAF-Nansen programme. We prepared 470 specimens of Decapoda and five&#13;
Stomatopoda, in sum representing 133 identified species, for DNA-sequencing using the&#13;
BOLD v3 system. Sequences were obtained from 351 samples, including 107 (80 %) of the&#13;
identified species. The BOLD-system assigned the sequences to 113 BINS (RATNASTINHAM&#13;
&amp; HEBERT, 2013) of which 64 BINS were taxonomically concordant and 33 were singletons.&#13;
Amongst 16 taxonomically discordant BINs, one was due to a previous record with a junior&#13;
synonym, four due to identical sequences of subspecies taxa or identification to genus only.&#13;
Interestingly, some of the discordant BINs, such as our sequences of the crab Menippe nodifrons&#13;
(Menippidae) contained conspecific matches with West-Atlantic sequences in BOLD&#13;
whereas another matching sequence from GenBank had been identified as a Pilumnidae. The&#13;
most striking conflicting identifications in BOLD were observed with respect to the genus&#13;
Macropodia, showing a need for taxonomic resolution and revision.&#13;
Reference:&#13;
RATNASTINHAM, S. &amp; HEBERT, P.D.N. (2013) A DNA-based registry for all animal species: the Barcode Index&#13;
Number (BIN) system. -- PLoS ONE, 8(7): e66213. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0066213.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>8th International Crustacean Congress. (18/08/2014 - 23/08/2014. Frankfurt am Main (Germany)). . conferenceObject. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>conferenceObject</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20443</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>