<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Identificación de stocks de rape (Lophius piscatorius) en aguas del suroeste europeo</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cañás Ferreiro, L.(Lucía)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de A Coruña</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2012-12-19T13:13:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-12-19T13:13:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-11-23</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Lophius piscatorius, anglerfish, Northeast Atlantic, stock identification, fisheries, parasite, anisakid nematodes, biological tag, otolith shape analysis, stock assessment</dc:subject><dc:description>tesis doctoral</dc:description><dc:description>Abstract&#13;
Anglerfish, Lophius piscatorius, is one of the most valuable species of bottom&#13;
fisheries of the Southwest of Europe. In the Northeast Atlantic, 3 stocks are considered,&#13;
with boundaries that were established for assessment and management purposes. This&#13;
Ph.D. Thesis explores whether the current stock structure in southwestern Europe has&#13;
a biological support. Chapter 1 introduces the biological features of the anglerfish,&#13;
its fishery and the assessment and management process of this resource. Chapter&#13;
2 outlines the objectives of this work and Chapter 3 explains the material and&#13;
general methodologies employed. The Chapters 4 and 5 describe the use of the otolith&#13;
shape analysis and the parasites as biological tags in stock identification studies of&#13;
anglerfish. In Chapter 6, the results of both techniques were evaluated together with&#13;
information from previous studies of genetic, body morphology and tagging-recapture.&#13;
The implications of considering a single stock of anglerfish in the perception of the&#13;
resource status are analysed in the Chapter 7.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Cañás Ferreiro, L. (2012). Identificación de stocks de rape  (Lophius piscatorius) en aguas del suroeste europeo. Tesis doctoral IEO-Universidad de A Coruña</dc:identifier><dc:type>doctoralThesis</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>