<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A check of traditional parameters based on fishing effort in the surface fishery of juvenile albacore in the Northern Atlantic</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pereiro-Muñoz, F.J. (Francisco Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:42:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:42:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1983</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In this paper, the authors try to check if there exists a relationship between catchability and stock size in the juvenile albacore surface fishery in the North Atlantic stock.&#13;
The conclusions are that this relationship does not seem to take place; fishing effort reflects &#13;
very well F, and CPUE changes reflect abundance changes in the stock in the period analyzed.&#13;
The authors call readers'      attention to the possibility that a "significant" correlation &#13;
between q and N does not mean a cause to effect relationship between these two variables.</dc:description><dc:description>Les auteurs du présent document ont tent de vérifier s'il existe une relation entre la capturabilité et la taille du stock dans la pêcherie de surface de &#13;
germon juvénile du stock de l'Atlantique nord.&#13;
Les conclusions sont que cette relation ne semble pas se présenter; l'effort de pêche reflète tres &#13;
bien F et les changements de la CPUE illustrent ceux de l'abondance du stock pour la période analysée.&#13;
Les auteurs attirent l'attention du lecteur sur la possibilité de ce qu'une corrélation &#13;
"significative" entre q et N puisse ne pas signifier qu'il existe une relation de cause   à effet &#13;
entre ces deux variables.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento intenta comprobar si existe una relación entre la capturabilidad y el tamaño del &#13;
stock de atún blanco juvenil en la pesquería de superficie del Atlántico Norte.&#13;
La conclusión es que no existe tal relación; el esfuerzo pesquero refleja bien la F y los cambios en la CPUE reflejan cambios en la abundancia del stock &#13;
durante el periodo analizado.&#13;
Los autores señalan que existe una posibilidad de que una correlación "significativa" entre q y N &#13;
no supone una relación causa-efecto entre estas dos variables.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1638</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González-Garcés, A. and J.A. Pereiro. 1983. A check of traditional parameters based on fishing effort in the surface fishery of juvenile albacore in the Northern Atlantic. Col.  Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 18 (2): 399-410.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>