<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Life cycle stages of the benthic palytoxin-producing dinoflagellate, Ostreopsis cf. ovata (Dinophyceae)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Bravo, I. (Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vila, M. (Magda)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Casabianca, S. (Silvia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rial, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Riobó, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Penna, A. (Antonella)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T10:59:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-04-09</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Ostreopsis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dinoflagellate life cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benthic dinoflagellates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediterranean Sea</dc:subject><dc:description>The asexual and sexual reproduction of Ostreopsis cf. ovata was studied in the field and in cultures isolated&#13;
from two locations in the Mediterranean Sea. Asexual division took place in the motile stage by the sharing&#13;
of theca (desmoschisis). High cell-size variability and differences in division capability were detected in the&#13;
cultures. Thecal analyses and nuclear division patterns allowed characterization of the different phases of&#13;
dividing cells obtained during an in situ cell-cycle sampling performed off Llavaneres beach (Northeast&#13;
Spain). During the 45-h cycle, binucleated cells accounted for 2.6% of the population. Division was initiated&#13;
with the onset of dusk and reached a maximum 3–4 h before dawn. No dividing cells were detected after&#13;
09:00 AM. Sexuality occurred both in cultures and in natural populations of O. cf. ovata. Mating gamete pairs&#13;
were the only sexual stages that could be distinguished from vegetative stages. The differences between&#13;
these pairs and dividing cells are described herein. None of the individually isolated gamete pairs&#13;
underwent fusion nor encystment, instead, in most of them one member of the gamete pair divided. Rather&#13;
than plasmogamy, there was evidence of nuclear migration from one gamete to the other. Pellicle cysts,&#13;
thin-walled cysts, and thecate cysts were also identified and studied. These cysts, embedded in abundant&#13;
mucilage in a bloom-derived incubated sample, were able to germinate for as long as 6 months after their&#13;
formation. Our results suggest that they constitute the overwintering population that causes recurrent&#13;
blooms of O. cf. ovata in some areas of the Mediterranean Sea.</dc:description><dc:identifier>1568-9883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Harmful Algae, 18. 2012: 24-34</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.hal.2012.04.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20017</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>