<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Selectivity of 130 mm Mesh Size in Deep Sea Bottom Trawl Fishery in NAFO Regulatory Area</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cárdenas-González, E. (Enrique) de</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Avila-de-Melo, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Martínez, S. (Sergio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Saborido-Rey, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-01-28T08:35:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-01-28T08:35:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1995</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In February 1995 the European Community carried out .a&#13;
selectivity campaign on board of a Spanish commercial trawler,&#13;
using the codend cover method. The objective was to study the&#13;
selectivity of 130 mm mesh size for the deep sea trawl fisheries in&#13;
the NAFO Regulatory Area. One hour and four hour hauls were used&#13;
and results obtained for Greenland halibut, American plaice,&#13;
roughhead grenadier and theebeard rockling. For the two flatfish&#13;
species the proportion of retention increase with the duration of&#13;
the haul. This increase, reflected in a decrease of the&#13;
corresponding selection factor, also varies with the size of fish,&#13;
being greater in smaller individuals, and induces an asymmetry in&#13;
the selectivity curve. For the roundfish species data were enough&#13;
only to fit the four hour selectivity curves, both appearing more&#13;
symmetrical than the flatfishes ones.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Cárdenas, E. de. 1995. Selectivity of 130 mm Mesh Size in Deep Sea Bottom Trawl Fishery in NAFO Regulatory Area. NAFO SCR Doc. 95/47: 7p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>