<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Air-sea CO2 fluxes in the Atlantic as measured during the FICARAM cruises</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Padín, X.A. (Xosé Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez-Rodríguez, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Castaño, M. (Mónica)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Velo, A. (Antón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alonso-Pérez, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gilcoto, M. (Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Conde-Pardo, P. (Paula)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Paz, M. (Mercedes) de la</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Ríos, A. (Aida)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Pérez, F. (Fiz)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:11:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:11:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2010</dcterms:issued><dc:description>A total of fourteen hydrographic cruises spanning from 2000 to 2008 were conducted&#13;
during the spring and autumn seasons between Spain and the Southern Ocean, under&#13;
the framework of the Spanish research project FICARAM. The performed underway measurements are processed and analysed to describe the meridional air-sea CO2&#13;
fluxes (F CO2) along the Atlantic Ocean. The data was organised into different biogeochemical&#13;
oceanographic provinces, according mainly to the thermohaline characteristics.&#13;
The obtained spatial and temporal distributions of F CO2 follow the generally expected&#13;
patterns and annual trends. The Subtropical regions in both hemispheres alternated the CO2 source and sink nature from autumn to spring, respectively. On the other&#13;
hand, Tropical waters and the Patagonian Sea clearly behaved as sinks of atmospheric&#13;
CO2 like the waters of the Drake Passage during autumn. The obtained results during&#13;
the cruises also revealed significant long-term trends, such as the warming of equatorial&#13;
waters (0.11±0.03 Cyr−1) and the decrease of surface salinity (−0.16±0.01 yr−1)&#13;
in tropical waters caused by the influence of the Amazon River plume. This reduction&#13;
in surface salinity appears to have a direct influence over the CO2 storage rates, fostering&#13;
the uptake capacity of atmospheric CO2 (−0.09±0.03 molm−2 yr−1). An analysis&#13;
of the biogeochemical forcing on the CO2 fugacity (fCO2) variability performed from&#13;
an empirical algorithm highlighted the major role of the Amazon River input in the tropical North Atlantic fluxes. In addition, it has provided a quantitative measure of the&#13;
importance of the thermodynamic control of F CO2 at temperate latitudes.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1680</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Biogeosciences, 7. 2010: 1587-1606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.5194/bg-7-1587-2010</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>