<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Temporal variation of the pseudo-selective transcribed spacer ITS1-rDNA in the Atlantic hake population (Merluccius merluccius)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pita, A. (Alfonso)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cuellar, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Presa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T13:25:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T13:25:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-15</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Merluccius merluccius, ITS1, molecular network, fishery evolution</dc:subject><dc:description>In this study we have tracked the internal transcribed spacer ITS1-rDNA in temporal hake samples (1976, 2000 – 2005 and 2007) to study its molecular behaviour throughout the overexploitation history of this fishery. Ninety-eight ITS1 haplotypes were recovered out of 304 sequences from 105 individuals. The haplotype MmITS1.1 valued 50.3% in the global dataset and was the most frequent one up to 2007 when frequency of a secondary haplotype MmITS1.2 overwhelmed it (39.3%). Ninety percent of haplotype involved rare variants (less than 1% each) and were cohort-specific without significant differences in their abundance across years. Molecular networks per year are congruent with the recent history of this fishery as well as with phenomena depicted using microsatellite data. All data indicate that the Atlantic hake population is recovering from a history of overexploitation, for strict neutral markers as well as for pseudo-selective ones.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2374</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES Annual Science Conference014. (15/09/2014 - 19/09/2014. A Coruña (Spain)). . ICES CM 2014/E. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES CM 2014/E</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20177</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>