<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Cambios bentónicos en la ría de Foz (Lugo) (noroeste de España) tras la construcción de un espigón</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Castellanos, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-Vega, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Junoy, J. (Juan)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:11Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Macrofauna</dc:subject><dc:subject>pradera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zostera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerastoderma</dc:subject><dc:description>Long-term changes in the benthos of Spain's coastal waters are still largely unknown. The present paper compares data from January 2002 taken in the ría de Foz (northwest Spain) with the results of a study conducted in 1984-1985, in order to detect possible changes in benthic macrofauna (species composition, abundance, distribution and benthic assemblages) after the construction of a seawall. The same sampling design was used as in the 1980s. This comparison of the 1984-1985 and 2002 samples shows changes in the distribution of the three benthic assemblages detected, and in the abundance and dominance of the main species. These changes are mainly attributed to the construction of a seawall in the mouth of the estuary, which has introduced modifications in its hydrodynamic and sedimentary regimes, making the inner ría more sheltered than before. The new conditions have also promoted the extension of the meadows of the seagrass Zostera noltii Hornemann, 1832 and the community of Cerastoderma edule (L., 1758)-Scrobicularia plana (Da Costa, 1778).</dc:description><dc:description>Se analizan los cambios ocurridos en las comunidades bentónicas de la ría de Foz (Lugo) (noroeste de España) tras la construcción de un espigón en la boca del estuario, comparándose la situación del año 2002 con la existente en 1984-1985. Si bien persisten en la ría las tres comunidades bentónicas detectadas en el estudio previo, se observan cambios en su distribución y en la dominancia y la abundancia de sus principales especies. Los cambios hidrodinámicos producidos por esta construcción han proporcionado un ambiente más resguardado en el interior de la ría, incrementándose notablemente el área ocupada por las praderas de Zostera noltii Hornemann, 1832 y por la comunidad de Cerastoderma edule (L., 1758)-Scrobicularia plana (Da Costa, 1778), que ocupaba la parte más interna de dicha ría.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>