<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Changes in distribution of Greenland halibut in a varying environment</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Morgan, J. (Joanne)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Garabana-Barro, D. (Dolores)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rideout, R. (Rick)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Román-Marcote, E. (Esther)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez-Rodríguez, A. (Alfonso)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Saborido-Rey, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-04-07T08:47:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-04-07T08:47:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-02-20</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>condition</dc:subject><dc:subject>depth</dc:subject><dc:subject>distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:description>Fish are expected to respond to changing oceanographic temperature by altering their distribution. Off the coast of Newfoundland,&#13;
Canada, there have been major changes in oceanographic temperature over the last several decades, with both record cold and record&#13;
warm years being observed. Greenland halibut is an important flatfish species in the area, and is distributed in deep waters over a very&#13;
wide geographic range. Thus, it might be buffered from temperature change in the overall area by reduced temperature variation at&#13;
depth, and the diverse temperature conditions over its wide range. We examined intrapopulation variation in temperature and depth&#13;
distribution, and the biological changes in relation to changes in available temperature. On the Flemish Cap, variation in available&#13;
temperature was limited, and changes in depth were related to changing age composition and the differential depth distribution&#13;
with age/size. In other areas there was a larger decline in available temperature, and associated with this, Greenland halibut&#13;
moved to deeper waters and occupied warmer temperatures than they had previously. Concurrently, growth declined and condition&#13;
increased. This study shows that shifts in distribution may not result in maintenance of homogeneous environmental conditions, and&#13;
that resulting biological changes will be difficult to predict.</dc:description><dc:identifier>doi: 10.1093/icesjms/fss179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1752</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Morgan, M.J., D. Garabana, R.M. Rideout, E. Román, A. Pérez-Rodríguez and F. Saborido-Rey. 2013. Changes in distribution of Greenland halibut in a varying environment. ICES Journal of Marine Science, 70 (2), 352-361</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>