<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Macrofitobentos mediolitoral y delimitación de áreas sensibles a la contaminación marina en el litoral ceutí (estrecho de Gibraltar)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz-Tabares, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gordillo, I.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Corzo, J. R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Gómez, J. C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:36Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Macrofitobentos mediolitoral</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ceuta</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensibilidad ambiental</dc:subject><dc:description>The Straits of Gibraltar has one of the highest levels of shipping traffic in the world; consequently, it runs a high risk of suffering ecological disaster. The main objective of the present study was to delimit areas sensitive to anthropogenic perturbations according to information gathered from midlittoral macrophytobenthic communities. We focused mainly on species richness, which was comparatively higher at the North Bay stations, examining similarities among stations using classification and ordination analyses, together with β diversity indices. Both the ordination and classification analyses discriminated between the stations based on their geographical location, and confirmed the Atlantic influence in the North Bay and the Mediterranean influence in the South Bay. Three levels of different environmental sensitivity were established for priorities in future conservation. The westernmost region of the North Bay, together with the eastern zone (transitional area between the two bays), are those having the highest ecological value and vulnerability. The South Bay can be divided into an area with low ecological value, close to Moroccan waters, and an area with intermediate characteristics.</dc:description><dc:description>El estrecho de Gibraltar es una de las áreas de mayor tránsito marítimo del mundo y, por tanto, de riesgo de catástrofe ecológica. El objetivo principal de este trabajo ha sido delimitar áreas sensibles a impactos antropogénicos, según la información obtenida del macrofitobentos mediolitoral. Se ha incidido especialmente en la riqueza específica, que fue comparativamente mayor en las estaciones situadas en la bahía norte. Mediante los análisis de clasificación y ordenación y la aplicación de los índices de diversidad β, se estudió la proximidad, en términos de similitud, de las estaciones de muestreo. Tanto el análisis de clasificación como el de ordenación discriminaron de forma clara las estaciones según su ubicación geográfica, confirmándose el carácter más atlántico de la bahía norte respecto a la bahía sur, de características más mediterráneas. Se fijaron tres niveles de diferente sensibilidad ambiental para establecer futuras prioridades de protección ante eventuales contingencias medioambientales. La región más occidental de la bahía norte junto con el tramo este (de transición entre bahías) constituyen áreas de mayor valor ecológico y vulnerabilidad, mientras que la bahía sur se divide en dos zonas: una de menor valor ecológico, correspondiente al tramo más cercano a la frontera con Marruecos, y otra con estaciones de valores intermedios.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1451</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>