<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Estimation of biological parameters for the common dolphin (Delphinus delphis) and its importance on dynamic models. An approximation of the mortality-at-age and the influence of the bycatch</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Saavedra-Penas, C. (Camilo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Howell, D. (Daniel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cerviño-López, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pierce, G.J. (Graham)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Read, F.L. (Fiona)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Santos, M.B. (María Begoña)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:41:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:41:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-15</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The short-beaked common dolphin (Delphinus delphis) is the most abundant small cetacean in the north eastern Atlantic and in some regions by-catch is considered to be unsustainable. To help inform conservation measures, population models are needed to explore how the population will react under different scenarios. In order to build a population model, mortality-at-age curves derived from stranding data were constructed, using a Siler model fitted to the total observed dataset. Due to the paucity of data for the youngest age classes, a separate model was fit to a subset of the data that did not include the youngest age classes. Finally, a Heligman-Pollard model was fitted to the second subset of data as well, taking into account the proportion of by-caught dolphins in the sample. The survivorship curves for the Siler models reported that a median of 30% of the females achieve maturity when we used the total observed data set but only the 18% if we remove the youngest ages. The Heligman-Pollard model showed a more realistic shape since by-catch mortality was taken into account. The results of this model show an effective growth of 0.912 which indicate a population decline, likely due to high rates of by-catch.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES 2014 Annual Science Conference. (15/09/2014 - 19/09/2014. A Coruña (España)). 2014. ICES CM 2014/J: 11. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES CM 2014/J: 11</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7578</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>