<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Moving towards an Ecosystem Based Management in the Gulf of Cadiz</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Fdez-Palacios, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Torres, M.Á. (María de los Ángeles)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Llope, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-23T12:03:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-23T12:03:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The concentration of the world's population in coastal regions, in addition to the direct human use, is leading to an accelerated process of change and deterioration of the marine ecosystems worldwide. In the case of the Gulf of Cadiz (GoC), intense fishing throughout history has resulted in the overexploitation of its major commercial stocks.&#13;
&#13;
The Ecosystem Based Management (EBM) is the framework currently used for restoration of marine ecosystems. Unlike conventional strategies which only focus on individual components, this new paradigm in ecosystem management implies the consideration of the entire system as a whole.&#13;
&#13;
Following the steps of other European seas, this work presents an Integrated Ecosystem Assessment (IEA) for the Gulf of Cadiz as first stone towards an eventual operational EBM. The IEA of the GoC is developed by combining a customized implementation of Levin's cycle with other complementary approaches, commonly used in other European seas.&#13;
&#13;
In particular we made use of a traffic light plot to describe the state and trends of the most important descriptors and an Ecopath model to depict the main trophic interactions in this specific ecosystem. From these analyses, we finally come up with candidate indicators suitable to be used within Levin’s cycle framework.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Congreso de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (Spain)). 2014. poster. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>poster</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20186</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>