<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Sampling protocol for skeletal structures of North Atlantic albacore tuna (Thunnus alalunga) and ageing interpretation</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Zárate-Vidal, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:28:10Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T11:28:10Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus alalunga</dc:subject><dc:subject>albacore</dc:subject><dc:subject>first dorsal spiny ray</dc:subject><dc:subject>age estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>protocol</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth marks</dc:subject><dc:subject>North Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:subject>South Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a standardized protocol for sampling skeletal hard parts (dorsal fin ray&#13;
and otoliths), preparation and age interpretation of albacore first dorsal fin ray. Ageing of&#13;
albacore is focused in interpretation and reading of annual temporal marks (translucent bands)&#13;
in first ray of dorsal fin. Preparation of fin ray sections (spines) is presented in detail using two&#13;
different methods. The spines are usually cut individually using a low speed cutter. Depending&#13;
of the size of spines, a new procedure has been developed for small spines based on encasing&#13;
spines in a matrix of plastic resin allowing multiple spines cutting. Interpretation of growth&#13;
marks on spine sections is explained and examples are presented for a range of size of albacore&#13;
aged using this method.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document présente un protocole standardisé pour l’échantillonnage des pièces dures du&#13;
squelette (rayon de la nageoire dorsale et otolithes), la préparation et l’interprétation de l’âge&#13;
du rayon du premier rayon de la nageoire dorsale du germon. La détermination de l’âge du&#13;
germon se centre sur l’interprétation et la lecture des marques temporelles annuelles (bandes&#13;
translucides) du premier rayon de la nageoire dorsale. La préparation des sections du rayon de&#13;
la nageoire (épines) est présentée en détail à l’aide de deux méthodes différentes. Les épines&#13;
sont généralement sectionnées individuellement en utilisant un couteau basse vitesse. Selon la&#13;
taille des épines, une nouvelle procédure a été élaborée pour les petites épines, consistant à&#13;
enfermer les épines dans une matrice en résine plastique qui permet le découpage de plusieurs&#13;
épines. L’interprétation des marques de croissance sur les sections des épines est expliquée et&#13;
des exemples sont donnés pour une gamme de tailles de germon dont l’âge a été déterminé à&#13;
l’aide de cette méthode.</dc:description><dc:description>En este documento se presenta un protocolo estandarizado para el muestreo de partes duras&#13;
del esqueleto (otolitos y rayo de la aleta dorsal) y para la preparación e interpretación de la&#13;
edad del primer rayo de la aleta dorsal del atún blanco. La determinación de la edad del atún&#13;
blanco se centra en la interpretación y lectura de las marcas temporales anuales (bandas&#13;
traslucidas) en el primer rayo de la aleta dorsal. Se presenta en detalle la preparación de las&#13;
secciones del rayo de la aleta (espinas) utilizando dos métodos diferentes. Las espinas suelen&#13;
cortarse generalmente de forma individual utilizando un cortador de baja velocidad.&#13;
Dependiendo del tamaño de las espinas, se ha desarrollado un nuevo procedimiento para las&#13;
espinas pequeñas, que consiste en introducir las espinas en una matriz de resina plástica que&#13;
permite cortar espinas múltiples. Se explica la interpretación de las marcas de crecimiento en&#13;
las secciones de espinas y se presentan ejemplos para una gama de tallas de atún blanco cuya&#13;
edad se determinó utilizando este método.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Ortiz de Zárate, V., J. Valeiras, M. Ruiz. 2007. Sampling protocol for skeletal structures of North Atlantic albacore tuna (Thunnus alalunga) and ageing interpretation. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 60 (2): 492-506</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>