<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Selectivity of 130 mm Mesh Size in Deep Sea Bottom Trawl Fishery in NAFO Regulatory Area</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cárdenas-González, E. (Enrique) de</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Avila-de-Melo, A. (Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Saborido-Rey, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Martínez, S. (Sergio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-01-28T09:07:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-01-28T09:07:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1997</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>American plaice</dc:subject><dc:subject>Greenland halibut</dc:subject><dc:subject>roughhead grenadier</dc:subject><dc:subject>selectivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>threebeard rockling</dc:subject><dc:subject>trawl</dc:subject><dc:description>In February 1995 the European Union carried out a selectivity survey on board a Spanish&#13;
commercial trawler, using the codend-cover method. The objective was to study the selectivity&#13;
of 130 mm mesh size for the deep sea trawl fisheries in the NAFO Regulatory Area. One&#13;
hour and four hour hauls were carried out and results obtained for Greenland halibut&#13;
(Reinhardtius hippoglossoides), American plaice (Hippoglossoides platessoides), roughhead&#13;
grenadier (Macrourus berglax) and threebeard rockling (Gaidropsarus ensis). For the two&#13;
flatfish species, the proportion of retention increased with the duration of the haul. This&#13;
increase reflected in a decrease of the corresponding selection factor. It also varied with&#13;
the size of fish. The selection factor was greater in smaller individuals, and this induced an&#13;
asymmetry in the selectivity curve. For the groundfish species, data were enough only to fit&#13;
the four hour selectivity curves, which appeared more symmetrical than the flatfish ones.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Cárdenas, E. de et al. 1997. Selectivity of 130 mm Mesh Size in Deep Sea Bottom Trawl Fishery in NAFO Regulatory Area. NAFO Sci. Coun. Studies, 30: 21-25</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>