<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Report of the FAO/CECAF Working Group on the Assessment of Demersal resources- Subgroup South. Freetown, Sierra Leona, 8-14 October 2008. / Rapport du Groupe de travail FAO/COPACE sur l’évaluation des ressources démersaux- Sous-groupe Sud.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Isarch, E. (Eva)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pascual-Alayón, P.J. (Pedro José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sobrino, I. (Ignacio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balguerías-Guerra, E. (Eduardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>FAO</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:08:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:08:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2008-10-14</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2008-10-08</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Demersal Resources, Guinea, Sierra Leona, Liberia,</dc:subject><dc:description>The second meeting of the FAO/CECAF Working Group on the Assessment of Demersal Resources,&#13;
Subgroup South met in Freetown, Sierra Leone, from 9 to 18 October 2008.&#13;
The overall objective of the Working Group is to contribute to improved management of demersal&#13;
resources in the Southern CECAF area through assessment of the state of the stocks and fisheries to&#13;
ensure optimal and sustainable use of the resources for the benefit of coastal countries.&#13;
Separate sections have been devoted to each of the following five groups: Demersal Fish South 1,&#13;
Demersal Fish South 2, Demersal Fish South 3, Shrimps South and Cephalopods South.&#13;
For each of the sections information is provided on: the fisheries, sampling intensity, biological&#13;
characteristics, stock identity, trends in data (catch, effort, biological data and abundance indices),&#13;
assessment, management recommendations and future research.&#13;
Trends and quality of the basic data (catch, effort and length frequencies) collected by each country, were&#13;
one the main topics of discussion during the 2008 Working Group meeting.&#13;
The results of the assessments show that many of the stocks analysed are fully to overexploited, and the&#13;
working group thus recommended that fishing effort should be reduced for the overexploited stocks to&#13;
avoid further depletion or not increased for the other stocks. For most of the stocks assessed, the only&#13;
series of stock abundance indices available were commercial catch per unit effort (CPUE) data series.&#13;
Commercial CPUE series are affected by changes in fleet size and fishing strategy. Consequently changes&#13;
observed in the CPUEs do not necessarily reflect the variations in stock abundance.&#13;
When possible, recommendations on catch levels are also indicated for each stock. Given that most&#13;
demersal fisheries in the region are multispecific, an overall reduction in fishing effort is necessary.</dc:description><dc:identifier>CECAF/ECAF Series 11/73. FAO. Rome, 2012. 311 pp</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2568</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>FAO/CECAF Working Group on the Assessment of Demersal resources- Subgroup South. (08/10/2008 - 14/10/2008. Freetown (Sierra Leone)). . CECAF/ECAF Series 11/73. FAO. Rome, 2012. 311 pp</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>CECAF/ECAF Series 11/73. FAO. Rome, 2012. 311 pp</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20321</dc:identifier><dc:type>report</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>