<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Datos preliminares sobre el cultivo de larvas y juveniles de centolla Maja squinado Herbst, 1788 en el Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo del Instituto Español de Oceanografía</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Estévez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Conde, F.J. (Francisco Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moxica, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fuentes, L. (Lidia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Otero-Pinzas, J.J. (Juan José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, J. L.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Centolla</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maja squinado</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproducción</dc:subject><dc:subject>cultivo larvario</dc:subject><dc:subject>engorde</dc:subject><dc:description>Preliminary data on reproduction, larval culture and growth of juveniles of spider crab Maja squinado, Herbst 1788 are given. Data were obtained from culture trials carried out during 2000 and 2001 at the Instituto Español de Oceanografía (IEO) in Vigo (northwest Spain). Each female spawned 3 to 5 times. Larval culture was carried out using intensive and semi-extensive systems; in the case of the former, the larvae survival rate ranged from 8-13 % during the first month of life. As to the semi-extensive system, the growth rate of 50-day-old juveniles was high, reaching a carapace length of 65.48 ± 7.53 mm, with a survival rate of 66 % at 9.5 months. However, at the same age, those from the intensive system had reached only 32.13 ± 7.86 mm, with a mortality of 100%.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se muestran los datos preliminares obtenidos en el Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo, del Instituto Español de Oceanografía (IEO), referidos a la reproducción, cultivo larvario y engorde de juveniles de centolla Maja squinado Herbst, 1788 a lo largo de los años 2000 y 2001. Se obtuvieron de 3 a 5 puestas de cada hembra estabulada. El cultivo larvario se realizó en dos sistemas: intensivo y semiextensivo; la supervivencia larvaria en el primero osciló entre 8 y 13% al mes de vida. A partir de los 50 días de edad, los juveniles procedentes del cultivo semiextensivo presentaron un crecimiento elevado alcanzando, a los 9,5 meses, una longitud de caparazón de 65,48 ± 7,53 mm y una supervivencia del 66 %. Sin embargo, los del cultivo intensivo alcanzaron solamente 32,13 ± 7,86 mm y una mortalidad del 100 % a la misma edad.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>