<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">La radiación fotosintéticamente activa o PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) en la recreación ambiental del acuario marino</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Castrillo, G. (Gerardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lanuza, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:37Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:37Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Acuarios</dc:subject><dc:subject>iluminación</dc:subject><dc:subject>extinción</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>gilvinas</dc:subject><dc:description>Values of PAR (Photosynthetically Active Radiation) have been obtained with an underwater Spherical Quantum Sensor at two shore stations and two large aquarium tanks from the Cantabrian Maritime Museum (Museo Marítimo del Cantábrico, MMC), to compare light environmental modelling. Photoperiod, sunrise, and sunset have been considered, as well as the vibration effect. PAR values indicate that the microcosmos contained in the tanks are essentially a scale or compressed model of the natural medium, as far was light is concerned, including 10 m of the shore water column in only 3 m. Many opportunities and problems are presented by this compression. Dissolved organic materials (DOM), especially gelbstoff, and concentration are related to this process.</dc:description><dc:description>Los registros del PAR (photosynthetically active radiation) obtenidos en dos estaciones costeras y en otros tantos acuarios del Museo Marítimo del Cantábrico (MMC) han servido para ajustar el modelo de iluminación de estos últimos. Las variaciones en el fotoperiodo, procesos como el amanecer y el ocaso, así como el centelleo, se han tenido en cuenta. Los valores del PAR y el coeficiente de atenuación muestran que los microcosmos de los tanques son esencialmente un modelo a escala o comprimido del presente en el medio natural, y este hecho plantea problemas a los organismos. La presencia y concentraciones de materia orgánica disuelta (MOD), especialmente gilvinas (gelbstoff), tienen relación con este proceso.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1462</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>