<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Amanay and El Banquete seamounts (Canary Islands): Vunerable Marine Ecosystems (VMEs) spatial distribution</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Falcón, Jesús Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Irusta, José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Jiménez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarralde-Vizuete, R. (Roberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brito, Alberto</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:15:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:15:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Amanay</dc:subject><dc:subject>El Banquete</dc:subject><dc:subject>montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecosistemas marinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>áreas marinas protegidas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversidad marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitats sensibles</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrecifes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directiva Hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>idoneidad de hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelización de comunidades e indicadores ecológicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine protected areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitive habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>reefs</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>habitat suitability</dc:subject><dc:subject>community and ecologic indicators modelling</dc:subject><dc:description>Amanay and El Banquete Seamounts (Southern Fuerteventura) is one of the areas chosen to be&#13;
depicted in the frame of INDEMARES project. The midpoint of the study area is located at 25 km from&#13;
Fuerteventura and 65 km from Gran Canaria. Methodology approach complies with a multidisciplinary&#13;
perspective, having described the area from geological, oceanographic, biological and fisheries points&#13;
of view. Habitat identification and mapping has been possible through intense sampling and the use of&#13;
habitat suitability modeling. Species structuring sensitive habitats have played a leading role, since&#13;
those habitats inventory and mapping were the project’s main aim. Direct samplers have been&#13;
complemented with visual samplers, the latter permitting a higher sampling effort without increasing&#13;
benthic habitat impact.&#13;
Several types of communities have been identified as “Habitat 1170, Reefs”, following Annex 1 from&#13;
Habitats Directive (Council Directive 92/43/CEE) from European Union, representing VMEs. We have&#13;
combined various types of multivariate analyses to describe the structure and spatial distribution of&#13;
benthic communities, to analyze the relationship between these communities and environmental&#13;
parameters, and subsequently, to build a community distribution model to predict the spatial distribution&#13;
of the communities, creating community distribution maps covering the entire area.&#13;
As a result of the analysis, we have identified, at circalittoral zone, Antipathella wollastoni (Gray, 1857)&#13;
black coral real forests at rocky bottoms. Regarding the bathyal zone, there are rocky bottoms with&#13;
anthipatarians, other with big size hexactinellid sponges (Asconema setubalense Kent, 1870), frequently&#13;
seen at rocky escarpments and outcrops. We also find at this depth Callogorgia verticillata (Pallas, 1766)&#13;
and Narella bellissima (Kükenthal, 1915) erect sea fans real forests, accompanied by Bebryce mollis&#13;
Philippi, 1842 and Eunicella verrucosa (Pallas, 1766) high densities. Pheronema carpenteri (Thomson,&#13;
1869) and Paramuricea biscaya Grasshoff, 1977 appear on rocky outcrops from 500 m down to 1500&#13;
m. Two kinds of VMEs are found from 500 m to 1000 m, isidid corals and lithistid sponges&#13;
(Leiodermatium-Neophryssospongia), siliceous sponges mixed on rocky bottom silted up with&#13;
sediments at upper bathyal zone. This community mixes with anthozoan Viminella flagellum (Johnson,&#13;
1863) from 500 m down to 1600 m, where we can also find Corallium niobe Bayer, 1964 and Corallium&#13;
tricolor (Johnson, 1899) deep water coral reefs. Dendrophyllia cornigera (Lamarck, 1816) and Phakellia&#13;
ventilabrum (Linnaeus, 1767) are remarkable 1170 habitat communities cohabiting with deep water&#13;
white corals Lophelia pertusa (Linnaeus, 1758) and Madrepora oculata Linnaeus, 1758 at lower&#13;
continental shelf and upper slope rocky bottoms. Here we can also find dead coral framework, and at&#13;
western El Banquete, we highlight the presence of Solenosmilia variabilis Duncan, 1873, another coldwater&#13;
white coral.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2585</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón). 2014. 7.5. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7.5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20338</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>