<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">The Spanish albacore (Thunnus alalunga) surface fishery in the northeastern Atlantic in 2005</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Zárate-Vidal, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Cabello-Ródenas, M.C. (María Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T10:06:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-04T10:06:02Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2007</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Thunnus alalunga</dc:subject><dc:subject>troll fishery</dc:subject><dc:subject>baitboat fishery</dc:subject><dc:subject>catch</dc:subject><dc:subject>size composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>age composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Northeast Atlantic</dc:subject><dc:description>The main features of the Spanish albacore (Thunnus alalunga) surface fishery operating during&#13;
summer and autumn months of 2005 in the northeast Atlantic and Bay of Biscay waters north of&#13;
40ºN parallel are presented in this document. The baitboat fleet increased its yield 30%;&#13;
likewise the troll fleet showed an increased catch of 36% respectively to the 2004 yield. Both&#13;
fleets increased their nominal fishing effort about 16% in 2005. The size composition of the&#13;
catches in 2005 obtained by both fleets showed a high proportion of age 2 derived by both&#13;
methods used to age catches: length slicing and age-length keys, which is in agreement with the&#13;
high proportion of age 1 present in 2004. However, in the case of age 3, the observed&#13;
proportion of the catch at age differs contingent on either method applied to age the catch in&#13;
the case of the troll fleet.</dc:description><dc:description>Este documento presenta un resumen sobre la actividad pesquera de las flotas de superficie&#13;
españolas: cebo vivo y cacea dirigidas a la pesca de atún blanco (Thunnus alalunga) que&#13;
desarrollaron su actividad en los meses de verano y otoño de 2005 en aguas del Atlántico&#13;
nordeste y golfo de Vizcaya al norte del paralelo 40 º N. La evolución de las capturas y&#13;
esfuerzo realizado por los barcos de cebo vivo y cacea, mostró un aumento del 30% y 36%&#13;
respectivamente frente a las capturas del año 2004. El esfuerzo nominal en días de pesca&#13;
aumentó prácticamente un 16% en ambas flotas. En 2005, la composición de tallas de la&#13;
captura, mostró un nivel elevado de capturas de edad 2 obtenido con los dos métodos&#13;
empleados: corte de tallas determinista (“filo de cuchillo”) y claves talla edad, que&#13;
corresponde a un nivel elevado de capturas de edad 1 observado en el año 2004 en ambas&#13;
flotas. Sin embargo la proporción de capturas de edad 3 observada difiere dependiendo del&#13;
método empleado en la obtención de la composición de edades de las capturas de la flota de&#13;
cacea.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document présente un résumé sur les activités de pêche des flottilles de surface espagnoles&#13;
(canne et ligne traînante) ayant ciblé le germon (Thunnus alalunga) pendant les mois d’été et&#13;
d’automne de 2005 dans les eaux de l’Atlantique Nord-Est et du Golfe de Gascogne, au nord du&#13;
parallèle 40ºN. L’évolution des prises et de l’effort déployé par les canneurs et les ligneurs a&#13;
présenté un accroissement de 30% et 36%, respectivement, par rapport aux prises de 2004.&#13;
L’effort nominal en jours de pêche a pratiquement augmenté de 16% pour ces deux flottilles. En&#13;
2005, la composition par tailles des captures a montré une forte proportion de prises d’âge 2,&#13;
obtenue à l’aide de deux méthodes, le découpage des tailles et les clefs âge-taille, qui&#13;
correspond à une forte proportion d’âge 1 observée en 2004 dans les deux flottilles. Toutefois,&#13;
la proportion observée de prises d’âge 3 est différente selon la méthode appliquée pour obtenir&#13;
la composition des âges des prises de la flottille de ligneurs.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1671</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Ortiz de Zárate, V., S. Barreiro, C. Rodríguez-Cabello, J. Valeiras. 2007. The Spanish albacore (Thunnus alalunga) surface fishery in the northeastern Atlantic in 2005. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 60 (2): 421-427</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>