<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Are the mitochondrial cox1 and cob genes suitable markers for species of Dionphysis Ehrenberg?</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Raho, N. (Nicolás)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Reguera, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Marín, I. (Irma)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-27T08:21:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-27T08:21:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>cob gene</dc:subject><dc:subject>cox1</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dinophysis species</dc:subject><dc:subject>D. acuminata complex</dc:subject><dc:subject>DSP</dc:subject><dc:description>The identification of Dinophysis species with similar morphology but different toxic (Diarrhetic Shellfish&#13;
Poisoning, DSP) potential is a crucial task in harmful algae monitoring programmes. The taxonomic&#13;
assignment of Dinophysis species using molecular markers is a difficult task due to extremely low&#13;
interspecific variability within their nuclear ribosomal genes and intergenic regions. Mitochondrial cox1&#13;
gene has been proposed as a better specific marker for Dinophysis species based on its higher resolution&#13;
for two morphologically related species (Dinophysis acuminata and Dinophysis ovum) of the ‘‘Dinophysis&#13;
acuminata complex’’. In this study, the potential of two mitochondrial genes (mt cox1 and cob) to&#13;
discriminate among six Dinophysis species (field isolates and cultures) associated with DSP events was&#13;
explored. Neither mt cox1 nor cob genes provided enough resolution for all species of Dinophysis. The cob&#13;
gene showed very poor resolution and grouped all Dinophysis spp. in a common clade. In contrast, the&#13;
cox1 phylogeny distinguished 5 clades in the Dinophysiales – the ‘‘acuminata complex’’, the ‘‘caudata&#13;
group’’, ‘‘acuta + norvegica’’ and Phalacromaspp. However, within the ‘‘D. acuminata complex’’ mtcox1 is&#13;
so far the unique marker that differentiates D. acuminata from other species: isolates of D. ovum and&#13;
Dinophysis sacculus had almost identical sequences (only four mismatches), but they were well separated&#13;
from D. acuminata. D. acuminata and Dinophysis skagii (considered a life cycle stage of the former) showed&#13;
identical cox1 sequences. Probes towards this gene can be useful in Mediterranean and Western Iberia&#13;
sites where the co-occurrence of close morphotypes of D. acuminata and D. sacculus pose a problem for&#13;
monitoring analyses. This is the first report on cultures of D. sacculus and its phylogenetic relation with&#13;
other species of the D. acuminata complex.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1737</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Harmful Algae, 28. 2013: 64-70</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.hal.2013.05.012</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>