<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Inventory and mapping of habitats and fisheries footprint off “Banco de La Concepción” seamount (Canary Islands). Criteria analysis for the marine protected area establishment</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Díaz, C. (Carolina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Falcón, Jesús Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pascual-Fernández, José Jaime</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bartolomé-Baraza, A. (Aurora)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Jiménez, J. (José)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sarralde-Vizuete, R. (Roberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Irusta, José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brito, Alberto</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T09:39:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T09:39:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Banco de La Concepción</dc:subject><dc:subject>montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecosistemas marinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>áreas marinas protegidas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversidad marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>hidrografía</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorfología</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitats sensibles</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades bentopelágicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades endobentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades epibentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocenosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrecifes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquerías</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquería artesanal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directiva Hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>idoneidad de hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelización de comunidades e indicadores ecológicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernanza</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine protected areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrography</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitive habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>endobenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>benthopelagic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>epibenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>reefs</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>artisanal fisheries</dc:subject><dc:subject>habitat suitability</dc:subject><dc:subject>community and ecologic indicators modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernance</dc:subject><dc:description>Banco de La Concepción is one of the areas chosen to be depicted in the frame of INDEMARES project.&#13;
It is located at 71 km to the NE of Lanzarote. The main aim of the project was to end up with an inventory&#13;
and mapping of habitats and fisheries footprint off the study area, information which would let the&#13;
administrations to establish a new Natura 2000 area, trying to reconcile protection of biodiversity with&#13;
artisanal local economic activities. Methodology approach complies with a multidisciplinary perspective,&#13;
having described the area from geological, oceanographic, biological and fisheries points of view.&#13;
Several surveys have taken place since 2009 to 2013 at Banco de La Concepción waters. Data from&#13;
VMS (Vessel Monitoring System) were used, combined with interviews to users (fishers), to describe&#13;
the fishery uses in the area.&#13;
Ten different types of communities have been identified as “Habitat 1170, Reefs”, following Annex 1&#13;
from Habitats Directive (Council Directive 92/43/CEE) from European Union. All of them have three&#13;
dimensional structure and species with certain size turning these areas into important containers of&#13;
biodiversity and hot spots for shelter. About protected species by Habitats Directive, Centrostephanus&#13;
longispinus (Philippi, 1845) belongs to Annex IV.&#13;
Neophryssospongia nolitangere (Schmidt, 1870) is included in the Canary Islands Catalog of Protected&#13;
Species as a vulnerable species. Within the Red List of Threatened Species of the International Union&#13;
for the Conservation of Nature, we can find several fishes as endangered species, while in the area can&#13;
also be found several vulnerable species, special importance have several elasmobranchs species.&#13;
Subsequent studies about deep water white corals Lophelia pertusa (Linnaeus, 1758) and Madrepora&#13;
oculata Linnaeus, 1758, present in the study area, could conclude with these species inclusion in the&#13;
list.&#13;
Fishery activities identified during this study with a higher degree of fishing intensity (tuna fishing with&#13;
pole lines and surface longlines for sworfish) don’t interact with the bottom. Electric reel hook and line&#13;
and bottom horizontal longline activities are not so frequent, but while the first one has very little impact&#13;
on the bottom (arose from anchoring), the latter is performed by only two vessels but with a high degree&#13;
of intensity and very spatially concentrated at rocky bottom areas, generating an important impact on&#13;
the bottom during the raising maneuver by getting snagged with benthic epifauna.&#13;
Ecological assessment results from values assigned to different community or species features or&#13;
parameters, not always in a quantitative manner, depending on their diverse nature. To use a totally&#13;
aseptic quantitative index is impossible; therefore, an often used tool is to resort to an expert panel&#13;
(group of experts) which members individually assign a value to each of the assessed parameters. This&#13;
solution absorbs bias produced by individual criteria. We established three value levels (low, medium&#13;
and high) for each of the twelve parameters used. After all we end up with a map of an ecological&#13;
assessment index (EAI) which is simple and weighs every parameter equally. Higher EAI is assigned to&#13;
bathial rocky bottoms with anthipatarians, closely followed by Corallium spp deep water coral reefs.&#13;
Bathial rocky bottoms with Callogorgia verticillata (Pallas, 1766) have a mid-high EAI.&#13;
We are not very optimistic about collective action preconditions, which explain the capacity of human&#13;
communities to design, implement and enforce designed institutions to resources management and protection. There is an absence of fishermen organizations closely linked to the area, of leadership&#13;
among effective users, which have a very limited experience in conservation initiatives and an a priori&#13;
reluctant attitude. A proper step-zero at Banco de La Concepción marine protected area will be provided&#13;
by sharing available scientific information with users, public report and open and full consultation about&#13;
the protection possibilities, giving time to assimilation, involving local stakeholders, and finding&#13;
coordination among institutions and security bodies to ensure protection measures enforcement</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón). 2014. 6.4. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>6.4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20312</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>