<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Tracking bluefin tuna cohorts from east  Atlantic Spanish fisheries since the 1980s</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Marín, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Urbina-Gutiérrez, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alot-Montes, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cort-Basilio, J.L. (José Luis)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Serna-Ernst, J.M. (José Miguel) de-la</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías-López, A.D. (Ángel David)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez-Cabello-Ródenas, M.C. (María Cristina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ruiz, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:53:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-05T08:53:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2009</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Atlantic bluefin tuna</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thunnus thynnus</dc:subject><dc:subject>year-class</dc:subject><dc:subject>catch at age</dc:subject><dc:subject>coastal fisheries connection</dc:subject><dc:subject>migrations</dc:subject><dc:description>Relative abundance and mean size at age analyses were performed for the catches of three Atlantic&#13;
Spanish fisheries, in search of an exceptionally abundant cohort in the recent history of the eastern&#13;
Atlantic and Mediterranean bluefin tuna stock. Length distributions of baitboat fisheries, both in the Bay&#13;
of Biscay and areas close to the Strait of Gibraltar as well as trap catches from the Spanish Atlantic&#13;
coast were converted to age distributions using age length keys from calcified structures. Results do&#13;
validate indirectly the ageing method. The 1994 cohort was clearly tracked for juveniles and young&#13;
adults, 3 to 7 years old, in baitboat catches, and also for older specimens, 9 to 11 years old, in the trap&#13;
fisheries. Based on these results, it is suggested that the juvenile and young adults fisheries in the&#13;
western part of the Iberian Peninsula are interconnected between one another and with the Balearic&#13;
Islands area of the western Mediterranean, as it is the nearest spawning ground described and because&#13;
it is also supported by tagging and other studies.</dc:description><dc:description>Afin de trouver une cohorte exceptionnellement abondante dans la récente histoire du stock de ton&#13;
rouge de l’Atlantique Est et de la Méditerranée, on a procédé à une analyse de l’abondance relative et&#13;
de la taille moyenne par âge des captures réalisées par trois pêcheries espagnoles de l’Atlantique. Les&#13;
distributions par tailles de deux pêcheries de canneurs dans le Golfe de Gascogne et dans les eaux&#13;
proches du Détroit de Gibraltar, ainsi que les prises des madragues de la côte atlantique espagnole, ont&#13;
été converties en âges à l’aide des clefs taille-âge obtenues à partir de la lecture de structures&#13;
calcifiées. Les résultats valident indirectement la méthode de détermination de l’âge. La cohorte de&#13;
1994 affiche une forte indication présente chez les juvéniles et les jeunes adultes, de 3 à 7 ans, capturés&#13;
dans les pêcheries de canneurs ainsi que chez les spécimens d’âge plus avancé, de 9 à 11 ans, pêchés à&#13;
la madrague. Ces résultats suggèrent que les pêcheries de juvéniles et de jeunes adultes de la partie&#13;
occidentale de la péninsule ibérique sont interconnectées entre elles ainsi qu’avec la zone des îles&#13;
Baléares, en Méditerranée occidentale, étant donné qu’il s’agit de la zone de frai la plus proche et qu’il&#13;
existe des indices de cette relation d’après les études de marquage et d’autres études.</dc:description><dc:description>Para encontrar una cohorte excepcionalmente abundante en la historia reciente del stock de atún rojo&#13;
del Atlántico este y Mediterráneo, se realizó un análisis de la abundancia relativa y la talla media por&#13;
edad de las capturas de tres pesquerías atlánticas españolas. Las distribuciones de tallas de dos&#13;
pesquerías de cebo vivo, en el Golfo de Vizcaya y en aguas próximas al Estrecho de Gibraltar, así como&#13;
las capturas de las almadrabas de la costa atlántica española, fueron convertidas a edades mediante el&#13;
uso de claves talla edad, obtenidas a partir de la lectura de piezas esqueléticas. Los resultados validan&#13;
indirectamente el método de determinación de la edad. La cohorte de 1994 presenta una fuerte señal&#13;
que pudo ser encontrada en los juveniles y adultos jóvenes, 3 a 7 años, capturados en las pesquerías de&#13;
cebo vivo y también en especimenes mayores, 9 a 11 años, pescados con las almadrabas. Con esto&#13;
resultados se sugiere que las pesquerías de juveniles y adultos jóvenes de la parte occidental de la&#13;
península Ibérica están interconectadas entre ellas y con el área de las Islas Baleares, en el&#13;
Mediterráneo occidental, puesto que es la zona de puesta más próxima y porque también hay evidencias&#13;
de esta relación mediante el marcado y otros estudios.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodríguez-Marín, E., J.M. Ortiz de urbina, E. Alot, J.L. Cort, J.M. de la Serna, D. Macías, C. Rodríguez-Cabello, M. Ruiz, X. Valeiras. 2009. Tracking bluefin tuna cohorts from east  Atlantic Spanish fisheries since the 1980s. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 63: 121-132</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>