<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Abyssal Cladorhizidae (Porifera) from Deep Sea African Basins (SE Atlantic)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cristobo, J. (Javier)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Gijón</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T16:19:47Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T16:19:47Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Porifera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carnivorous sponges</dc:subject><dc:subject>Africa, Abyssal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taxonomy</dc:subject><dc:description>The expeditions Diva 1 and Diva 2 on board R/V Meteor dealt with species composition, biogeography and with diversity and dominance patterns along a latitudinal transect in the southeastern Atlantic ocean.&#13;
Samples were gathered from more than 5000 m depth in the Cape Basin, Angola Basin and Guinea Basin (SE. Atlantic); in a total of 5 working areas, sampling was performed for organisms of all size classes.&#13;
The DIVA expeditions represent a German contribution to the multinational “Census of the Abyssal Marine Life” programme (CeDAMAr) which aims to compare and understand global abyssal biodiversity and biogeographic patterns.&#13;
Sponges were collected with a modified Agassiz-trawl.&#13;
Carnivorous sponge’s collection of genus Asbestopluma and Chondrocladia is represented by 23 specimens of 6 species: Asbestopluma sp.; Chondrocladia levii Cristobo, Urgorri &amp; Rios, 2005; C. vaceleti Cristobo, Urgorri &amp; Rios, 2005; C. nicolae Cristobo, Urgorri &amp; Rios, 2005; C. guiteli Topsent, 1904 and Chondrocladia sp. nov.&#13;
In this work we discuss about the presence of these species in the West Africa abyssal basins and describe the new species.&#13;
Six specimens were collected in the Diva 1 cruise (Angola basin) and seventeen in the Diva 2 cruise: 3 in Cape basin, 2 in the Angola basin that belong to two species described in the results of Diva 1 Expedition (Cristobo et al, 2005), C. levii and C. vaceleti, and 10 specimens in the Guinea basin belong also to this genus but it is perhaps a new species.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2661</dc:identifier><dc:type>oralRecording</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>