<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Distribución pasada y reciente de Acipenser sturio L., 1758 en la península Ibérica</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Almaça, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Elvira, B.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:22Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:22Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Esturión atlántico</dc:subject><dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject><dc:subject>España</dc:subject><dc:subject>golfo de Vizcaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>golfo de Cádiz</dc:subject><dc:subject>mar Mediterráneo</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper reviews the ichthyological and historical literature referring to sturgeon on the Iberian Peninsula. Three different species of Acipenseridae, namely Acipenser sturio L., 1758, A. naccarii Bonaparte, 1836, and Huso huso (L., 1758), have, in the past, been recorded in the Iberian seas and rivers. However, examination of specimens housed in zoological collections has clearly proved that just one, the Atlantic sturgeon A. sturio, is native to the Iberian Peninsula. Analysis of captures and observations suggests a regression of the species in Portugal and Spain, notable from the middle of the 20th century. However, A. sturio is not technically extirpated, at least not in Spain, since it was fished in 1988 off the coast of Cantabria, and in 1992 near the mouth of the Guadalquivir. Consequently, two local populations are reported as still living on the Iberian littoral: one in the Bay of Biscay and the other in Cadiz Bay. This is not contradicted by historical and present data on the Iberian distribution and status of the sturgeon.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se revisa la bibliografía ictiológica e histórica relativa a la presencia del esturión en la península Ibérica. En el pasado se han citado hasta tres especies distintas de Acipenseridae en los mares y ríos ibéricos: Acipenser sturio L., 1758, A. naccarii Bonaparte, 1836 y Huso huso (L., 1758). Sin embargo, el estudio de los ejemplares conservados en colecciones zoológicas ha probado que sólo una, el esturión atlántico A. sturio, es nativo de la península Ibérica. El análisis de capturas y observaciones sugiere una grave regresión de la especie en Portugal y en España, muy acentuada desde mediados del siglo XX. Todavía, A. sturio no se puede considerar técnicamente extinguido, al menos en España, ya que ejemplares aislados fueron capturados en la costa de Cantabria en 1988 y cerca de la desembocadura del Guadalquivir en 1992. Por tanto, se reconocen dos poblaciones locales supervivientes en el litoral ibérico: una en el mar Cantábrico y otra en el golfo de Cádiz. Esto no se contradice con los datos históricos y actuales de la distribución ibérica y del estado de conservación del esturión.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1321</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>