<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Life cycle, morphology and phylogeny of species of Fragilidium Balech from west Iberia</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Amorim, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Veloso, V. (Vera)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fraga, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-04-04T08:45:00Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-04-04T08:45:00Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Specimens belonging to the mixotrophic genus Fragilidium were isolated from coastal&#13;
waters of west Iberia (NE Atlantic). Based on plate morphology and large subunit ribosomal DNA&#13;
(LSU rDNA) sequences two species were identified: F. subglobosum and F. cf. duplocampanaeforme.&#13;
The life cycle is similar in both species. The asexual cycle is characterized by an alternation&#13;
between a thecate motile stage and a reproductively active coccoid stage. The sexual cycle is&#13;
characterized by heterogamous anisogamy and includes a sexual benthic hypnozygote. The first&#13;
apical plate in vegetative cells does not touch the apical pore plate while in gametes it does, confirming&#13;
in Fragilidium the homology of what is frequently referred to as the first pre-cingular with&#13;
the first apical plate in Gonyaulacales. Both species were observed to prey on Ceratium horridum.&#13;
Molecular phylogenetic analyses with strains isolated from other geographical areas and Fragilidium&#13;
gene sequences available in GenBank identified three different clades: one comprising F. subglobosum&#13;
from the type locality and strains from Iberian waters; a second comprising the&#13;
morphological species F. cf. duplocampanaeforme from Iberia and other strains from NE Atlantic,&#13;
SE Atlantic and the south Pacific; and a third with an unassigned species from the SE Atlantic.</dc:description><dc:identifier>978-1-86239-368-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1749</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Amorim, A., Veloso, V., Rodríguez, F., Fraga, S. 2013. Life cycle, morphology and phylogeny of species of Fragilidium Balech from west Iberia. Pág. 215-224 In: Lewis, J. M., Marret, F. &amp; Bradley, L., editor(es). Biological and Geological Perspectives of Dinoflagellates (10 pp.). The Micropalaeontological Society, Special Publications. Geological Society, Londres (Reino Unido).</dc:identifier><dc:type>bookPart</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>