<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Distribution of anionic and nonionic surfactants in a sewage-impacted Mediterranean coastal lagoon: Inputs and seasonal variations</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Traverso-Soto, J.M. (Juan Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lara-Martín, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Mazo, E. (Eduardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>León-León, V.M. (Víctor Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-25T11:56:43Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-25T11:56:43Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Linear alkylbenzene sulfonates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nonylphenol polyethoxylates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alcohol polyethoxylates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lagoon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Distribution</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work we have monitored the seasonal inputs, occurrence and distribution of the world’s most widely used surfactants (linear alkylbenzene sulfonates, LAS, nonylphenol polyethoxylates, NPEOs, and alcohol polyethoxylates, AEOs) in Mar Menor lagoon (SE Spain) and its main tributary (El Albujón) for the first time. Concentration of target compounds was determined in both surface waters and sediments after solid phase extraction and pressurized liquid extraction, respectively, followed by liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS). There were significant differences in surfactant fluxes from El Albujón towards Mar Menor depending on the season and the day of the week, with maximum estimated annual inputs being detected for LAS (406 kg) and their metabolites, sulfophenyl carboxylic acids (482 kg). Average concentrations of surfactants in the lagoon were between 44 and 1665 µg/kg in sediment, and between 0.3 and 63 µg/L in water. These levels were significantly higher for samples collected near the shore than for those measured inside the lagoon itself. Overall, the occurrence and distribution of surfactants in the system could be explained due to a combination of different sources (surface and groundwater inputs, treated and untreated wastewater effluents, towns, ports, etc.) and simultaneous in-situ physicochemical and biological processes, with an special emphasis on degradation during warmer months.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0048-9697</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Science of the Total Environment, X. 2014: 1-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2014.06.107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20224</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>