<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Resistencia a la infección por virus de salmónidos: inducción y potenciación, in vitro e in vivo, de un estado antivírico celular</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez Saint-Jean, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez Prieto, S. I.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>IPNV</dc:subject><dc:subject>IHNV</dc:subject><dc:subject>VHSV</dc:subject><dc:subject>coinfecciones víricas</dc:subject><dc:subject>interferón</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mx</dc:subject><dc:subject>inmunidad inespecífica</dc:subject><dc:subject>virus de peces</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study aimed to analyse comparatively the protection induced by polycytidylic acid (poly I:C), a potent interferon inductor, and several salmonid fish viruses against homologous or heterologous viruses in vitro (in BF-2 cells) and in vivo in the brown trout Salmo trutta L., 1758), in single or dual infections. The expression of MxmRNA protein was used as an interferon marker. The results showed strong interference activity against rhabdoviruses in the supernatants of macrophages stimulated with poly I:C and with heterologous rhabdoviruses. The antiviral effectiveness of the cytokine-like activities differed amongst the several viruses tested. Moreover, high reduction of cumulative mortality was shown in poly I:C stimulated (3 days before infection) and IPNV-IHNV coinfected trout. A correlation between stimulation, antiviral activity and mRNA-Mx protein expression was also observed. The results indicate that interferon-mediated activity plays a significant role in the loss of IHNV virulence when it is coinfected with IPNV.</dc:description><dc:description>El propósito de este trabajo fue analizar comparativamente la protección inducida por el ácido polycitidílico (poly I:C), un potente inductor de interferón, y algunos virus de salmónidos frente a infecciones producidas por virus homólogos o heterólogos, tanto in vitro (en células BF-2) como in vivo (en trucha común Salmo trutta L., 1758). Los resultados demostraron que los sobrenadantes de macrófagos de trucha común, estimulados con poly I:C y rhabdovirus, inducen una actividad antivírica e interferente considerable, especialmente frente a rhabdovirus heterólogos. La efectividad antivírica de esta actividad citokina-like fue distinta según los virus ensayados. También se constató una reducción alta de la mortalidad acumulada en truchas estimuladas con poly I:C (tres días antes de la infección) y coinfectadas con una mezcla de IPNV-IHNV en la misma proporción. Se observó una correlación entre estimulación, actividad antivírica y expresión de Mx mRNA. Los resultados indican que el interferón desempeña un papel importante en la pérdida de infectividad del IHNV en las coinfecciones con IPNV.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1365</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>