<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Aplicación de marcadores microsatélites a los programas de cultivo del rodaballo Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Borrell, Y.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vázquez, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Sánchez-Prado, J.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Pato, C. (Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez-Tapia, C. (Concha)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Blanco, G.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:12Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Parentesco</dc:subject><dc:subject>paternidades</dc:subject><dc:subject>acuicultura</dc:subject><dc:subject>genética</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, eight microsatellite loci were used to estimate genetic relatedness and pedigree determination in turbot Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758). Through genotypic analysis of broodstocks and their progenies, from two different turbot hatcheries, the capacity of these loci to correctly classify individuals as related or non-related was examined. Relatedness coefficients among related and non-related individuals presented means close to those theoretically expected, and the percentages of related individuals included in all relatedness coefficients found to be below the R = 0 value ranged from 0% (hatchery A) to 29 % (hatchery B). The identification of both parents for each individual was possible in more than 80 % of the cases from hatchery A, but only 41% of those from hatchery B.</dc:description><dc:description>Se utilizaron ocho loci microsatélites en la estimación de relaciones genéticas y determinación de pedigríes en rodaballo Scophthalmus maximus (L., 1758). Mediante el análisis de los genotipos de reproductores y descendientes de dos piscifactorías se investigó la capacidad de los loci para clasificar correctamente a los individuos como emparentados o no. Las distribuciones de los coeficientes de relación genética (R) entre individuos emparentados y no relacionados exhiben medias cercanas a las esperadas teóricamente y el porcentaje de individuos emparentados que forman el total de coeficientes de relación genética que se encuentran por debajo del valor R = 0 oscilan entre el 0 % (estación A) y el 29 % (estación B). Así mismo, la identificación correcta de ambos parentales para cada descendiente fue posible en más del 80 % de los casos en la estación A y en sólo el 41 % en la estación B.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1238</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>