<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Study on the migrations and stock structure of Albacore (Thunnus alalunga) from the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean sea based on conventional tag release-recapture experiences</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrizabalaga, H. (Haritz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Rodas, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Zárate-Vidal, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Costas, E. (Eduardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:27:53Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:27:53Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002</dcterms:issued><dc:description>In this paper a study on the migrations of albacore from the North Atlantic Ocean and the&#13;
Mediterranean Sea is made, based on the information from conventional tag release-recapture&#13;
experiences. Information on 643 recaptured fish from a total of 23,777 tagged fish has been&#13;
analyzed. This information highlights the long distance movements of albacore, their&#13;
transoceanic migrations and the possibility of an interchange of fish between the North&#13;
Atlantic and the Mediterranean.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent document fait état d'une étude sur les migrations du germon de l'Atlantique nord et&#13;
de la Méditerranée, d'après des informations provenant d'expériences de marquage et de&#13;
recapture avec marques conventionnelles. L'information correspondant à 643 poissons&#13;
recapturés sur un total de 23.777 poissons marqués a été analysée. Cette information révèle les&#13;
déplacements du germon sur de grandes distances, ses migrations transocéaniques et&#13;
l'éventualité d'échanges de poissons entre l'Atlantique nord et la Méditerranée.</dc:description><dc:description>En este documento se hace un estudio de las migraciones del atún blanco del Atlántico norte y&#13;
Mediterráneo en base a las informaciones procedentes de las experiencias de marcado-recaptura&#13;
convencionales. Se ha analizado la información procedente de 643 peces&#13;
recapturados de un total de 23.777 peces marcados. Con esta información se ponen de&#13;
manifiesto los grandes movimientos del atún blanco, sus desplazamientos transoceánicos y la&#13;
posibilidad de intercambio de peces entre el Atlántico norte y el Mediterráneo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1661</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Arrizabalaga, H., V. López Rodas, V. Ortiz de Zárate, E. Costas, A. González-Garcés. 2002. Study on the migrations and stock structure of Albacore (Thunnus alalunga) from the Atlantic Ocean and the Mediterranean sea based on conventional tag release-recapture experiences. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 54 (5): 1479-1494</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>