<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Analysis of the relationships between Patagonian squid (Doryteuthis gahi)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez-Portela, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez, R. (Roi)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernandes, W. (Wendy)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-24T15:23:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-24T15:23:49Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-16</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>cephalopods, Doryteuthis gahi fisheries, Southwest Atlantic, environmental parameters, GIS</dc:subject><dc:description>Doryteuthis (Loligo) gahi is the second most important cephalopod species in the SW&#13;
Atlantic from a fisheries point of view. This species and hence, the fisheries profitability&#13;
and sustainability, are subject to large inter-annual variability in recruitment strength,&#13;
mainly due to interannual and seasonal variations of the Falkland/Malvinas Current. In&#13;
this working document we analyse the environmental, geographical, temporal and&#13;
physical factors affecting the distribution (abundance) of D. gahi in two areas where its&#13;
abundance is highest, using geographic information systems tools. We found a slight&#13;
positive correlation between CPUE and longitude, as well as between CPUE and depth&#13;
in the northern area, but no correlations could be found between SST and the other&#13;
explanatory variables. Regarding the southern area in summer-autumn, we found that&#13;
CPUE increases with longitude as we go to the east, and with latitude. We also found&#13;
positive correlations between SST and CPUE, as well as with depth. In winter spring&#13;
our study revealed a slight relationship between CPUE and location, and with depth.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES WGCEPH 2014. (16/06/2014 - 19/06/2014. Lisboa (Portugal)). 2014. ICES WGCEPH 2014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>ICES WGCEPH 2014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20214</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>