<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Comparative skin mucus and serum humoral defence mechanism in the teleost gilthead seabream (Sparus aurata)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Guardiola, F.A. (Francisco A.)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cuesta, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arizcun-Arizcun, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Meseguer, J. (Jose)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Esteban, M.A. (Maria A.)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-03T12:57:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-03T12:57:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Skin mucus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mucosal immunity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humoral immunity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bactericidal activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gilthead seabream (Sparus aurata)</dc:subject><dc:description>Mucosal surfaces of fish, including skin, gill and gut, contain numerous immune substances poorly&#13;
studied that act as the first line of defence against a broad spectrum of pathogens. This study aimed to&#13;
identify and characterize for the first time different constitutive humoral defence mechanisms of the skin&#13;
mucus of gilthead seabream (Sparus aurata). To do this, the levels of total immunoglobulin M, several&#13;
enzymes and proteins (peroxidase, lysozyme, alkaline phosphatase, esterases, proteases and antiproteases),&#13;
as well as the bactericidal activity against opportunist fish pathogens (Vibrio harveyi, Vibrio&#13;
angillarum, Photobacterium damselae) and non-pathogenic bacteria (Escherichia coli, Bacillus subtilis) were&#13;
measured in the skin mucus and compared with those found in the serum. This study demonstrates that&#13;
gilthead seabream skin mucus contains lower levels of IgM, similar levels of lysozyme, alkaline phosphatase&#13;
and proteases, and higher esterase, peroxidase and antiprotease activities than serum. In&#13;
addition, skin mucus revealed stronger bactericidal activity against tested fish pathogen bacteria&#13;
compared to the serum activity, while human bacteria can even grow more in the presence of mucus. The&#13;
results could be useful for better understanding the role of the skin mucus as a key component of the&#13;
innate immune system with potential application for the aquaculture.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2098</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Fish and shellfish immunology, 36. 2014: 545-551</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.fsi.2014.01.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20063</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>