<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Selectividad de artes de arrastre en aguas de Mallorca (Illes Balears)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Massutí, E. (Enric)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Guijarro, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mas, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Guardiola, Mª. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:20Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Selectividad</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrastre de fondo</dc:subject><dc:subject>malla rómbica</dc:subject><dc:subject>malla cuadrada</dc:subject><dc:subject>copo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mallorca</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediterráneo occidental</dc:subject><dc:description>Sixty-two bottom-trawl hauls carried out off the southern coast of Majorca (western Mediterranean) are analysed. They were carried out at depths ranging from 54-772 m, by the F. V. Moralti Nou, using three commercial bottom trawls with 40 mm diamond- and square-mesh cod-ends, during the surveys SELBAR0902 (from 23rd September to 22nd October, 2002) and SELBAR0503 (from 12th May to 6th June, 2003). The objective was to compare, for the main target species in this fishery, the commercial yields, selectivity parameters and selection curves, and percentage of discards captured with both mesh shapes. The covered cod-end method was employed. From 35 species or commercial categories analysed, higher yields with diamond mesh were found in three of them, but only one of them -Spicara smaris (L., 1758)- can be considered as a target species for bottom trawl-fishing in that bathymetric range. Size at first capture was larger with square mesh than with diamond mesh in all the species, except one. The percentage of total catch discarded and the discards of commercial species were also lower with square mesh than with diamond mesh.</dc:description><dc:description>Se analizan 62 pescas realizadas por el B. P. Moralti Nou al sur de Mallorca (Illes Balears) (Mediterráneo occidental) a profundidades de entre 54 y 772 m con tres artes comerciales de arrastre de fondo y copos de malla rómbica y cuadrada de 40 mm durante las campañas SELBAR0902 (del 23 de septiembre al 22 de octubre de 2002) y SELBAR0503 (del 12 de mayo al 6 de junio de 2003). El objetivo fue comparar rendimientos comerciales, rangos y curvas de selección y porcentajes de captura descartada con ambos tipos de malla para las principales especies objetivo de esta pesquería. El método aplicado fue el de copo cubierto. De las 35 especies o categorías comerciales consideradas, en tres se obtuvieron mayores rendimientos con malla rómbica, si bien sólo una de ellas -Spicara smaris (L., 1758)- puede considerarse objetivo de la pesca de arrastre en el estrato batimétrico considerado. Las tallas de primera captura con malla cuadrada fueron superiores a las de malla rómbica en todas las especies, excepto en una. Los porcentajes de captura total descartada y de descartes de especies comerciales con malla cuadrada fueron también menores a los de malla rómbica.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0212-1565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1305</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Informes Técnicos. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>656-07-004-6</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>