<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Characteristics (abundance, type and origin) of beach litter on the Galician coast (NW Spain) from 2001 to 2010</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lahuerta, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Antelo, P. (Pilar)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Scientia Marina</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T08:29:04Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T08:29:04Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>beach litter</dc:subject><dc:subject>types</dc:subject><dc:subject>sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galician coast</dc:subject><dc:subject>NW Iberian Peninsula</dc:subject><dc:subject>basuras en playas</dc:subject><dc:subject>tipos</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuentes</dc:subject><dc:subject>costa gallega</dc:subject><dc:subject>NO Península Ibérica</dc:subject><dc:description>In order to assess the situation of beach litter on the Galician coast (NW Spain), we conducted a seasonal series of sampling on three beaches: A Lanzada, Baldaio and O Rostro. A total of 79 surveys were conducted from 2001 to 2010 on a stretch of 100 m and a stretch of 1 km. A total of 37862 beach litter items were counted and classified on the 100-m stretch and 7845 on the 1-km stretch. The average annual value of litter items for the 100-m beach stretch was 1016±633, 88±31 and 332±183; for the 1-km stretch, the average value of litter items was 163±87, 42±31 and 81±38, for A Lanzada, Baldaio and O Rostro beaches, respectively. The most common element found in beach litter was made of plastic, with average percent of 63, 38 and 83 for A Lanzada, Baldaio and O Rostro, respectively. We found that the main source of beach litter was the fishing and aquaculture sector, with an average percent value of 23, 14 and 38 for A Lanzada, Baldaio and O Rostro, respectively.</dc:description><dc:description>Con el fin de evaluar la situación de las basuras marinas en playas de la costa de Galicia (noroeste de España) se realizó una serie de muestreos estacionales en tres playas: A Lanzada, Baldaio y O Rostro. 79 muestreos se llevaron a cabo desde 2001 hasta 2010 en tramos de playas de 100 metros y 1 km. 37862 elementos fueron contados y clasificados en el tramo de 100 metros y 7845 en los estudios de 1 km. El valor promedio anual de basuras por cada 100 m de playa fue 1016±633, 88±31 y 332±183; en los muestreos de 1 km de playa, el valor medio fue de 163±87, 42±31 y 81±38, para A Lanzada, O Baldaio y Rostro, respectivamente. El elemento más común que se encuentra en la basura de la playa se compone principalmente de plástico con un porcentaje promedio de 63, 38 y 83 en A Lanzada, Baldaio y O Rostro, respectivamente. Se encontró que las principales fuentes de basura en playa son la pesca y la acuicultura, con un porcentaje promedio de 23, 14 y 38 en A Lanzada, Baldaio y O Rostro, respectivamente.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0214-0358</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1643</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Scientia Marina, 78 (1). 2014: 125-134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.3989/scimar03883.31B</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7254</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>