<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">European initiatives to disseminate the Geo-information of marine environmnet: EMODNET. Marine Knowledge 2020. IEO contributions.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Tello-Antón, M.O. (María Olvido)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mata-Chacón, D. (Dulce)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Serrano-López, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Tel, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lavín, A. (Alicia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nogueira, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Sede Central IEO</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-26T15:41:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-26T15:41:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-26</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Geo-information</dc:subject><dc:subject>Marine environment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Knowledge 2020</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMODNET</dc:subject><dc:description>Marine Knowledge 2020 brings together marine data from different sources with the aim of helping&#13;
industry, public authorities and researches find the data and make more effective use of the to develop&#13;
new products and services, and improving our understanding of how the seas behave.&#13;
On this way, it is necessary to develop tools and platforms to provide accessibility to marine information.&#13;
The UE is developing several initiatives on this way. EMODnet is an initiative from the European&#13;
Commission Directorate-General for Maritime Affairs and Fisheries (DG-MARE) as part of its Marine&#13;
Knowledge 2020 strategy.&#13;
The EMODnet aim is to unlock fragmented and hidden marine data resources and to make these available&#13;
to individuals and organizations (public and private), and to facilitate investment in sustainable&#13;
coastal and offshore activities through improved access to quality-assured, standardized and harmonized&#13;
marine data. There are six sub-portals in operation that provide access to marine data from the following&#13;
themes: bathymetry, geology, physics, chemistry, biology, and seabed habitats. IEO are implicated in&#13;
the collecting data about bathymetry, physics, chemistry, biology and seabed habitats.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2453</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV International Symposium of Marine Sciences. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (España)). . 003. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20244</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>CC0 1.0 Universal</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>