<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Banco de La Concepci´on: A new Natura 2000 Marine Site off Canary Islands</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Martín-Sosa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Porto, M. (Marcos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Almón-Pazos, B. (Bruno)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Acosta-Díaz, C. (Carolina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrese-González, B. (Beatriz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Irusta, José Manuel</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Barreiro-Jueguen, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jiménez, S. (Sebastián)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Canarias</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:47:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:47:58Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Banco de La Concepción</dc:subject><dc:subject>montes submarinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecosistemas marinos</dc:subject><dc:subject>áreas marinas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversidad marina</dc:subject><dc:subject>hidrografía</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorfología</dc:subject><dc:subject>hábitats sensibles</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades bentopelágicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades endobentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>comunidades epibentónicas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocenosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrecifes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquerías</dc:subject><dc:subject>pesquería artesanal</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directiva Hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>idoneidad de hábitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelización de comunidades e indicadores ecológicos</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernanza</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seamounts</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine ecosystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine protected areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrography</dc:subject><dc:subject>geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitive habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>endobenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>benthopelagic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>epibenthic communities</dc:subject><dc:subject>reefs</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>artisanal fisheries</dc:subject><dc:subject>habitat suitability</dc:subject><dc:subject>community and ecologic indicators modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>gobernance</dc:subject><dc:description>The main objective of the LIFE+ INDEMARES project is to contribute to the protection and sustainable&#13;
use of the biodiversity in the Spanish seas through the identification of valuable areas for the Natura 2000&#13;
Network. The Spanish Institute of Oceanography (IEO) has been in charge of implementing scientific&#13;
surveys to map sensitive habitats of seven of the ten INDEMARES areas, and to determine the fisheries&#13;
footprint over these areas.&#13;
Banco de La Concepci´on is one of the areas chosen to be depicted in the frame of INDEMARES project.&#13;
Located at 71 km to the NE of Lanzarote, at the coordinates 29º 55’ Latitude N and 12º 45’ Longitude&#13;
W, Banco de la Concepci´on raises from 2,541 m up to its summit at 170 m deep.&#13;
The biological richness of Banco de la Concepci´on is very influenced by the deep water up-welling&#13;
phenomena, which create a high productivity, attracting a multitude of pelagic species, such as cetaceans,&#13;
turtles, sharks, and tunas looking for food. In its vicinity, fishery resources such as goraz, anglerfish, and&#13;
hakes, are abundant, and a rich invertebrate fauna cohabits in their bottoms. Banco de la Concepci´on is&#13;
a traditional fishing area of oceanic pelagic species, and very good to catch demersal fish; it is highly&#13;
visited by Galician and Portuguese drifters and long liners that fish in Mauritania, and mainly by the&#13;
Andalusian longliners. In general, its main impacts are related to uncontrolled fishing pressure. The&#13;
available information on the anthropogenic impact of the area was scarce, and its level of research was&#13;
very poor as well, before INDEMARES project.&#13;
Methodology approach complies with a multidisciplinary perspective, having described the area from&#13;
geological, oceanographic, biological and fisheries points of view. Several surveys have taken place since&#13;
2009 to 2013 at Banco de La Concepci´on waters. Traps, longlines, beam trawls, benthic dredges and box&#13;
corers have been used to sample benthic fauna. These last two, plus EM 3002 multibeam echosounder,&#13;
PS 18 parametric sub bottom profiler, EA600 monobeam sounder, Seapath 200 positioning sensor and&#13;
SV Plus sound velocity calibration sensor were used to make a geophysical study which provides a range&#13;
of environmental factors. CTD was used to depict physical conditions of the water column. Finally,&#13;
Remote Operated Vehicle Liropus 2000 and different photogrammetric tugged sleds were used to make&#13;
a great effort of visual sampling.&#13;
Data from VMS (Vessel Monitoring System) were used, combined with interviews to users (fishers), to&#13;
describe the fishery uses in the area.&#13;
Results from all this field work provide enough information for the administrations to establish a new&#13;
Natura 2000 area, trying to reconcile protection of biodiversity and artisanal local economic activities.&#13;
This establishment should take place at the end of a process of public consultation to stakeholders which&#13;
is taking place in the present and which will help to shape the future Management Plan which will give&#13;
details about permitted and prohibited uses.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Simposio Internacional de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas). 2014. 95. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>95</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20328</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>