<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Histological Assessment of Sexual Maturity of the Flemish Cap Cod in 1995</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Junquera, S. (Susana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Saborido-Rey, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Northwest Atlantic Fisheries Organization (NAFO)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-07T13:03:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-07T13:03:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1996</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>age-at-maturity</dc:subject><dc:subject>cod</dc:subject><dc:subject>cortical alveoli</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flemish Cap</dc:subject><dc:subject>length-at-maturity</dc:subject><dc:subject>postovulatory follicles</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper the proportion of females with postovulatory follicles in their ovaries in July&#13;
1995 is used to determine the length- and age-at-maturity of cod (Gadus morhua) in the&#13;
year 1995. The proportion of females in the cortical alveoli stage is then used to estimate&#13;
the same parameters for 1996. This histological method allows to accurately detect the&#13;
proportion of both adult and primiparous females in the population at the very beginning of&#13;
the gonad development, as it happens in the summer, and few months after spawning, when&#13;
it is very difficult to make a visual diagnosis of the sexual maturity stage. Length and age at&#13;
50% maturity obtained from the curves plotting the proportion of cortical alveoli were 39.07&#13;
cm and 3.1 years, respectively. The same parameters obtained from postovulatory follicle&#13;
frequencies were 42.65 cm and 3.9 years, respectively. During the period from 1990 to&#13;
1995, a decrease in both length- and age-at-maturity was observed for cod on Flemish&#13;
Cap. It seems likely that in those recent years the age-at-maturity of female cod was fixed&#13;
around age 3. The possibility that these features could be a density-dependent response is&#13;
discussed.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Junquera, S. and F. Saborido. 1996. Histological Assessment of Sexual Maturity of the Flemish Cap Cod in 1995. NAFO Sci. Coun. Studies, 27: 63-67</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>