<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Diferencias en el crecimiento de las sagittae de Prionotus nudigula Ginsburg, 1950 (Pisces: Triglidae) en relación al sexo</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Volpedo, A. V.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Thompson, G. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Prionotus nudigula</dc:subject><dc:subject>Triglidae</dc:subject><dc:subject>otolitos</dc:subject><dc:subject>morfometría</dc:subject><dc:subject>morfología</dc:subject><dc:description>The objetive of the present paper is to study the morphology of the sagittaand calculate the morphometric parameters of the otolith in relationship to growth in length and weight of the fish. These parameters are necessary in age and growth studies of Prionotus nudigula Ginsburg 1950.For each one of the 354 Prionotus nudigula specimens sex, total weight (P) and height (LT) were recorded, as well as maximum length (LO) and maximum width (AO) of the sagittae. The following relationships were analysed: P vs LT, LO vs LT, AO vs LT, LO vs P and AO vs LO for female and males, as well as without discriminution between sexes. For the study of these relationships, the regression model with potential adjustment roas used.The right and left sagittae of the same individual did not present meaningful differences; therefore, they are morphometrically and morphologically equal. The otoliths of males and female did not present differences in the topography of the internal and external side.y, though is was observed that the sagittae of females are longer than those of males.The analysis of relationships P vs LT and LO vs LT and P show that at the same length, females are heavier than males. The relationships LO vs LT and P and AO vs LO indicated a differential growth between sexes.</dc:description><dc:description>El objetivo de este trabajo es el estudio de la morfología de la sagitta y el cálculo de los parámetros morfométricos del otolito en relación al crecimiento en longitud y peso del pez. Dichos parámetros son necesarios en estudios de edad y crecimiento de Prionotus nudigula Ginsburg 1950.De cada uno de los de 354 ejemplares de Prionotus nudigula estudiados se registraron sexo, peso total (P) y talla (LT), midiéndose asimismo la longitud máxima (LO) y la anchura máxima (AO) de las sagittae. Se analizaron las relaciones entre: P y LT, LO y LT, AO y LT, LO y P, AO y P, AO y LO tanto para hembras y machos como sin discriminación entre sexos. Para el estudio de dichas relaciones se empleó el modelo de regresión con ajuste potencial.Las sagittae derecha e izquierda de un mismo individuo no presentaron diferencias significativas, por tanto son morfométrica y morfológicamente igual. Los otolitos de machos y hembras no presentaron diferencias en la topografía de las caras interna y externa, aunque se observó que las sagittae de las hembras son más largas que las de los machos.El análisis de las relaciones entre P y LT y de LO con LT y P muestran, para una misma talla, que las hembras son más pesadas que los machos. Las relaciones entre LO y LT y de P y AO con LO permitieron observar un crecimiento diferencial entre sexos.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1996. 12 (1)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>