<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Seasonal variability of oceanographic conditions off NW Galician waters influencing the early life trophic ecology of European hake Merluccius merluccius by stable isotope analysis</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Uriarte-Ramalho, A. (Amaya)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Laiz-Carrión, R. (Raúl)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cabrero-Rodríguez, Á.H. (Águeda Henar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Quintanilla-Hervás, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-de-Rojas, A. (Alma)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-García, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:15:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T12:15:13Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Trophic ecology, oceanography, hake, stable isotopes, M. merluccius</dc:subject><dc:description>Stable isotopes of nitrogen (δ15N) and carbón (δ13C) have been used as tracers for analyzing&#13;
the trophic ecology of European hake larvae collected during the winter and summer of 2012 off&#13;
NW Galicia. The sampling times correspond to periods of high and low hake spawning activity,&#13;
respectively. Trophic enrichment was analyzed using as baseline two different plankton size&#13;
fractions, corresponding to micro- (55-200μm) and mesozooplankton (&gt;200μm). During both&#13;
seasons, the δ15N signatures of hake larvae showed higher values than the zooplankton&#13;
fractions. The first survey carried out in late February was characterized by a preceding marked&#13;
upwelling, low geostrophic velocities in the hydrographic circulation and an intense mixing of the&#13;
water column. This environmental scenario is hypothesizing that originated a great nutrient&#13;
availability for primary consumers showed its effect in the low δ15N values observed in plankton&#13;
and hake larvae. During July, the environmental setting corresponded to period where the water&#13;
column was stratified, an anticyclonic gyre was formed in the center of the study area that&#13;
concentrated particles and weak upwelling conditions and strong geostrophic currents where&#13;
found. This scenario was characterized hypothetically by low nutrient availability in which&#13;
production is mainly based on regenerated nutrients which would explain the higher δ15N values&#13;
found during this period. On the other hand, the greater δ13C values observed in summer in&#13;
comparison to winter suggest differences in the energetic sources of carbon (Fig. 1). The&#13;
discussion of results is centered in how oceanographic variability conditions signatures of stable&#13;
isotope fractionation in the early life trophic food web influencing the variable trophic pathways&#13;
of larval hake subject to contrasting environmental conditions, thereby affecting their larval&#13;
nutritional condition as estimated by RNA/DNA ratios and the Fulton index. This study was&#13;
financed by the projects: CRAMER-CTM2010-21856-CO3 y ECOPREGA-10MMA602021PR</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina.. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón (España)). 2014. pg 102. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>pg 102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20337</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>