<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Estimating albacore movement rates between the North Atlantic and the Mediterraneal from conventional tagging data</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Arrizabalaga, H. (Haritz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>López-Rodas, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Costas, E. (Eduardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T11:50:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T11:50:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003</dcterms:issued><dc:description>A tag attrition model is fit to albacore tag-recapture data in order to estimate albacore movement &#13;
rates between the Atlantic and the Mediterranean. The estimated transfer rate from the Atlantic to &#13;
the Mediterranean is not significantly different from zero, and the estimated annual transfer rate &#13;
in the opposite direction, under the assumptions of the same catchability and reporting rates is &#13;
5,49%. Sensitivity tests to assumed reporting rates and relative catchabilities are performed, and &#13;
observed lower recovery rates in the Mediterranean may suggest either a lower catchability or &#13;
reporting rate in this area, that would give an even lower estimate of the transfer rate, which is &#13;
also supported by information from later tag recaptures of fish tagged in the Mediterranean. The &#13;
small impact of these transfer rates on stock assessment is discussed and a preliminary assessment &#13;
of the amount of tagged fish needed in order to get accurate and precise estimates of these low &#13;
transfer rates is also done by simulating different tagging scenarios.</dc:description><dc:description>Un modèle de déperdition des marques est ajusté aux données de marquage-recapture du germon afin d’estimer les taux de déplacement du germon entre l’Atlantique et la Méditerranée.&#13;
Le taux de transfert estimé de l’Atlantique à la Méditerranée n’est pas sensiblement différent de&#13;
zéro, et le taux de transfert annuel estimé dans la direction opposée, en prenant comme postulat&#13;
une capturabilité et des taux de soumission de données identiques, s’élève à 5,49%. On a réalisé des tests de sensibilité aux taux de soumission de données supposés et à la capturabilité&#13;
relative. Les taux de récupération inférieurs observés en Méditerranée suggèrent&#13;
éventuellement une capturabilité ou un taux de soumission de données plus faible dans cette&#13;
zone, ce qui donnerait une estimation encore plus faible du taux de transfert. Cela est&#13;
également appuyé par des informations provenant de récupérations tardives de marques de&#13;
poissons marqués en Méditerranée. Le faible impact de ces taux de transfert sur l’évaluation du&#13;
stock est discuté et une évaluation préliminaire du volume de poissons marqués nécessaire pour&#13;
obtenir des estimations exactes et précises de ces faibles taux de transfert est également&#13;
réalisée en simulant différents scénarios de marquage.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ajusta un modelo de tasa de pérdida de marcas a los datos de marcado-recuperación de&#13;
atún blanco con el fin de estimar las tasas de movimiento del atún blanco entre el Atlántico y el&#13;
Mediterráneo. La tasa de transferencia estimada del Atlántico al Mediterráneo no se diferencia&#13;
significativamente de cero, y la tasa de transferencia anual estimada en la dirección opuesta,&#13;
bajo el supuesto de la misma tasa de capturabilidad y comunicación, es de 5,49%. Se&#13;
realizaron pruebas de sensibilidad de las tasas de comunicación y capturabilidades relativas supuestas, y las tasas de recuperación inferiores observadas en el Mediterráneo pueden sugerir&#13;
una tasa de capturabilidad o de comunicación más baja en esta zona, lo que proporcionaría&#13;
una estimación aún más baja de transferencia, que se ve sustentada por la información de&#13;
recuperaciones de marcas posteriores de peces marcados en el Mediterráneo. Se discute el&#13;
bajo impacto de estas tasas de transferencia en la evaluación del stock y también se realiza una&#13;
evaluación preliminar de la cantidad de peces marcados necesarios para obtener estimaciones&#13;
precisas y exactas de estas bajas tasas de trasferencia mediante una simulación de diferentes&#13;
escenarios de marcado.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1659</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Arrizabalaga, H., V. López Rodas, E. Costas, A. González-Garcés. 2003. Estimating albacore movement rates between the North Atlantic and the Mediterraneal from conventional tagging data. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 55(1): 280-291.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>