<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Características morfométricas y estructuras internas de barras intermareales en el litoral noroccidental de Cádiz</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Anfuso, G.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Andrés, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vindel, B.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez, J. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Barras intermareales</dc:subject><dc:subject>playa reflectiva</dc:subject><dc:subject>playa disipativa</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper deals with morphometric bar characteristics, to discriminate between bars that are associated with dissipative beaches and reflective ones. We shall focus on the former: their internal structures and migration rate. The beaches studied are located between the cities of Chipiona and Rota (southwest Iberian Peninsula). Dissipative beaches have a gentle slope (2 %) and are 120 m wide; moderately reflective beaches have a 5 % slope and are 90 m wide. We found that bars associated with reflective beaches are larger than those associated with dissipative beaches. On the reflective beaches, bars are convex upwards, with a seaward slope of 9° and a landward slope of 5°. On the dissipative beaches, bars have a wide, smooth crest, a seaward slope of 2°-3°, and a landward slope of 1°-2°. They are generally composed of thin sets of plane bedding laminae, parallel to the beach surface.</dc:description><dc:description>Este trabajo pretende una descripción morfométrica de las barras intermareales para distinguir entre las asociadas a perfiles disipativos y las asociadas a perfiles reflectivos, profundizando más en las primeras en cuanto a estructuras internas y migración. El litoral estudiado se sitúa entre las ciudades de Chipiona y Rota (suroeste de la península Ibérica). Las playas disipativas presentan pendiente muy suave (2 %) y anchura de aproximadamente 120 m; las reflectivas tienen pendiente media del 5 % y anchura en torno a 90 m. Se ha encontrado que las barras asociadas a perfiles reflectivos son de mayores dimensiones que las asociadas a perfiles disipativos. Aquéllas son convexas y tienen una elevada pendiente en su lado hacia el mar (9°) y una pendiente menor en el lado hacia tierra. Las últimas presentan una amplia y aplanada cresta, el lado hacia el mar tiene una pendiente de 2°-3° y el lado hacia tierra de 1°-2°. Sus estructuras internas están constituidas por láminas paralelas a la superficie.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1501</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>