<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Isópodos marinos (Crustacea: Isopoda) de las islas Chafarinas (Mediterráneo occidental)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Castellanos, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Hernández-Vega, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Junoy, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:38Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:38Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Mar de Alborán</dc:subject><dc:subject>taxonomía</dc:subject><dc:description>We present an extensive study on the isopod fauna of the Chafarinas Islands (west Mediterranean). A total of 2 556 specimens, comprising 13 genera and 24 species, was collected from 56 samples during 1991, 1992 and 1993. Five species are the first record for Spain: Gnathia illepida (Wagner, 1869); G. inopinata Monod, 1925; Carpias stebbingi Monod, 1933; Joeropsis dollfusi Norman, 1899; and Synisoma mediterranea Rezig, 1989. One species was recorded for the first time for the Spanish Mediterranean coast: Gnathia venusta Monod, 1925. C. stebbingi was the most abundant and frequent species, collected in high numbers on a wide variety of substrata, at depths of 0-25 m. The percentages of species collected, by suborders, were: Asellota, 45.4 %; Flabellifera, 23.8 %; Anthuridea, 18.9 %; Gnathiidea, 9.7 %; and Valvifera, 1.9%.</dc:description><dc:description>Se exponen los resultados del estudio de la fauna de isópodos recogidos en las islas Chafarinas (Mediterráneo occidental) durante los años 1991, 1992 y 1993. Los 2 556 ejemplares de isópodos incluidos en 56 muestras pertenecen a 13 géneros y 24 especies, cinco de las cuales constituyen primeras citas para España: Gnathia illepida (Wagner, 1869); G. inopinata Monod, 1925; Carpias stebbingi Monod, 1933; Joeropsis dollfusi Norman, 1899 y Synisoma mediterranea Rezig, 1989. Se cita por primera vez Gnathia venusta Monod, 1925 para el Mediterráneo español. La especie más abundante y frecuente fue Carpias stebbingi, distribuyéndose por todas las islas y sobre todo tipo de sustratos, desde 0 a 25 metros de profundidad. La dominancia media por subórdenes en las islas fue: Asellota, 45,4 %; Flabellifera, 23,8 %; Anthuridea, 18,9 %; Gnathiidea, 9,7 % y Valvifera, 1,9 %.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1468</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>