<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Out of the Celtic cradle: The genetic signature of European hake connectivity in South-western Europe</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Pita, A. (Alfonso)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balado, M. (Miguel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Presa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T11:57:08Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-22T11:57:08Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>European hake</dc:subject><dc:subject>Connectivity pattern</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fish grounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic markers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Merluccius merluccius</dc:subject><dc:subject>Migration rate</dc:subject><dc:description>Population genetic data of marine genetic resources add up to establish their pattern of connectivity. Such pattern determines the choice of a suitable management strategy to those resources in space and time. This study addresses the pattern of connectivity among European hake grounds upon the largest sampling effort so far developed in this species. Bayesian inference made on multilocus genotypic data provides evidence that a large genetic connectivity exists among Atlantic grounds and is mediated by significant migration rates stepping up from the Celtic Sea towards its adjacent Atlantic grounds. Therefore, the spawning biomass of the northern hake population could play a crucial role at ensuring the sustainability of southern hake fish grounds. The deepest restriction to gene flow was observed at the easternmost side of the Alboran Sea what suggests that the Almeria–Oran Oceanographic Front is an effective barrier keeping apart the two major gene pools so far shown in this species. A molecular clock calibrated for cytochrome b sequences of fishes and applied to the divergence between hake pools (0.3%) suggests that the Atlantic–Mediterranean population split might date back to the Middle Pleistocene (150,000 years BP). Complementarily, Bayesian treatments of multilocus genotypes indicate that such barrier to gene flow remains active nowadays. This study shows the upmost interest of future integrative efforts to incorporate population genetic data into current assessment practices, in order to better manage European hake populations and make its exploitation sustainable.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Sea Research, 93. 2014: 90-100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.106/j.seares.2013.11.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20026</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>