<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Impacto ambiental de jaulas flotantes: estado actual de conocimientos y conclusiones prácticas</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Molina Domínguez, L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Vergara Martín, J. M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Impacto ambiental</dc:subject><dc:subject>jaulas</dc:subject><dc:subject>evaluación</dc:subject><dc:description>All human activities produce some impact on the surrounding environment, and aquaculture is no exception. As the aquaculture sector has developed, environmental aspects have became motives for increasing concern, as reflected in the large number of published studies now available. The effects of aquacultural activity, and the sources of its wastes, have been described in many papers. The present paper draws practical conclusions for the Mediterranean aquaculture sector from a review of the most recent and relevant published works on the environmental impact of farms using marine cages.</dc:description><dc:description>Todas las actividades humanas ejercen una influencia sobre el medio en que se desenvuelven, y la acuicultura no es una excepción. En el desarrollo de la acuicultura, los aspectos medioambientales acaparan una atención especial, reflejada en la abundante bibliografía existente. Sus efectos y las fuentes que los originan han sido descritos en múltiples trabajos. Se revisan aquí los más recientes y relevantes estudios referidos a los efectos medioambientales de las jaulas marinas, extrayéndose conclusiones prácticas para el sector.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>