<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Engorde de pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797 en jaula flotante en la costa mediterránea de Levante</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Oltra, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alemany, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fuertes-Roig, M.C. (María del Carmen)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mezquita, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:27Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Supervivencia</dc:subject><dc:subject>crecimiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>sexo</dc:subject><dc:subject>dieta natural</dc:subject><dc:subject>primavera</dc:subject><dc:subject>otoño</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediterráneo</dc:subject><dc:description>In order to test the growth of the octopus Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797 in Mediterranean coastal waters, two ongrowing experiments were carried out in floating cages, located inside the area of Denia harbour (Alicante, Spain). During the first experiment (October 2004-January 2005), carried out over 94 days, males and females were kept separately. Females had higher survival rates (52.2 %) than males (30.3 %); average final weight was not significantly different in males and females, and average weight increase was 652 g/month. During the second culture experiment (March-June 2005), which lasted for 86 days, two diets with different crustacean content were used. Survival and growth were not improved by an increase of crustacean content in the diet. Increase in survival and average weight over the course of the entire cycle were 53.6 % and 975 g/month, respectively.</dc:description><dc:description>Se han efectuado dos engordes de juveniles de pulpo Octopus vulgaris Cuvier, 1797 en jaula flotante en el puerto de Denia (Alicante) con el objetivo de comprobar su rendimiento en aguas de la costa de Levante. En el primer engorde -de octubre de 2004 a enero de 2005 (94 días)- se han mantenido separados machos y hembras. La supervivencia ha sido mayor en hembras (52,2 %) que en machos (30,3 %), el peso medio final no ha diferido significativamente y el incremento medio de peso ha sido de 652 g/mes. En el segundo engorde -de marzo a junio de 2005 (86 días)- se han proporcionado dos dietas con diferente contenido en crustáceos a sendos grupos de subadultos. El aumento de crustáceos en la dieta no ha implicado mayor supervivencia y crecimiento. La supervivencia global en el engorde ha sido del 53,6 % y el incremento medio de peso 975 g/mes.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1370</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2005. 21 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>