<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Estructura de la macrofauna y propiedades sedimentarias en una playa arenosa mesotidal de baja energía de la ría de Aveiro (noroeste de Portugal)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Cunha, M. R.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ravara, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:39Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Playa</dc:subject><dc:subject>zonación</dc:subject><dc:subject>macroinvertebrados</dc:subject><dc:subject>estuarios</dc:subject><dc:subject>Portugal</dc:subject><dc:description>We present the results of a study on faunal zonation and sediment properties on a low-energy, mesotidal sandy beach located on Ria de Aveiro (northwestern Portugal). The topography of the sampling area was mapped and five strata were defined in situ according to their macroscopic characteristics. A stratified random design was used to sample the fauna and environmental parameters. Anova (for environmental parameters) and multivariate analysis (for faunal data) showed that significant differences occurred across the shoreline. The beach is of an intermediate morphodynamic type, with a reflective, more physically controlled upper shore, and a dissipative, more chemically controlled lower shore. Although our multivariate analysis of the fauna fits in with the classical tripartite zonation of sandy beaches, the variation we found in faunal distribution makes it possible to further subdivide the two lower areas, resulting in a total of five valid faunal zones, matching the strata defined a priori.</dc:description><dc:description>Se han investigado la zonación faunística y las propiedades del sedimento en una playa arenosa, mesotidal y de baja energía, situada en la ría de Aveiro (noroeste de Portugal). Se determinó la topografía de la playa y se definieron cinco estratos en relación a sus características macroscópicas. La significatividad de las diferencias entre las subáreas fue evaluada utilizando un muestreo estratificado aleatorio, que abarcaba las características faunísticas y ambientales, y aplicando a los datos obtenidos los análisis anova y multivariante. La playa estudiada es de tipo morfodinámica intermedia, más reflectiva en la zona alta, donde se efectuó un control preferentemente de tipo físico, y más disipativa en la zona baja, más controlada químicamente. El análisis multivariante de la fauna concuerda con la clásica zonación tripartita de las playas arenosas. No obstante, la variación en la distribución de la fauna permite hacer otra subdivisión de las dos áreas más bajas, resultando, en total, cinco zonas faunísticas válidas, coincidientes con los estratos de muestreo definidos a priori.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1473</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2003. 19 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>