<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Partitioning of physical and biogeochemical contributions to short-term variability of pCO2 in a coastal upwelling system: a quantitative approach</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Salgado, X.A. (Xosé Antón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Pérez, F. (Fiz)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fernández-Ríos, A. (Aida)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:56:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-27T13:56:45Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003-06-24</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>pCO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carbon cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inversebox-methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coastal upwelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galician rías</dc:subject><dc:subject>NW Spain</dc:subject><dc:description>A considerable body of literature has addressed the role that coastal upwelling systems&#13;
may play in global processes, especially in the ocean carbon cycle. It is often difficult to separate the&#13;
effects of physical and biogeochemical processes on the partial pressure of carbon dioxide (pCO2) in&#13;
coastal upwelling systems due to the tight coupling between these processes. In this work we propose&#13;
a novel approach to quantify physical (advection and diffusion of inorganic carbon species, in situ&#13;
warming) and biogeochemical (production and consumption of inorganic carbon species) effects on&#13;
surface pCO2 using an inverse method. It is applied to the Ría de Vigo, a large coastal indentation in&#13;
the NW Iberian shelf. Physical and biogeochemical processes affecting surface pCO2 variability are&#13;
quantified during spring, summer, autumn and winter. Our results show the dominance of vertical&#13;
advection, turbulent diffusion and net ecosystem production of organic carbon (ΔCorg) components&#13;
over other processes (calcification and surface warming) on a short timescale (2 to 4 d). The study&#13;
reveals that physical transport of inorganic carbon species explains -50% of the observed pCO2 variability&#13;
and ΔCorg accounts for most of the remaining 50%.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1662</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Gago, J., X.A. Álvarez-Salgado, F.F. Pérez, A.F. Rïos. 2003. Partitioning of physical and biogeochemical contributions to short-term variability of pCO2 in a coastal upwelling system: a quantitative approach. Mar. Ecol. Progr. Ser. 255: 43-54</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>