<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Perfil de ecdisteroides en el ovario del camarón Palaemon serratus Pennant, 1777 a lo largo del ciclo reproductor</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Azevedo, B.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cortez, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abreu, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Carvalho, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:07Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Palaemon serratus</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecdisteroides</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecdisona</dc:subject><dc:subject>20-OH-ecdisona</dc:subject><dc:subject>ovogénesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>vitelogénesis</dc:subject><dc:description>The ecdysteroids ecdysone and 20-OH-ecdysone are steroid hormones found in arthropods, such as crustaceans, which control their moult. This characteristic form of growth, as well as the particularities of its reproduction (e.g., fecundation, spawning), involve simultaneous regulation of these two basic biological functions. These functions are hormonally regulated in a way similar to that of insects, for which the relationship between moulting hormones and reproduction hormones is already well known.  With the aim of studying the profiles of the ecdysteroids ecdysone and 20-OH-ecdysone during the reproductive cycle in the shrimp Palaemon serratus Pennant, 1777, they were extracted from the ovaries and purified. Subsequently, the hormones were quantified with an enzymoimmunoassay (EIA). Results confirm the extraction method's precision and accuracy; a variation in the overall level of ecdysteroids during the oogenesis was also found, suggesting a relationship between these moult hormones and the vitellogenesis.</dc:description><dc:description>Los ecdisteroides ecdisona (α-ecdisona) y 20-OH-ecdisona (β-ecdisona) son hormonas esteroides existentes en los artrópodos, específicamente en crustáceos, que regulan la muda de estos animales. Las características de crecimiento de este grupo, así como las particularidades de su reproducción (fecundación, puesta, etc.), implican una regulación simultánea de estas dos funciones biológicas fundamentales. Estas funciones están reguladas hormonalmente de manera similar a la encontrada en los insectos, en los que es bien conocida la relación entre las hormonas de la muda y la reproducción.  Con el objetivo de estudiar el perfil de los ecdisteroides ecdisona y 20-OH-ecdisona en el ovario del camarón Palaemon serratus Pennant, 1777 a lo largo del ciclo reproductor, se extrajeron dichos ecdisteroides de los ovarios y se purificaron por extracción en fase sólida (SPE). Posteriormente se cuantificaron las hormonas por enzima-inmunoensayo (EIA).  Los resultados obtenidos demuestran una buena precisión y exactitud del método, y la existencia de una variación del nivel de ecdisteroides totales a lo largo del ciclo reproductor, sugiriendo la relación de la hormona de la muda con la vitelogénesis.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1207</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>