<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Development and evaluation of a novel EST-diverted microsatellite set for the genetic management of populations and stocks of the European hake Merluccius merluccius</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Santafé-Muñoz, A. (Angie)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pita, A. (Alfonso)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Presa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T10:17:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T10:17:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-07</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-03</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Comunicación oral</dc:description><dc:description>The European hake (Merluccius merluccius) has a high commercial and organoleptic value in Europe that has fueled the overexploitation of its fisheries during the last three decades. Therefore, initial taming attempts have been carried out recently to found hatchery stocks of this species on a long term perspective. The effective management of hatchery stocks and very specially its foundation, require a proper knowledge on the genetic background of source populations as well as the broodstock reproductive structure. The genetic background of the Atlantic hake population acting as source of the hatchery stock is well known at the population level. However, little is known on the reproductive system of this species as well as on the genetic load of the unique world hatchery stock of the European hake cultured in Galicia. In this study we have screened 476,747 sequences from a transcriptome library of the European hake, identified 17,655 containing simple repeated regions, selected 3,495 non-redundant contigs, and selected microsatellite PCR primers for 1,483 sequences. One-hundred and ninety microsatellite-containing sequences passed the most stringent criteria for primer performance. Forty-eight sequences passed the cross-sequence primers matching test as well as the optimal in silico PCR multiplex amplification. Cold PCR amplification analyses on ten hakes allowed to excluding additional potential markers upon their lack of apparent polymorphism or their weak amplification. Finally 23 markers (2 tetranucleotides, 8 trinucleotides, 6 dinucleotides) ranging 82-237bp, were combined with five previously used markers and clustered in seven tetraplexes for quick genotyping analyses. Present results indicate that the molecular tool designed herein is analytically and statistically powerful and permits the quick genotyping of large pools. We provide evidence of the broodstock reproductive structure and the genetic load of the whole domestic stock as compared to the wild source population. Since the markers characterized map within expressed genes, marker assisted selection of candidate genes is underway.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2341</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquaculture 2013. (03/11/2013 - 07/11/2013. Las Palmas (España)). 2014. 07.2. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>07.2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20151</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>