<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Probiotic supplementation influences the diversity of the intestinal microbiota during early stages of farmed Senegalese sole (Solea senegalensis, Kaup, 1858)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Tapia-Paniagua, S.T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Lobo, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moreno-Ventas, X.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-de-la-Banda, I. (Inés)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moriñigo, M.A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balebona, M.C.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Santander</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:53:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-02T10:53:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Solea senegalensis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Probiotics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Larviculture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intestinal microbiota</dc:subject><dc:description>Ingestion of bacteria at early stages results in establishment of a primary intestinal microbiota which likely undergoes several stages along fish life. The role of this intestinal microbiota regulating body functions is crucial for larval development. Probiotics have been proved to modulate this microbiota and exert antagonistic effects against fish pathogens. In the present study, we aimed to determine bacterial diversity along different developmental stages of farmed Senegalese sole (Solea senegalensis) after feeding probiotic (Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11) supplemented diet for a short period (10–30 days after hatching, DAH). Intestinal lumen contents of sole larvae fed control and probiotic diets were collected at 23, 56, 87, and 119 DAH and DNA was amplified using 16S rDNA bacterial domain-specific primers. Amplicons obtained were separated by denaturing gradient gel electrophoresis (DGGE), cloned, and resulting sequences compared to sequences in GenBank. Results suggest that Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11 induces a modulation of the dominant bacterial taxa of the intestinal microbiota from 23 DAH. DGGE patterns of larvae fed the probiotic diet showed a core of bands related to Lactobacillus helveticus, Pseudomonas acephalitica, Vibrio parahaemolyticus,and Shewanella genus, together with increased Vibri o genus presence. In addition, decreased number of clones related to Photobacterium damselae subsp piscicida at 23 and 56 DAH was observed in probiotic-fed larvae. A band corresponding to Shewanella putrefaciens Pdp11 was sequenced as predominant from 23 to 119 DAH samples, confirming the colonization by the probiotics. Microbiota modulation obtained via probiotics addition emerges as an effective tool to improve Solea senegalensis larviculture.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2632</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Marine Biotechnology, -. 2014: ---</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1007/s10126-014-9588-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20384</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>closedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>