<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Contenido y distribución de glucógeno en relación con el ciclo gametogénico de Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758) en una población natural de las lagunas de Baldaio (Galicia, noroeste de España)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Ojea, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Martínez, D.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Novoa, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pazos, A. J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Abad, M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2002-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Almeja fina</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ruditapes decussatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>acondicionamiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproducción</dc:subject><dc:subject>reservas energéticas</dc:subject><dc:description>Bivalve reproduction is associated with complex cycles of energy reserve storage. We studied the gametogenic cycle of the clam Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758), as well as variations in its glycogen composition, using individuals from a natural population located in the Baldaio lagoons (Galicia, northwestern Spain). The gametogenic cycle, as well as variations in glycogen composition, were studied throughout the life cycle of the clam Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758), using individuals from a natural population located in the Baldaio lagoons (Galicia, northwestern Spain). The gametogenesis begins in December and January, after a period of sexual inactivity during the months of November and December. This population reaches sexual maturity during a period extending from mid-May until August, and spawning takes place from June to August, followed by a post-spawning period. To study of glycogen content and its distribution, the clams were dissected out into different parts: foot, ledge of the mantle, gills, adductor muscle and gonad-digestive gland. The lowest content of glycogen was found at maturity, especially during spawning. The gonad and the visceral mass accumulate between 36 and a 50% of the total glycogen present in the animal, whereas the lowest values are in the foot, which contains 6%.</dc:description><dc:description>La reproducción en bivalvos está asociada a ciclos complejos de almacenamiento de reservas energéticas. Se ha estudiado la gametogénesis de la almeja fina Ruditapes decussatus (L., 1758), y la variación en ella de la composición de glucógeno, con ejemplares de una población natural de las lagunas de Baldaio (A Coruña). La gametogénesis se inicia entre diciembre y enero, después de un periodo de reposo sexual durante noviembre y diciembre, y la madurez sexual se alcanza desde mediados de mayo hasta agosto; la puesta tiene lugar de junio a agosto y va seguida de un periodo de pospuesta. Para el estudio del contenido en glucógeno y su distribución, se diseccionaron las siguientes partes de las almejas: el pie, el reborde muscular del manto, las branquias, los sifones, el músculo aductor y la gónada con la masa visceral, que incluye el aparato digestivo, los palpos labiales, los ganglios nerviosos y la región reno-pericárdica.  El contenido en glucógeno más bajo se obtiene en la madurez y, sobre todo, en época de puesta. La gónada y la masa visceral acumulan entre el 36 y el 50% del glucógeno total existente en el animal, mientras que los valores más bajos se encuentran en el pie, con el 6%.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2002. 18 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>