<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Combining genetic markers with classic domestication strategies for the wreckfish (Polyprion americanus): A candidate species with high aquaculture potential</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Matusse, N. (Nédia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pérez, M. (Montse)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Pita, A. (Alfonso)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Peleteiro-Alonso, J.B. (José Benito)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Trucco, M.I. (María Inés)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Presa, P. (Pablo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T12:37:08Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22T12:37:08Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-22</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-07</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-11-03</dcterms:issued><dc:description>The wreckfish Polyprion americanus is a long-living pelagic fish with a demersal adult phase that shows an antitropical distribution. In the eastern Atlantic, juvenile and adult wreckfish are found off the Norwegian coast along shallow portions of the Mid-Atlantic ridge and associated islands (Macaronesian Islands), and along northern and southern Africa including the Mediterranean.&#13;
&#13;
This species is a component of directed and admixed species fisheries throughout its range and has recently been focused for its large aquaculture potential: adults reach 100cm in length, show low natural mortality rates and a large longevity. Therefore it is one of the most promising species for aquaculture and consequently it has recently been brought to Galician hatcheries for taming.&#13;
&#13;
These good priors for aquaculture are however devoid of useful information on its whole life cycle, taxonomic classification and genetic status. It is well known that domestication and management of hatchery stocks require an adequate strategy for the initial broodstock foundation and its further reproductive management. Therefore the combination of genetic markers with classic domestication strategies seems to be a useful approach to skip consanguineous adverse effects and genetic drift.&#13;
&#13;
In this study we have first isolated new microsatellite markers for ecumenical tasks in this species. Then we have applied those markers to assess the genetic status of the four wreckfish stocks being harvested in n Galicia hatcheries as compared to the genetic diversity present in its source population from the Eastern Atlantic. Since the first successful spawning of wreckfish in captivity has recently been achieved in a Galicia hatchery, we provide here the first assessment on the reproductive structure of such stock, based on the genetic assignment of its progenies. Preliminary results show a significant genetic differentiation (2.25% of the whole inter-stock genetic variance) among broodstocks from the four Galician hatcheries and a pronounced loss of diversity in two of them regarding the genetic richness of the wild source population.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2364</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquaculture 2013. (03/11/2013 - 07/11/2013. Las Palmas (España)). . AQUA2013-1363. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>AQUA2013-1363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20167</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>restrictedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>