<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">El esfuerzo del viento, su rotacional y el transporte de Sverdrup en el Atlántico sur</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>da S. Mascarenhas, Jr, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Tiemi Sato, O.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gil Silva, E.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Larios Castillo, S.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:31Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Transporte de masa de Sverdrup</dc:subject><dc:subject>océano Atlántico sur</dc:subject><dc:subject>esfuerzo del viento</dc:subject><dc:description>Monthly mean values of Hellerman and Rosenstein (HR) wind stress and eight oceanographic transects of the South Atlantic Ocean obtained at different latitudes were used to test the Sverdrup relationship. Seasonal mean wind-stress charts for each season are presented. The zonal migration and splitting of the South Atlantic atmospheric high-pressure centre can be observed, as well as other seasonal changes of the wind field. Charts of the mean wind stress curl show a line of zero curl sloping northeastward across the South Atlantic basin, with negative values north of this line and positive values south of it. The annual mean chart of the Sverdrup mass transport show the same feature, with northward transport below this line and southward transport above it. Zonal values of Sverdrup (S), Geostrophic (G), and Ekman (E) transports, as well as the total transport (R = G + E), were calculated. There is no established relationship between the Sverdrup and total transport with latitude. Within the calculated interval of error (± 1.2 Sv for G and ± 2.3 Sv for S), a good qualitative agreement between R and S was attained at 9°, 11°, 16° and 24° S. The Brazil Current geostrophic transports, at different latitudes, are close to the Sverdrup transport values at the western boundary. However, the poleward increase of the Brazil Current transport with latitude is not presented by the Sverdrup transport.</dc:description><dc:description>Se utilizaron valores promedios mensuales del esfuerzo del viento de Hellerman y Rosenstein (HR) y ocho secciones oceanográficas distribuidas en el Atlántico sur, a diferentes latitudes, para verificar la relación de Sverdrup. Se muestran mapas medios estacionales del esfuerzo del viento y se observa la migración zonal y la partición del centro atmosférico de alta presión del Atlántico sur, así como otros cambios estacionales del campo del viento. El mapa del rotacional del esfuerzo medio del viento muestra una línea con valor cero extendiéndose desde la costa oeste de áfrica hasta la costa nordeste de Brasil, con valores negativos al norte de esta línea y positivos al sur de la misma. El mapa del promedio anual del transporte de Sverdrup muestra la misma característica, con transportes hacia el Norte por debajo de esa línea y hacia el Sur por encima de ella. Se calculan los valores zonales del transporte de Sverdrup (S), geostrófico (G) y de Ekman (E), así como el transporte total (R = G + E). No se observa una relación establecida entre los transportes de Sverdrup y total y la latitud. Dentro del intervalo de error calculado (± 1,2 Sv para G y ± 2,3 Sv para S), existe una buena concordancia entre R y S en las latitudes 9°, 11°, 16° y 24° S. Los valores del transporte geostrófico de la corriente de Brasil a diferentes latitudes están más cerca de los valores de transporte de Sverdrup en la frontera oeste. El incremento con la latitud del transporte geostrófico de la corriente de Brasil, hacia el Sur, no es observado en el transporte de Sverdrup.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1408</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2001. 17 (3 y 4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>