<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">The link between descriptors 8 and 9 of the Marine Strategy Framework Directive: lessons learnt in Spain</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Viñas, L. (Lucía)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Besada, V. (Victoria)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bellas-Bereijo, J.D. (Juan Domingo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-10T08:05:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-07</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Marine Strategy Framework Directive</dc:subject><dc:subject>Descriptor 8</dc:subject><dc:subject>Descriptor 9</dc:subject><dc:subject>Contaminants</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of this note is to discuss the relevance of the interaction/integration of monitoring of contaminants for the protection of the marine environment and for human health safety (descriptors 8 and 9, respectively) within the Marine Strategy Framework Directive (MSFD). The identification of possible relations between contaminant levels in sediments and tissues of fish and other seafood, as well as the association of those levels to pollution sources, are major challenges for marine researchers. The Spanish initial assessment in the North-East Atlantic marine region was used as an example to show some gaps and loopholes when dealing with the relationship between descriptors 8 and 9. The main problem to deal with is that monitoring programmes intended for the assessment of marine environmental quality and for human health safety usually apply different approaches and methodologies, and even different tissues are analysed in some species (mainly fish). It is therefore recommended to make a profound revision of current sampling strategies, procedures and methodologies, including the selection of target species and tissues and to improve the traceability of samples of fish and other seafood for human consumption. On the other hand, despite the scope of descriptor 9 which is limited to commercially relevant species, this fact should not be an obstacle in the application of the ‘ecosystem approach’ within the MSFD. In order to appropriately solve these shortcomings, an information exchange system between authorities dealing with descriptors 8 and 9 should be strongly encouraged for the next steps of the MSFD’s implementation</dc:description><dc:identifier>0944-1344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2137</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Environmental Science and Pollution Research, -. 2014: ---</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1007/s11356-014-3283-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7581</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>