<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">A production model analysis of North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus Alalunga), 1957-1978</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:12:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-21T09:12:44Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1981</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Two production model adjustments of the North Atlantic albacore stock between 1957 and 1978 are &#13;
presented.  The first adjustment, case A, is based on data from Shiohama and Yang for longline and &#13;
Bard, Antaine, and González-Garcés for trolling and baitboat.  The second adjustment, case B, is &#13;
based on data from Shiohama, ICCAT and Yang for longline and Bard, Antaine, and González-Garcés for &#13;
trolling and baitboat.&#13;
The production models show that the MSY of the North Atlantic albacore stock is between 55,000 and &#13;
65,000 t., with an optimum effort that can range between 85,000 and 105,000 standard&#13;
baitboat fishing days.&#13;
&#13;
Studies involving the prevailing tendency of the CPUE of all the fisheries show that no clear &#13;
dominant trend exists, but rather that it is stable with slight fluctuations.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document présente deux ajustements du modèle de production au stock de germon de l'Atlantique &#13;
nord entre 1957 et 1978. Le premier (cas A) est basé sur les données de Shiohama et de Yang&#13;
pour la palangre, et sur celles de Bard, Antoine et Gonzalez-Garces pour ce qui est de la peche à &#13;
la ligne trainante et à l'appât vi­vant.  Le second (cas B) est basé sur les données de Shiohama,ICCAT et Yang pour ce qui est de la palangre, et de Bard, Antoine et Gonzalez-Garces pour la pêche &#13;
à la ligne traînante et à l'appât vivant.&#13;
&#13;
Les modèles de production indiquent que la PME du stock de germon de l'Atlantique nord se situe &#13;
entre 55.000 et 65.000 TM, avec un effort optimum oscillant entre 85.000 et 105.000 journées de &#13;
peche standard de canneur.&#13;
Les études portant sur la tendance de la CPUE de l'ensemble des pêcheries n'indiquent pas de &#13;
tendance claire, mais plutôt un état stable avec de légères fluctuations.</dc:description><dc:description>Se presentan dos ajustes de modelos de producción al stock de atún blanco del Atlántico Norte entre &#13;
los años 1957 y  1978. Un ajuste, (caso A), se basa en datos de Shiohama y  de Yang para el &#13;
palangre y de Bard, Antoine y González- Garcés para curricán y  cebo vivo. El otro ajuste, (caso &#13;
B), se basa en datos de Shiohama, ICCAT y Yang para el palangre, y de Bard, Antoine y González-Garcés para el curricán y  el cebo vivo.Los modelos de producción indican que el RMS del stock del atún blanco del Atlántico Norte se encuentra entre 55.000 y 65.000 toneladas, con un esfuerzo óptimo que puede oscilar entre 85.000 y 105.000 días de pesca standard de cebo vivo.Los estudios sobre la tendencia de la CPUE del conjunto de las pesquerías no indican que exista una tendencia clara, más bien parece estable con ligeras oscilaciones.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1636</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González-Garcés, A. 1981. A production model analysis of North Atlantic albacore (Thunnus Alalunga), 1957-1978. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 15 (2): 211-221</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>