<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Decapod crustacean larval communities in the Balearic Sea (western Mediterranean): Seasonal composition, horizontal and vertical distribution patterns</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Torres, A.P. (Asvin Pérez)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Dos Santos, A.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Balbín, R. (Rosa)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alemany, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Massutí, E. (Enric)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Reglero, P. (Patricia)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Baleares</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:50:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:50:25Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Larval assemblages</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decapoda</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adult habitats</dc:subject><dc:subject>Developmental stage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vertical distribution patterns</dc:subject><dc:subject>Western Mediterranean</dc:subject><dc:description>Decapod crustaceans are the main target species of deepwater bottomtrawl fisheries in the Balearic Sea but little is&#13;
known about their larval stages. This work focuses on the species composition of the decapod larval community,&#13;
describing the main spatio-temporal assemblages and assessing their vertical distribution. Mesozooplankton&#13;
sampling was carried out using depth-stratified sampling devices at two stations located over the shelf break&#13;
and themid slope, in the north-western and southern Mallorca in late autumn 2009 and summer 2010. Differences&#13;
among decapod larvae communities, in terms of composition, adult's habitat such as pelagic or benthic, and distribution&#13;
patternswere observed between seasons, areas and station. Results showed that for both seasonsmost species&#13;
and developmental stages aggregatedwithin the upperwater column (above 75 mdepth) and showed higher&#13;
biodiversity in summer compared to late autumn. Most abundant species were pelagic prawns (e.g., Sergestidae)&#13;
occurring in both seasons and areas. The larval assemblages' distributions were different between seasonal hydrographic&#13;
scenarios and during situations of stratified and non-stratified water column. The vertical distribution&#13;
patterns of different larval developmental stages in respect to the adult's habitat were analyzed in relation to&#13;
environmental variables. Fluorescence had the highest explanatory power. Four clearly different vertical patterns&#13;
were identified: two corresponding to late autumn, which were common for all the main larval groups and other&#13;
two in summer, one corresponding to larvae of coastal benthic and the second to pelagic species larvae.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0924-7963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2577</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Marine Systems, 138. 2014: 112-126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20330</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>