<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Ribosomal DNA Organization Patterns within the Dinoflagellate Genus Alexandrium as Revealed by FISH: Life Cycle and Evolutionary Implications.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Figueroa, R.I. (Rosa Isabel)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Cuadrado, Á. (Ángeles)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Stüken, A. (Anke)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Fraga, S. (Santiago)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:49:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-08-11T09:49:59Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Chromosomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>genome size</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nuclear Organizer Regions (NORs)</dc:subject><dc:subject>protists</dc:subject><dc:subject>ribosomal genes</dc:subject><dc:subject>life cycle</dc:subject><dc:description>Dinoflagellates are a group of protists whose genome differs from that of other eukaryotes in terms of&#13;
size (contains up to 250pg per haploid cell), base composition, chromosomal organization, and gene&#13;
expression. But rDNA gene mapping of the active nucleolus in this unusual eukaryotic genome has&#13;
not been carried out thus far. Here we used FISH in dinoflagellate species belonging to the genus&#13;
Alexandrium (genome sizes ranging from 21 to 170 pg of DNA per haploid genome) to localize the&#13;
sequences encoding the 18S, 5.8S, and 28S rRNA genes. The results can be summarized as follows:&#13;
1) Each dinoflagellate cell contains only one active nucleolus, with no hybridization signals outside&#13;
it. However, the rDNA organization varies among species, from repetitive clusters forming discrete&#13;
nuclear organizer regions (NORs) in some to specialized “ribosomal chromosomes” in other species.&#13;
The latter chromosomes, never reported before in other eukaryotes, are mainly formed by rDNA genes&#13;
and appeared in the species with the highest DNA content. 2) Dinoflagellate chromosomes are first&#13;
characterized by several eukaryotic features, such as structural differentiation (centromere-like constrictions),&#13;
size differences (dot chromosomes), and SAT (satellite) chromosomes. 3) NOR patterns&#13;
prove to be useful in discriminating between cryptic species and life cycle stages in protists.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1825</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Protist, 165. 2014: 343-363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.protis.2014.04.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7290</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>