<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Control geomorfológico para la sedimentación de fangos en la zona norte de la plataforma continental portuguesa</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Drago, T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Araújo, F.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valério, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Weber, O.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Jouanneau, J.M.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:14Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Fangos</dc:subject><dc:subject>plataforma continental</dc:subject><dc:subject>tasa de sedimentación</dc:subject><dc:subject>control geomorfológico</dc:subject><dc:subject>composición química</dc:subject><dc:subject>resedimentación</dc:subject><dc:description>Six cores sampled at two mud fields located on the northern Portuguese continental shelf have been studied in order to evaluate the control processes of fine sedimentation. The southern mud patch, offshore from the Douro River, is limited on the western side by some Cretaceous and Paleocene outcrops that constitute reliefs of 5-30 m in width; on the contrary, the northern mud patch, offshore from the Minho River, extends along a flat region. Granulometric distribution shows that the sediments from the Minho mud patch are coarser than those from the Douro mud patch, where the grain size diminishes towards the west. Carbonate content is also higher in the Minho mud field. The sediment organisation in fining-up sequences in the Minho mud patch and in the eastern part of the Douro mud patch indicates sediment remobilisation by storms. The Douro mud patch has higher sedimentation rates than the Minho mud patch. The highest values are probably related to the existence of reliefs, which may offer hydrodynamic protection or function as a fine sediment barrier. The elemental distribution for chemical elements was determined in different fractions of these cores. Geochemical patterns are generally quite similar for both mud fields, indicating a common continental origin for the sediments. The major differences in the chemical composition are mainly controlled by the grain-size distribution, either reflecting the presence of coarse quartz particles or a local enrichment in biogenic material.</dc:description><dc:description>En este trabajo se han estudiado seis testigos de la zona norte de la plataforma continental portuguesa con el objetivo de evaluar los procesos que controlan la sedimentación de materiales finos en esta región. Los fangos acumulados más al sur, frente a la desembocadura del río Duero, están limitados al oeste por relieves cretácicos y paleocenos de 5 a 30 m de altura. Los fangos septentrionales, frente a la desembocadura del río Miño, se extienden sobre una región plana. La distribución granulométrica muestra que estos últimos son más gruesos que los depositados frente al Duero, en los que el tamaño de grano disminuye hacia el oeste. El contenido en carbonato es más elevado en la zona del Miño. Las secuencias granodecrecientes encontradas en los fangos del Miño y en los del sector oriental del Duero indican retrabajamiento del sedimento por tormentas. La tasa de sedimentación es mayor en los fangos situados frente al Duero, donde los valores más altos están relacionados probablemente con la existencia de relieves, los cuales ofrecerían una protección hidrodinámica o actuarían como una barrera para los sedimentos. La distribución de la concentración de diversos elementos químicos a lo largo de los testigos fue determinada para diferentes fracciones. El patrón geoquímico es bastante similar en ambas zonas y pone de manifiesto una procedencia continental de los sedimentos. Las principales diferencias en la composición química están fundamentalmente controladas por la distribución granulométrica, bien por la presencia de granos gruesos de cuarzo, bien por un enriquecimiento local en material biogénico.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 1999. 15 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>