<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Growth of Octopus vulgaris (Cuvier, 1797) in tanks in the Ebro Delta (NE Spain): effects of temperature, salinity and culture density</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Delgado Fernández, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Gairín, J.I. (Joan Ignasi)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Carbó, R. (Ricard)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Aguilera, C. (Cristóbal)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Cádiz</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T13:24:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-01-28T13:24:40Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2011</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Octopus vulgaris</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>ongrowing</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>salinity</dc:subject><dc:subject>culture density</dc:subject><dc:description>To assess the possibility of O. vulgaris ongrowing using tanks or cages in the bays of the Ebro Delta, we performed&#13;
several growth trials of common octopus held in tanks. Effects of environmental factors (temperature and salinity) and zootechnical aspects (culture density) were studied. The thermal ranges that defined positive growth periods in the bays of the Ebro Delta were 19.5ºC to 23ºC (spring-summer) and 23.5ºC to 12.3ºC (autumn-winter), the latter being the most suitable period for ongrowing. Salinity did not affect survival (100%) or growth within the range tested (34-29 psu), though feeding rates (AFR, SFR) were directly related to salinity. On the other hand, after 60 days, final culture density increased three-fold (D1: 12.36 → 44.37 kg m–3; D2: 24.13 → 67.76 kg m–3), with optimal survival results (&gt;90%) for the two densities&#13;
tested. Growth and feeding rates showed a slight inverse relationship with density. Finally, growth and feeding rates showed a clear dependence on temperature in the two experiments (density and salinity). Our results conclude that industrial production of O. vulgaris in tanks is promising: this system offers an alternative to cages and allows for a more exhaustive control of culture.</dc:description><dc:description>Con el fin de evaluar la posibilidad de engorde de O. vulgaris en tanques o jaulas en las bahías del Delta del Ebro, se llevaron a cabo varias experiencias de crecimiento de individuos&#13;
mantenidos en tanques. Se estudiaron tanto aspectos medioambientales (temperatura y salinidad) como zootécnicos (densidad de cultivo). Los rangos térmicos que definieron periodos positivos de crecimiento en las bahías del Delta del Ebro fueron: 19.5ºC-23ºC (primavera-verano) y 23.5ºC-12.3ºC (otoño-invierno), siendo este último el periodo más favorable para el engorde. La salinidad no afectó a la supervivencia o al crecimiento dentro del rango testado (34-29 psu), a pesar de que las tasas de alimentación (AFR, SFR) mantuviesen relación directa con la salinidad. Por otro lado, y transcurridos 60 días, observamos que la densidad de cultivo se multiplicó por tres (D1: 12.36 → 44.37 kg m–3; D2: 24.13 → 67.76 kg m–3), con resultados óptimos de supervivencia (&gt;90%) bajo las dos condiciones probadas. Las tasas de crecimiento y alimentación mostraron una relación indirecta con la densidad de cultivo. Finalmente, se observó que tanto las tasas de crecimiento como las de alimentación presentan una clara dependencia de la temperatura en ambas experiencias (salinidad y densidad de cultivo).&#13;
Nuestros resultados concluyen que la producción industrial de O. vulgaris en tanques es prometedora: este sistema ofrece una alternativa a las cajas y permite un control más exhaustivo del cultivo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0214-8358</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>doi: 10.3989/scimar.2011.75n1053</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Scientia Marina 75(1) 2011: 53-59</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>