<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Continental inputs of C, N, P and SI species to the Ría de Vigo (NW Spain)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gago, J. (Jesús)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Álvarez-Salgado, X.A. (Xosé Antón)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nieto-Cid, M. (Mar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Brea, S. (Samanta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Piedracoba, S. (Silvia)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-28T12:31:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-28T12:31:55Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2005-07-05</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>nutrients</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>river fluxes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ría de Vigo (NW Spain)</dc:subject><dc:description>C, N, P and Si in dissolved, particulate, organic and inorganic forms, determined from 12 surveys in the river Oitabén-Verdugo&#13;
during 2002, allowed quantification of the chemical composition, phase partitioning and fluxes of continental materials to the inner&#13;
Ría de Vigo (NW Spain). Despite the large fluxes normalised to the drainage basin of the river Oitabén-Verdugo (280 mmol&#13;
Cm -2 y- 1, 56.5 mmol N m- 2 y -1, 1.35 mmol P m -2 y -1, and 61.3 mmol Si m- 2 y-1), its reduced dimensions (350 km2) yielded&#13;
relatively low concentrations of these species. Organic C, N and P represented 62%, 43% and 48% of the total C, N and P fluxes,&#13;
respectively. About 90% of the organic C and N and 60% of the organic P was in the dissolved form. The chemical composition of&#13;
the organic materials was compatible with detrital organic matter derived from aquatic plants, phytoplankton and soil leaching but&#13;
not with unprocessed terrestrial plants. Significant temporal changes were observed in the chemical composition, related to the&#13;
seasonal cycle of the biological activity in stream waters and soils, as well as the chemical weathering reactions. Spatial differences&#13;
were due to the contrasting dynamic regime and, likely, the origin of the materials.</dc:description><dc:identifier>doi: 10.1016/j.ecss.2005.05.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Gago, J., X.A. Álvarez- Salgado, M. Nieto- Cid, S. Brea, S. Piedracoba. 2005. Continental inputs of C, N, P and SI species to the Ría de Vigo (NW Spain). Estuarine, Coastal and Shelf Science, 65: 74-82</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>An error occurred getting the license - uri.</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>cerrado</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>An error occurred on the license name.</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>