<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Patrones hidrológicos y variabilidad temporal de la circulación oceánica en la región plataforma/talud del golfo Ártabro, noroeste de Galicia</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Díaz-del-Río-Pérez, G. (Guillermo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2008-06-01T00:00:00+02:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Golfo Ártabro</dc:subject><dc:subject>noroeste de España</dc:subject><dc:subject>hidrología</dc:subject><dc:subject>afloramiento</dc:subject><dc:subject>filamentos</dc:subject><dc:subject>marea interna</dc:subject><dc:subject>ondas de inercia</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents an analysis of data related to the hydrology and currents in the Gulf of ártabro -a region located in the north-western corner of the Galician coast- that were collected from May to September, 1996. The work has been divided into two broad sections; the first of which examines the data collected during two different oceanographic surveys carried out in May and September, in an area covering some 30 ˟  35 nautical miles, while the second section analyzes the time series of data collected by means of two lines moored outside the area sampled.  The first dataset was subjected to a quasi-synoptic analysis (the data collection took place within a timeframe of roughly 5 days), of the distribution of the water masses in the region and their dynamics, based on geostrophic calculations. This is the first comprehensive description of the oceanography in this region. Moreover, since the information comes from two different time periods -one at the beginning and the other in the middle of the upwelling season- it was possible to investigate the variability of the circulation patterns. The most important differences were observed in the upper-layer circulation, ranging from a situation in which the Poleward Current (May, 1996) was still distinguishable, to another one which led to the identification of the basic characteristics of seasonal upwelling episodes in the eastern contours of the subtropical gyres of the large ocean basins. In September, 1996, the upwelling was in a stage of (almost) maximum activity, and hydrological sampling enabled us to identify a structure with filament features emanating from Cape San Adrián (the most rugged topography of the coast in this area), towards the open sea. Minor changes were also observed in the circulation of the vein of Mediterranean water.  With the time series, it was possible to examine the variability of the dynamics on different time scales. The most important was found to be the one associated with the tides that exhibit an intense baroclinic mode contribution, with large internal fluctuations and, more interestingly, a marked increase in the intensity of the bottom currents. Detailed analysis of the data collected would suggest that this increase is a consequence of the total reflection of the energy transported by the internal tide, as it hits the continental slope with its supercritical topographic inclination. The recordings of the currents also helped to indentify a less intense inertial wave activity, associated with the passage of strong atmospheric fronts and the transfer of inertial energy contained in the wind field. The most important inertial episodes coincide with pronounced changes in the sub-inertial velocity field, which has led to the hypothesis that the two phenomena might be related. At a lower frequency, the near-surface currents recorded would appear to indicate the regular formation of filaments in the vicinity of Cape San Adrián, insofar as the deepest currents show large fluctuations (tens, or even up to a hundred, meters), in the depth at which the core of the Mediterranean water flows. A curious relationship was noted between the alternation of energy episodes in the near-surface and the deep layers. This relationship has not been studied in this paper.</dc:description><dc:description>La presente memoria analiza un conjunto de datos hidrológicos y de corrientes recogidos entre mayo y septiembre de 1996 en el denominado golfo ártabro, región situada en la esquina noroccidental del litoral gallego. El trabajo se ha separado en dos grandes bloques, el primero trata los datos recogidos durante las campañas oceanográficas llevadas a cabo en mayo y septiembre en un área de unas 30 ˟  35 millas náuticas; el segundo analiza las series temporales de datos recogidos por dos líneas de fondeo colocadas en la parte exterior del área muestreada.  Con el primero de los conjuntos de datos se ha realizado un análisis casi-sinóptico (los datos fueron recogidos en un lapso de tiempo de, aproximadamente, 5 días) de la distribución de las masas de agua en la región y de su dinámica basada en cálculos geostróficos. Es la primera descripción exhaustiva de la oceanografía de esta región. Además, el hecho de disponer de información en dos épocas diferentes, una al principio de la estación de afloramiento y otra en pleno afloramiento, ha permitido investigar la variabilidad en los patrones de circulación. Las mayores diferencias se observan en la circulación de la capa superior, cambiando desde una situación donde aún es identificable la Poleward Current (mayo, 1996) hasta otra donde se identifican las características esenciales de los afloramientos estacionales en los contornos orientales de los giros subtropicales de las grandes cuencas oceánicas. En septiembre de 1996, el afloramiento estaba en una fase de (casi) máxima actividad y el muestreo hidrológico permitió identificar una estructura con características de filamento emanando desde el cabo San Adrián (la irregularidad topográfica más notable de la costa en la zona) hacia alta mar. También se observaron cambios menores en la circulación de la vena de agua mediterránea.  Las series temporales permitieron investigar la variabilidad de la dinámica a distintas escalas temporales. La más importante es la asociada a las mareas, las cuales muestran una intensa contribución baroclina con importantes oscilaciones internas y -más interesante- con una notable intensificación de las corrientes en el fondo. Un análisis detallado de los datos recogidos sugiere que esta intensificación es consecuencia de la reflexión total de la energía transportada por la marea interna al incidir sobre un talud continental con pendiente topográfica supercrítica. Los registros de corrientes también han identificado una actividad de ondas inerciales de menor intensidad vinculadas al paso de frentes atmosféricos intensos y a la transferencia de energía de inercia contenida en el campo de vientos. Los episodios inerciales más importantes coinciden con cambios notables en el campo de velocidad subinercial por lo que se postula una relación entre ambos fenómenos. A más baja frecuencia, los registros de corriente más superficiales sugieren la formación regular de filamentos en las inmediaciones del cabo San Adrián en tanto que los más profundos indican importantes oscilaciones (de decenas a, tal vez, un centenar de metros) en la profundidad a la cual fluye el núcleo de agua mediterránea. Se apunta una relación curiosa entre la alternancia de episodios energéticos en las capas superficial y profunda, relación que no ha sido estudiada en esta memoria.</dc:description><dc:identifier>1578-410X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1420</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Tesis Doctorales. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2008. 28</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>473-08-013-2</dc:identifier><dc:type>doctoralThesis</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>