<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Estudio multiescalar de la ictiofauna asociada a praderas de Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813 en Alicante (sudeste ibérico)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Valle, C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bayle Sempere, J. T.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramos Esplá, A. A.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:42Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Posidonia oceanica</dc:subject><dc:subject>ictiofauna</dc:subject><dc:subject>variaciones diarias</dc:subject><dc:subject>escalas espaciales</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of this study is to describe a Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813 fish community and detect any daily changes in its composition at different spatial levels. Posidonia oceanica appears at depths from 0 to 30-40 meters, depending on water transparency. Its importance is based on the high number of associated fishes and invertebrates attracted by its spatial heterogeneity and variety of habitats compared with no vegetated areas. The fishing gear knows as beam trawl (1.8 meters of width and 0.8 meters of height) was used, at six localities. Each of these localities was divided in six subdivision (sites), of which we randomly sampled three by the day and three at night. Three replicates were performed at each site, for a total of 108 samples. In an overall catch of 8 747 specimens, 53 species were found, the most numerous being Diplodus annularis (1 493), Serranus scriba (1 326), Symphodus rostratus (1 156) and Symphodus cinereus (665). The nocturnal catches, compared with the diurnal, were more abundant, with a higher number of species and specimens.</dc:description><dc:description>En este estudio se pretende describir la comunidad de peces de Posidonia oceanica (L.) Delile, 1813 y detectar el efecto producido por el periodo del día considerando diferentes escalas espaciales. Posidonia oceanica se encuentra desde la superficie hasta los 30 o 40 metros de profundidad, en función de la transparencia del agua. Su importancia se basa en el alto número de peces e invertebrados que están asociados a ella debido a su alta heterogeneidad espacial y a su gran variedad de hábitats si se compara con zonas sin vegetación. Para ello, se utilizó un gánguil (1,8 metros de anchura por 0,8 metros de altura), y se consideraron seis localidades. En cada una de ellas, se eligieron seis sitios, de los que se muestrearon, al azar, tres de día y tres de noche. En cada uno de estos sitios se realizaron tres réplicas, lo que da un total de 108 muestras. Se capturaron 8 747 individuos pertenecientes a 53 especies, siendo las más numerosas Diplodus annularis (1 493), Serranus scriba (1 326), Symphodus rostratus (1 156) y Symphodus cinereus (665). Las capturas nocturnas fueron más abundantes en cuanto a diversidad y abundancia.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1506</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2001. 17 (1 y 2)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>