<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Análisis molecular de Acipenser sturio L., 1758 y Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815: una revisión</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Birstein, V. J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Doukakis, P.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Esturión atlántico</dc:subject><dc:subject>citocromo b</dc:subject><dc:subject>diversidad genética</dc:subject><dc:subject>filogenia</dc:subject><dc:description>Molecular phylogeny based on the analysis of partial sequences of mitochondrial (mt) cytochrome b (cyt b), 12S, and 16S genes supports a close relationship between the European Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser sturio L., 1758, and the American Atlantic sturgeon, Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815. These sister species form a separate clade within the genus Acipenser and appear to be the most basal clade with respect to all other species of the genus. Intraspecifically, at least two different genetic forms have been found within A. sturio (in the Northern and Baltic seas), but no defined subspecies exist. For A. oxyrinchus, fixed differences in the control region and cyt b gene distinguish the two subspecies, the Atlantic sturgeon A. oxyrinchus oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815 and the Gulf of Mexico sturgeon A. oxyrinchus desotoi Vladykov, 1955. Within A. o. oxyrinchus, a pronounced latitudinal cline in haplotype diversity exists from north to south along the eastern coast of North America. This greater genetic diversity in southern populations is most likely a result of population continuity through the Pleistocene. Monomorphism within the two northernmost, post-Pleistocene A. o. oxyrinchus populations indicates a probable founder effect. A. o. desotoi also displays a significant geographic structuring of populations in different river systems. Because of the lack of A. sturio individuals necessary for population studies and the close relationship between this species and A. oxyrinchus, the genetic characteristics and structure of A. oxyrinchus can be regarded as a model for A. sturio. The only opportunity for future detailed molecular study of A. sturio resides in using tissue samples from sturgeon specimens kept in various European museums.</dc:description><dc:description>La filogenia molecular basada en el análisis de secuencias parciales de los genes mitocondriales (mt) citocromo b (cyt b), 12S y 16S apoya la próxima relación entre el esturión atlántico europeo Acipenser sturio L., 1758 y el esturión atlántico americano Acipenser oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815. Estas especies hermanas forman un clado separado dentro del género Acipenser y parecen constituir el clado más basal con relación a todas las otras especies del género. Intraespecíficamente se han encontrado, al menos, dos formas genéticas diferentes dentro de A. sturio (en los mares del Norte y Báltico) pero no existen subespecies definidas. Para A. oxyrinchus las diferencias fijadas en la región control y en el gen del cyt b distinguen las dos subespecies: el esturión atlántico A. oxyrinchus oxyrinchus Mitchill, 1815 y el esturión del golfo de México A. oxyrinchus desotoi Vladykov, 1955. Dentro de A. o. oxyrinchus existe un pronunciado cline latitudinal en la diversidad de haplotipos desde el norte hasta el sur a lo largo de la costa este de América del Norte. Esta mayor diversidad genética en las poblaciones meridionales es, más probablemente, un resultado de la continuidad poblacional durante el Pleistoceno. El monomorfismo dentro de las dos poblaciones post-pleistocénicas más septentrionales de A. o. oxyrinchus indica un probable efecto fundador. A. o. desotoi siempre muestra una significativa estructuración geográfica de poblaciones en diferentes sistemas fluviales. Debido a la falta de individuos de A. sturio necesarios para los estudios poblacionales y a la próxima relación entre esta especie y A. oxyrinchus, las características y estructura genéticas de A. oxyrinchus pueden ser consideradas como modelo para A. sturio. La única oportunidad para un futuro estudio molecular detallado de A. sturio reside en el uso de muestras de tejidos de ejemplares de esturión almacenados en varios museos europeos.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>