<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Glutathione S-transferase, glutathione peroxidase and acetylcholinesterase activities in mussels transplanted to harbour areas.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Vidal-Liñán, L. (Leticia)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bellas-Bereijo, J.D. (Juan Domingo)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Etxebarría, N. (Néstor)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Nieto, Ó. (Óscar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Beiras, R. (Ricardo)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:39:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-18T08:39:35Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Mytilus galloprovincialis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biomarkers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Integrative assessment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bioaccumulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acetylcholinesterase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Antioxidant enzymes</dc:subject><dc:description>As part of an integrative monitoring campaign involving water and sediment chemistry, in situ bioassays, and mussel bioaccumulation and biomarkers, Mytilus galloprovincialis mussels of standard size were transplanted from a clean location to five sites in two important harbours from the Atlantic coast of Spain (Vigo and Pasaia). After a 30-day field exposure, the concentrations of major contaminants (trace metals, polychlorinated biphenyls and polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons) accumulated in mussel tissues were measured at each site, and a mussel bioaccumulation index (MBI) was calculated. The enzymatic activity levels of glutathione S-transferase (GST), glutathione peroxidase (GPx) and acetylcholinesterase (AChE) were quantified in the gills of transplanted mussels (n = 12). Mussels from the most polluted sites consistently exhibited significantly higher GST and GPx activities compared to the control site, whereas AChE activity was significantly inhibited. The responses of the GST and GPx activities were related to MBI, trace metals and PAH concentrations in mussels, whereas AChE activity was related to the trace metals concentrations in mussels. The above results suggest that GST and AChE activities can be used as potential biomarkers for active monitoring in marine coastal ecosystems. However, at this moment, GPx activity is not robust enough to be applicable to harbour areas.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Science of the Total Environment, 470-471. 2014: 107-116</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.scitotenv.2013.09.073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7496</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>