<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Preliminary study of growth of megrim (Lepidorhombus Wiffiagonis Walb.) from ICES Sub-area VII</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Rodríguez, J.L.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Iglesias-Martínez, S. (Sergio)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Council for the Exploration of the Sea (ICES)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-01-30T13:21:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-01-30T13:21:23Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1985</dcterms:issued><dc:description>Growth of megrim (Lepidorhombus Wiffiagonis) from ICES Sub-área VII is analysed based on 625 otolith readings. The type of edge (hyaline or opaque), through out the different seasons of the year is discussed. A linear relationship between otolith size and fish length is indicated, and also the mean length of fish corresponding to each anual ring is back calculated. The parameters of the Von Bertalanffy growth equation are obtained from the back-calculated lengths-at-age, for males, females and both sexes combined. The age length keys for 1984, for males, females and combined sexes are given.</dc:description><dc:description>La croissance du cardine (Lepidorhombus Whiffiagonis) de la Sub-aire VII du CIEM a été analysée a partir de 625 otolithes. Ou a etudié le type du bord (hyalin ou opaque) pendant les différentes saisons de l'année. La relation lineal entre la grandeur de l'otolithe et la longeur du poisson est preentée, aussi que les tailles moyennes du poisson en relation avec chaque anneau annuel. A partir des longeurs obtenus, nons avons calculé les parametres de l'equation de Von Bertalanffy pour mâles, femalles et les deux sexes combinées. Nous presentans ici les clés taille-âge pour mâles, femalles et sexes combinées pour l'année 1984.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1605</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Rodríguez, J.L. and S. Iglesias. 1985. Preliminary study of growth of megrim (Lepidorhombus Wiffiagonis Walb.) from ICES Sub-area VII. ICES CM Doc. 1985 / G: 53: 17p.</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>