<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Efectos de posibles variaciones en el esfuerzo sobre las poblaciones de pez espada, Xiphias Gladius, de las áreas BILL-94 y BILL-95</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>González-Garcés-Santiso, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Mejuto-García, J. (Jaime)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T13:17:51Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-02-24T13:17:51Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>1985</dcterms:issued><dc:description>This document examines the short- and long-term changes in the populations of Xiphias gladius in &#13;
the areas BIL-94  and  BIL-95  if changes in fishing  effort  are  introduced.  To  do  this,  size &#13;
frequences  were  used as the  method  of  analysis  due  to  the  difficulty  of  applying  a  &#13;
size-age key well accepted by the scientists. Also, a relationship  to  transform Lower  jaw-fork &#13;
length to fork length is presented.&#13;
Based on the assumptions carried out for the northeast Atlantic for 1978-1982, it appears that the &#13;
effort applied was associated with the maximum possible yield and  that  increases  or  decreases  &#13;
in  effort  would not  produce  significant  increases  in catches.&#13;
On the contrary,  in the   Mediterranean  under   the  same   assumptions, the analysis indicates &#13;
that  the  population  was  highly exploited  in  this same period and that only by  reducing  &#13;
fishing effort  could increases  in catch  be  obtained in the  long term.</dc:description><dc:description>Ce document  analyse les changements qui se produiraient à court et à long terme dans les populations de Xiphias gladius des secteurs BIL-94  et BIL-95 si l'effort  &#13;
de  pêche changeait. La   méthode  d'analyse  des  fréquen­ces de taílie a été utilisée à cet égard, étant donnée  qu'il  était difficile d'appliquer une clef taille âge accepter par &#13;
l'ensemble des scientifiques.  D'autre  part,  une relation qui  permet de transformer la  taille (LJ-LF) en  taille (LF) est également offerte.&#13;
Sur la base  des hypothèses  réalisées pour la période  1978-1982 dans l'Atlantique  NE, il semble que  l'effort  appliqué  à cette période  soit associé aux  rendements maximus  &#13;
possibles,  et que des accroissements  ou des  diminutions de l'effort ne   produiraient pas   d'importantes   hausses dans les prises.&#13;
Au contraire,    dans le cas de   la Méditerranée   et avec les mêmes prémisses,    &#13;
l'analyse indique   que la population  est fortement   exploitée durant  cette période, et  que  l'on  n'arriverait a  augmenter la  prise à long terme qu'en réduisant l'effort.</dc:description><dc:description>En el presente documento se analizan los  cambios que  sucederán a corto y largo plazo en las &#13;
poblaciones de  Xiphias gladius  de las áreas BIL-94 y BIL-95, si se introdujeran  cambios en el esfuerzo de pesca. Para ello se usa el método de análisis de frecuencias de tallas, debido  a  la dificultad de aplicar una clave talla edad ampliamente asumida por los científicos. Por otra parte, es &#13;
ofrecida una relación que  permite transformar la  talla (LJ-FL)  en  talla (FL).&#13;
En base a las asunciones realizadas, para el periodo 1978-1982 en  el Atlántico  NE, parece que  &#13;
el esfuerzo  aplicado en  dicho período estuvo asociado a los  máximos rendimientos  &#13;
posibles y que  aumentos o  disminuciones en  el esfuerzo no   producirían   aumentos   &#13;
importantes en   las capturas.&#13;
Por el contrario,  en el caso del  Mediterráneo,con  las mismas premisas, el  &#13;
análisis indica   que la población  estuvo fuertermente   explotada en ese mismo período, y  que solo  reduciendo el esfuerzo de pesca   se podrían conseguir  &#13;
aumentos de la captura, a largo  plazo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>González-Garcés, A., J. Mejuto. 1985. Efectos de posibles variaciones en el esfuerzo sobre las poblaciones de pez espada, Xiphias Gladius, de las áreas BILL-94 y BILL-95. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 23 (2): 342-353</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>