<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">El atún blanco (Thunnus alalunga) del Mediterráneo occidental</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Serna-Ernst, J.M. (José Miguel) de-la</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valeiras-Mota, J. (Julio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Alot-Montes, E. (Enrique)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Godoy-Garrido, M.D. (María Dolores)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT)</dc:publisher><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T11:47:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-03-03T11:47:28Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2003</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Longline</dc:subject><dc:subject>albacore</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thunnus alalunga</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mediterranean</dc:subject><dc:description>The situation of the Spanish fishery of albacore (Thunnus alalunga) in the western&#13;
Mediterranean during the last years is presented. Catch data, fishing effort, CPUEs and size&#13;
distributions are presented by gear and spatial-time strata. The mean annual catch of albacore&#13;
in the last ten years reaches 310 MT, which makes a temporary alternative fishing method to&#13;
the longline fisheries of swordfish. The finding of spawning areas around the Balearic Islands&#13;
and the information from CPUE analyses by strata, in the future, could contribute, from a&#13;
qualitative point of view, to important biological information of the species in the western&#13;
Mediterranean.</dc:description><dc:description>Le présent document fait état de la situation de la pêcherie espagnole de germon (Thunnus&#13;
alalunga) dans l’ouest de la Méditerranée au cours de ces dernières années. Les données de&#13;
capture, l’effort de pêche, les CPUE et les distributions de tailles sont présentés par engin et&#13;
par strate spatio-temporelle. La capture annuelle moyenne du germon ces dix dernières années&#13;
a atteint 310 t, ce qui offre aux pêcheries palangrières d’espadon une alternative temporaire.&#13;
L’existence de zones de frai autour des îles Baléares et l’information que fourniront les futures&#13;
analyses de CPUE par strate spatio-temporelle et par engin de pêche pourraient apporter, d’un&#13;
point de vue qualitatif, d’importantes informations biologiques sur l’espèce dans l’ouest de la&#13;
Méditerranée.</dc:description><dc:description>Se expone la situación de la pesquería española del atún blanco (Thunnus alalunga) durante los&#13;
últimos años en el Mediterráneo Occidental. Se presentan datos de captura, esfuerzo, CPUEs y&#13;
distribuciones de tallas por arte y estrato espacio-temporal. La captura media anual de atún&#13;
blanco para los últimos diez años alcanza las 310 Tm., lo que supone una alternativa temporal&#13;
a la pesca de pez espada con palangre de superficie. La existencia de áreas de reproducción en&#13;
torno al archipiélago Balear, unido a la información aportada por futuros análisis de CPUE&#13;
por estrato espacio-temporal y arte de pesca, podrían aportar, desde el punto de vista&#13;
cualitativo, importante información biológica sobre la especie en el Mediterráneo Occidental.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1667</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Serna, J. M. de la, J. Valeiras, E. Alot, D. Godoy. 2003. El atún blanco (Thunnus alalunga) del Mediterráneo occidental. Col. Vol. Sci. Pap. ICCAT, 55 (1): 160-165</dc:identifier><dc:type>workingPaper</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>