<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="spa">Morfometría de la cigala Nephrops norvegicus (L., 1758) de Galicia (noroeste de España)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Fariña, A. C.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Freire, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2006-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Crecimiento alométrico</dc:subject><dc:subject>heteroquelia</dc:subject><dc:subject>morfometría</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nephrops norvegicus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Galicia</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study focused on the relative or allometric growth of Norway lobster Nephrops norvegicus (L., 1758) from Galicia (northwest Spain). The variables analysed in relation to the carapace length included total size, length and width of chelipeds, length of first pair of male pleopods, width of female abdomen, and live weight. In females, total length, length and width of chelipeds, and abdominal width showed positive allometry. In males, the length and width of chelipeds also showed positive allometry, whereas the total length and first pair of pleopods' length showed negative allometry. Differences were found between males and females regarding the relationship of carapace length to live weight. Most of the individuals sampled (96 %) showed handedness, with the cutter or the crusher claw indistinctly placed on the left or right side.</dc:description><dc:description>Se ha estudiado el crecimiento relativo o alométrico de la cigala Nephrops norvegicus (L., 1758) de Galicia (noroeste de España). Las variables analizadas en relación con la longitud del caparazón fueron la longitud total, la anchura y la longitud de los quelípedos, la longitud del primer par de pleópodos de los machos, la anchura abdominal de las hembras y el peso húmedo. En hembras, la longitud total, la longitud y anchura de los quelípedos y la anchura del abdomen presentaron un crecimiento alométrico positivo. En machos, la longitud y anchura de los quelípedos mostraron alometría positiva, mientras que la longitud total y la longitud del primer par de pleópodos presentaron alometría negativa. Se encontraron diferencias entre sexos en las ecuaciones alométricas que relacionan la longitud del caparazón y el peso húmedo. La mayor parte de los individuos de cigala examinados (96 %) mostró heteroquelia, con la quela fina (cortadora) o la gruesa (trituradora) situada indistintamente en el lado izquierdo o el derecho.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1196</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2006. 22 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>