<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Stereological comparison of oocyte recruitment and batch fecundity estimates from paraffin and resin sections using spawning albacore (Thunnus alalunga) ovaries as a case study.</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Saber-Rodríguez, S. (Sámar)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías-López, A.D. (Ángel David)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Urbina-Gutiérrez, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Kjesbu, O.S.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:50:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T11:50:06Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Shrinkage,Paraffin,Resin,Oocyte Packing Density,Fecundity,Albacore</dc:subject><dc:description>Traditional histological protocols in marine&#13;
fi&#13;
sh reproductive laboratories using paraf&#13;
fi&#13;
n as the embedding&#13;
medium are now increasingly being replaced with protocols using resin instead. These procedures entail differ-&#13;
ent degrees of tissue shrinkage complicating direct comparisons of measurement results across laboratories or&#13;
articles. In this work we selected ovaries of spawning Mediterranean albacore (&#13;
Thunnus alalunga&#13;
) as the subject&#13;
of our study to address the issue of structural changes, by contrasting values on oocyte recruitment and&#13;
fi&#13;
nal&#13;
batch fecundity given from the same tissue samples in both paraf&#13;
fi&#13;
nandresin.Amodernstereologicalmethod,&#13;
the oocyte packing density (OPD) theory, was used supported by initial studies on ovarian tissue sampling and&#13;
measurement design. Examples of differences in the volume fraction of oocyte stages, free space and connective&#13;
tissue were found between the embedding media. Mean oocyte diameters were smaller in paraf&#13;
fi&#13;
nthaninresin&#13;
with differences ranging between 0.5% in primary growth and 24.3% in hydration (HYD) stage oocytes. Fresh&#13;
oocyte measurements showed that oocytes shrank as a consequence of the embedding process, reaching the&#13;
maximaldegreeofshrinkageforoocytesintheHYDstage(45.8%inparaf&#13;
fi&#13;
nand26.5%inresin).Inordertoassess&#13;
the effect of oocyte shrinkage on the OPD result, and thereby on relative batch fecundity (F&#13;
r&#13;
), oocyte diameters&#13;
corrected and uncorrected for shrinkage, were used for estimations. Statistical signi&#13;
fi&#13;
cant differences were&#13;
found (&#13;
P&#13;
b&#13;
0.05) between these two approaches in both embedding media. The average F&#13;
r&#13;
was numerically&#13;
smaller in paraf&#13;
fi&#13;
n compared to resin (86 ± 61 vs. 106 ± 54 oocytes per gram of body mass (mean ± SD)).&#13;
For both embedding media statistical signi&#13;
fi&#13;
cant differences (&#13;
P&#13;
b&#13;
0.05) were seen between F&#13;
r&#13;
results based on&#13;
either oocytes in the germinal vesicle migration stage or HYD stage. As a valuable adjunct, the present use of&#13;
the OPD theory made it possible to document that the oocyte recruitment of spawning ovaries of Mediterranean&#13;
albacore followed the typical pattern of an asynchronous oocyte development and indeterminate fecundity</dc:description><dc:identifier>1385-1101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2576</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Journal of Sea Research, 0. 2014: 0-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20329</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>