<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Maternal transference of isotopic signature (δ15N, δ13C) and Its evolution during ontogenic development of reared bluefin larvae (Thunnus thynnus)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Uriarte-Ramalho, A. (Amaya)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-García, A. (Alberto)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortega-García, A. (Aurelio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>de-la-Gándara, F. (Fernando)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Laiz-Carrión, R. (Raúl)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T13:17:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T13:17:30Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-05</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-02</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>bluefin larvae, trophic ecology, stable isotopes, maternal transference</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental rearing experiment of bluefin tuna larvae was undertaken in the Spanish&#13;
Oceanographic Institution (IEO) based in the aquaculture plant of Murcia that started June 24,&#13;
2013 when caged bluefin spawned naturally. Bluefin tuna eggs were transferred to rearing tanks&#13;
and where hatched larvae were sampled regularly every 2 days till 15dph. After this period,&#13;
larvae were sampled every 3 days till 37dph (Temperature range 22-26ºC). The standard length&#13;
(SL) of larvae were measured after frozen and conserved deep-frozen in a -80ºC for&#13;
undertaking posterior nitrogen (N) and carbon (C) stable isotope analysis. The results of the&#13;
experiment showed very high initial values of δ15N and δ13C in the eggs and lecitotrophic larvae&#13;
till 4dph, explaining a transgenerational transference of the heavy isotopes through maternal&#13;
inheritance. After this time lapse, the stable isotope values declined progressively till 12dph and&#13;
maintained this low level till 15dph. This period coincides with the notochord post-flexion&#13;
development established at a mean SL of 6,7mm (±0,57) measured. Coinciding with this&#13;
ontogenic stage, larvae were started to be fed with newly hatched larvae of aquaculture-bred&#13;
gilt-head seabream whose δ15N and δ13C values were consequently enriched. This diet&#13;
produced an increasing trend in the δ15N and δ13C values till 24dph reaching similar values of&#13;
the initial developmental times. The results show that pre-flexion larvae of bluefin have high&#13;
δ15N and δ13C signature as a result of their maternal transference. A similar decreasing pattern&#13;
was also observed in field-based research on bluefin larvae which justified the need to carry out&#13;
this rearing experiment. The data acquired in this experiment allows to formulate an estimate of&#13;
the maternal δ15N and δ13C signatures from larvae between 3-6mm SL which opens research&#13;
horizons in the estimation of maternal trophic qualities that may relate to larval growth and&#13;
condition potentials. This work was financed by the project ATAME CTM2011-29525-C04-02.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>XVIII Simposio Ibérico de Estudios de Biología Marina. (02/09/2014 - 05/09/2014. Gijón (España)). 2014. pg. 103. En: , . 2014: -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>pg. 103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20352</dc:identifier><dc:type>poster</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>