<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Lugares de freza del esturión en los afluentes del río Oder: una valoración inicial</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gessner, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bartel, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:19Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Acipenser sturio</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alemania</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polonia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mar del Norte</dc:subject><dc:subject>reproducción</dc:subject><dc:description>As part of a feasibility study for the re-establishment of Acipenser sturio L., 1758 in its previous range in German and Polish waters, a habitat assessment was initiated for the Odra River watershed. Spawning habitat for sturgeons is considered to be of major importance for the successful restoration and subsequent reproduction of the species, since it supports the most vulnerable life stages. The ongoing restoration project comprises three distinct phases; the first phase included the evaluation of readily available habitat. Habitat requirements were identified based on published information on sturgeon reproduction, historical catch data, and early life history. Potential spawning habitats were determined in a first step based on historic records. For the identified historic spawning sites, recent data on migration obstacles and water pollution were evaluated, thus excluding non-accessible or adversely affected sites. In the Drawa River -described as a sturgeon spawning habitat until 1939- potentially suitable habitats were determined to be readily available. Data were gathered on the dynamic of the discharge, water quality, longitudinal profiles and cross-sections of the river, as well as substrate composition. Five river stretches comprising approximately 15 000 m³ were identified as being potentially suitable for sturgeon spawning. Assuming an average fertility of 1 million eggs per female and a maximum density of 3 500 eggs/m³, the spawning-site surface required for an average female would comprise approximately 350 m³. Thus, the Drawa River could provide a spawning habitat for approx. 50 females.</dc:description><dc:description>Como parte de un estudio de viabilidad para el restablecimiento de Acipenser sturio L., 1758 en su distribución original en aguas alemanas y polacas, se inició una valoración del hábitat en la cuenca del río Oder. Se considera que el hábitat de freza para los esturiones es de mayor importancia para el éxito de la recuperación y subsecuente reproducción de las especies, ya que mantiene los estados vitales más vulnerables. El proyecto de recuperación en marcha comprende tres fases diferentes; la primera incluyó la evaluación de hábitat fácilmente disponible. Los requerimientos de hábitat fueron identificados a partir de información publicada sobre la reproducción del esturión, datos históricos de capturas, e historia natural temprana. Los hábitats potenciales de freza fueron determinados, en una primera fase, a partir de citas históricas. Para los lugares de freza históricos identificados, los datos recientes sobre obstáculos a la migración y contaminación del agua fueron evaluados, excluyendo los lugares no accesibles o adversamente afectados. En el río Drawa -descrito como un hábitat de freza para el esturión hasta 1939- los hábitats potencialmente apropiados fueron determinados para ser fácilmente disponibles. Se reunieron datos sobre dinámica de la descarga, calidad del agua, perfiles longitudinales y secciones transversales del río, así como de la composición del sustrato. Cinco secciones fluviales, comprendiendo aproximadamente 15 000 m³, fueron identificadas como potencialmente apropiadas para la freza del esturión. Asumiendo una fecundidad media de un millón de huevos por hembra y una densidad máxima de 3 500 huevos/m³, la superficie de lugar de freza requerida para una hembra media comprendería aproximadamente 350 m³. Así, el río Drawa podría proporcionar un hábitat de freza para aproximadamente 50 hembras.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>