<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Impact assessment of agricultural inputs into a Mediterranean coastal lagoon (Mar Menor, SE)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Campillo-González, J.A. (Juan Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Albentosa-Verdú, M. (Marina)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Valdés-García, N.J. (Nadia Juliana)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Moreno-González, R. (Rubén)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>León-León, V.M. (Víctor Manuel)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Murcia</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-09-25T11:14:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-09-25T11:14:33Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-10-15</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Biomarkers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organic pollutants</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pesticides</dc:subject><dc:subject>AchE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oxidative stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>SFG</dc:subject><dc:subject>Clams</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coastal areas</dc:subject><dc:description>The Mar Menor is a coastal lagoon threatened by the development of intensive agriculture in&#13;
the surrounding areas. Large amounts of pesticides from these areas are discharged into El Albujón, a&#13;
permanent watercourse flowing into the lagoon.&#13;
We have used a multi-biomarker approach to assess the biological effects arising in bivalve species&#13;
affected by agricultural pollution. Biomarkers indicative of neurotoxicity (acetylcholinesterase, AchE),&#13;
oxidative stress (catalase, CAT; glutathione reductase, GR and lipid peroxidation, LPO), phase II&#13;
biotransformation of xenobiotics (glutathione S-transferase, GST) and physiological stress (scope for&#13;
growth, SFG) were measured in clams transplanted to four sites of the lagoon (two reference sites and&#13;
two sites affected by the dispersion of the effluent of the El Albujón), for exposure periods of 7 and 22&#13;
days.&#13;
The hazards of this effluent were also examined by simultaneously measuring up to 83 contaminants&#13;
(pesticides, PCBs, PAHs and others) in samples of fresh water from the watercourse mouth and&#13;
seawater from the deployed sites, as well as the bioaccumulation of organochlorinated compounds and&#13;
PAHs in the transplanted animals.&#13;
Biomarker responses showed marked differences between reference and affected sites after 7 and 22&#13;
days. However it was only after 22 days that Principal Component Analysis (PCA) of the biomarker&#13;
responses distinguished between clams deployed in sites affected by the dispersion of the effluent of&#13;
the watercourse and those from the reference sites. The chemical analysis of water showed high&#13;
concentrations of pesticides close to El Albujón watercourse mouth, with the greatest input flux&#13;
corresponding to the organophosphate chlorpyrifos, followed by pendimethalin and naphthalene, and&#13;
at lower levels acenaphthene, terbuthylazine-desethyl and chlorpyrifos-methyl. In this regard, PCA&#13;
analysis showed that the biological effects of the mixture of pesticides in caged clams after 22 days&#13;
were reduced levels of AchE and SFG and increased levels of GR and phase II GST activity. An&#13;
Integrated Biomarker Response index was calculated from the combination of these biomarkers,&#13;
proving useful for the assessment of the impact of agricultural pollution in caged clams.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0166-445X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Aquatic Toxicology, 142-143. 2013: 365-379</dc:identifier><dc:type>preprint</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>