<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="">Distribución de Acipenser sturio L., 1758 en el mar Negro y su cuenca</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Bacalbasa-Dobrovici, N.</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Holčík, J.</ags:creatorPersonal><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2013-08-20T11:34:26Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2001-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Esturión atlántico</dc:subject><dc:subject>río Danubio</dc:subject><dc:subject>río Rioni</dc:subject><dc:subject>río Inguri</dc:subject><dc:subject>ecología</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservación</dc:subject><dc:description>The Atlantic sturgeon Acipenser sturio L., 1758, was always rare in the Black Sea, and the least numerous in comparison with other sturgeons. At the end of the 19th and the first half of the 20th centuries, it occurred along almost the entire Black Sea coast. It has been distributed predominantly in the eastern part of the Black Sea, especially in the region adjacent to Georgia's Inguri and Rioni rivers, with spawning grounds in the latter. It has also been recorded occasionally in the Danube River, where it occurred mostly in its delta. Earlier records even indicate its reproduction in the Danube. Recently its distribution and population density has been dramatically reduced. The distribution of this species is limited only to the eastern part of the Black Sea, and the recent total density of adults is estimated at only several hundred specimens. This situation has placed A. sturio on the list of critically endangered fish species. Existing data on its morphology and ecology indicate some differences between the Black Sea stock and populations from the Atlantic Ocean and the Baltic and Mediterranean Seas.</dc:description><dc:description>El esturión atlántico Acipenser sturio L., 1758 siempre ha sido raro en el mar Negro, y el menos numeroso en comparación con otros esturiones. A finales del siglo XIX y primera mitad del XX se encontraba a lo largo de toda la costa del mar Negro. Se distribuía predominantemente en la parte oriental del mar Negro, en especial en la región adyacente a los ríos Inguri y Rioni en Georgia, con áreas de freza en este último. También ha sido citado ocasionalmente en el río Danubio, donde ocupaba sobre todo su delta. Las citas más antiguas incluso indican su reproducción en el Danubio. Recientemente su distribución y densidad de población se han visto dramáticamente reducidas. La distribución de esta especie se limita sólo a la parte oriental del mar Negro, y la densidad total reciente de adultos se estima en sólo algunos cientos de individuos. Esta situación ha colocado a A. sturio en la lista de especies de peces en peligro crítico. Los datos conocidos sobre su morfología y ecología indican algunas diferencias entre la población del mar Negro y las del océano Atlántico y los mares Báltico y Mediterráneo.</dc:description><dc:identifier>0074-0195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/1367</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>Boletín. Instituto Español de Oceanografía. 2000. 16 (1-4)</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>openAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>