<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">By-catch frequency and size differentiation in loggerhead turtles as a function of surface longline gear type in the western Mediterranean Sea</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Báez, J.C. (José Carlos)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Macías-López, A.D. (Ángel David)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Camiñas-Hernández, J.A. (Juan Antonio)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ortiz-de-Urbina-Gutiérrez, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>García-Barcelona, S. (Salvador)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Bellido-Millán, J.M. (José María)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Real, R.</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Málaga</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T09:06:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-01T09:06:46Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2012-11-19</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>by-catch, conservation biology, fisheries, long-lived animals</dc:subject><dc:description>Fisheries by-catch is considered to be a major threat to loggerhead turtles in the Mediterranean Sea. Technical differences in&#13;
both gear configurations (e.g. hook and bait type) and fisheries operations carried out by the Spanish Mediterranean surface&#13;
longline fleet could have an effect on by-catch rates and size selectivity. The aim of the present study was to test the differences&#13;
in by-catch per unit effort and body size of loggerhead sea turtles caught using different gear types in the Mediterranean&#13;
surface longline fishery. Our results suggest that differences in the gear type used have an effect on catch rates and size selec-&#13;
tivity. Thus, surface longliners targeting albacore (LLALB) using smaller hooks tend to capture smaller loggerheads but have&#13;
the highest by-catch per unit of effort (BPUE), whereas other longlines, such as surface longliners targeting bluefin tuna&#13;
(LLJAP) and traditional surface longliners targeting swordfish (LLHB), using larger hooks tend to select the larger&#13;
animals; moreover, LLHB had the lowest BPUE. Disproportionate rates of fisheries-induced mortality on certain size/age-&#13;
classes can differentially affect sea turtle populations, as each sea turtle age-class contributes differently to current and&#13;
future reproduction. Thus, fisheries management should not only be focusing on preserving the large juvenile and mature&#13;
turtles, but also on reducing the total by-catch. Thus, we recommend encouraging the use of LLHB versus other surface&#13;
gears. We suggest that it is very important to take into account the gear type (and its particular catch rates) when&#13;
making inferences about the impact of longline fisheries on sea turtle populations.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2555</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom, 93(5). 2012: 1423-1427</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1017/S0025315412001841</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20309</dc:identifier><dc:type>article</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>