<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"><ags:resource><dc:title xml:lang="eng">Mauritanian deep-water Plumularioidea (Cnidaria, Hydrozoa)</dc:title><ags:creatorPersonal>Gil, M. (Marta)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramil, F. (Francisco)</ags:creatorPersonal><ags:creatorPersonal>Ramos, A. (Ana)</ags:creatorPersonal><dc:publisher>Centro Oceanográfico de Vigo</dc:publisher><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03T09:56:57Z</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-10-03</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>indefinido</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-13</dcterms:issued><dcterms:issued>2014-06-11</dcterms:issued><dc:subject>Biodiversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>biogeography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plumularioidea</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrozoa</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cnidaria</dc:subject><dc:subject>deep-waters</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mauritania</dc:subject><dc:subject>Northwest Africa</dc:subject><dc:description>Deep-waters are one of the most unknown habitats on Earth, but the displacement of fishing fleets into ever deeper waters, the emerging exploitation of mineral resources and climate change threaten to destroy these ecosystems whose functioning we just begin to understand (Levin &amp; Sibuet, 2012).&#13;
Superfamily Plumularioidea is the most important group of deep-water Hydrozoa, both in species richness and abundance. In spite of being typical epifauna living on hard substrates, many species also colonize soft bottoms by adaptions on their hydrorhiza. The morphology of their colonies, feather shaped, often branched, and  with sizes that can exceed one meter length, contributes effectively to the development of a three-dimensional habitat and provide secondary substrata for other hydrozoans (auto-epizoism sensu Millard, 1973) and for other invertebrates (see Ansín Agis et al., 2001), thus enhancing the biodiversity.&#13;
This communication deals with the results of the study of this superfamily in the continental margin of Mauritania, between 80 and 2,000 m depth. Samples were collected in 329 trawling stations during the four multidisciplinary Spanish–Mauritanian surveys (Maurit) carried out from 2007 to 2010 onboard R/V Vizconde de Eza. Most samples were collected using a commercial trawl gear (Lofoten type) following a stratified random sampling methodology program. Moreover 25 stations were also sampled along five transects perpendicular to the coastline at five bathymetric strata with an Agassiz trawl, and 26 samples with a rock dredge were carried out over the cold-water coral reef, the canyon edges and the seamount. &#13;
A total of 4,073 colonies of Plumularioidea were collected, and 20 species were identified; nine of them reported for the first time in Mauritanian waters. The greatest diversity corresponded to Plumulariidae family (8 species), followed by Aglaophenidae (6 species.), Halopterididae (4 species.) and Kirchenpaueriidae (2 species.). Most of them showed an eurybathic distribution and were collected along the continental shelf and the slope, in agreement with the results of previous studies (Calder, 1997).&#13;
The biogeographical analysis showed a clear dominance of, Atlantic species (55%) over species with a wide distribution (45%). Within the Atlantic species the most representatives were those with amphi-Atlantic (25%), Atlantic-Mediterranean (15%) and Eastern Atlantic (15%) distributions, which generally agrees with the results obtained by Ansín Agis et al. (2001). The absence of the medusa stage in the group is not a limiting factor for their geographical distribution that seems to be more dependent on their environmental tolerance than on the particularities of their life-cycle (Boero &amp; Bouillon, 1993). Their ability to spread by rafting (Cornelius, 1992) together with ocean circulation patterns in North-eastern Atlantic waters may explain the faunal composition in Northwest Africa (Ansín Agís et al., 2001). The importance of the Atlantic-Mediterranean component and the influence of the Canary Current as a southward larval dispersal route were also emphasized by Van Soest (1993) in his study about the distribution of sponges in the continental shelf off Mauritania. &#13;
&#13;
References:&#13;
Ansín Agis, J., Ramil, F. &amp; Vervoort, W. ( 2001) Zool. Verh. Leiden 333: 1-268.&#13;
Boero, F. &amp; J. Bouillon (1993) Biol. J. Linn. Soc., 48: 239-266.&#13;
Calder, D.R. (1997). Proc. 6th Int. Conf. Coel. Biol.1995: 85-90.&#13;
Levin, L.A. &amp; Sibuet, M. (2012). Annu. Rev. Marine. Sci. 2012.4: 79-112.&#13;
Millard, N.A.H. (1973). Publ. Seto Mar. Biol. Lab., 20: 23-34.&#13;
Van Soest, R.W.M. (1993). Hydrobiologia 258: 95-106.</dc:description><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10508/2683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>IV Simposio Internacional  de Ciencias del Mar. (11/06/2014 - 13/06/2014. Las Palmas de Gran Canaria (Spain)). . conferenceObject. En: , .</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>conferenceObject</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>20428</dc:identifier><dc:type>conferenceObject</dc:type><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/es/</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>embargoedAccess</ags:rightsTermsOfUse><ags:rightsTermsOfUse>Atribución-NoComercial-SinDerivadas 3.0 España</ags:rightsTermsOfUse></ags:resource></ags:resources>