<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Polluted soil rehabilitation using genetically engineered mix microbial inoculum</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Isinguzo</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">N. S.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Head HSE, Offshore Operations, Shell Nigeria Exploration and Production Company (SNEPCo) NAL Towers, 21/22 Marina, Lagos Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Bello</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">O. S.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Soil Science, Ambrose Alli University, Ekpoma, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Every natural system is self purifying. This is made possible by the diverse micro- and macroflora and -fauna in soils. Bacteria and fungi constitute the greatest population in soils implying that in the case of pollution, microbes are the major agents of purification. A study was carried out in situ with Nigerian crude oil (Bonny light) in polluted teak soil using axenic cultures of bacteria and fungi, a mix culture of bacteria and fungi and a mixed culture of genetically engineered bacteria (Bacillus sp.) and a fungus (Aspergillus niger). The ability to degrade crude oil was measured directly (spectrophotometrically) by oil disappearance and indirectly by the amount of CO2 produced in a controlled environment. Results showed that mixed cultures of the isolated bacteria and fungi degraded the crude oil in the teak soil better than axenic cultures by about 85% over a month period. This is a reduction of the pollution to less than 15%, while the genetically engineered mix culture (mutant Bacillus sp. and Asp. niger) degraded crude oil in a similar soil and condition by 99.3% over the same period, thus reducing pollution to less than 1% and can be applied in bioremediation.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>299</start>
          <end>301</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_2/e5.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>