<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Chemical and functional properties of full fat and defatted Dioclea reflexa seed flours</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Akinyede</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A.I.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Food Science and Technology Department, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Ondo State, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Amoo</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">I.A.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Chemistry Department, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Ondo State, Nigeria.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Eleyinmi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A.F.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Food Science and Technology Department, Federal University of Technology, Akure, Ondo State, Nigeri.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The chemical and functional properties of full fat and defatted Dioclea reflexa (FDR and DDR) seed flour were investigated using standard methods. Results showed the following respective values for FDR and DDR: fat 14.4 and 5.35%, ash 2.80 and 3.65%, protein 39.38 and 46.85%, fibre 1.48 and 1.73%, carbohydrate 33.34 and 34.22%, moisture content 8.60 and 8.20%. The respective mineral contents (mg/kg) were P 1.33 and 1.37, Zn 232.73 and 290.99, Fe 258.39 and 290.99, Mn 25.42 and 32.19, Mg 818.60 and 826.03, Na 129.83 and 182.45, Ca 983.13 and 963.14, K 937.68 and 865.04. The respective phytic acid and tannin contents were 0.34 and 0.20%; 7.54 and 7.48%. The water absorption capacity, oil absorption capacity, emulsion capacity, least gelation capacity, foaming capacity and foaming stability (after 4 hours) of FDR and DDR were: 610 and 670%, 272.60 and 291.40%, 60 and 40%, 6 and 6% (m/v), 13.72 and 17.65%, 9.8 and 13.8% respectively. The protein solubility of FDR and DDR was least between pH 4–5 and highest between pH 7–10. Defatting significantly influenced the chemical composition and functional properties of DR.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>3</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>112</start>
          <end>115</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2005</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2005-issue_2/f21.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>