<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effects of fluidized-ceramics treatment on the flocculation of suspension in water treatment system</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Kalam Azad</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Md. Abul</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Kochi University, Monobe B-200, Nankoku-shi 783-8502, Japan.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ishikawa</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Katsumi</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Kochi University, Monobe B-200, Nankoku-shi 783-8502, Japan.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>There is growing concern about water environment protection as water environment has polluted rapidly, and the development of effective water treatment system is desired from the point of view of ecological energy and non-pollution. Elce water treatment system (manufactured by Nihonjisui Co, Ltd.) used in this study can help to solve serious modern water environment problems. For example, one of Elce’s properties seems to be a flocculation effect, which can reduce the amount of chemical agents. Adding a large amount of flocculants will have a negative influence on human and environment in the future, therefore, it is very important to reduce the amount of flocculants. The purpose of this study was to focus on how to reduce the amount of flocculants by means of Elce i.e. through the effects of ceramics treatment over colloidal materials. The most unique character of this device was using of granular ceramics (having electrical charges at the surface) in a stainless steel vessel. In this test, kaolin (anionic agent) was used as a suspension and polyaluminium chloride (PAC) as a flocculant. The kaolin concentration was prepared with a turbidity of 100 in water; 1-20 ppm of PAC was added in the solution and the pH was adjusted with 0.01 N NaOH. Thus, this study compared the flocculation effect of the ceramics-treated water with the non-treated water by measuring the transmittance of each supernatant based on the standard method. The transmittance percentage of the flocculation effect was measured by using absorption photometry. As a result, it was found that the changes of transmittance depended on the amount of NaOH (=change of pH) in various PAC concentrations where each PAC concentration had an optimal pH. The ceramics-treated water showed significant changes in transmittance percentage. When the pH changed at maximum values of transmittance, kaolin particles formed the largest flock in various PAC concentrations. At those values, the transmittance percentage of the ceramics-treated water was 8% higher than non-treated water in optimal PAC quantity. Therefore, the ceramics-treated water was considered to indicate an effective flocculation.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>234</start>
          <end>237</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2004</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2004-issue_3_4/e4.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>