<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Studies on postharvest calcium chloride application on storage behaviour and quality of Asian pear during cold storage</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Mahajan</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">B.V.C.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Punjab Horticultural Postharvest Technology Centre, Punjab Agricultural University Campus, Ludhiana - 141 004, India.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Dhatt</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">A.S.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Punjab Horticultural Postharvest Technology Centre, Punjab Agricultural University Campus, Ludhiana - 141 004, India.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The fruits of Pathernakh pear, cultivar of Asian pear were harvested at physiological mature stage and divided into requisite lots for further handling. These were dipped into calcium chloride solution at concentrations of 1, 2 and 4 per cent each for 20 minutes. The control fruit were dipped into water for the same duration. The fruits were air-dried packed in corrugated fibreboard cartons and stored at 0-1°C and 90-95% RH. The fruits were analyzed for various physiological and biochemical constituents at 30, 45, 60 and 75 days of storage interval. The postharvest application of 4 per cent calcium chloride proved to be the most effective treatment in reducing the weight loss (3%) as well as core browning (5%) and maintained the firmness (14 lbs force) and quality of pear fruits up to 75 days of storage, as compared to control where considerably high level of core browning (30%), breakdown of firmness (11 lbs force) and deterioration of quality was observed after 75 days of storage. An extended storage period of pear fruits for 15 days was achieved with postharvest application of 4 per cent calcium chloride over the control.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>157</start>
          <end>159</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2004</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2004-issue_3_4/a14.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>