<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ags:resources
  SYSTEM "http://purl.org/agmes/agrisap/dtd/">
<ags:resources xmlns:ags="http://purl.org/agmes/1.1/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:agls="http://www.naa.gov.au/recordkeeping/gov_online/agls/1.2" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
   <ags:resource ags:ARN="UA2015600001">
      <dc:title>ADAPTATION OF TRANSLATIONAL APPARATUS OF PLASTIDS OF DAYLILY SORTS (НEMEROCALLIS L.) TOWARDS THE POLLUTION BY HEAVY METALS</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>Chipilyak, T.</ags:creatorPersonal>
         <ags:creatorPersonal>Gryshko, V.</ags:creatorPersonal>
      </dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>
         <ags:publisherName>Bogdan Chmelnitskiy Melitopol State Pedagogical University</ags:publisherName>
      </dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>
         <dcterms:dateIssued>2014</dcterms:dateIssued>
      </dc:date>
      <dc:description>
         <dcterms:abstract>The specificity of the accumulation of heavy metals (Fe, Pb, Cu, Ni, Zn, Cd) by cultivars Hemerocallis and peculiarities of adaptation of the photosynthetic system of daylilies in the conditions of industrial pollution and impact of emissions of motor transport were presented. The highest values of the indices of interstitial pollution of leaves by Pb ions and the fastest rate of lipid peroxidation in leaf cells were typical for cv. Stagecoach. The lowest rate of accumulation of the majority of heavy metals were registered for cv. Winnie the Pooh. The overall pattern of adaptive reactions of daylilies to the pollution was the alteration in chlorophyll a and b ratio. It was lower in more sensitive (cv. Stagecoach) and higher in more persistent (cv. Winnie the Pooh) sorts. The translocation indices for barrier block "soil-sheets" suggest that all the cultivars have persistent anti-concentration barrier only for Ni, which actively operates both in normal and industrial conditions (translocation indices &amp;lt; 1,0). Keywords: Нemerocallis L., H. x hybrida hort. cv. American Revolution, cv. Winnie the Pooh, cv. Stagecoach, heavy metals, pigments of photosynthesis, TBA-active compounds.</dcterms:abstract>
      </dc:description>
      <dc:identifier scheme="dcterms:URI">10.7905/bbmspu.v4i2.886</dc:identifier>
      <dc:format>
         <dcterms:extent>p.83-97</dcterms:extent>
      </dc:format>
      <dc:language scheme="ags:ISO639-1">UK</dc:language>
      <ags:citation>
         <ags:citationTitle>Biological Bulletin of Bogdan Chmelnitskiy Melitopol State Pedagogical University</ags:citationTitle>
         <ags:citationIdentifier scheme="ags:ISSN">2225-5486</ags:citationIdentifier>
         <ags:citationNumber>v.4(2)</ags:citationNumber>
      </ags:citation>
   </ags:resource>
</ags:resources>