<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Double-sided UV-C treatments delayed chlorophyll degradation but increased chilling injury of green bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L. cv. Helda) during storage</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Kasım</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M. Ufuk</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>University of Kocaeli, Vocational School of Arslanbey, Arslanbey, Kocaeli, Türkiye.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Kasım</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Rezzan</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>University of Kocaeli, Vocational School of Arslanbey, Arslanbey, Kocaeli, Türkiye.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>In this work a study of one-sided and double sided UV-C treatments on chilling injury and chlorophyll degradation of green beans (Phaseolus vulgaris L. cv. Helda) was conducted. In this way green beans kept better in one-sided UV-C treatments, maintaining bright green color and good texture. Nevertheless treatments of double-sided UV-C, especially higher doses, induced chilling injury because of the cell damage of pods as measured by electrolyte leakage during 14 days of storage. UV-C treatments produced different changes on the green beans chlorophyll a and chlorophyll b content. Green beans of DS-3 and DS-5 showed a continuous degradation of chlorophyll b during the storage while the other samples showed decrease at the first 7 days and then increase. However, chlorophyll a and b remained best in pods treated with double-sided UV-C. Visual quality scores of pods in double-sided UV-C treatments were lower than those of one-sided UV-C treatments.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>6</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>176</start>
          <end>180</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2008</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2008-issue_3_4/f37.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>