<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effect of nitrogen fertilisation reduction on yield, quality and N utilisation on processing spinach</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Canali</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Stefano</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Consiglio per la Ricerca e la Sperimentazione in Agricoltura (CRA), Centro per lo Studio delle Relazioni tra Pianta e Suolo, Via della Navicella, 2 - 00184 Roma, Italy.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Montemurro</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Francesco</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Consiglio per la Ricerca e la Sperimentazione in Agricoltura (CRA), Unità di Ricerca per lo Studio dei Sistemi Colturali, SS 106 Jonica km 448.2 - 75010 Metaponto (MT), Italy.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Tittarelli</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Fabio</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Consiglio per la Ricerca e la Sperimentazione in Agricoltura (CRA), Centro per lo Studio delle Relazioni tra Pianta e Suolo, Via della Navicella, 2 - 00184 Roma, Italy.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Masetti</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Olimpia</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Consiglio per la Ricerca e la Sperimentazione in Agricoltura (CRA), Centro per lo Studio delle Relazioni tra Pianta e Suolo, Via della Navicella, 2 - 00184 Roma, Italy.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Nitrogen (N) fertilizer is one of the main growth limiting nutrients in leafy crops and represents one of the highest input costs in horticultural systems and a potential concern for the environment. As a consequence, any environmental and economic considerations need a deep analysis of N fertiliser utilisation in vegetable production. This study was carried out to evaluate the effect of the reduction of N fertilisation on yield, quality, N uptake and N utilisation efficiency of processing spinach (Spinacia oleracea L.). To accomplish this objective two field experiments were carried out in the Foggia Plain (Southern Italy) to determine the optimum N-application level and ways of modulating it during the growing cycle through the application of different N rates. In a completely randomized experimental design with four replications the following three N fertilization treatments were compared: 50% (N 150 kg ha-1), 75% (N 225 kg ha-1) and 100% (N 300 kg ha-1) of the normal rate applied by the farmers in the trial area. Subdividing the total amounts in equal parts, the urea fertiliser was broadcasted in three times: before sowing, at the stage of second couple of leaves (38 days after sowing, DAS) and at fast growing stage (81 DAS). The results indicate that lower N fertilization level ensured a satisfactory yield, quality (dry matter and nitrate contents), N uptake and N utilisation pattern. It also decreased the amount of N available for leaching during the whole cropping cycle. The higher quantity of N applied at the maximum level did not increase the majority of the measured parameters, whereas the N utilization efficiency decreased significantly from the intermediate to the highest N treatment level in both field experiments. The results of this research indicated the way to optimise N fertilisation of processing spinach, in terms of quantity and time of fertiliser application, to obtain satisfactory crop performances and reducing environmental risks.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>6</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>242</start>
          <end>247</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2008</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2008-issue_3_4/a12.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>