<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effect of foliar N and B application at different growth stages of sugar beet cultivars on root and sugar yield, sugar percent and root dry matter</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Tabrizi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">E. Farajzadeh Memari</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Islamic Azad University, Malekan Branch, Iran.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Yarnia</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Islamic Azad University, Tabriz Branch, Iran.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Khorshidi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">M.B.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>East Azerbaijan Agricultural and Natural Resources Research Center, Tabriz, Iran.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Khoei</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">F. Rahimzadeh</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Faculty of Agriculture, Islamic Azad University, Tabriz Branch, Iran.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>For studying N and B containing fertilizers and different application methods on sugar beet cultivars, an experiment was conducted in Islamic Azad University, Tabriz Branch, Agricultural Faculty Station in 2005-2006. Three replicates, three cultivars (7233 - calibrate, IC and PP22) and fertilizer application methods (soil and foliar N and B and mixed N and B application at 6-8 and 14-16 leaf stages) were arranged in a RCBD based factorial design. Root yield, sugar and root dry matter percentage and root neatness were measured after harvesting. ANOVA showed that N and mixed N and B application did not have significant effect on root and sugar yield but had significant effect on sugar percentage. Soil B application had more significant effect than spraying on PP22 and 7233. Effect of foliar N and B application on root yield depends on cultivar and application time. N foliar application in PP22 led to increasing sugar yield, and root yield reached 100 ton/ha. B soil application led to increasing sugar yield in PP22 and 7233 but N and B foliar application at 6-8 leaf stage led to increasing sugar yield in PP22 and IC and soil application in 7233. B application increased quality beet production. Foliar N and B application is recommendable but foliar B application only recommendable on IC. Soil application of N increased sugar yield in 7233 and IC but foliar application at 14-16 leaf stage increased sugar yield in PP22. Soil B application in 7233 and N and B application in 7233 increased sugar yield. If the aim is to increase root yield, then foliar N and N and B application will be suitable, but for increasing sugar percent, foliar N application at 14-16 leaf stage for IC and PP22 and soil application of N for 7233 is recommend. Soil application of B for PP22 and IC and foliar B application at 14-16 leaf stage for 7233 increased sugar percent. Foliar application at 6-8 leaf stage for PP22 and soil N and B application is recommendable for IC and 7233.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>6</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>253</start>
          <end>255</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2008</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2008-issue_3_4/a14.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>