<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Correlation of PCR and IFAS with eggplant bioassays for identification of Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. sepedonicus</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Abdel-Mawgood</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Ahmed L.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Faculty of Agriculture, Minia University, Minia 61111, Egypt. Current address: Faculty of Food and Agricultural Sciences, King Saud University, P.O. Box 2460, Riyadh, 11451, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">German</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Thomas L.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Entomology Department, University of Wisconsin- Madison, 1630 Linden Drive, Madison WI 53706.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Correlation was examined among immunoflurorescence, eggplant pathogenicity bioassays and a PCR assay for identification of Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. sepedonicus (Cms) using the novel primer pair Cms A/Cms B designed based upon the sequence of the 16S rRNA gene. These primers identified 11 Cms isolates in eggplant extracts and an additional 14 isolates in pure culture, and results of PCR using these primers correlated 100% with results of IFAS and eggplant pathogenicity assays. Cmm, Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. michiganensis, did not produce symptoms in eggplant and was not identified by IFAS or PCR. These results demonstrate that PCR with the primer pair Cms A/Cms B can be as a complimentary test to IFAS and eggplant pathogenicity assays for the detection of Cms isolates found in the Midwestern United States.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>4</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>179</start>
          <end>182</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2006</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2006-issue_2/a9.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>