<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Polyphenol oxidase in Ocimum basilicum during growth, development and following cold stress</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Shafran</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Einat</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Aromatic, Medicinal and Spice Crops, ARO, Newe Ya’ar Research Center, P.O. Box 1021, Ramat Yishay 30095, Israel. Department of Plant and Environmental Sciences, the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem 91904, Israel.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Dudai</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Nativ</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Plant and Environmental Sciences, the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem 91904, Israel.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Mayer</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Alfred M.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Aromatic, Medicinal and Spice Crops, ARO, Newe Ya’ar Research Center, P.O. Box 1021, Ramat Yishay 30095, Israel.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The activity of polyphenoloxidase (PPO) in the chloroplasts of leaves of basil (Ocimum basilicum L.) was followed during the growth and development of the plants and following exposure to cold stress. The levels of activity showed very great variability in the leaves of a given plant, the youngest leaves had the highest activity and mature leaves generally the lowest. Different cultivars of basil differed in the level of activity of their PPO and this level changed during development and with the season of the year. Levels of activity and sensitivity of different cultivars to stress were not correlated. Total phenolics showed no clear correlation with sensitivity to cold. The implications of these findings on reports on correlations between levels of PPO activity in plants and their responses to environmental stress are discussed. The great variability of PPO activity within a plant and during its growth and development must always be taken into account. Simple sampling techniques can result in seriously flawed conclusions about correlations.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>5</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>254</start>
          <end>257</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2007</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2007-issue_3_4/a17.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>