<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Soil fertility management in North-East Romania</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Jitareanu</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Gerard</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>University of Agricultural Sciences and Veterinary Medicine, Iasi, M. Sadoveanu 3, 700490, Romania.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Ailincai</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Costica</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Agricultural Research and Development Station of Podu-Iloaiei, Nationala 86, 707365, Iasi County, Romania.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Bucur</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>University of Agricultural Sciences and Veterinary Medicine, Iasi, M. Sadoveanu 3, 700490, Romania.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The effect of different soil tillage systems on crop yield and soil chemical and physical characteristics were studied during 1985-2006. Experiments were established in split-split plots on a typical cambic chernozem of clay-loam texture, a mean humus content of 3.3%, a weakly acid reaction and a moderate level of mineral nutrients. Twenty-two years of ploughing to a depth of 20 cm resulted in settling of the soil at a depth of 19-27 cm; causing high bulk density (1.52 g/cm3), low porosity (43.3%) and a high degree of settling (16.4% of volume). In the case of chisel tillage, bulk density decreased from 1.41 to 1.33 g/cm3, settling degree was lower at 0.8% and hydraulic conductivity increased from 6.4 to 21.5 mm/hour at a depth of 40cm. The mean wheat yield over the period, using 20 cm ploughing was 3690 kg/ha. Compared to 20 cm ploughing, using chisel ploughing and disks and also by repeated disking produced lower yields by 5.0% (-170 kg/ha) and 11.0% (-423 kg/ha), respectively. In maize, fertilizers were better utilized under conditions of deeper soil tillage (30 cm ploughing; chisel ploughing and disks) where yield increases varied with fertilizer rates from 98 to 131% (3940-5260 kg/ha). In soybean, mean yields using 20 cm ploughing and chisel ploughing and disk tillage were similar; in the case of chisel ploughing and disks, yield was higher by 12.0% (260 kg/ha) and with disks alone, yields were lower by 15.0% (336 kg/ha). The results indicate that soil tillage systems must be adjusted to plant requirements for crop rotation and to the pedoclimatic conditions of the area.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>5</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>3&amp;4</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>349</start>
          <end>353</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2007</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2007-issue_3_4/e1.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>