<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Effect of small wheel tractor and crawler tractor on soil physical properties</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Mari</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">G. Rasool</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Mechanization, College of Engineering, Nanjing Agricultural University, Postal Code 210031, Nanjing, China.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Changying</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Ji</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Agricultural Mechanization, College of Engineering, Nanjing Agricultural University, Postal Code 210031, Nanjing, China.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The use of the two-wheel small tractors and crawlers’ tractors developed rapidly in China. In this study it was investigated the impact of these relatively small tractors and crawlers on compaction of a clay loam soil in south east China. Penetrometer resistance (Rp) and bulk density (ρb) due to one, two and four passes were studied in three transects, using soil penetration resistance (Rp) and bulk density (ρb) as soil compaction indicators. The relationship between soil water content and Rp, the comparison of soil compaction induced by wheel tractors and the crawlers, the effect of tractor mass on compaction, the effect of number of tractor passes and tillage on Rp, and the effect of compaction on soil was studied. Compared with wheel tractor, the crawler tractor created a more compacted plow layer due to increased passes required with this system. Crawler tractors had significantly higher Rp than wheel tractor. After trafficking in a corn harvested field, the values of Rp were investigated in the 0-5, 5- 10 and 10-15 cm depth intervals. With the development of mechanical tillage in China, mean values between properties were determined. The problem of soil compaction may be significantly increased, causing use of more passes in field.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>6</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>190</start>
          <end>194</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2008</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2008-issue_1/e10.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>