<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Green tea and health: An overview</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Pham-Huy</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Lien Ai Nguyen</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Lucile Salter Packard Children’s Hospital, Stanford University Medical Center, 725 Welch Road, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">He</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Hua</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Analytical Chemistry, China Pharmaceutical University, Nanjing, 210009, China.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Pham-Huy</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Chuong</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Laboratory of Toxicology, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Paris 5, 4 avenue de l’Observatoire, 75006 Paris, France.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Tea is the most widely consumed beverage in the world, except water. Recently, numerous researches have discovered the strong antioxidant potential mostly in green tea. This property is essentially due to catechins belonging to the polyphenolic flavonoids. These compounds are strong scavengers of free radicals and oxidants that could develop many ailments such as cancer, cardio-vascular disorders, inflammatory diseases, etc. Recent in vitro, animal and human studies have reported that green tea or its catechins may prevent cancer development, reduce cholesterol levels and hypertension, protect neurodegenerative diseases, improve dental health, etc. Although the antioxidant potential of green tea is evident, the results from epidemiological and clinicalstudies of the relationship between green tea and prevention of these diseases in humans are mixed. More controlled, well-designed clinical trials are needed to determine the effectiveness of green tea in human chemoprevention. The aim of this overview article is to revise the most recent medicinal studies of green tea, its chemical composition, its catechin pharmacokinetics and its side-effects.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>6</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>6</start>
          <end>13</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2008</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2008-issue_1/f1.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>