<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Poverty alleviation, food security and the well-being of the human population trough family poultry in low-income food-deficit countries</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Guèye</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">E.F.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Senegalese Institute of Agricultural Research (ISRA), B.P. 2057, Dakar-Hann, Senegal.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Family poultry (FP), which are still very important in low-income food-deficit countries (LIFDCs), have been kept by local communities for many generations. These birds usually make up more than 80% of the national poultry flock in many LIFDCs. Although requiring low levels of inputs, FP are a valuable asset to local populations, especially in underprivileged groups and less favoured areas. FP represent an appropriate system to provide additional income to the generally resource-poor small farmers, especially women, to supply the fast-growing human population with high quality protein, hence their significant contribution to poverty alleviation, food security and the overall well-being of household's members. Nevertheless, there is a strong need for governments, non-governmental organizations, international agencies and donors to design, implement, monitor and evaluate FP development programmes by taking socio-cultural issues into account.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>12</start>
          <end>21</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_2/j2-food-3.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>