<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>An Analysis of space-filling fractal dimensions, resulting from measurements on plant canopies</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Critten</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">D. L.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Silsoe Research Institute, Silsoe, Bedfordshire MK45 4HS, UK.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>We first describe experiments designed to obtain fractal dimensions (dk) associated with different plant canopies. The method involves 2 or 3-dimensional Fourier analyses of grey levels within photographic or video images of square sections of the canopy, viewed vertically downwards. From these analyses amplitude/wavenumber relationships are used to obtain fractal dimensions (dk). We find plausible values of between 1 and 3 for space-filled vector dimensions (n) that correspond to the measured fractal dimensions (dk). A linear relationship between the exponent (σ) from the amplitude/wavenumber relationship and vector dimensions (n) is discovered. This relationship is shown not to match the non-linear (bijection) equation which defines (n). A theory which brings these results into concord is then presented, generating a correction factor (L) for the linear relationship. The factor recognises the restriction of ‘information’ which must occur when a single defining vector dimension is used to represent isotropic patterns from 2 or more vector dimensions. Agreement between predicted values of (L) and values gleaned from the literature is broadly satisfactory, and synthesised values of (dk) obtained using (L) agree well with those obtained from the defining bijection equation.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>238</start>
          <end>243</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_2/j2-agriculture-79.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>