<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Application of controlled and modified atmospheres for the preservation of postharvest quality in fresh fruits and vegetables</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Fonseca</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Susana C.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Escola Superior de Biotecnologia, Universidade Católica Portuguesa, R. Dr. António Bernardino de Almeida, P-4200-072 Porto, Portugal.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Malcata</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">F. Xavier</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Escola Superior de Biotecnologia, Universidade Católica Portuguesa, R. Dr. António Bernardino de Almeida, P-4200-072, Porto, Portugal.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>Uses of preservation technologies for fruits and vegetables based on alteration of the overhead atmosphere have been increasing in the latest decades, as consumers demand fewer and less extensive treatments (of chemical nature or otherwise) of food items. This paper provides a specific review of available technologies which share as common core the deliberate formulation of the overhead atmosphere, with the goal of extending the useful life of fresh fruits and vegetables. Classical and novel technologies pertaining to controlled and modified atmospheres are duly presented and discussed, in terms of principles, advantages, limitations and applications. Finally, updated recommendations encompassing controlled and modified atmospheres are listed.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>82</start>
          <end>87</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_2/j2-food-73.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>