<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<modsCollection xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <mods version="3.5">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Vitamin C and E can alleviate negative effects of heat stress in Japanese quails</title>
      <subTitle />
    </titleInfo>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Sahin</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Kazim</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Animal Nutrition, University of Firat, 23119 Elazig, Turkey.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Sahin</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Nurhan</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Internal Diseases, Veterinary Faculty, University of Firat, 23119 Elazig, Turkey.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Onderci</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Muhittin</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Veterinary Control and Research Institute, 23119 Elazig, Turkey.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Gursu</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Mehmet F.</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, School of Medicine, University of Firat, 23119 Elazig, Turkey.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart type="family">Issi</namePart>
      <namePart type="given">Mustafa</namePart>
      <role>
        <roleTerm type="text" authority="marcrelator">author</roleTerm>
      </role>
      <affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, School of Medicine, University of Firat, 23119 Elazig, Turkey.</affiliation>
    </name>
    <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
    <genre>article</genre>
    <originInfo>
      <dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf" keyDate="yes"></dateIssued>
    </originInfo>
    <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      <languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm>
    </language>
    <physicalDescription>
      <form authority="marcform">electronic</form>
    </physicalDescription>
    <abstract>The present study investigates the effects of vitamin C (L-ascorbic acid) and E (α-tocopherol acetate) supplementation on egg production, egg quality, apparent digestibility, serum metabolites, and antioxidant status of Japanese quails (Coturnix coturnix japonica) exposed to a high ambient temperature (33 °C). One hundred and twenty laying Japanese quails (45-d-old) were divided into four groups, 30 birds per group. Quails were fed a basal diet or the basal diet supplemented with either 250 mg of L-ascorbic acid/kg of diet, 250 mg of α-tocopherol-acetate/kg of diet, or 250 mg of L-ascorbic acid plus 250 mg α-tocopherol-acetate/kg of diet. Separately or as a combination, supplemental vitamin C and E significantly increased live weight, feed intake and egg production (P &lt; 0.05). Separately, dietary supplementation of vitamin C and E improved the egg quality, and the combination of vitamins C and E resulted in a greatest egg weight, specific gravity and Haugh unit value, thickest egg shell, and heaviest egg shell weight (P &lt; 0.05). Apparent digestibility of nutrients (DM, OM, CP, and EE) was increased by supplementation of vitamin C and E (P &lt; 0.05). Separately or as a combination, supplemental vitamin C and E increased serum concentration of total protein but decreased corticosterone, glucose, and cholesterol concentrations (P &lt; 0.05). Supplemental vitamin C and E also increased serum vitamin C and E but decreased MDA (malondialdehyde) concentrations (P &lt; 0.05). Results of the present study show that dietary supplementation of vitamin C and E, particularly as a combination, improved the performance, egg quality and antioxidant status of laying Japanese quails exposed to heat stress. Such a combination of supplement can offer a potential protective management practice in preventing heat stress-related losses in performance of laying Japanese quails.</abstract>
    <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
        <title>Journal of Food, Agriculture and Environment</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <originInfo>
        <publisher>WFL Publisher</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <identifier type="issn">1459-0263</identifier>
      <part>
        <detail type="volume">
          <number>1</number>
          <caption>v.</caption>
        </detail>
        <detail type="issue">
          <number>2</number>
          <caption>no.</caption>
        </detail>
        <extent unit="pages">
          <start>244</start>
          <end>249</end>
        </extent>
        <date>2003</date>
      </part>
    </relatedItem>
    <identifier type="uri">http://world-food.net/download/journals/2003-issue_2/j2-agriculture-85.pdf</identifier>
  </mods>
</modsCollection>