<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<records>
  <record>
    <language>eng</language>
    <publisher>Estonian Academic Agricultural Society</publisher>
    <journalTitle>Agraarteadus</journalTitle>
    <issn>1024-0845</issn>
    <eissn>2228-4893</eissn>
    <publicationDate>2014-12-20</publicationDate>
    <volume>25</volume>
    <issue>2</issue>
    <startPage>59</startPage>
    <endPage>63</endPage>
    <documentType>article</documentType>
    <title language="eng">The method of correction of amino acid metabolism of cows in the area of micronutrient deficiency in Ukraine</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <name>S. P. Doletsky</name>
        <email>vet_uaan@meta.ua</email>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
          </authors>
    <affiliationsList>
      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
        The National Academy of Agrarian Sciences of Ukraine, 37 Vasilkovskaja Str, Kyiv, Ukraine     
      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>
    <abstract language="eng">
Using the original method the new effective "Pankorm"
feed supplement was developed, made from a pig’s pancreas after
extraction of insulin from it. The aim of the study was establishment of
preventive action effectiveness of the new "Pankorm" feed supplement
for cows in case of amino acid metabolism disorder in their bodies in the
area of micronutrient deficiency. For the purpose of conduct of the
research a group of 30 cows was formed on the basis of similarity. The
control group consisted of animals that received the basic ration. The
cows received the feed supplement daily during two months of winter
housing season in the amount of 20 percent of the total amount of
concentrated feed. the animals that received the "Pankorm" feed
supplement during 1.5 months demonstrated a significant reduction of
signs of iodine, cobalt and copper deficiency, and normalisation of pulse
and breathing rate.
	</abstract>
    <fullTextUrl format="pdf">
      http://agrt.emu.ee/pdf/2014_2_doletsky.pdf
    </fullTextUrl>
    <keywords language="eng">    
      <keyword>cow</keyword>
      <keyword>feed supplement</keyword>
      <keyword>amino acid</keyword>
      <keyword>blood nutrients</keyword>
    </keywords>
  </record>

<record>
    <language>est</language>
    <publisher>Estonian Academic Agricultural Society</publisher>
    <journalTitle>Agraarteadus</journalTitle>
    <issn>1024-0845</issn>
    <eissn>2228-4893</eissn>
    <publicationDate>2014-12-20</publicationDate>
    <volume>25</volume>
    <issue>2</issue>
    <startPage>64</startPage>
    <endPage>69</endPage>
    <documentType>article</documentType>
    <title language="eng">Effect of thermal shock and pre-sprouting on formation of structural elements of yield</title>
    <title language="est">Soojalöögi ja eelidandamise mõju kartuli saagikusele ning selle kvaliteedile</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <name>Viacheslav Eremeev</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
	<author>
        <name>Berit Tein</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Peeter Lääniste</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Erkki Mäeorg</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Raido Laes</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
            <author>
        <name>Kalle Margus</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
            <author>
        <name>Juhan Jõudu</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
    </authors>
    <affiliationsList>
      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
		Estonian University of Life Sciences, Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences, Kreutzwaldi 5, Tartu 51014 Estonia
      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>
    <abstract language="eng">
The trials were carried out in 2012 and 2013 at the Estonian University of Life Sciences. Total yield, marketable yield, number of tubers per plant, average weight of tubers, tuber starch content was studied in cultivar 'Ants' &#x0028;medium late&#x0029; and 'Laura' &#x0028;medium early&#x0029;. Following treatments were used: untreated control &#x0028;T0&#x0029; Seed tubers were planted directly from storage house &#x0028;storage temperature 4°C&#x0029;; Thermal shock &#x0028;TS&#x0029;. Seed tubers were kept before planting 5 days in a room with a temperature of 30°C and 2 days in a room with a temperature of 12°C; Pre-sprouting &#x0028;PS&#x0029;. Seed tubers were kept before planting 26 days in a room with a temperature of 15°C and 10 days in a room with a temperature of 12°C.
<br/>From the results in 2012 it was observed that pre-planting thermal treatments increased the number of tubers per plant compared to pre-sprouting. Pre-sprouted tubers gave higher average weight of tubers than in thermal shock variants. Hence, there were lower number tubers with higher weight of tubers in pre-sprouted variants in 2012. The results of experiments &#x0028;2012–2013&#x0029; indicated that pre-planting treatments did not have any significant effect on the yield of cultivar 'Ants'. In 2013 the yield of cultivar 'Laura' was significantly increased by pre-sprouting, showing higher number of tubers and higher weight of tubers. Therefore also the share of marketable tubers in the yield of both varieties was higher in pre-sprouted variants in 2012. Therefore, in case of cultivar 'Ants' it could be concluded that the thermal shock increases the number of tubers and decreases the weight of the tubers. The starch yield of cultivar 'Laura' was significantly higher in pre-sprouted variant in 2012. That was due to the significantly higher tuber yield in the same variant.
    </abstract>
    <fullTextUrl format="pdf">
      http://agrt.emu.ee/pdf/2014_2_eremeev.pdf
    </fullTextUrl>
    <keywords language="eng">    
      <keyword>Solanum tuberosum L.</keyword>
      <keyword>tubers per plant</keyword>
      <keyword>tuber weight</keyword>
      <keyword>tuber yield</keyword>
      <keyword>starch yield</keyword>
      <keyword>starch content</keyword>
    </keywords>
  </record>

<record>
    <language>est</language>
    <publisher>Estonian Academic Agricultural Society</publisher>
    <journalTitle>Agraarteadus</journalTitle>
    <issn>1024-0845</issn>
    <eissn>2228-4893</eissn>
    <publicationDate>2014-12-20</publicationDate>
    <volume>25</volume>
    <issue>2</issue>
    <startPage>70</startPage>
    <endPage>76</endPage>
    <documentType>article</documentType>
    <title language="eng">Ammonia and hydrogen sulphide emission from liquid manure storages</title>
    <title language="est">Ammoniaagi ja väävelvesiniku emissioonist vedelsõnnikuhoidlatest</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <name>Allan Kaasik</name>
                <email>allan.kaasik@emu.ee</email>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Marek Maasikmets</name>
        <affiliationId>2</affiliationId>
      </author>
    </authors>
    <affiliationsList>
      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
		Estonian University of Life Sciences, Institute of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Sciences, F.R. Kreutzwaldi 62, 51014 Tartu, Estonia 
      </affiliationName>
            <affiliationName affiliationId="2">
		Estonian Environmental Research Centre 
      </affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>
    <abstract language="eng">
The aim of this study was to determine relationships between ammonia and hydrogen sulphide emissions and the type of manure storage, and correlations between emissions and Estonian climatic conditions. Total ammonia &#x0028;NH<sub>3</sub>&#x0029; and hydrogen sulphide &#x0028;H<sub>2</sub>S&#x0029; emissions depend directly on the open area of manure storage. Of ring-shaped manure storage, with permanent roofing &#x0028;H1, open area 3.9 m<sup>2</sup>&#x0029;, 2.7 kg NH<sub>3</sub> and 0.02 kg H<sub>2</sub>S were emitted per year. Emissions from plastic lagoons &#x0028;H4, open area 4100 m<sup>2</sup>&#x0029; were 920 kg NH<sub>3</sub> and 4.6 kg H<sub>2</sub>S per year. Emissions per animal unit &#x0028;AU&#x0029; per year from storage H1 were 14.6 g NH<sub>3</sub> and 0.08 g H<sub>2</sub>S, and from storage H4 722.8 g NH<sub>3</sub> and 3.65 g H<sub>2</sub>S. The emission of pollutants, per m<sup>2</sup> of open area also depended on the depth of stored manure. The highest emissions were from the ring-shaped uncovered storage systems with high walls &#x0028;H2&#x0029;, at 1.05 g m<sup>-2</sup> 24h<sup>-1</sup>. Emissions from ring-shaped uncovered storage with low walls &#x0028;H3&#x0029; was 25% smaller, 0.79 g m<sup>-2</sup> 24h<sup>-1</sup>, and from the manure lagoons &#x0028;H4&#x0029; 42% lower, 0.61 g m<sup>-2</sup> 24h<sup>-1</sup>. However the variation between storage systems was not significant &#x0028;P &gt; 0.05&#x0029;. Temperature &#x0028;°C&#x0029; had the greatest effect on increasing ammonia emission &#x0028;r = 0.65***&#x0029;. The correlation between temperature and hydrogen sulphide emissions was not significant &#x0028;r = 0.18&#x0029;. Relative humidity &#x0028;%&#x0029; had no effect to ammonia and hydrogen sulphide emission &#x0028;r = 0.02 and 0.16 respectively&#x0029;.
    </abstract>
    <fullTextUrl format="pdf">
      http://agrt.emu.ee/pdf/2014_2_kaasik.pdf
    </fullTextUrl>
    <keywords language="eng">    
      <keyword>ammonia emission</keyword>
      <keyword>hydrogen sulphide emission</keyword>
      <keyword>liquid manure</keyword>
      <keyword>manure storage</keyword>
      <keyword>cattle</keyword>
    </keywords>
  </record>
  
<record>
    <language>eng</language>
    <publisher>Estonian Academic Agricultural Society</publisher>
    <journalTitle>Agraarteadus</journalTitle>
    <issn>1024-0845</issn>
    <eissn>2228-4893</eissn>
    <publicationDate>2014-12-20</publicationDate>
    <volume>25</volume>
    <issue>2</issue>
    <startPage>77</startPage>
    <endPage>81</endPage>
    <documentType>article</documentType>
    <title language="eng">Isolation of Eimeria oocysts from soil samples: a simple method described in detail</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <name>Brian Lassen</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Triin Lepik</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
    </authors>
    <affiliationsList>
      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
		Estonian University of Life Sciences, Institute of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Sciences, Kreutzwaldi 62, 51014 Tartu, Estonia 
		</affiliationName>
    </affiliationsList>
    <abstract language="eng">
Molecular methods are currently available to detect parasitic DNA in soil, but do not replace the need for direct parasitological methods that can identify the extent of contamination. This report describes an inexpensive and fast flotation method for retrieving Eimeria oocysts from soil that requires few tools. Soil samples were experimentally contaminated with 50,000 E. bovis oocysts and compared with soil-free controls. A separate experiment tested the effect of mechanical stress by shaking the soil and oocyst mix 0, 1, 5, and 10 times before attempting to retrieve the oocysts. The percentage of oocysts retrieved using the flotation method was 22%, which was similar to the results obtained with previously described, more labour-intensive methods. The presence of soil reduced the percentage of oocysts that could be retrieved by 23%. A single shake of the oocysts and soil mixture was sufficient to significantly reduce the recoverable proportion of oocysts. The results indicated that the developed simple method can be applied to recover oocysts, and that gentle handling of soil samples prior to oocyst isolation is important.
    </abstract>
    <fullTextUrl format="pdf">
      http://agrt.emu.ee/pdf/2014_2_lassen.pdf
    </fullTextUrl>
    <keywords language="eng">    
      <keyword>Eimeria</keyword>
      <keyword>soil</keyword>
      <keyword>diagnosis</keyword>
      <keyword>contamination</keyword>
      <keyword>flotation</keyword>
      <keyword>method</keyword>
    </keywords>
  </record>

<record>
    <language>est</language>
    <publisher>Estonian Academic Agricultural Society</publisher>
    <journalTitle>Agraarteadus</journalTitle>
    <issn>1024-0845</issn>
    <eissn>2228-4893</eissn>
    <publicationDate>2014-12-20</publicationDate>
    <volume>25</volume>
    <issue>2</issue>
    <startPage>82</startPage>
    <endPage>95</endPage>
    <documentType>article</documentType>
    <title language="eng">The impact of using humic substance for growing potato on quality indicators of tubers</title>
    <title language="est">Humiinainete mõju kartuli saagikusele ja mugula mõningatele kvaliteedi näitajatele</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <name>Kalle Margus</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Viacheslav Eremeev</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Peeter Lääniste</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Erkki Mäeorg</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Berit Tein</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Raido Laes</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
      <author>
        <name>Juhan Jõudu</name>
        <affiliationId>1</affiliationId>
      </author>
              </authors>
    <affiliationsList>
      <affiliationName affiliationId="1">
      Estonian University of Life Sciences, Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Sciences, Kreutzwaldi 5, Tartu 51014 Estonia
            </affiliationName>
                </affiliationsList>
    <abstract language="eng">
The impact of using humic substance for growing potato on quality indicators of tubers. Humic preparations are concentrated and economical form of organic matter which can relieve humus depletion caused by conventional fertilization methods. The trials were carried out in 2012 and 2013 at the Estonian University of Life Sciences in Estonia. The yield of tubers and starch, and commercial yield of potato, number of tubers per plant, tuber weight was studied in cultivar 'Ants' and 'Laura'. In the experiments humic preparation (HP) "Ruponics" was used in two different treatment variants. "Ruponics" 50 l ha<sup>-1</sup> (HP50), "Ruponics" 25 l ha<sup>-1</sup> (HP25) and control (HP0) 0 l ha<sup>-1</sup> variant. The experiments showed that potato cultivars 'Ants' and 'Laura', HP did not have any significant positive effect on the tuber yield, commercial tuber yield or starch yield in 2012. Yields were higher in 2013 reaching up to 52.4 t ha<sup>-1</sup> and year 2013 'Laura' HP50 had yield 35.9 t ha<sup>-1</sup>. The main role of the addition of HP is improving nutrient mobility in the soil and higher uptake of nutrients to plants. Positive effect of HP should appear when plant is growing under unfavourable conditions.
    </abstract>
    <fullTextUrl format="pdf">
      http://agrt.emu.ee/pdf/2014_2_margus.pdf
    </fullTextUrl>
    <keywords language="eng">    
      <keyword>meat</keyword>
      <keyword>Solanum tuberosum L.</keyword>
      <keyword>number of tubers per plant</keyword>
      <keyword>tuber weight</keyword>
      <keyword>tuber yield</keyword>
      <keyword>starch yield</keyword>
      <keyword>starch content</keyword>
    </keywords>
  </record>
  </records>